Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
So, have you finished?
Yes, that's it.
Any other plans?
I've got an address.
I'll go see tomorrow.
Where are you going?
To work.
It's not too early?
Recently, I've had to be there early.
So, it's finished?
Yes, that's it.
That's good.
- How much?
- Count!
Jean-François?!
What are you doing there?
Come into the house.
Hear me, Jean-François?
Where are you going, you pig?
Help me!
Who do you think you are,
you animal?
Wake up, asshole!
Wake up, you shit!
Wake up!
- What's wrong?
- He's just a pig.
- Should I call a doctor?
- No, he'll be alright soon.
We'll lift him up.
We have to make him run.
Come on.
No, that way.
If we don't bring him round,
he's had it.
I think I passed out.
Come on, let's walk a bit.
- Who are you?
- Me?
He's working on the house.
You hired him.
There.
How old are you?
22.
That's really something.
Some people are 25 or 30...
but to be 22...
that's amazing.
Absolutely amazing.
I need to know what to expect.
I'll have lots of money soon.
Who'd give money to such an idiot?
I've already been paid.
Remember?
I never understood that.
- You never understood?
- Never.
And you never will.
Don't worry your head about it.
Did he give you the advance?
He promised me it in 3 days.
I can help you this weekend
if you want.
That'd be great.
The roof beams need changing.
I'm off. I'm working tonight.
Leaving already?
Yeah.
Do you want a coffee?
- Want a coffee?
- No, thanks.
What's it about? Dope?
Nothing like that.
That workman up there...
needs his advance, but after that,
I don't know how I'll pay him.
Don't you need someone?
No, and it's not my decision.
If it's to make someone pay up,
that's my thing.
It's not. I can't tell you any more.
I'm not sure I'll make it.
Put in a word for me.
Want to take my place?
I'm not sure they'll need me.
I'm stone-broke. I'm on the street.
If it works, I'll help you out.
How long will it take?
A day.
You'll earn that much in a day?
I doubt I'll get through it.
- It worked last time.
- That was last time.
When do you go?
I don't know. Last month,
they said they'd summon me,
but I haven't heard.
What did he want?
Money.
His business isn't going too well.
I don't think there's anything left.
Pity. He paid for your lawyer
when you were in jail.
I haven't forgotten.
- Know what your sister said?
- Don't start.
You belong in prison, nowhere else.
My sister always speaks the truth.
Always...
- How's it going?
- OK.
How long now?
10 days.
And the other side?
It'll all be finished in 10 days.
Good.
Hello. I think he's had it.
A striped envelope.
No, I couldn't get it back.
I'll send you the photos.
Shit!
Hey, mister!
Where are you?
- What is it?
- Can you help me?
Quick!
What's wrong?
We must break the door down.
He's passed out.
There's an ax on the terrace.
Jean-François!
What're you doing?
He's dead.
- Aren't you tired?
- A bit.
How's things, Dad?
Fine.
- Hello, madam.
- Hello. Come in.
Go on.
Thank you for yesterday.
That's OK. I'm sorry for you.
Don't be.
With the quantities he'd been taking,
it was inevitable.
I hope you'll continue the work.
No.
His sister will inherit the house,
so it's not my problem now.
Oh?
Look, I'm really sorry.
Who's going to pay me now?
I doubt his sister will ever come.
She'll get an agency
to sell the house.
I never encouraged him
to take that shit.
He doesn't need it anymore.
When are you leaving?
After the funeral.
He was waiting on a job.
Do you know about it?
Maybe the letter will come
before you leave.
It came yesterday.
You've got it?
Can I see it?
There's nothing to see.
A train ticket and a paid hotel bill.
What'll you do with it?
Get the ticket refunded.
I'll buy it off you.
OK, you can have it.
If it works, I won't forget you.
A train ticket
and a paid hotel bill.
Where was the ticket for?
Paris.
The name of the hotel?
That I do remember: Windsor.
What did Pierre Bléreau
intend to do with it?
To replace Jean-François.
What does he know?
He just knew there was
a lot of money at stake.
When did they discuss it?
Yesterday morning.
Did anyone go in
other than the police and doctors?
No... Yes, the workman.
I asked him to smash the door
to the bathroom.
When did Mr. Godon intend to leave?
Today.
Thank you very much.
Where were you during their talk?
- In the corridor.
- You heard their words?
Of course.
Sorry, my brother over there has got it.
He'll show it to you.
Come with me, sir.
If you want the ticket,
go see my brother over there.
But you have to be present.
Want me to throw you out, asshole?
You're crazy!
What is it, Ludo?
He wants the ticket,
but won't move his fat ass.
Come on, I'll show you his ticket.
- Hello?
- Mr. Godon?
Yeah.
Got a pen and paper?
Just a second.
By noon tomorrow,
go to Gare du Nord. Locker 103.
You'll find a train ticket
with instructions.
The code is 402 #4.
Get out one stop
before the station on the ticket.
Don't forget: one stop before.
Jesus...
Good day, sir. Your ticket, please.
Thank you. Pleasant journey.
His stop's Valen?
- What time?
- 5:08.
I'll see to it.
I need 2 unmarked cars,
Valen? Station, 5:08.
Hello.
- Hello.
- Where to?
- Know where that is?
- Yes.
- Is it far?
- It's a fair way.
The number's 375 MHJ 45.
Get out.
Go over there.
- Undress.
- Why?
Gotta search you.
And the rest.
What the hell are you doing?
Get dressed.
I stopped there.
As I did a U-turn,
he went to the sign.
Didn't it seem strange
that he stopped here?
People can stop where they like.
You didn't notice anything else?
Nothing in particular.
Go sit down.
- You're here?
- Yeah, guess so.
- Found a player?
- Yeah.
- Don't like him?
- I do.
Each to his own!
Who's that?
I can explain.
Shut up!
Call José!
Go get José!
Hello, Alain.
This the boy who's playing?
Yes, it's him.
Good...
Brave...
There's only 13 of us. Not many.
In Istanbul,
there were 42 of us.
The opening bet was 500,000.
How much is it here?
If it's under 100,000,
there's no point.
At least, otherwise it's not worth it.
Have you been around the place?
It's not very big.
Well, I'll wait downstairs.
Who's he?
What do you mean?
The guy from the crossroads.
- He had the card.
- I wasn't expecting him.
Jean-François is dead.
What're you talking about?
He took an overdose.
Let me see your papers.
Did he tell you about this?
I knew he was waiting
for a letter.
He hoped to earn a lot.
I found it
and followed the instructions.
Do you know what it's about?
No idea.
Maybe the cops sent him.
Who would agree to do that?
Maybe they didn't tell him.
That'd mean the cops are watching us
and will show up.
So, it's now or never to get out.
If the cops show up and we've gone,
they'll think I ratted.
I'd rather be arrested.
- Is your man here?
- Yes, no problem.
- We're about to start.
- Coming.
If I don't suit you, I can leave.
You can't leave now.
What if it doesn't suit me?
You gotta play now.
- How much are you betting?
- Dunno.
What do you think?
Dunno. Don't ask me.
I'm gonna bet the minimum.
My cylinder doesn't work.
What's going on?
- His gun won't work.
- So, change it!
Supervisors, hand out
one bullet to each player.
I should get my share now.
You've gotta see it through.
Man is only born once
and only dies once.
Get ready!
Nothing else happens.
- Be philosophical.
- Round 1's starting.
You're a descendant of Schopenhauer.
Mr. Schlondorff, go the other side,
please.
OK, I'm going.
Be philosophical about it.
Get ready!
Round 1 is about to start.
Excuse me.
Blow up a head for me.
The audience must step back.
Step back... back...
This'll bring you luck.
More... Thank you.
Load your cylinder!
Number 13, got a problem?
Problem with your gun?
Got a problem?
Nobody get in the ring.
- Get out.
- He can't load it.
Give it here.
This is to open the cylinder, OK?
OK, that's enough.
Raise your gun!
Spin the cylinder!
More!
Take aim!
Cock the hammer.
Number 13,
don't turn your head.
When the bulb lights up,
you shoot!
Everyone stare at the bulb.
Wait! Wait!
Number 13 didn't shoot.
Shoot!
Why won't you shoot? Shoot!
Mr. Alain, what's got into your player?
If he doesn't, we'll shoot him,
and you'll get fined!
I'll count to three.
One...
Go on, shoot!
Two...
Hey, get out of the ring.
You finished your scene, you shit?
Shit to you, too!
Don't start that crap again.
Why didn't you shoot?
Why didn't you?
You gotta shoot, dammit!
Want some morphine?
No, I don't.
Morphine's fuckin' cool.
They all take it.
Who's not had his dose?
- Us.
- Come on, then.
I bet 500,000 on Number 13.
Get lost!
I want to bet on you.
Beat it, you little shit!
I've lost my player.
Can I bet on yours?
I want 50% of your cut.
Alright.
Just for this round.
OK.
Put your name down on Number 13.
350 on Number 13.
350 on Number 10.
C'mon, get him up here.
It's OK, he's here.
What are you playing at?
You can't get out of here.
Put your bullets in the cylinder.
2 bullets!
Raise your gun!
Spin your cylinder!
More!
Stop!
Take aim!
Cock the hammer!
Don't look me in the eyes.
When the bulb lights up,
you shoot!
Shit!
He didn't have time.
The bullet's in the barrel.
Hans!
Come here, Hans.
Go get him.
350 on Number 7.
I lost my player.
I know, it's written here.
Shit happens.
No one will let me bet
on another player.
Why not?
I don't know, I'm bad luck.
What can I do about it?
Don't you run this organization?
What's that change?
I'm here to gamble
the 2 million in this case.
It's in your interest.
We don't force anyone into the shit.
You've already killed two.
That's great.
You can make big money.
When you start, you finish.
What's it to you?
1.5 million on Number 6.
Very well.
I did well to bet on your player.
You staying with us?
No.
With the 2 brothers.
I've gambled the lot.
If I lose,
you'll have to go home alone.
Cut the crap.
Weird... They're brothers.
God, I hate that number!
Forget it, it's nothing.
I said, forget it.
If he kills a third, you get a bonus.
That'd be wonderful.
Gentlemen!
Third round.
Let's go.
Now!
Get up!
Number 8...
Number 3...
Number 11...
Number 11!
Mr. Schlondorff,
your player must get in the ring.
Just a second.
What is it?
Oh, nothing. A touch of diarrhea.
Get him up there.
I'm gonna get you.
What a fucker!
What's he playing at?
He better calm down.
Supervisors, hand out the bullets now.
3 bullets per player.
Hand out 3 bullets!
Excuse me, Mr. Schmitt.
Can our player have a chair?
He's in pain.
Mr. André's asking, too.
You shouldn't be here.
Go back to the other side.
Give him a chair.
The gamblers must step back.
Sir!
Step back!
What's wrong with him?
He's drugged up.
Take him up to his room.
Quick!
Put the bullets in the cylinder!
Raise your gun!
Spin the cylinder!
More!
Stop!
Take aim!
Cock the hammer!
When the bulb lights up,
you shoot!
Oh, fuckin' hell!
Come.
Come here.
Gentlemen!
We've reached
the final leg of our game.
The duel.
3 bullets in the cylinder.
Here are 4 balls.
2 are white.
2 are colored.
The 2 colored balls
indicate the duelists.
I call on Numbers 1, 3, 6, and 13.
So everyone can see,
I want you to open them
above your heads.
I want no ambiguity.
Gentlemen, good luck.
Numbers 6 and 13.
Gentlemen, place your bets.
I want to bet on your player.
- He's got no experience.
- Precisely.
I'm always luckier
when I go against logic.
80%.
- That's a lot.
- You won't get less.
Well, I'll bet then.
I should get my share now.
The bets are low.
We won't make much.
I know you.
I fell...
because of you.
What do you mean?
I've been thinking.
I want my share.
Go over to the wall.
You go over to your wall.
It's a piece of shit.
They're all the same.
Gentlemen, please.
One...
Two...
Three...
Very good.
OK with me.
Gentlemen, please be silent.
Silence, please.
Thank you.
I want the players to step forward.
Raise your gun!
Spin the cylinder!
Stop!
Take aim!
When the bulb lights up,
you shoot!
Get ready!
The duel continues
with 4 bullets in the cylinder.
One more bullet in the cylinder.
Supervisors, hand each player
an extra bullet.
One, two,
three, four bullets.
Players, step forward.
Raise your gun!
Spin the cylinder!
Stop!
Take aim!
When the bulb lights up,
you shoot!
It's over, gentlemen.
Finished. All over, gentlemen.
Calm down. It's over, finished.
The winner is Number 13.
Bravo! Number 13, bravo!
Here's the winner.
Congratulations.
Go get your money.
Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- 850.
Thanks to you,
I've won back all I'd lost.
It was far from certain.
I'm not very lucky at the moment.
9...
10...
Give them a wad.
You're lucky, you know.
Your opponent already won 3 duels.
What about me?
Not giving me anything?
Got your money?
Yeah.
Are you pleased?
Want a lift?
Where to?
We'll leave you
at the nearest station.
I'll get dressed and wait outside.
- Want a drink?
- No.
Where are you going?
- I'll go with him.
- Go up and get the coats.
- See Number 13?
- He took his stuff.
- Where is he?
- Open the trunk.
It was lucky he came.
What'd we have done?
Off you go.
10 euros, please.
Your receipt.
Goodbye.
Oh, it's you?
Yes, listen.
I sent you a parcel with money in it.
What money?
A lot of money.
Who gave it to you? What is all this?
I'll tell you when I get back.
When will you be back?
No doubt tomorrow.
Why send it?
You could've brought it.
Something might happen before then.
It was safer that way.
When you get
the receipt, go get the parcel.
What's going on? Where are you?
Don't worry for now.
Everything's fine.
"For now"? Where are you?
I'm calling just in case.
See you soon.
In case of what?
Everything's fine.
Take care.
Pleasant journey. Bye.
- He's over there.
- OK, thanks.
Police! Please stand up.
Raise your arms, please.
Please come with us.
Thanks.
What did you do with the money?
What money?
You're lucky
you came back from there.
I don't know what you mean.
Sit down.
Sit!
I know where you were.
You stole the envelope from Godon's
and you went in his place.
I'm not wrong, am I?
No, that's what happened.
Tell me in detail
what happened there.
Where?
You know very well.
You went for the money.
I didn't make it. I didn't get there.
Don't bullshit me.
You'll regret it.
I'm telling you the truth.
What car were they in
at the crossroads?
A black Peugeot.
What did you say to the driver?
Nothing.
He refused to talk.
He said his job was to get me there.
Where did he drop you?
Somewhere in the forest.
What could you see there?
Other guys waiting for us.
Near a car.
What did you talk about?
I told them Mr. Godon was dead.
I offered to take his place,
but they refused.
It didn't work out.
They must've decided
I wasn't suitable.
You're lying.
You must've convinced them.
Otherwise you'd be dead now.
Who says
they were going to let me live?
I ran away.
Once we'd talked, I saw one guy
pull out his gun, and I ran for it.
Didn't they shoot?
Yes, they ran after me,
shooting at me, but I got away.
I ran so much, I broke my heels.
Look.
Could you identify them?
Yes, of course.
Could you take me
to the place in the forest?
I panicked and ran in the dark.
How could I remember?
You could,
in a car from the crossroads.
No.
As I got in,
the driver put a blindfold on me.
You're lying.
When I look at you,
I smell the stink of blood.
I've told you everything.
You've told me nothing.
I had a plan. If you'd got out
at the right station,
I'd have arrested the henchmen
and made them talk.
Now I've lost my only lead.
What's this all about?
It's a dirty business.
A dirty business of murder.
There was another car in the forest.
I remember the number.
Tell me.
GR 1313.
What make of car was it?
A blue Peugeot 607.
But that's all I know, believe me.
10 euros, please.
Thanks. Bye.
Subtitles: J. Miller
Processed by L.V.T. - Paris
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org