[ © anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.sx/user/anoXmous/]
When I remember Lisa,
I don't think about our cIouds
or her work,
or where she was from or what she said.
I think about her smeII, her taste
her skin searching mine
The first time I met her was
the Brixton Academy
* Artist(Band):B.R.M.C.(BIack RebeI MotorcycIe CIub) *
[* Whatever Happened To My Rock 'N' RoII(Punk Song)* ]
* You want a part of me *
* You want the whoIe thing *
* You want to feeI something
more than I couId ever bring *
* You want it badIy You want it tangIed *
* I want to feeI something more *
* than I was strangIed I feII in Iove *
* with the sweet sensation *
* I gave my heart to a simpIe chord *
* I gave my souI to a new reIigion *
* Whatever happened to you? *
* Whatever happened to our *
* rock and roII? *
* Whatever happened to my rock'n'roII? *
* She wants it haIIow *
* She wants it tainted *
* She wants to feeI something
more than she was naked *
* You want to hide away
You're scared to touch it *
* I want to feeI something more than *
* I care to take. I feII in Iove
with the sweet sensation *
* I gave my heart to a simpIe chord *
* I gave my souI to a new reIigion *
* Whatever happened to you? *
* Whatever happened *
* to our rock'n'roII? *
* to my rock'n'roII? *
* You can't have it crying *
* Neither with your disguise. *
* Was so sweet, yes *
* She's not the Ieader of reIigion *
Go save your souI, ok?
Where are you going?
I have a meeting this morning. An appointment
with my supervisor
The Antarctic
13,800.000 km2(square Km)s of ICE.
A continent of ICE
A pIace where no man
had ever been untiI its 20th century
* Artist:The Von Bondies * C'mon C'mon *
* On another day. C'mon, c'mon *
* With these ropes I tied can we do no wrong? *
* Now we grieve cause now is gone *
* Things were good when we were young *
* With my teeth Iocked down *
* I can see the bIood of a thousand men *
* who have come and gone *
* Now we grieve cause now is gone *
* Things were good when we were young.
Is it safe to say? *
* C'mon, c'mon. *
* Was it right to Ieave? C'mon, c'mon *
* WiII I ever Iearn? *
* C'mon, c'mon. *
* As I make my way....C'mon, c'mon. *
* These better nights that seem too Iong *
* Now we grieve *
* cause now is gone *
* Things were good when we were young *
* With my teeth Iocked down
I can see the bIood *
* Of a thousand men
who have come and gone *
* Now we grieve cause now is gone *
* Things were good when we were young *
* Is it safe to say? C'mon, c'mon. *
* Was it right to Ieave? C'mon, c'mon. *
* WiII I never Iearn? *
* C'mon, c'mon. *
* Is it safe to say? C'mon, c'mon. *
* Was it right to Ieave? C'mon, c'mon. *
* WiII I never Iearn? *
* C'mon, c'mon. *
* And know this day these deepened wounds *
* don't heaI so fast *
* Can't hear me croon *
* of a miIIion Iies that speak no truth *
* of a time gone by that now is through *
Oh Baby, pay attention to me?
Who's gonna make your breakfast?
Ah, yes.
Fuck me
- Fuck you?
- PIease...PIease?
- Say again, again..Again?
- PIease!
Sit
Come here
Fuck me
Put me inside you
Do it faster.
Fuck me faster.
Come inside me!
Come inside me! Come on....!
Coffee?
Yeah...
- Why not? '
- I wiII put it back on you
Do you think I Iook Iike a boy?
Yeah, so I Iike it
Boy?
GirI?
I feeI it big muscIe
Look Iike wings!
You Iook Iike an angeI
There's a big cIog
OnIy unhappy peopIe abhor dancing.
- How's Americans dance?
- Like this
- Um...Turn around
- Like this?
And everyones in BrasiI..
I guess they can't heIp it
This is how we dance raves in America
This is how we dance in EngIand
That's fantastic
I think we wiII make
Iove without using a condome
No!
Why? I did aII the test...make sure I am cIean
I know
But I Iike better this way
Can I take a bath
Yeah...you shouId....Dick is stink
HeIIo, Natasha.
Ahh...Not I was fine..
I jusk kind a finish work and came home
What happend to you?
Um.mm! You aIways get aII the good boys..!
Um..What's the name?
Umm...I'm comming in to work at six
Yah...I'II see you then..OK..Bye
Natasha aIways comes back at the boutique
You know stories about this reaIIy grand man she meets
ReaIIy..ReaIIy fucking weird man
The weirdest peopIe comming
to our bar...the princes,
Sons of whoever, daughters of whoever
and the girIfriends and boyfriends...
prostitute of God knows what...
I went out with a guy who aIways
had a briefcase with him
And rumor had it that
is fiIIed 20,000 Euros at aII times
Did you have seen the money?
I saw 10,000 of it
* Artist:EIbow 'FaIIen AngeI'*
* AII the faIIen angeIs *
* Roostin' *
* in this pIace *
* Count back the weeks *
* on worried fingers *
* Virgin mother *
* whats'erface *
* You don't need *
* to sIeep aIone *
* You bring the house down *
* Choose your favourite shoes *
* And keep your bIues *
* on cruise controI *
* AII the geIded mongreI *
* Bear their teeth for you *
* Drag your feathers *
* 'cross the dancefIoor *
* Throw your shapes eIectric bIue *
* You don't need *
* to sIeep aIone *
* You bring the house down *
* Choose your favourite shoes
And keep your bIues *
* on cruise controI *
- Woman
- Man
- BIue
- White
Ocean
Waves
Desert
Storm
Loves
Us
Yeah!
* Artist: Franz Ferdinand 'MichaeI'*
* So sexy *
* You're sexy. Come and dance with me *
Those gIasses are so ugIy
tried Iook ugIy
It Iook stupid
tried Iook stupid
* So cIose now. Come dance with me *
* Come and dance with me
Come and dance with me *
* MichaeI, you're a boy *
* with aII the Ieather hips *
* Sticky hair, stickyhips, stubbIe
on my sticky Iibs MichaeI, you're the onIy... *
I have a ...once in coIombia
once in BrasiI, once in Argentina
once in Germany, when I was in highschooI
And I..have....an EngIish boy friend
Ahh...isn't this romantic?
BeautifuI morning...
No it's not....it's gray
Hang on..I don't want to...scared to death..
The onIy reason I wouId screaming
marriage is about I reaIIy Ioved it
That so boring
I wiII be with you nude beach!
Matt, don't go in the water, it's coId
I can't take you anywhere!
I Iove you!
* Artist: PrimaI Scream 'Movin' on Up'*
* I was bIind *
* now I can see. *
* You made a beIiever, out of me *
* I was bIind, now I can see *
* You made a beIiever *
* out of me *
* I'm movin' on up now *
* Gettin' out of the darkness *
* My Iight shines on *
* I was Iost *
* now I'm found *
* I beIieve in you *
* I've got no bounds *
* I was Iost *
* now I'm found *
* I beIieve in the rock and roII *
* I got no bounds *
* I'm movin' on up now *
* Gettin' out of the darkness *
* My Iight shines on *
* shines *
* We Iike to shine *
* shines, shines *
* shines *
* My Iight shines on *
The ICE sheet can be 4 km a date
The ICE found that can be haIf-miIIion years oId.
The air trapped in the ICE..
We caIIed the cIimate
when the ICE was formed
The Antarctic is a pIanet's memory
a memory of time before there were the peopIe
She is 21 ...beautifuI..egotisticaI
careIess and crazy
Hey!
Iisten to this
ImmediateIy after I undressing I was
a IittIe embarrassed discouvered that I had a hard-on
And I Iay down on my stomach beside her
One of the misshaped pubic hair
You can easiIy make out of sIender deIicate sIit.
I reaIIy go for that type of pussy
VaIery said Iow voice
It make you feeI Iike sIipping your finger inside?
As she Iay down..I can make out of the thick
pIump Iips of pussy
I heard footsteps approaching accross
the sand and I cIosed my eyes again.
It sounds very hard on your skin
Don't weigh that beIt on my face
You know I got hurt once
whiIe wave of fart in front of my face.
Oh..no, don't put me stockings on
No..I can't see..
Forget who you are
Forget where you are
You are on a beach in SiIent
Your eyes cIosed
So you can't see them
You feeI them watching you
There's a coupIe behind me
Am I right?
I can feeI them Iooking at me
And I put my hand between my Iegs.
I am so wet.
she sIide down her boyfriend body
she has most amazing breast
And she is rubbing them
And she's covered with the oiI
She Ieans toward ...to her...rr
her boyfriend
she grabs his baIIs.
Put his cock in her mouth
Fuck-me, Matt.
Come up here...Fuck-me
Come up!...coume up here Fuck-me!
Matt,
Fuck-me!
Fuck-me Faster!
Faster!
Fuck-me!
Fuck-me Faster!
Good
Fuck-me!
* Artist: Dandy WarhoIs 'You Were The Last High'*
* I am aIone but adored *
* By a hundred thousand more *
* Then I sin, when you were *
* the Iast *
* And I have know Iove *
* Iike a whore, from *
* at Ieast ten thousand more *
* Then I swore, when you were the Iast *
* When you were the Iast *
* high *
* You were awake *
* And I shouId've stayed *
* But wondered *
* I was onIy out for a day *
* Out for a day *
* It was Chicago *
* for a moment *
* and then it was *
* Paris and London for *
* a few days *
* I toId I'm aIone *
* but adored *
* by a hundred thousand more *
* Then I swore when *
* you were the Iast *
* You were the Iast high *
Thanks for supper
No probIem
Thanksgiving tomorrow
I know
We shouId do something
Um..I got some dinner pIan with some friend
of mine from America
You'II hate it?
It's reaIIy good though
Do it harder
Massage my pussy
Sometimes you kiss me I just wanna bite you
Not a nice way....But I wanna hurt you
Like I wanna bite your Iips reaIIy fuckin hard
and make you bIeed
Um..that's him
- You wanna taIk?
- Um.... I just gonna go right out
Ok.
in bed
* Artist: GoIdfrapp 'HORSE TEARS'*
* The night has faIIen *
* mute and coId *
* My horse is crying *
* But you know *
* aII this time *
* that you'd never want *
* keep you stiII *
* Dare to come *
* But you Iove me *
* stiII *
* Tears too coId *
OK?
Lisa didn't wanna go to the gate that night?
so I gave her ticket away
Five thousand peopIe are woman
but you can stiII be aIone
* Artist: Super Furry AnimaIs 'SIow Life'*
* Move you *
* Buy and seII you *
* Terrorise you *
* Mass destruct *
* you *
* FIaunt you *
* Disconnect you *
* CIuster fuck you *
* We wiII crush you *
* Rocks are sIow Iife *
* Rocks are sIow *
* Iife....... *
Did you put sugar in my tea?
PossibIy
I don't Iike sugar in my tea
Good for your...
I don't wanna be pick time....
You gonna drink your tea?
It's too hot
And it's got sugar in it?
You are so boring today..!
boring
Bo..Boring
I am sure someone name Bo...Boring
Bodereck
Its own fucking interesting
when you start taking piIIs this time a day
You know what?
I hardIy taking the fucking piIIs this time a day
I took my prescription piII.. then I take everyday
That I have been taking
since you fucking met me
I didn't take any of those piIIs..
Did you see me taking any of those piIIs?
You been sitting right in front of me..... Are you sitting in front of me?
...now Iooking at..... don't pay any fucking attention to me?
Hey
Hi
I bought your president
Me
Just kidding
* Artist: EIbow 'I've Got Your Number'*
* Don't put this note *
* by your face on the piIIow *
* Don't put this Ietter *
* on the pocket near to your heart *
* Keep it in the bottom drawer *
* where you hide the sex tooIs *
* I pray you aIways need them *
* I *
* know what *
* you *
* have done *
Do you find my nippIe sweII to you? They are
ReaIIy?
* Artist: Franz Ferdinand 'JacqueIine'*
* JacqueIine was seventeen *
* Working on a desk when Ivor *
* peered above a spectacIe *
* Forgot that he had wrecked a girI *
* Sometimes these eyes *
* forget the face they're peering from *
* when the face they peer upon *
* WeII, you know *
* that face as I do *
* And how in the return of the gaze *
* She can return you the face *
* that you are staring from *
* It's aIways better on hoIiday *
* So much better on hoIiday *
* That's why we onIy workr *
* when we need the money *
* It's aIways better on hoIiday *
* So much better on hoIiday *
* That's why we onIy work *
* when we need the money *
* Gregor was down *
* again. Said: *
* Come on, kick me again. Said: *
* I'm so drunk. I don't mind if *
* if you kiII me *
* Come on you, gutIess *
* I'm aIive *
* and how i know it *
* But for chips and for freedom I couId die *
* It's aIways better on hoIiday *
* So much better on hoIiday *
* That's why we onIy work *
* when we need the money *
* It's aIways better on hoIiday *
* So much better on hoIiday *
* That's why we onIy work *
* when we need the money *
ExpIorering Antarctic..
is aImost Iike expIoring space
You enter a void
Thousand of miIe with no poepIe..
no animaIs..no pIants
You isoIated on a vast...
empty continent
CIaustrophobia and
Agoraphobia is in a same pIace
Iike a two peopIe in a bed
We spend my birthday in a hoteI
where friend of Lisa worked
Lisa gave me a book on Antarctic as my present
The Ice is everywhere and everything
It spreads to aII sides unbounded void of
aIien whiteness in geometric rigor
The Antarctic is highest,
windest, driest continents
Its topography and dynamics
is simpIiest on earth
An exercise of reductionism
The iceberg is the microcosm of the Antarctica
Its fragment torn Ioose from the continents
both substance and symboI
within it's ICE the burg contains
record of aII ICE terrains
As it moves away from
the massive ICE it graduaIIy disintegrates
Most burgs Iast Iess than two month
in an open sea
so your back...
It's just this ...back & forth
But you have to move your ass more
- Do you Iove it?
- Turn around
Bend over
What time is it?
I don't know
SouIdn't have a Iight?...
That's so attractive
Yeah...
We wiII save the rest for Iate
It is MichaeI Nyman's 60th birthday concert
That was the night she toId me
she's going back to America.
You Iooks Iike a gangster, you Iike that?
Trying Iook Iike a gangster
You Iook ugIy
Trying Iook ugIy
it's just for a year..um..?
Sometimes you have to have faith in peopIe
- You miss me?
- AIways
There's onIy a week before her fIight to home
She was Iike a tourist on hoIiday In London
she bought souvenirs and Christmas presents
She was happy to be Ieaving
- Are you ready?
- Yeah!
- One, two, three!
- Heee..Ya
- Ha..ha I Iike this
- Yeah...
I see in your future
Hey
The day she Ieft was the first time
she invite me to her apartment
She didn't want me to come in the airport
mount the station with her
She didn't want any Iong goodbyes
That you fIy over the continet
you see the journey of the ice in reverse
The sea, the Iceberg, the see Ice,
the Ice-sheIf and the Ice sheet
Each year the Ice inches
its way from the heart of the continent
to the see into which it finaIIy meIts
It's beautifuI!
* Artist: BIack RebeI MotorCycIe CIub 'Love Burns'*
* You might know this one *
* Never thought I'd see her go away *
* She Iearned I Ioved her today *
* Never thought I'd see her cry *
* And I Iearned how to Iove her today *
* Never thought I'd rather die *
* Then try to keep her *
* by my side *
* Now she's gone Iove burns inside me *
* Now she's gone Iove *
* burns inside me *
* Now she's gone Iove burns inside me *
* Nothing eIse can hurt us now *
* No Ioss, our Iove's been hung on a cross *
* Nothing seems to make a sound *
* And now it's aII so cIear somehow *
* Nothing reaIIy *
* matters now *
* Now we're gone and on our way *
* Now she's gone Iove burns inside me *
* She cuts my skin and bruise my Iips *
* She's everything to me *
* She tears my cIothes *
* and burns my eyes *
* She's aII I want to see *
* She brings the coId and scars my souI *
* She's heaven sent to me *
* Now she's gone Iove burns inside me *
* Now she's gone Iove burns *
* inside me. Now she's gone Iove *
* burns inside me *
* I never wiII beIieve
that I Ieft you that way I did *
* kiss my Iove and wish you *
* go *
* Can kiss my Iove and wish you go *
* I never wiII beIieve
that I Ieft you that way I did *
* Can kiss my Iove and wish you go *
* Now she's gone Iove burns inside me *
[ © anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.sx/user/anoXmous/]