You want to know
what this is all about?
You could say
it's about drugs or guns
or disaffected youth,
or whatever you like.
But this whole thing
is about parenting.
It's about taking care
of your children.
You take care of yours,
I take care of mine.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
What does that mean?
That's all I have to say about
that subject. Next question.
Your son
was a drug dealer?
A drug dealer? No. Did he
sell a little weed? Yeah.
A little weed? He was a major
supplier to the San Gabriel Valley.
I don't know
anything about that.
What about the D.A.'s assertion that
your son got his marijuana from you?
And that you have ties
to organized crime?
What is this
amateur night bullshit?
This isn't an interrogation,
all right?
I'm a taxpayer
and I'm a citizen.
And you are a jerk-off.
Did I tell you that?
Come on, Johnny, I don't
let fiend jump in the alley.
If you don't give me
fucking 12 reps,
I'm fucking your mom
and your girl.
Tell him, Tiko!
What'd you say?
I couldn't hear you.
You say you want
to suck my cock, right?
First you got to grow one.
Shit, my dick's
so big it's got a knee.
Five foot three,
hung like a flea.
Fuck, it's hot
out there.
What are you doing, Elvis?
Is it dark outside?
- What?
- I'm paying you for a full day, right?
I've been here
since 10:00 this morning.
Fuck that shit.
I asked you a question.
Do you see
the fucking moon, Elvis?
- It's definitely daylight.
- I'll show you my moon.
Johnny, I did everything
that you said.
The house is clean. I went to the store.
There's food and beer in the fridge.
The wash is done. Adolf's fed. The
grass is cut. It's all done, man.
Well, I guess you shouldn't
have finished so fast, huh?
Shut the fuck up.
- Never mind that. Never mind that.
- Shut the fuck up!
Get back to fucking work.
You want shit to do? Go wash the floors.
Scrub out the toilets.
Or better yet, pick up all the
dog shit in the backyard.
And if you finish too fast,
dump it out...
And pick it
back up again.
- Party's over, man.
- Shut the fuck up, Pick.
- I can get you a pooper scooper.
- Why are you so touchy?
- That's messed up, man.
- What?
When am I going
to get my money, Elvis? When?
I told you.
I get my check on Thursday.
All right. Well,
how much is the check?
I don't know.
It depends on the hours.
Well, how many hours
did you work, bitch?
I can't remember.
Fucking deadbeat, man.
Go on,
get the fuck out of here.
The walk of shame.
The walk of shame, man.
Yo! What up, little B?
- What up, B?
- It's 911.
$8,500.
All of it, huh?
- Surprise, surprise.
- Yeah.
Okay.
So?
So I got this guy.
He wants five.
Plus my regular two.
So I figure
I'm going to need seven.
I don't know, B. I don't...
I don't like having
that much shit out.
I'm going to see my guy on Monday
and I'll clear you right out, man.
He's good for it, Johnny.
You don't need to tell him
I'm good for it, man.
I'm not looking
for any fucking favors, J.T.
If it makes sense, do it.
If not, fuck it.
All right.
We'll try it.
Where are you going, right?
That's what
I'm talking about.
But come Friday,
I don't want to hear
any fucking stories.
You won't.
Be ready, be ready.
Soft hands, right?
Soft hands.
Nice. Nice. That's major league
stuff right there, baby.
Grab a bat,
and I'll throw you a couple.
- Hey.
What do you say, Tarzan?
I need seven.
Seven?
- Seven? Who?
- Bobby "911".
Yeah? Well,
we could put together.
I don't want
to get picked off.
All right.
- You know where he's been?
- Yeah.
I mean, I don't know,
but it feels good.
All right.
It's on you anyway, right?
It always is, Pop.
Hey, look at this kid. How handsome he is.
Look at this!
You must be knocking them dead.
You knocking them dead?
No. Let go of me.
So, what are you doing tonight?
You chasing tail?
No, I'm just chilling.
On a Friday night?
- Sonny?
- I know. I know.
Don't make me wonder about you, kid.
You sound like half a fucking fag.
- Always had my suspicions.
- Just make the fucking call.
Wait a minute.
Remember what I told you.
Men are not supposed to be monopolous.
It's in our nature to spread the seed.
Yeah, very poetic.
Come on. Come on.
Angela's a nice girl and all, but you
got to plow some fucking fields!
Did you hear me,
you fucking fruitcake?
Come on, buddy.
- He's a great kid.
- Yeah, he is.
Hello?
Hey!
We didn't expect
to see you. Come on in.
- Hi. You hungry?
- Yeah.
There's plenty of food.
- Hey.
- I like your hair, Jakey.
- Thank you.
- You look handsome with a little hair.
- What's going on with the job?
- Lot of sales. Really busy.
Just, everything's going
really great.
How's your mother?
Wonderful, thank you.
- Tell her I said hello.
- I'll do...
- And Wanda?
- She's fine.
Could I talk to you
for a second?
Yeah, sure.
Excuse us.
I need to borrow money.
I thought we talked
about this.
Yeah.
You haven't paid me back
for the last time.
I know. I'm sorry. I...
It's not the money. You
know that, don't you, Son?
I just can't keep
bailing you out all the time.
I know, man!
I mean, do you...
Do you think I'd fucking be here if
this wasn't the last stop on earth?
How much?
800 bucks.
Hey.
- What's going on?
- Jake wants to borrow money.
How many times are we
going to do this, Butch?
Kid comes in here
stoned out of his mind,
and you keep throwing money at him
because you don't want to deal with it.
I'm working! I have a job.
- I'll pay you back.
- No.
No, I can't do it, Son.
Right. Sorry to interrupt. Go back
to your perfect little family.
- That's not fair.
- Don't fucking touch me!
Hey. Can I come with you?
No, kid, not tonight.
I got some shit to do.
Okay.
Yeah.
You okay? You all right?
- Okay, well, page me later.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
- I love you.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Punk-ass bitches.
Look at these
fucking wannabe motherfuckers
with their fucking guns
and their fucking gold chains.
They got nothing!
They're worthless!
The only thing these motherfuckers
are shooting are music videos, dawg.
- That's what I'm saying.
That's what
I've been saying all along.
I'm talking about.
- Now I'm feeling it.
Now I'm feeling it, bitches.
You don't want that shit.
No!
Go, Elvis!
Dance, bitch!
You want to call me out?
You want to call me out? Okay.
Yeah, I want to call you out.
- I want to call you out.
- Oh, that is so nasty!
- Hey, you know he has herpes, right?
Bring it on!
I'm fucking high, dawg.
I can't even... I can't even
see you right now.
You ain't shit, Elvis!
Go back to your shelf.
Yeah, dance, bitch.
He's so fucking
brain-dead.
Rape her more!
Oh, shit!
Come here.
I need a fucking beer.
Hey, would you
get me a cerveza?
- Oh, you need a beer, Johnny?
- I'll get you a beer.
Don't worry about it, Angie.
I got it. I got it. I got it.
Yo, I got it, Johnny.
- Run, bitch.
- Bitch, we're fucking thirsty.
Look at that slave-ass motherfucker.
"I got it, Johnny."
He's like a spook, man.
He loves Johnny.
Yes, he does.
Don't you, Elvis?
- What?
- You love him, motherfucker. Johnny?
Yeah, I do.
I love him a lot.
I owe him a lot. I do.
No, no, no.
I don't mean like that.
I mean you fucking love him.
You'd fucking do
anything for him.
If he asked you to suck his
cock, you probably would.
Shut the fuck up.
No, no, no.
Tell the truth, Elvis.
Tell me you wouldn't drop
to your fucking knees
and suck Johnny's cock in two
seconds, if he asked you.
You'd give it a kiss on the tip.
I bet you would, motherfucker.
- No, I wouldn't.
- You wouldn't?
Johnny, come on, man.
Oh, you see that?
Dude, you are
a fucking full-on
dick-in-the-mouth, balls-across-the-nose,
dildo-up-the-ass...
Fag!
- You're a faggot, dude. 100 percent.
- You're a fag.
Shut the fuck up,
bitch. Suck my cock.
You know what? Don't talk
to me anymore, okay?
- I fuck bitches. You're a homo.
- Suck my cock.
That's it.
- That's fucking mean.
- Shut the fuck up!
Suck my fucking cock.
Come on, Schmidt,
I'm dead serious.
Suck it, bitch.
Suck my fucking cock.
I got it.
Come on, do it!
No, I got it, all right?
Suck my cock.
Pretty soon it's going
to come out, Elvis.
Pretty soon you're
going to come out, Elvis.
That you're fucking gay.
What up, Jake?
You got to start calling a
motherfucker before you just show up.
- Christ-killers ain't got no respect.
- Yeah.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- What's up, Jake?
Oh, shit! Yo, come here, man. Elvis
is just about to suck a dick.
Yeah.
Let's go on in here.
So what's going on, homie?
You know that thing I told you I was going
to take care for you down in San Diego?
- Yeah.
- It's a washout.
Really? What happened?
Well, I go down there
and I put the screws to him.
And I tell him, something bad
is gonna happen to him,
unless he comes up with your
money, and, like, fast.
Which he doesn't,
because he's fucking tapped.
But he's scared,
so he leans on his neighbor,
and I walk on the guy
for 150 bombs.
So?
So, the bombs are no good.
The X was fucking bunk.
And I had a guy lined up
to take it all, man.
We would have made
so much money on that shit.
But you said that you would take care
of it. You said that it was your debt.
Are you coming in here,
trying to nigger-talk me?
What do you want me to do? I can't exactly
go back to the guy that I ripped off
and say, "Yo dude,
your shit was no good."
Okay, well,
I still got to get paid.
I know. Calm the fuck down.
I got $800.
And I thought
that we could split it.
You thought
we could split it?
Fuck that.
Pay me all of it.
- I'm trying.
- How?
You make dog shit
at your fucking job.
Be careful, Johnny.
I'm not fucking Elvis.
Yeah, well,
you're short, asshole.
Watch your fucking mouth,
you little fucking midget.
I'm not one of
your little faggot friends.
And remember
who you're talking to.
Give me
my fucking money!
You're going
to stiff me, huh?
I'm going
to fucking kill you!
Take a fucking drink,
you motherfucker.
Why don't you fucking die?
I'm going to kill you,
you fucking bitch!
- Take your fucking hands off him!
- Get back!
You motherfucker!
Oh, fuck, Frankie. Get
this fucking bitch off me.
- Fucking psycho, man.
- Get the fuck off, bitch!
Who do you think you're messing
with, you fucking cocksucker?
Get away from me.
Sit the fuck down,
you crazy bitch!
Piece of shit.
- Whoa, goddamn it, man!
- All right, motherfucker!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on, man.
You point that thing at me, you
better pull the fucking trigger!
Well, come on,
you fucking pussy, do it!
Come on, bitch!
Why don't you try me,
you fucking kike?
- I will! I will!
- I love it.
You have everyone else fooled around
here, but I ain't fucking buying it.
Get this fucking piece
of shit out of my house.
Get the fuck out, dawg!
All right, Johnny.
It's on.
Ain't no turning back now.
Get the fuck
out of here!
Fucking walk away, okay?
Come on.
Whoa!
Fuck me.
Bitch, shut up.
What's going on?
- Who's there?
- It's Zack.
- Who? It's fucking midnight!
- It's me, Zack.
Get in here.
What are you doing,
you fucking maniac?
Hi! Hi!
Okay. Go put on some clothes.
My brother's here.
Heil! Yes, sir!
- You want a drink?
- Yeah.
And she's always
telling me what to do.
Like what clothes to wear and
what girls she thinks are pretty.
Like I couldn't fucking
figure it out for myself!
That's your mom.
That's Olivia.
Come on, she loves you.
You're her baby.
Yeah, I know.
It's embarrassing.
Do you know that
we have homework parties?
- What?
- Homework parties with little hats.
No.
- Yeah.
- Like...
- ...for birthdays?
Yeah! Yeah!
Another thing.
I'll be sleeping, right?
And she'll wake me up
by looking at me.
Like I'll open my eyes, and she'll be
right there looking at me, like...
Fucking A!
It's goddamn creepy, you know. Like she's
in love with me, and breathing on me!
You're lucky, you know that.
I mean, my mother,
she'd never...
Boo-hoo for me!
Yeah, I know.
But, you know,
I'd trade you.
I just got to get out.
Wow, I'm drunk.
I got to smoke.
Well.
Look at Zacky! All grown up!
Look at his little one-hitter
and his stress weed.
Shut up.
Take a drink.
Like a pro.
Wacky Zacky.
That's me.
Hello?
Wanda, put my kid
on the phone. Now.
One minute.
- It's Olivia.
- No, no. Fucking A!
All right, give it to me.
Hello?
Zack was supposed to be home
two hours ago. Is he with you?
- Yeah, he's here.
- Fucking A, dude.
No, we're talking.
- I said we're talking.
- Put him on the phone...
Don't get your panties all in a wad,
Olivia. I'll drive him home later.
Do you know what time it is?
Yes, I do know
what time it is, thank you.
Put my son on the phone or I am coming
over there right now, God damn it.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, okay. All right!
You got to go home.
- No!
- Wait, no, stop!
Come on, Zack!
Tonight we ride!
- Come on.
- No!
Come on.
Jake. Hey, Jake.
- Jake, am I a funny guy?
- You're hysterical.
- Am I a good guy?
- You're the best.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, you are a good guy.
- You are the best, man.
- Oh, boy.
- Get inside.
- Oh, Dad!
You wanted him,
you got him.
Hi!
Bye!
You're a real son of a
bitch, you know that?
Come on!
I was fucking my dog
one time, right?
No, no, no. Hey...
Hey, look at the caboose
on that one.
I could crack that open
like a peach.
Are you fucking kidding me?
You are a fucking dinosaur,
Cosmo.
Come on. You're dead.
You can't do anything.
Your balls
are all wrinkled up.
- What?
"What?" You deaf fuck.
I said you're old.
I can knock the bottom
out of her.
You don't even know what a bottom is.
You don't know what to do.
Balls deep.
Hey, waitress!
What can I do for you?
What did you have in mind?
Just get another
round of drinks.
- You haven't finished the last ones.
- I didn't ask you that.
- Just get us some more fucking drinks.
- Get us some drinks, bitch!
Come on.
Mind your manners.
We're fine.
Just give me the bill.
Hey, no, Dad.
Come on, I got it.
Oh, you got it, huh? What are you...
Look at this guy.
- Special occasion.
- Big spender over here!
- Come on, Cos, let's go.
- Johnny says we're leaving, let's go!
Hey, Johnny,
watch this.
- Tell Jake we stopped in.
- Oh, I will.
When I told Jake what happened,
he fucking flipped out.
And I had to calm him down.
He was going to kill Johnny.
Jake's like that. He's a
very passionate person.
But I told him, "No. If
you're gonna do something,
"you got to fucking
hit him where it hurts."
Johnny had a car stolen
by a mutual acquaintance,
and he was trying to collect
on the insurance money.
Jake comes in,
salts the whole fucking deal,
insurance company
catches wind of it,
they don't pay out.
Costs Johnny $30,000.
Of course, Johnny had to retaliate.
It's fucking business.
Mr. Johansson
wants to see you.
You wanted to see me?
Sit down.
What's up, Pete?
Your probation officer called.
You talked to Mr. Lampington?
I thought he was out of town.
Yeah. Well,
I talked to him.
He says you've been getting
into trouble again.
Breaking into houses,
using drugs. Speed, mainly.
It's not true.
- Yeah, it is.
- No, it's not.
Pete, I swear to God.
Dude. Dude! It's...
I feel you. I'm right here.
Don't look at me that way. I'm
telling you the fucking truth!
I'm totally
fucking straight, man!
I mean, I'm a little...
Mr. Lampington is so full of shit.
He's out of fucking town.
How would he know
what I'm doing?
- You disappoint me.
- Pete.
Pete.
I swear to fucking God.
I need you
to take a drug test.
Pete, come on.
I need this job.
- I really need this job.
- Fill it up.
I need this fucking job!
Back off!
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Fuck you!
Get the fuck out of here!
You're fired!
Get your shit and get out!
Do not let him back in here!
I will take you down
to hell with me!
Get the fuck out of here!
I will take you down
to fucking hell with me!
to hell with me!
You want to play some games, Truelove?
Let's play some motherfucking games.
Motherfucker. Fuck that!
Where's this motherfucker?
Where you at? Johnny?
- Johnny!
- Go check the bathroom.
Johnny!
Jake!
Truelove!
- Oh, shit, look at this fucking TV!
- Fuck the TV.
Shut the fuck up!
Shoot the fucking...
Fuck the motherfucking dog,
man.
The bitch ain't here,
man. Let's get out of here.
What the fuck
are you doing, man?
did you eat, bro?
Be careful,
don't step on your own shit.
Oh, man, this fucker's
real heavy. Shit.
No, don't drop it. Wait.
Don't fucking drop it.
Yo, I'm keeping
this motherfucking TV.
Don't fuck with it. Don't
fuck with it, all right?
- You ready or what?
- Let's go, come on.
- Let's get the fuck out of here.
- Let's go!
Fiesta, motherfuckers,
we ready?
Yo, what the fuck, dude?
We're moving, bro.
- Moving?
- Goddamn right.
It's too fucking hot. Too many
assholes know where I live.
You see this?
Holy shit!
Yo, Johnny,
what happened, man?
I come home last night.
My window was busted
and my TV is missing.
- Fuck, right?
- Fuck!
- Tell him about the shit.
- The shit?
Fucking crackhead Mazursky took a
sideways shit on the living room carpet.
- What? Where?
- Right here.
On the wet spot.
A big fucking steaming crap.
Longways, like this, dawg.
- That's fucked up.
- Is that nuts or what?
What this motherfucker
wipe his ass with? His hand?
I don't know, fucko.
I told you I wasn't here.
Whatever. That fool
is fucking nasty, man.
Check this shit out.
Sunday, 12:00 a.m.
This is just the beginning, bitch.
This is Li'l Shooter.
You're dead, homes. You
hear me, you fucking dwarf?
I know where
your mother lives.
I know where your brother lives.
I know where your papi lives.
We going to play some games,
motherfucker!
- Mazursky, right?
- Can you believe that shit?
After everything I've done
for that motherfucker?
Look, Johnny, fuck him.
Let's get the hell out of Dodge.
Go to Fiesta. Fuck some bitches.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- Right?
Let's run through some shit!
Schmitty, we're going to go to
the Springs for a couple days.
You stay here and get everything
all boxed up and out.
I don't want to see shit here
when I get back, okay?
- All right.
- All right. I want a receipt, too.
Yeah, and maybe if you guys are
still there when I get finished,
I'll cruise down there.
- Yeah. Maybe you can blow me.
- Fuck you, dick. I wanna come.
Yeah, yeah. Just make sure you get the
shit smell out of the carpet, bitch!
I don't get it.
What are we doing?
Let's go break
this fucking guy's head.
Mazursky!
He's not here.
I'm telling you, he's gone, man.
Look, his car is not even here.
That don't mean shit.
There's not even
any fucking lights on.
How are the lights going to be on?
It's the middle of the fucking day.
What the fuck are we doing?
I don't know, but I'm not standing
here like a fucking idiot.
- What are you doing?
- I'm just kidding.
All right,
so quit fucking around.
Hey! Yo, J!
Check it out.
97 miles an hour,
motherfucker!
- Okay.
- Let's see what you got.
Manny motherfucking Ramirez,
motherfucker!
You guys are fucking idiots.
Jesus! Make more noise.
He's 15. You remember
when you were 15?
You know what? For once in your
life, your tennis match will wait.
Why do you have to be such a fucking pussy?
What are you thinking?
What are you
getting crazy about?
- It's not that big a deal.
- I am not crazy!
- If you were ever here...
- Would you just leave it?
...you might notice that.
- Oh, great. Let's just let him turn out like...
- Like what, Olivia? Like who?
- Like what?
- Say it. Like Jake?
Hey.
What's going on?
Oh, jeez.
Come here.
Your mother found this
in your room.
- It's a pipe.
- I know what it is. It's a bong.
- You want to tell me about it?
- No.
- You smoking pot?
Now, look at me!
We have to talk, Son.
I don't want
to fucking talk, Dad.
Well, that's too bad.
Sit down.
Dad! I just fucking woke up!
Goddamn it! Let me put
some fucking clothes on.
God! Fucking dick!
Yes, he should be grounded. He
should be something, for God's sake!
Zack, come down here!
Zack?
- Are you fucking kidding me?
- What?
That's Tattooey's brother.
Pull over.
Hey, what's up?
Come here.
Come here,
you little fucker.
What the fuck
you running for, bitch?
Let's go, let's go.
Come on.
Dude, what the fuck are you doing?
I didn't fucking do anything.
Shut the fuck up
and get in the fucking van!
Fucking idiot.
Just take him to your place.
We can't take him to my place.
I told you, my dad's there.
I thought you said
he was cool.
Bitch, he is cool.
But you didn't tell me
we'd be bringing along
a fucking hostage!
Dude, he's not a hostage,
all right?
I told you, I don't know what
I'm doing right now, all right.
- I'm thinking.
- Well, think.
Well... Hey,
we got to take him someplace.
All right.
I know somewhere we can go.
But you got to be
fucking cool.
- Yeah?
- Yo!
Hey, what's up, man?
- What's up, Chucky?
- What's up, bro?
- Lot of dudes, bro.
- I know, man.
All right. Bring them in.
Hey, Chuck, this is Truelove, the
guy I was telling you about.
- Hey, what's up, man?
- Do you have a room we could use?
- A room?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I got one
all the way down to the left.
Thanks.
So, what's up, man?
You know,
we're just chilling, man.
- Getting high. Getting ready to go to Fiesta.
- Smoking weed.
Thanks, man.
So, how you been?
Been good. Chilling.
Ripping waves. Hanging out.
Yo! What the fuck is going on
back there, man?
Do you want me
to go check it out?
Yeah. I mean, four dudes I've never
met are in my fucking bedroom.
Yeah.
- Give me your hands.
- Give me the tape.
Whoa! What the fuck
are you doing, man?
Are you nuts?
You can't do that!
- You guys are out of your fucking mind.
- What the hell is this?
- Who the fuck are you?
- Shut up.
Hey, Chucky, they got a kid
tied up in your bedroom!
- Hey, calm down.
- There's a kid!
- What?
- It's not like that.
- Johnny's just a little crazy right now.
- A little crazy right now?
- We stole this kid...
- What?
- I don't know...
- Hey!
I thought I told you
to shut your mouth.
And you
mind your fucking business.
Mind my business?
This is my fucking house!
Frankie, you better put your boy in check.
Tell them what fucking time it is.
- Oh, it's like that, huh?
- Just like that, bitch.
I get it. Yo, Lump,
let's get out of here.
Yo! I'm going
to fucking Fiesta.
And when I get back, none of you
motherfuckers better be here.
Let's get out of here, girls.
Lump, let's go.
- Fuck.
- Fucking shitheads.
Hey, Chucky, man, I'm really
sorry about all this, bro.
Fuck!
What's going on?
Why aren't you guys ready?
- What are we going to do with the kid, man?
- Who cares?
Throw him in the fucking closet. Pick
him up later. Leave him in the van.
I don't give a fuck.
Hey, yo, Johnny.
I got a date
back in the Valley.
I got to get back, man.
Me, too.
You just remembered now, huh?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, man.
Hey, my girl gets mad
if I don't fuck her.
You pussies want to go home?
Fine. Take the fucking van.
Listen. You don't have
to do that, you know.
I mean, you can put me in a closet.
I'm not gonna run anywhere.
Do me a favor. Shut up before
I shut you the fuck up.
Johnny.
Why is this motherfucker
even talking, anyway?
I thought we taped him up.
He couldn't breathe.
Just drop me off on the strip.
I'm going to fucking Fiesta.
I'm not letting this little
motherfucker throw my weekend.
He couldn't breathe.
- What about me?
- No.
- No what?
- He stays with you.
What?
I said, "All fucking queers
are deaf," motherfucker.
- Why me, dude?
- Because I fucking said so.
Don't fuck around, man.
I can't fucking take him
to my dad's house like that.
Well, then, untie him, genius.
You heard the kid.
He ain't running, are you?
- What? No.
- There you go.
Go home, tell Juergen he's your new little
butt buddy and he's spending the night.
Meanwhile,
I'll talk to Mazursky.
He must be going crazy
right now.
Hey, what's going on?
It's a madhouse.
Your brother's scaring
the shit out of all of us.
You try his friends?
Maybe he has a girl.
We've tried everything. Friends,
cops, hospitals. Nothing.
You don't think the kid's just,
like, out fucking around?
I mean, you can't keep the kid
locked in the house forever.
Maybe. I don't know.
We did have an argument
this morning.
Okay, well, that's what it is,
then, right?
I hope so.
- Well, what do you think?
- I don't know.
But, we can't
rule anything out, so...
I have to ask you
a few questions.
- Okay?
- Okay.
You know anybody
who'd want to hurt Zack?
- No.
- You?
Me what?
You have a beef with anybody
I should know about?
- No.
- That person you owe money to?
You owe somebody money?
Oh, Jesus! You just tell me how
much and I will write the check.
- It's not really like that, Olivia.
- Really? What's it like?
Tell me what it's like, you...
Goddamn you! You fuck!
- Get him back here!
- Please relax.
Get him back here to me.
Bring him back here!
I'm going to find him,
I promise you.
I'll find him.
Where are you going?
De Rosa! Where's Johnny?
I don't know, dawg.
Is he here?
- That's what I'm asking you, "dawg"!
- Excuse me, we were talking.
- Klemash, where's the fucking crew?
- Man, I ain't seen them dudes.
What the fuck was that? You give me
your back? You turn away from me?
- Why are you tripping, homes?
- Back up, freak-ass!
Don't touch her!
You fucking asshole!
If anybody
sees Johnny Truelove,
tell them Jake Mazursky
is looking for him!
Thank you.
Hey, suck my dick!
Dude.
You better
back the fuck off me, man!
- I'm going to get a beer. You want one?
- Yeah, sure.
- Here you go, man.
- Thanks.
- Cigarette?
- No, I don't smoke.
Fuck that.
It's good for you.
Hey, man,
what if I said you could
walk over there right now,
jump on a bus,
catch a ride home?
I turn my back, tell Truelove you
fucking ran away or something.
What do you think about that?
I don't know, Frankie.
I mean, I don't want to cause any
problems for my brother, you know?
So, I think, I'm just going to
ride it out, see what happens.
All right?
All right.
Try and
keep it down, okay?
Dad?
Frankie?
Frankie.
- I'm so glad to see you, bro!
- I know.
- So glad. Oh, my beautiful baby!
- Come on, Dad, don't do that.
Hey, come to bed.
I love you.
I want you to meet
this beautiful...
All right, all right,
all right.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yes, hi.
- Give her a kiss. Be a gentleman.
- Dad! Seriously!
Just fucking
join in the fun, man.
No, you have fun.
I'm gonna go.
- Let me go, Dad.
- No, stay! The party's just getting started.
Come on, man, smoke a
doobie with your old man!
- Have a drink!
- No!
- Come on. Something.
- No, Dad. Come on.
Who's your little friend?
You babysitting?
Fuck you!
- Take the couch.
- All right.
- You good?
- Yeah.
Wake up.
Come on, you got
chores to do. Let's go.
- Hello?
- I fucking hear you!
There's coffee. But Destiny got up late,
so I need you to straighten up the house.
I'm supposed to clean up
after your party?
I'm hung over like a bitch. Don't
argue with me. I'm in no mood.
Hey, look, I come home here yesterday,
and your shit's all over the house!
We had a deal, remember?
You get a job, you pay rent,
- or you work here.
- All right! Fuck!
- Get out of my room!
- Nice fucking mouth.
Fucking dick.
Hey, don't worry about it.
I'll help you with the work.
Juergen's a botanist. He grows
everything we eat right here.
Tomatoes, cucumbers, corn.
Fucking spices and shit.
Motherfucker's a full-blown
alcoholic, smokes like a chimney,
but goddamn if we don't
eat healthy, right?
Oh, yeah. Look at
this shit right here.
- Oh, boy!
- Daddy's pride and joy.
Of course, that greedy bastard
will smoke them all,
but it's Frankie's job
to take care of them.
Water them, pull the males, throw a little
eggshells on them, every now and then.
- Dope.
- Yeah, right?
Well, fuck it.
Let's get to work.
- Shit. I'll be right back.
- All right.
- Hello.
- Hey!
- Hey, girl.
- What's going on?
Nothing. Working.
You guys coming over?
- You got that shit?
- You know I do.
- Mom, we're going to Frankie's!
- Hey, did you talk to him?
It's all good.
- When will you be home?
- I don't know. Late, probably.
Darling, can you stay with
Julie and Sabrina tonight?
It's your father
and my anniversary.
Anniversary.
- You going to have a little sex or...
- That's disgusting!
Whatever. I'm interested.
I mean, really. Are you
going to go down on him?
- Give him a little tubesteak boogie?
- No.
Oh, come on. Live a little.
I mean, you guys have been
married, what, like, 500 years?
Keith Stratten!
I will smack the shit out
of you, you little skunk!
All right, okay,
we're leaving.
You got your keys. Let's
go get Sabrina and Julie.
Bye.
Hey! Yo! Yo! Youngblood!
Come here, man. Come here.
- Ladies. Dickwad.
- Fuck you.
- Susan.
- Hi.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Sabrina. Julie.
- Dickwad.
- Hey, buddy. Fucking Keith, man.
Okay, okay, let's go smoke
some fucking weed, man!
- All right. Yo!
- Hey, but listen.
- No!
- Nobody mess up my shit, all right?
This house has never been
so fucking clean.
- Fuck you, dude.
- You fucking suck at these games.
- You suck.
- You fucking blow at this game, dude.
I don't fucking blow.
You just died, man!
- I thought I was the other guy.
- No, dude, that's me.
- I thought I was playing the other dude.
- No. Fuck you, dude.
You're fucking high, dude.
- Yeah, I'm high.
- I'm ruined after five minutes of this shit.
This shit is creepy
as a motherfucker.
- You're a lightweight, dawg.
- I'm not a lightweight.
- Suck my balls.
- Dude, fuck you. Suck my balls, man!
You suck it, bitch.
You fucking wimp.
- So, how old are you?
- How old do I look?
About 12.
Oh, well, I'm 17,
but I do look really young.
I'm gonna kill your ass.
Answer your phone.
Go. Go answer your phone!
- Suck it! Suck it! Suck it!
- No, bitch, fuck you!
- Shut up!
- Fuck you!
Hello? Yo, Johnny! What's up?
Have you talked to anybody?
Not yet. Why?
Look, man. I can't keep
the kid here much longer.
- Why?
- Nothing.
I'm just having
some people over.
- What?
- Nobody. Shut up!
- What? Are you crazy?
- Nobody. Just some people.
Dude, I didn't tell you
to play fucking grab-ass!
Chill out, dawg.
No, fuck that! Get everyone
the fuck out of there!
All right. All right.
I'll clear it out.
I need you to do
a favor for me, bro.
Johnny's coming over
and I need the house.
Will you watch the kid for me
for a little while?
- Watch him?
- Yeah. Keep an eye on him.
No phones
and no leaving him alone.
No phones?
I don't get it.
All right, look. If I tell you something,
can you keep your fucking mouth shut?
Yeah, of course, man. Yeah.
The kid's older brother
owes Truelove money
and Johnny's holding him like a marker
or something, until he gets paid.
That's fucked up.
No. No, bitch,
it's not like that.
The kid knows what's happening,
and he's cool with it.
I mean, look at the motherfucker.
He ain't going nowhere.
Just take him someplace, hang out,
bring him back in a couple of hours.
Can you do that for me?
I don't know, man.
It sounds
pretty fucking dubious.
Keith, who the fuck
are you talking to, man?
If I tell you something's
good, then that's what it is.
Are you going to take care
of this for me or not?
Susan, I swear to God,
it's cool. Trust me.
- Would you fucking calm down?
- Hey! Fuck you! Let go of me!
You're not supposed to know
any of this.
Jesus, don't say anything,
okay?
You're gonna get me
in a lot of fucking trouble.
From who, Keith? From your little
fucking gangster friends from L.A.?
Yeah! From my...
- Oh, I'm real scared!
- Well, you fucking should be.
You're a little fucking
faggot, you know that?
Whoa, you guys, dude,
what's going on?
- This kid has been kidnapped!
- No, he hasn't!
- You mean like "abducted" kidnapped?
- Fucking stolen! Ask him.
Yeah.
Yeah, they took me. But
it's okay.
They took you? Why?
Because his scumbag brother
owes Johnny Truelove money.
Shut up!
- Whoa!
- That's fucking hot.
Dude, so you're like ransom
or something.
Yeah. Stolen boy.
Yeah.
- You don't look stolen.
- Yeah.
I know. It's weird.
Dude, I want you to know that you
can do anything you want, okay?
- No, he can't!
- I don't play that shit.
You want to fucking leave, go for it.
You want make a call...
You shut the fuck up,
you fucking bitch!
I'm a fucking bitch?
You're a fucking little bitch!
Guys! Whoa! Fuck!
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
- Sit down right now, you fucking bitch!
- I'm gonna knock your ass out.
- Keith, fucking chill out!
God, my brother is...
My brother is gonna
pay the money, okay?
See?
So, like, in the meantime,
you're, like, on vacation.
- Yeah. Exactly. Why not?
- That's fucking awesome.
It's, like, another story
to tell my grandkids.
Dude, that is so fucking cool.
Dude, this shirt is fucking cool.
Bob Marley is cool.
You guys think
that kidnapping is cool?
Yeah, Susan,
it's fucking exciting!
I think it's romantic, dude,
he's doing this for his brother.
- Are you insane?
- Susan, chill out.
Dude, this is fucking wrong!
Doesn't anybody else think
that this is fucking wrong?
- No!
- Susan, take a fucking Valium! Okay?
- It's not even any of your business.
- No! It is my house!
Jesus Christ,
calm the fuck down. All right.
I'm going to roll us the biggest
fucking joint anyone has ever seen.
- You down with that, Zack?
- Absolutely.
Hey. What's up,
you blunted faggot?
What's up,
you short bitch?
Make yourself busy, baby.
We got to talk some business.
- Can I get you guys a drink?
- Pia Colada?
It's not a bar, baby. There's
no fucking Pia Colada.
Not even a little can?
No, but I got some wine.
I can make you a spritzer.
Okay.
Sit down.
What's the fucking deal?
I don't know what to do.
- What do you mean?
- About the kid.
We could be
in a lot of trouble.
- Trouble?
- Yeah.
Big-ass,
serious-as-shit trouble.
I mean, you can't just take a
kid and have no one notice.
That's what I told you.
Didn't I say that?
- You did, all right?
- Fuck!
But, still, we are where we are.
Right here, you know?
I mean, it's a big problem
and we got to fix it.
- So what do we do?
- I don't know.
There's an answer here.
There's, like, a solution.
But I'm just...
I'm just not seeing it.
I don't know.
Maybe we're fucked.
We're not fucked.
- What do you mean, fucked?
- Jail fucked, motherfucker.
If we let the kid go, he runs back to
Mommy and Daddy and he rats us out.
- Maybe he won't.
- Not to mention Tattooey.
Who knows what that crazy
motherfucker is gonna do?
We're all gonna be looking
over our fucking shoulders.
I don't think the kid
will spill. I really don't.
Yeah, but what if he does?
- Fuck that shit.
- You see what I'm saying?
I'm not fucking going to prison!
Look, I just won't.
Yeah. Me neither, bitch. What the
fuck you think I'm talking about?
I'm not fucking kidding, John.
This is really fucking bad.
The best thing we could do would
be to get ahold of Tattooey,
and to straighten him and all
this shit out once and for all.
Well, where is
that motherfucker?
Who the fuck knows, man?
I don't know.
He's probably laying low, looking
to shoot me in the fucking head.
I mean, think about it.
That's what I'd be doing.
Stop already, all right! You know
how I get with this anxiety shit.
Frankie?
- Frankie?
- Yeah.
I swear to God, man,
I'm hyperventilating.
I want to ask you something.
What? Fuck.
Hypothetically, all right?
This isn't real, right?
We're just talking here.
But...
What would you say if I were to offer
you $2,500 just to kill the kid?
Kill him?
Yeah, fucking wax him.
Are you fucking insane?
I'm not going to fucking kill the kid.
That's a fucking joke, right?
Of course it's a fucking joke, man!
You're so fucking stupid.
- You're an asshole, man!
- All right, man, I'm just playing.
Well, stop fucking around.
Look, man, can't we just
grease the kid?
You know tell him he can hang out anytime.
That he's our boy.
Throw a fucking arm around him
or something.
- Give him a few bucks?
- Right.
And tell him
when Mommy and Daddy ask,
to say that he ran away
with some girl or something.
- Yeah, maybe, yeah.
- I mean, look...
I mean, we'd have to get the story
straight, but we can make it work, man.
- I know we could. We just grease the kid.
- Yeah.
- And then it's taken care of.
- Yeah. Yeah.
And that way we're not running around
here like a bunch of fucking Chinamen.
Done.
See, that's what I love
about you, man.
You're smarter than me.
Fuck!
Whoa, whoa.
Let me see that.
Come here.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
Could I talk to you alone
for a minute?
What's up?
I just wanted to say
sorry about all this shit.
You know, I know that
this is a big pain in the ass.
This whole thing
is really fucking ridiculous.
- Yeah.
- Are you okay?
I mean, is everybody treating you all
right? I mean, you got enough to eat?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
You need anything?
You need some dough?
No, I'm good.
- Are you sure? I mean, I...
- No, no, I'm really good. Really.
I mean, I know this is hard,
but this is all going to get squared
away soon, you know, I promise.
All right, cool.
All right.
I got to jet, but...
You know something?
You know, you're...
You're a pretty stand-up guy.
- Thanks.
- I mean, your brother is a dickhead.
I mean, he's my boy and I love
him, but he's just, you know...
I mean, he's acting a motherfucking
fool right now, you know.
- Yeah, I know.
- Yeah.
Well...
Anyways, tomorrow.
This will all be over
by tomorrow.
Hi.
Hey, baby. What's up? I thought
you were spending the night out.
I was. I just...
I really needed to talk.
- Talk?
- Yeah.
- What, now?
- Kind of.
One night. I ask for one night
out of the whole fucking year
to make love to your father and
you won't even give that to me?
I'm X-ing right now. I can't
understand anything you're saying.
- I'm sorry, Mom, okay?
- Fuck!
He was wearing a brown shirt, a
blue sweatshirt, brown tennis shoes
and his grandfather's ring.
It has a red stone.
Baby, you got a phone call.
I'll take it upstairs.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Hello. Hello.
Yo. It's me.
The midget.
You got some set of balls
calling me here.
What's the matter? You don't
answer a motherfucking page?
- We got nothing to talk about.
- Oh, I think we do, don't you?
Straighten out all this
shit once and for all?
There's nothing to straighten out,
motherfucker. I know it was you.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Johnny, I know. I know!
And you're dead.
- Don't threaten me.
- Fuck that! It's a promise.
No matter where you go, no matter what
you do, I'm going to hunt you down.
I'm going to hunt you down, and
then I'm going to slit your throat
and then I'm going
to cut you open
and then I'm gonna eat
your motherfucking heart!
You better pray!
Johnny, you better fucking pray
that the cops find you before I do!
Get on your cocksucking knees
and pray!
Hello? Hello?
Mr. Nolder,
Johnny Truelove on two.
Hey, Cock and Balls,
what can I do for you?
Question for you.
Let's say, someone owes someone
I know money and won't pay.
So that someone I know
has his boys snatch the deadbeat's
kid brother till does he does pay.
- What kind of problems is he looking at?
- Big ones.
If he asks for ransom,
he's looking at life.
Hello? You there, Cock?
- Life?
- Life, yeah.
- So what does he do?
- I don't know.
Probably digs a deep hole. Why?
What's the matter? Who's in trouble?
What the hell
is he still doing here?
You got to
chill the fuck out, Susan.
I mean, you keep
running your fucking mouth,
Truelove could go to jail
and we can wind up dead.
Fuck you, all right. You don't know.
That motherfucker's crazy.
Yesterday he offered me
2,500 bucks to kill the kid.
- What?
- Right. Kill him.
Oh, Jesus.
First you give me mouth and now
you give me fucking tears?
Do me a favor, Susan.
Have a period or something.
Of course I'm not going to do it! I told
him. I'm just saying, that's how spun he is.
I got it under control.
I got it under control,
all right?
Say it. Say, "You, Frankie,
have it under control."
Say it!
- You, Frankie, have it under control.
- Right.
Now say "I, Susan,
am a whiny fucking bitch
"and you, Frankie,
have it under control."
I, Susan, am a
whiny fucking bitch
and you, Frankie,
have it under control.
Right.
Worst comes to worst, I tell
everybody to go fuck themselves
put 50 bucks in the kid's
pocket, and stick him on a bus.
- You promise?
- I swear.
See, bitch? Johnny. Hey.
- Hey, what up?
- What's the word?
- We're picking the kid up.
- Great! What time?
About 8:00, 8:30.
Listen, man, I'm gonna have to take
him to a hotel or something, then.
What's going on?
My dad's bitch girlfriend is up
my ass with a fucking broom.
- Call me when you get there.
- All right.
- Okay?
- All right, man.
- I'm on my cell.
- I'll call you when I get straight.
All right, later.
The kid's going home!
What up, buddies?
- What up, buddy, buddy?
- Buddy, buddy, buddy!
Hey, we need to borrow
your mom's car.
- Moving?
- Yeah. Moving.
- That one right there.
- Yeah, let's go!
Get off me.
You kids have a good time!
Go!
- What up?
- Well, when am I gonna fucking get paid?
Get in there. Get in there.
- You like this shit? This is dope, right?
- Yeah.
Everybody out.
Get the fuck out of here! Can't
you see me on the toilet?
I don't give a fuck what you're doing.
I said get the fuck out.
I'm trying to pee here!
Let go of me!
This is my party, and I
say you're getting out.
- What the fuck are you doing, crazy-ass?
- Hello! Jesus.
- I can't believe I just saw that.
- I don't give a fuck!
Listen, to me, Ziggy,
I said, you pay me today.
Oh, you don't have it? Listen,
let me tell you something.
If you see me, you don't
want to fucking see me.
Yeah, it's like that,
bitch. Fuck you.
- Baby, get off the phone.
- I'm getting off!
- Is that guy giving you a problem?
- Yeah, why?
Let's kick his ass.
All of a sudden
you're a tough guy?
I can fight him. I'm a fucking
black belt in tae kwon do.
Shut the fuck up.
- Your ass.
- I am.
Looks like I picked
the wrong man.
No shit. Come here,
you little fucker.
Come on, bitch. How does that feel?
Think you're bad, huh?
You're going
to break his neck.
Give the little fucker
a kiss.
Come on, you're fucking
getting it everywhere!
What are you gonna do now, huh?
Who's your fucking daddy, huh?
- Show me one of your fucking moves.
- What?
Well, hell, no, bitch. Hell fucking no.
You sizing me up?
You sizing me?
That was fucking awesome!
- You're fucking awesome!
- Dude.
That was awesome, dude.
This little bitch can fight!
- My God, that was amazing.
- Open the door!
Hey, open up, man!
Fuck off! We're fighting.
There's no room for bitches!
Or fucking queers!
- Come on, open the door, assholes!
- Okay, open it.
Let that sack of
monkey shit in here.
Don't call me a sack
of monkey shit.
Jesus, what happened
to your shirt, bitch?
I don't know. Dude,
we're out of booze, man.
Already?
Tell your little freeloader friends
to slow the fuck down, Keith.
I'm not made of money.
- I need a cigarette.
- All right.
We're leaving. Keep
everything under control.
Hey.
- Is this him?
- Zack, this is Alma.
Watch how fast
I can down this shit.
Holy motherfucking shit.
Nice.
You should have seen me
with the beer bong.
Quit staring at me.
Your turn.
Okay. Ready?
Go.
- So you're really stolen?
- Yeah. I really am.
He's cute.
- You got a girlfriend, stolen boy?
- No.
- How old are you?
- Seventeen.
Seventeen? This
motherfucker's 15 years old.
Dude,
what's your fucking problem?
I'm sorry. Jesus.
They don't care anyway, man.
Ever been laid, stolen boy?
- It's my birthday!
- Happy birthday, girl.
- Can you guys give us a second?
- Why?
I need to talk to you
about something in private.
Hurry.
Love it.
So?
So what?
What do you think?
- What do I think?
- Yeah, what do you think?
What do you mean,
what do I think?
I mean
about this whole thing.
I think no more music videos.
That's what I think.
Right.
Fuck it.
You need anything?
Money?
No.
You got gas?
I got gas.
Okay, then.
Truelove!
Are you ready to drink for my birthday?
No, where's he going?
I hate it that
you have to work, Schmitty.
Happy birthday, Angie.
Eat a piece of cake for me.
Okay.
What are you doing? This is
your lucky night. Get in.
Hi.
Turn around.
- I don't get it.
- Just turn around.
Start counting.
One, two, three four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten. Ready or not, here I come.
- Marco.
- Polo!
Polo!
- Marco.
- Polo.
Polo.
- Do you want to know what I wished for?
- What?
- I'll tell you. I want to suck your cock.
- Oh, shit.
Wait, the wish is coming true!
It's coming true! Oh, Lordy!
Wait, my wish is coming true! My
wish is coming true! Oh, shit!
- Baby, I got to go make a phone call.
- No, you don't.
- I got to make a phone call for a second.
- No. No. Why?
Bad!
- He's bad.
- Let's open the gifts.
Yes!
- Hello.
- What up, jerky?
- Yeah, I'm kind of busy.
- Dude, it's me.
- Johnny?
- Yeah, I'm on my way.
- Oh, great. How long?
- Half an hour. Clear it out, all right?
Yeah, you got it.
Hey, hey, hey,
Zack's going home!
Party's over. All you
motherfuckers got to go.
- Bye, Zack. I'm glad you're going home.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
- Now you got your story to tell.
- Yeah, bye.
- See you.
- Call me sometime.
- I will.
You better.
Bye, stud.
And wipe that smile off your face.
You're a dead fucking giveaway.
Okay.
No.
Don't fucking move.
What?
Yo, dude,
just hang out with us.
- Oh, man, I was going to catch a ride home.
- You love weed.
- Fuck.
- You love it.
- Fuck you, ladies.
- We'll see you guys later, all right?
Drive really fast
with your eyes closed.
You're an asshole.
Roll up, Stratten.
- Bye, bitches!
- We love you, Zack!
Thanks for
the virginity, baby!
- Sonny.
- Hey, Elaine, how you doing?
Is my boy here?
I'm looking for him.
No, they went out
for Angela's birthday.
Something's come up.
You mind if we wait?
- What are you doing here?
- Outside.
What's the deal, Elvis? You
driving the kid home or what?
- What.
- What?
- That's right.
- What the fuck are you talking about?
What the fuck?
The kid ain't going home.
- But I thought Johnny was going...
- Well, you thought wrong.
- Fuck that. Johnny didn't tell me shit.
- The decision's been made.
Fuck you.
Fuck me? Fuck you!
Johnny sent me here
to take care of something
and I'm gonna fucking do it
with you or through you!
Who's sucking
whose cock now, huh, Frankie?
- Fuck that! I'm out.
- Fuck that? You're fucking in.
I'm up here to clean up your mess,
and you're gonna fucking help me,
or the whole world is gonna
come down on your head.
All right!
Fucking let go of me!
What the fuck
do you want me to do?
We need some tape.
- Fuck that!
- You're gonna dig.
Dig this, bitch!
- You're gonna do it. You're gonna help me.
- Fuck that! No fucking way.
Ain't no fucking way, Elvis.
I'm not digging.
Fuck you! I did my shit. This
is the line, motherfucker!
Everybody's got one and mine's
a fucking grave, all right?
You want to shoot me? Shoot me right
fucking here. I don't give a fuck!
Hey, excuse me?
Where's Frankie?
I need a ride home.
Whoa.
- What's going on, man?
- Come on, I need your help.
What the fuck do you need
duct tape for, dude?
Where is everybody?
Keith said he needed a ride
home, so that guy gave him one.
What are you watching?
- Austin Powers.
- All right.
Shit's so funny.
This shit's been going on for,
like, I don't know, two minutes.
You wanna run to the store for me?
Get me some cigarettes?
Dude, I'm too young
and they won't sell to me.
Let's take a drive, let's go somewhere.
You want to?
No, I'm cool.
I just want to watch a movie.
Okay.
- Angela.
- What the fuck is going on?
- What did you do?
- Nothing.
- Are you all right?
- She's fine.
We're going in the other room,
we need to talk.
Fuck that.
It is my birthday.
- No, we're going right now!
- Don't you fucking touch me!
- Hey, the party's over, wait a second.
- Fuck!
You don't talk to your mother like that.
We're trying to help you!
- Where's the kid?
- Who?
- Where's Mazursky?
- I don't know who you're talking...
Dad, I swear.
Fucking get off me!
You're fucking stupid! Stupid, John!
Don't you fucking get it, you moron?
There's a Missing Persons
poster on every street corner!
You're in deep shit, Johnny.
The cops pick you up,
you're doing 25 to life.
- You don't think I know that?
- You've fucked your life up so bad.
The only way you're going to unfuck
it is that you come clean now, John.
- You come clean now!
- Calm down, calm down.
Let me talk to him, all right?
Come on, let me talk to him.
Look, everybody's
getting excited here.
What your father's trying
to say is we have a plan.
You bring the kid home,
we have a sit-down.
Me, you, the mother,
the father, everybody.
Sonny brings his checkbook,
and we settle it right there.
- That will never work.
- I'm not saying it will.
You're probably looking
at some jail time.
But if that's
our only option,
I'll walk you right through
custody, we'll do it the right way.
I guarantee you do
minimum sentence.
Be smart, kid. Let the
spooks do the hard time.
Fuck that. No jail.
Two years? A piece of cake. Winter,
summer, winter, summer, done.
- No.
- Then you tell us your plan, Einstein.
You tell us
how this all turns out.
- Hey, Keith, what's up?
- I fell.
You fell?
- Hey.
- Don't fucking touch me.
- What's up?
- What's up, buddy?
- You're Zack, right?
- Yeah.
Well, I'm Elvis and I'm going
to take you home, man.
You coming?
You got to do this, man.
It's got to be unanimous.
If the kid goes home,
everybody's looking at life.
- Life?
- Life.
We talked to a lawyer, man,
and there's no way around it.
Life for what?
For taking care of the kid?
For letting him sleep
at my fucking house?
You were there
from square one.
You sat on him the whole fucking time.
You think you're going to walk?
Goddamn. Life?
There it is.
I mean, I like the kid.
What's not to like?
He's 15.
He's just too much
of a liability.
Think about it. We send the kid
home, you got Jake looking for you.
You don't want that.
You don't go along, then Johnny don't
trust you and he's coming after you
and you sure as shit don't want Sonny
Truelove knocking at your door.
We don't have a choice, man.
God, my parents
are going to fucking kill me.
I can just see my mom.
She's fucking...
Oh, God. Oh, God.
But, hey, guys, listen,
I would never
rat you guys out.
You guys and me are like... We're
like this. You know that, right?
Frankie, you know that,
right?
Yeah, we know that, man.
Right. Cool.
I'm probably
just going to say that I...
I don't know, that I ran
away or something to, like,
Bakersfield or Fresno
or something.
Fuck it, you know?
Hey, does anybody know
where Bakersfield is?
Say you were with a girl.
They'll believe that.
Yeah, like Julie.
You know, when I get back, I'm going
to start fresh. You know that?
Like, I just want to start completely
fresh. You ever feel like that, Frankie?
- What's up?
- Like...
Like, I don't know. Like you want to, I
don't know, go to Europe or something.
Or take a class, or something like that. Or
learn to play an instrument. Like guitar.
It sounds really fucking hard.
I mean, it's guitar.
But it bugs me that I don't know
how to do anything, you know.
I'm pretty sure I could.
Yeah.
- Johnny, call it off.
- Nothing's gonna happen.
These guys are such fuck-ups, the
kid's probably loose right now.
Make the fucking call!
What are we doing?
We're meeting somebody
who's gonna take you home.
Oh, cool.
You know, I think I'm going to
start being nicer to my mom.
It's kind of gay, but if you
think about it, she's the shit.
She's, like, my best friend
in the whole world, you know?
- Hi.
I can't do this. I can't do this, man.
I got to fucking go home.
Come on, Keith.
Keith?
Dude, what's going on?
You're crying.
- Get away from me!
- Hey!
Keith?
What's the matter
with him?
Him?
Frankie, what's going on?
Frank?
Frankie?
Dude.
- Oh, man!
- All right, you ready? Let's do this.
- Oh, man, please, I didn't do anything.
- Move it. Shut the fuck up.
- I swear to God, please.
- Relax! Move, move, move.
- Frankie, please.
- Relax, buddy, relax, okay?
- It's not what you think, okay?
- Yeah, it is, Frankie!
- Please, I thought we were boys.
- We are boys.
Frankie, there's nobody up there!
Nobody is picking me up!
- Yes, there is, okay. Just stop freaking out.
- Frankie, you promise?
- I promise, all right?
- Do you swear?
Zack, everything's cool, on my
life, okay, I swear to God.
- Come on.
- Okay.
- All right, I swear to God.
- All right.
- Come on, man.
- All right, man.
- Let's just walk.
- All right.
We're just going to take a walk.
Come on, man.
Frankie? Oh, please! I won't tell
anybody, I swear to God, Frankie!
Hey, we're not gonna do this, right?
We're not really gonna do this.
- Shut your fucking mouth!
- We're not gonna do this?
- If you want to live, shut your mouth.
- Please, mister! Please!
Are you crazy?
This is fucking stupid, man.
Goddamn it, Frankie,
I can't fucking concentrate!
I swear I won't tell
my mom or anything!
Shut his fucking mouth
or I'll fucking shoot him!
- I mean it! I'll fucking shoot him!
- All right! All right!
You'll never see me again!
I swear!
Look, little man, you got
to calm down, all right?
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Everybody's nervous, all right?
- I don't want to die, Frankie.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
- Everything's okay.
- Okay.
- All right?
- Frankie.
What's the tape for,
Frankie?
- I would never hurt you, Zacky, all right?
- Okay.
But I'm going to have to tape you up.
So give me your hands.
- Okay.
- Everything's going to be all right.
- Hey. Hey, I'm your boy.
- I know.
- Okay.
- All right?
See? Everything's okay.
Everything's okay.
I don't want to die, Frankie.
I don't want to die.
Now I'm gonna have to
tape your mouth up, okay?
All right.
Okay.
You're my boy.
I wouldn't hurt you.
Okay?
- Hey, everything's okay.
- All right. I know.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
What the fuck are you doing?
Oh, fuck.
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ.
It was 6:00 in the morning
and several black cars
pulled up.
There were men in suits and the
doorbell was just ringing.
"We found your son,"
they said.
"We found your son and it's
"bad news," they said.
About the funeral?
- Jake didn't show?
- No.
Oh, he said it was out of respect for me.
That's a crock.
He just didn't
want to get hit.
- I'm sorry, I don't understand.
- Shot. Killed. Murdered.
I happen to know he owes
$50,000 to one drug dealer.
They have their own rules
in the drug world.
They killed my son
for $1,200.
I'm just so sorry for your loss.
I mean, I can't even imagine.
When my son died, I died.
I loved him
every single day of my life
and I wasn't afraid
to show him.
What made you try
and kill yourself?
I don't know.
You know, it seemed like a
long time to my natural death.
I don't know.
You know, all three times I tried to commit
suicide, there was alcohol involved.
When I tried to kill myself in
the hospital, I did it wrong.
You know, you're supposed
to do it like this.
Maybe it was the pills.
It's all bullshit, anyway.
They say
there's a reason
for everything.
Well,
if that God's
got a purpose for me,
he better get the fuck down
here and tell me what it is!
Because I don't see it.
I think that might be enough
for today. Okay?
- Thank you for your time.
- Okay.
- Was that okay?
- Yeah.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Yo, what's up?
Zack's dead.
How do you know that?
I had nothing
to do with this.
I never laid
a finger on him.
I didn't know
this happened, Susan!
I can't believe it happened.
- Fucking what is going on, Frankie?
- I don't know.
- Tell me the truth!
- I don't know, okay!
I think I'm getting set up!
Did you
fucking take him home?
Yes! I dropped him off
in Pomona.
Where? What street? You dropped
him off at his fucking house?
I don't fucking know, okay?
I dropped him off in Pomona!
You better get yourself
a good lawyer.
Fuck you!
You can't come in here, man. I'm
serious, man. Get the fuck out of here.
- I'm in trouble, Pick.
- Yeah, no shit. And with my mom's car, man!
- Why'd you do it, huh?
- I'm sorry.
Motherfuckers. Do you have any
idea how much fucking shit
I've been through
for this?
I'm fucked, Pick. You gotta help me, man.
Can you just give me your car?
No, man. Fuck that!
Can you give me
a ride out of town?
No. Get the fuck
out of here, man!
- Where the fuck do you want me to go?
- That's your fucking problem.
Man, you got to let me use your phone.
I gotta call Johnny. Please. Please.
Look, man, I love you,
but you're on your own.
Put your hands behind your head, or I'll
blow your fucking head off! Get down!
I'm not fucking with you, asshole!
Get down on the ground, now!
Get on your knees,
asshole.
I can't believe it.
They got Tiko, too?
Yeah. Tiko, Elvis, Nuts, 911.
They got everybody.
Well, for what?
What the fuck do you think, baby?
That kid turned up dead.
Hey, the Captain
and Tennille.
- What can I do for you guys?
- Hey, I'd like to trade that for that.
- You want to trade this car for that car?
- Yeah.
- All right. Let's go get you a loan app.
- We don't need to do that.
You want to fuck?
All right.
- Something wrong?
- No.
No? Your dick's
not even hard.
- It's getting there.
- Getting there?
- Yeah, it's getting there.
- It's like a piece of bubble gum.
Then do something
about it, bitch.
Sorry.
Sorry? Yeah, you're a sorry
little bitch who can't even fuck!
Excuse me for being a little
distracted, all right!
Give me a break. I've got a
lot on my mind right now.
Well, what do you want to fucking do?
You want to play cards?
You want to cuddle?
- Can't we just...
- No, fuck that shit! I want to fuck!
- Hey, suck my dick, all right?
- I tried that. It didn't work, did it?
- You're a fucking bitch.
- Shut the fuck up.
You know that?
You're a fucking cunt.
- Where's my fucking shoe?
- I don't know.
Okay, all right, all right. Fucking truce.
Do you want one of mine?
Fuck you. I'm taking a walk.
- Buzz! Johnny's here.
- Johnny who?
Yeah,
it was unbelievable.
I hadn't seen Johnny
since junior high.
I mean, what a coincidence, right?
I look up and he's right there.
Did he tell you
what happened?
Yeah. He told me
that some friends of his
had done some bad shit and
that he was going down for it.
He said that he was in big trouble. He
needed help to get out of the country.
- And you agreed to drive him, just like that?
- Yeah.
He's my boy. He was stuck.
All right. Go on.
All right.
So we go up by I-25, right? And this
guy is acting fucking weird, dude.
Talking about God and forgiveness,
all kinds of crazy shit.
So we get to the border crossing and
he starts flipping out, going crazy.
I'm like, "Dude,
fucking calm down, bro.
"We'll stop, we'll pull over, you'll
get in the trunk. It's all good."
He's like, "No, no, no! They know!
They know! I'm serious! I'm fucked."
I'm, like... You should have seen it.
He was going out of his mind.
So we turn around, we turn around again.
Now he wants to go to Mexico.
So we go all the way back down,
we're driving back down.
We get to Cheyenne.
He changes his mind again.
I'm like, "All right, dude, that's it.
I can't do this forever.
"Where the fuck
do you want to go?"
- Be right back.
- Okay.
Hey, I mean it,
all right. Five minutes.
All right.
I'll wait for you.
It's been four years
since your son's escape,
and you know what?
I think you helped him. I think
you know exactly where he is.
There it is. Million
dollar question, right?
What you, the cops, the D.A., the Feds,
what everybody wants to know, right?
Somebody had to help him
get out of the country.
Somebody has to be
sending him money.
I do not know
where my son is.
And if I knew, you think I'd tell
you and this fucking camera?
I think he's lost.
What?
The day they dropped him off at my house, I
reached into the fridge to get a sandwich,
I turned around,
he was gone.
- Come on.
- I'm telling you, he's lost.
I think he's right.
I mean, I ain't seen him.
He ain't here.
He must be lost.
Now get the fuck
out of my house.