Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
They're shooting people!
Where are you calling from?
I'm calling from Ridgeline High.
Stay calm.
What's your name?
My name is Rebecca.
Okay, Rebecca,
are you injured?
No. No. But there are
a lot of people who aren't moving.
Are you in any danger?
Can you see the shooter...
I drive myself crazy with the...
with the what-ifs
and the shoulda-beens.
No, no, uh...
I look and I look, but...
there's nothin' I regret, there's nothin'
I would have done different.
You ever shoot anybody?
No.
You never seen anybody shot?
Yeah.
I'm here with Janet Huttensen,
the mother of Robbie Huttensen,
one of the two Ridgeline High School
shooters.
Obviously this has been
an incredibly hard couple of years for you.
On this, the three-year anniversary
of the Ridgeline shooting...
how could a parent not know
that their child is thinking of...
Well, it's...
it's not that simple.
- There was nothing unusual?
- No.
How could this happen?
- Something around the house?
- No.
- In his room?
We're just trying to understand.
Well, you're trying to
understand something that I can't explain.
I don't know what
you want me to say.
Where were they shot?
In the chest.
- And in the face.
- And in the face? Oh.
Pretty nasty, huh?
You have another son, David.
David is now currently in high school.
He is now the same age
as Robet was when...
I'm sorry, I don't see the question.
Are you scared?
Scared? No.
Why would I...
This thing... in your hand.
It doesn't make people
stop bothering you...
it doesn't make things go away.
It does that. What you saw.
Do you ever think
about the children who
- lost their lives that day?
- Yeah, yeah.
I cared about those kids.
They were... for God's sake.
I mean, a lot of 'em,
I'd seen 'em, you know...
- You'd watched them grow up.
- Yeah.
Don't you ever bring one of these...
into my school again.
So when am I gonna get my check?
Let me see.
Excuse me, Pansy? She wants to
know when she's gonna get her check.
We'll make sure to
get you the rest of it.
Thank you.
Hey, kiddo. Get up.
Go to bed.
- Finish your homework?
- Hmm.
I'll get you up in the morning.
You can finish it then.
Okay.
- And brush your teeth.
- Okay.
It was one of those skirts with
a high slit up the side.
- Was it cute?
- Hell, no. She looked like a slut.
- You think everyone looks like a slut.
- She did!
- Where'd she get it?
- Her mom's closet.
Ooh, feisty this morning.
Fuckin' genius.
No, actually she got at the Gap,
and she cut it herself.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey! Hey!
What's the matter with you?
Wait. Why can't I have
my bottle of water?
- I don't make the rules, okay?
- It's a clear plastic bottle.
It's obvious that there's
water inside of there.
- It's really a bottle of water.
- I don't make the rules.
- Yeah, but the plastic is clear...
- I don't make the rules!
- Get out of here! Go learn something!
- I'm just trying to have a discussion.
What's so threatening
about a bottle of water?
- Hey, Frank.
- License and registration?
I'm Shelley's husband. She plays bridge
with your sister all the time.
I know who you are, Earl.
I'm just doing my job.
License and registration.
Okay.
Hey, Frank.
Can't we... why don't you...
- Can you give me a warning or something?
- You got a permit for that?
What's that?
That gun.
You got a permit for it?
- Uh, yeah.
- Good.
Listen, do me a favor...
don't keep it up here, okay?
If anybody pulls you over,
you tell 'em it's in the trunk.
I suppose you're gonna
give me a ticket for that, too.
You were doing seventy miles per hour
up the hill.
- What do you expect me to do?
- I don't know...
Earl. What do you
expect me to do?
You take care now.
There's a lot of things
you guys could do, Rachel.
Depends on how much
you want to do.
I can open up a parking lot for you.
You want some car wash,
you want a bake sale...
whatever you want.
You guys are doing gr...
Okay, hold on! Hold on!
I'm gonna have to go.
I'll talk to you later, okay?
My disciplining him is very different
from you disciplining him.
How many times
do I gotta tell you?!
Enough! What the hell
is the matter with you?
Hey, Reggie? What you doing
talking to our kids like that?
- Mr. Carter, they hear that all day!
- I don't care what they hear.
You want me to come in here
and talk to 'em like they're second-graders?
- That's not gonna work!
- Reggie.
You will not talk to these kids like that.
- Where have you been?
- I subbed in Reggie's class.
They were giving speeches for...
whatever the heck today is.
- What's going on over here?
- Two fights, smoking,
and that one decided to
bring in a handgun today.
Sara called three hours ago.
She wanted you to remember to get
Hakeem a new backpack today.
She said the plastic bag he had
been using ripped again.
Don't we have a backpack
in Lost & Found?
Carter, no. You cannot give
your son some old...
- This has been here over a year, right?
- That is a girl's bag.
There's no such thing
as a girl's backpack.
It's got little pink flowers
all over it.
Yeah... it does.
You know, when I was a kid,
my family couldn't afford
to buy me new clothes.
I'd have to wear my sister's.
I'd go to school wearing a blouse.
That's just the way it was.
He'll be fine.
Okay.
- Keep your eyes up.
- Sorry.
Here we go.
Can I move yet?
Uh, yeah. I'm done.
- Okay, you ready for this?
- Yeah, let's see it.
- You ready?
- Yes! Let me see it.
Ewww! Oh, my God! That is...
Do you like it?
Come on! That's terrible!
What?
It's really bad.
Look at my forehead!
Well, look at your forehead.
Oh, my God!
Look at my chest. That's obnoxious.
When did I get a boob job?
And what's with the cowboy thing?
Okay, that is the last time I draw you.
It's not the last time,
it's not even the first time.
- That's not me.
- Okay, whatever.
- I'm going to class.
- Shit, what time is it?
- Like noon.
- Gotta go to my crappy job.
If you hate your job so much,
why don't you just quit
and get something on campus?
It's not that I hate it,
it's just that it's...
I don't know, it's like everything else.
Why did I move
halfway across the country
so my parents pay for college?
Because everyone in my family
goes to the University of Virginia.
No exceptions.
Why do I work in
my grandfather's shop?
Because everyone in my family
works in my grandfather's shop.
No exceptions. Right.
My mom thinks that's a normal job
for a college student to have.
Around here everyone just ends up
doing what their family does anyway.
Well, I hope no one in your family
is an artist.
Ha ha! I was just kidding.
- There's nothing wrong with it.
- Yeah?
And it's just the same as his.
Sure it's not your eyes?
- Heya.
- Hey.
God.
I don't know what
he could have done with this.
- Some people switch the scope out.
- That could have been it.
Or loosened the trigger.
Anyway, I took the liberty of
ordering you a new scope.
- You ordered a scope?
- Yeah. If you like it, fine.
If you don't like it, I'm sure I'll be able
to sell it to somebody else
or it'll just come out of
my own pocket.
Maryanne? There's a scope box
out there on the cabinet
with Mr. Stewart's name on it.
Would you bring it in to me, please?
Carl, that's not... your granddaughter?
- Yeah.
- She's out here now?
God, I haven't seen her in,
wow... not since...
- She was knee high to a grasshopper?
- Yeah.
Yeah, she's been here, oh,
nigh-on three months now.
- She's Lindy's daughter?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
She's not making the best of things
out here.
Well, it's a big change, you know.
You can't blame yourself
if she doesn't like it.
Well, she sure doesn't like it.
She drags herself in here like...
I don't think she's got
the personality to make friends.
That's the problem.
That's a big problem.
Now that she's back at UVA
she should do okay.
They'll loosen her up.
What do you think?
Maryanne, you find it okay?
Open it up, please.
- What's up, Playboy?
- How ya doin'?
You just might be psychic, man,
not even know it.
- I'm serious.
- You dumb.
I read it in some magazine.
Dude did a study,
and like 87% of people can tell when
people are starin' at 'em from behind.
People just know.
So what you sayin', people just know
that they psychic?
Our brain does stuff
we can't even understand.
They can't even explain
how much knowledge...
Hey, yo, Jay, read my mind, dawg,
what am I thinkin' right now?
Go on!
I'm thinkin' that
you read too damn much, man!
Hey, yo, Jay! You feel me lookin'
at you, right, dawg?
You feel me lookin' at you, right?
Yeah, man, I feel you lookin' at me.
Hey, Connie, wait up!
Hey, hold it. I got you.
A'ight.
- A'ight, man.
- A'ight.
- Where you goin'?
- Home.
Take that with you.
Don't just leave it out here.
I ain't takin' that home.
- I don't want it in front of my place.
- You think I want it in front of mine?
- Put it in the lot.
- Unh-unh.
- Why not?
- You gotta push me in the morning.
Like I'm gonna stick it in the lot
so some bum can steal it.
Like no one's gonna steal it out here?
Just put the cart in the damn lot.
- Man, you put the cart in the lot!
- You put it in the lot.
I'm gonna tell yo mama
to put it in the lot!
I'm gonna tell your auntie you said
to put the cart in the lot.
- I'm just tellin' you it's truthful.
- What?
- Country music records are ill.
- You're high, man.
No, I'm tellin' you,
if you break it down, man...
This is worse than in fifth grade
when you were whispering
Bobby Brown lyrics to girls.
I'm tellin' you, they just melt
over country music lyrics, man,
they just as good as any R & B lyrics,
except for they new
and they fresh,
you know what I'm sayin'?
Even if they old.
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
That's... sad.
Honestly, that's real sad, man.
- Take Johnny Cash, for example.
- Johnny Cash?
No, no, just stop. Don't tell me nothin'
about no Elvis Presley.
Why do you think
they called him The King?
Who called him The King?
The cat was like 350 pounds
with bell-bottoms.
What kinda king you know
wear bell-bottoms?
You're just close-minded.
It's gettin' late.
Yeah.
Got a book this thick to read.
I got algebra, man, but all the answers
is in the back of the book,
so I'm good.
A'ight, man.
You should really
try to learn that shit, man.
It's your eyes.
- My what?
- Your eyes.
I like 'em.
- What color are they?
- Ohh... why you gotta do that?
- I know you don't know.
- I know.
I know.
Hazel.
He's not talking to me.
- Same shit?
- It's never the same.
Yeah, well, what is it this time?
He doesn't like Barry.
That loser spend the night
last night?
Yeah.
And you're wondering why
David's not talking to you.
Listen, he left at four.
I don't know, what,
does he want me to...
does he want me to be... celibate?
David is sixteen years old.
He doesn't care what the hell you are.
- You can't have other guys...
Hey, Lou!
You can't smoke here!
- It ain't lit.
- I don't care.
I thought you were
wearing the patch.
- Does that thing work?
- Well, no.
But you put a couple
across your chest,
a few on your ass,
and you're good to go.
You workin' a double tonight?
Depends on who doesn't show.
What?
It happened suddenly.
When I raised my head
and opened my eyes
I couldn't recognize anyone.
I don't think that I can ever forget
the parents and the police
going from body to body
in the parking lot of the school.
It was three years ago today
in Ellisburgh, Oregon,
that Robbie Huttensen
and Donnie McDaniel
opened fire on
the students and teachers
of Ridgeline High School.
Tonight we're going to
take a closer look
at the stories behind the headlines,
and the families affected
by this tragedy
are going to talk about it
for the first time.
I cared about those kids.
They were... for God's sake...
How does a parent not know
that their child is ready to do...
It's not that simple.
No, I drive myself crazy with the...
you know, the what-ifs
and the shoulda-beens.
Anything around the house?
No.
In his room?
No. No. Uh...
I look and I look, but...
there's nothing I regret,
there's nothing I would have
done different.
Mmm.
He asleep?
No, but he's laying there.
... on this,
the three-year anniversary
of the Ridgeline shooting.
- You have another son.
- Why don't we watch something else?
- David.
- Just give me a minute, okay?
He is now about the same age
Robet was when...
I'm sorry, I don't see the question.
Are you scared?
Scared? No. Why would I...
Did the kids ever come to your house?
Spend time with Robbie?
You're asking me if any of
the dead kids ever came around?
- The "dead kids"?
- I don't mean it like that. but I...
I mean, you're asking me if
in seventeen years of sleep-overs...
What about the summer of 1996 when
the police were called to your house,
just three months before?
- It was a disturbance of the peace call.
- Yeah, I didn't...
- Just three months before.
- The neighbors made that call.
- Janet, did your husband beat you?
- Beat me? No.
Was he physical with Robet and David?
Physical? What? No.
What are you trying to say?
We just want to understand.
You want to understand something
that I... can't explain.
When Newsline returns,
more with Janet Huttensen,
mother of a Ridgeline school shooter.
But first, could these officers have saved
the children of Ridgeline?
Why didn't they act?
What went wrong?
Do you think more could have
been done than was?
Well... yeah. I think those
officers could have done a lot more...
than they did right then.
I think they could have done
a lot more.
Yeah. Okay, I understand that,
but who should I be talking to, then?
This is the TV station, is it not?
Is this not the TV station?
I don't get enough mail here
that I would miss a consent form.
You put me on TV, all right?
This is not... I live here,
I live in this town, do you understand that?
Well, darn it, who am I
supposed to talk to, then?
The first person said
I should talk to you,
now you're telling me
I should be talking to somebody else.
Just give me a name.
Well, that would be good.
I'd appreciate that. Thank you.
My fucking job!
That's what I was doing!
I am the other side of the story.
How dare you question...
What?
When I came there...
when I was there,
they held me back at the gates.
They held me back there
while the kids...
there are children in there
that are hit.
The kids are in there getting killed,
they're getting slaughtered!
Some died instantly.
Your son bled to death.
Do you ever think about that officer
that was first on the scene?
Yeah, I think about him.
I'm goin' to work.
It ain't workin'.
- What's not workin'?
- The pump.
Pull around. I'll put it in
the other side.
Can't you just come out and check it?
Pull around. I'll put it on two.
I ain't got no gas in the car.
- You want your money back?
- I ain't asked for my money back,
I just want you to... I'll push it,
then you just put it in neutral.
I can't leave the booth.
I gotta stay here.
Hmm.
I'm sorry, dude.
Shift change, man.
Hey, wipe the drool off, man.
See? I told you.
Jimmy! Hakeem!
You boys get away from here!
Hakeem! Come on through,
little man.
How you doin', little man?
How many of you are here because of
the fight in 201? Raise your hand.
I want you all to sign this sheet,
go to your last class,
I'll call you in tomorrow
individually.
Tasha, what are you still doing here?
You can't just sit here.
You gotta go to class.
Sit down, buddy.
"Notorious B.I.G."?
I want you to go in my office.
Go wait in my office.
You think that's funny?
All right.
Okay. Go to class.
Okay, so, I think Paco's
gonna have a party tonight.
- Paco?
- He's cool.
I'm kind of over the whole
backwoods party thing.
- I'm gonna study.
- Oh, you mean call Brian?
I mean exactly what I say.
Hey, buddy.
Buddy.
It's time to get up.
It's time to go.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- There aren't any more greens?
- Nope.
- I thought we bought four cans.
- I did.
What happened to the greens?
'Cause I wanted to have some.
How'd the day go?
Parent conferences?
A couple.
Reggie quit.
- Couple of days ago.
- Of course he did.
You talked to your son today?
On the way home?
Why?
A body was found
in the school parking lot today.
Know who found it?
- Jimmy Frank.
- Who's Jimmy Frank?
Your son's best friend!
David, how do you walk
a mile and a half with your son,
take the train, and don't even
talk to the boy?
- It's not a mile and a half.
- I don't care.
It's twelve blocks,
and then the train.
I don't want to argue. I'm just
telling you, it's not a mile and a half.
Your son saw a half-naked hooker
with her stomach cut out,
with the knife still sticking in her!
I'm 37 years old, and I've never,
ever seen anything like that. Never.
You wouldn't let him go
to your mother's funeral,
- today he sees a dead prostitute.
- What do you want me to do?
What do I want you to do?
I want you to talk to your son.
You spend more time talking to the parents
of those thieves and gun-toting...
- That's my job.
- No, it's not your job!
- Look, I got 2,000 kids...
- They're not your responsibility!
At the end of the day there's one
little boy that's your responsibility,
and that little boy
just saw a dead prostitute, Carter.
That's not normal!
I can't just leave in the middle of my day
and go out and do something...
- You're out of your mind!
- What do you want from me?
You want me to tell all the hookers
to stop tricking on Adams?
Do you want me to go out there
with a shotgun and say,
"Stop! You know what,
my son is coming out here.
- You guys gotta go inside."
- I want you to talk to your son!
- I don't have a vice principal,
- Just talk to him!
I don't have a counselor,
I got nobody!
These parents, they come in
and went to put their foot up my ass,
always got some complaint...
this one doesn't get on the football team,
this teacher's giving him
sex positions or something like that...
- You're not even listening to me!
- I cannot remember the last time
one of 'em just said, "Thank you."
And I'm not listening to you?
Hello?
I'm sorry I called, I didn't know
what else to do. She's in the back.
- What did she drink?
- Nothing! I don't know!
- Open up!
- I already tried that.
- Who's she in there with?
- I don't know, I wasn't watching her.
Some guys, I think. I saw the door open
and it was like ten men!
- Hey, Cicily?
- I don't know what to do!
Find somebody who knows
how to open this door.
Please? Find somebody now!
Open up!
Open this fucking door right now!
What could you possibly want
so right-fucking-now?!
You fucking bitch! Stop kicking!
Get him off her! You asshole!
Get off!
Oh, my God! Cicily!
Come here. It's okay.
Stop it.
Cicily? Here.
Wake up, okay?
I just need you to wake up
for one minute, okay?
I just want to make sure
you're not hurt.
Hey, Cicily! I just want to make sure
I don't have to take you to the hospital.
Stop it. Hey, hey, hey... stop it.
Wait one second.
Let me see if you're okay.
Where are you bleeding at?
Are you hurt?
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Are you okay?
Are you okay?
All right.
It's okay.
Hey.
Hi, honey.
No, I don't want to worry you.
I was just askin'.
Well, you know,
she comes in here all hang-dog,
her head hangin' down.
Yeah. She doesn't call me Papa
anymore.
I'm Grandpa now,
it's my new official title.
I did okay with you, didn't I?
Yeah.
I know. I was wondering if maybe
she thinks she has to work here
'cause you did and Ronnie did,
and...
Yeah.
I know, I'm doin' it right now.
Well, okay. Let me know if she
calls you Mother instead of Mom, okay?
Hi.
You... you okay?
Yeah.
I'm really sorry.
Well, what about our money?
Miss Huttensen, it's almost
halfway through the session.
We discussed that
if anything were to happen
- But what has happened?
- we would terminate the semester.
We can't have the media
at the gates of our school.
- You said you saw a camera.
- Miss Huttensen...
- No, a camera is not the news media.
- Okay, hold on.
No. No, no, no, I won't.
Because I only want my son
to get an education,
that's what I paid for,
that's what I brought him here for.
I'm just trying to help you.
I have lost my job.
I have lost two jobs.
We are broke.
So if you want to kick
my only son out of school
and keep the money,
you know, that's just...
that's great.
Mom?
Hey, what are you doing home?
- No. No.
- David...
So where am I supposed to go?
No.
No, you're crazy. Shit!
Believe me,
I don't want you to go there either.
No way I'm going to Ridgeline!
Wh-why do you think that...
why do you think that I want...
You have to go to school, it's the law.
That's the district...
What do you expect to happen?!
I don't want to go, Mom,
I really don't want to go...
Davey, I don't want you to go.
It's because of that interview, though.
Why would you do that interview?
How do you expect me to
make enough money
- for you to go St. Anthony's?
- Get a better friggin' job!
- Get a better job. Great.
- If you gave a crap about me,
you would make sure,
and you would do anything
to make sure that I didn't go to
that school... that's what you would do.
- For two years, double shifts, okay?
- Why can't we move?
- Move?
- Why can't we get out of here?!
Let's go right now.
Why can't we get out of here?
There's not enough hours in a day
for me to make enough money
- for us to just move!
- So what am I supposed to do?!
Fuck!
- Good morning, guys.
- Hey. How ya doin'?
I'm all right.
- Are Schmidt and Pallus in yet?
- I don't think so. Not yet, no.
- Huh. They're usually in by now.
- Yeah, they usually are.
Listen, Frank, I saw...
I saw that thing on TV.
I am so sorry, man. I tried calling you.
It's all right.
Don't worry about it, Donnie.
We're cool.
I just want you to know
you still got a job here.
Well, yeah.
Shit, I should hope so.
I mean, I, uh,
I don't want you to worry about your job.
Just 'cause some TV station
puts on a show that says that...
That thing, that scenario,
that's not the way it was. You know that.
Yeah.
That in no way resembles
what actually went down.
The city wants you to do a show.
The what?
Uh, Mayor Dougherty
and some of the council members,
they got a call from
one of those TV news shows.
So they want me to go on TV and..?
It's not somethin' you gotta do.
I figure since you, uh,
called the TV station yourself...
Oh, man.
- Look...
- They called the city the next morning.
That's how this whole thing
got started.
Fuck.
I just couldn't believe that they,
you know...
I want you to talk to the psychologist.
Wait a minute, boss,
hold on a second.
Look, there's a tremendous
amount of pressure in this job,
- and especially what you been through...
- Wait a minute.
It's been three years since the shooting.
Two years pass
and Curry stuck that shotgun in his...
- I am not Curry.
- I know you're not Curry,
- but Curry didn't have TV news shows...
- I am not Curry.
Frank.
So what you're saying is,
you don't ever think about the children
at the school?
- No.
- Not at all?
Uh... um...
There's a lot to worry about.
I have a job to do.
Mm-hm.
I just... you know, I try not to
let things set.
There's nothing I can do
about a past crime.
I know, and that's...
that's very healthy, Frank.
But what I'm talking about are
your basic normal human emotions...
regret, remorse.
I mean, I just want to be clear here
that you don't ever find yourself
in the situation that...
What? Why are you...
What's so funny?
Nothing, it's just, um...
I don't know, it's just I just feel like...
like that woman on the TV show,
you know, the mother.
Like you're interviewing me
or something. I just feel stupid.
Oh, you saw the news show
about you and the shootings.
No, I mean, I saw a little...
'Cause they named you.
And they showed pictures.
- And maps.
- Yeah. I know.
And how you weren't able to save...
those kids.
Mm-hm. I heard.
And that doesn't bother you?
Why would I be bothered by something
that's a complete fabrication of reality?
Hey, Tasha.
You're gonna go to
all your classes today, right?
- Mm-hm.
- Okay.
Hey.
You stay right there.
Let's go.
- Let's go.
- Wait...
Out of the way.
Out of the way!
What are you thinking?
You weren't thinking at all, were you?!
Let's go.
Why you gonna
bring a gun into my school?
- It's not mine.
- It's not?
Nope.
What do you think you're playing?
You think this is a game?
You're expelled, Jelani.
- You can't expel me for this.
- You're expelled.
You're out of my school.
I don't want to see you.
You act like I was bringing a gun
into school, trying to shoot people.
Shootings happen in the parking lot
just the same as they happen in here.
- There's no bullets in there!
- You're expelled.
You can call your parents
on the phone in the main office.
You can't expel me for...
I'm one of the best students you got.
No. You're not.
You tell 'em to pick you up
by the front gate.
- I don't want you by the steps.
- My parents don't pick me up, man.
- I walk to school by myself.
- Then you can walk home by yourself.
Every day I come here early
for a class I don't even have to take.
You know where I have to
walk in the morning and at night?
You know what? We're done.
You know how many kids been shot
walking to this school? Your school?
From home I walk down 75th,
cross over to Halstead,
hop a fence on 70th to...
So yeah, I carry a gun.
- You're expelled, Jelani.
- Come on, man.
What's wrong with you?
You're not even listening to me, are you?
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Okay, J.
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
What kind of a question is that, man?
It's a good question, I think.
I want to be principal of a high school.
Well...
you know, that's a tough job.
You don't want to have a wife
and a kid with a job like that.
You don't have any time,
none at all,
'cause most of the time
you're spending your time
talking to knuckleheads
and hoodlums.
You have no time
to talk to your wife and kid.
I came here from Ohio.
What's in Ohio, man?
Schools without kids carrying guns.
Yeah, right.
Oh, so you're here to save
our streets, right? Be some kinda hero?
My wife, she had a great job,
and my son, he was just born.
I had opportunity to make a difference.
Less pay, longer hours.
But there was a couple of thousand
dum-dums that needed some help,
so I thought I'd give it a try.
Well, test scores are up.
- You read the paper?
- I read that part.
- And you brought this gun to my school.
- Yeah, but I leave it outside.
- If you're doing a bad job, I'd...
- You'd bring it inside?
- Exactly. But I don't...
- Because of the metal detectors?
That's right.
Smart move gettin' those installed.
I didn't do that.
Guy before me did that.
Right before he left.
Can't take credit for that.
So why you still here?
Last year thirty-one kids went to college.
Yeah before that it was twenty-six.
Four years ago Shannon Cordero
couldn't read or write,
now she's tutoring in
freshman literature.
Latron Barnes couldn't even
write his name...
How many guns
you got in your drawer?
I got two more guns
than I had last month in my drawer.
And one of those guns is from a kid who,
judging from his grades...
and a long conversation,
could do a heck of a lot more
with his life
than most of the fools around him.
Can I have it back?
It's for my job.
It's for your job. What do you do?
What do you do, J? Are you a cop?
I work at a place
where I need it to protect...
If you have to have a gun
to work where you work
or to be where you are...
then maybe you need to try your best
not to be there.
What are you doing?
What?
- Don't touch his bed.
- Why? He's not gonna use it.
I have it like this for a reason.
David, what are you doing?
- What are you doing?!
- I'm pushing the beds together.
- Are you going to sleep in his bed?
- I'm pushing 'em together!
You're going to sleep
in your brother's bed?!
This is my room!
David! No! No!
You can't just come in here
and start moving it around!
Get off me!
Get off of me now!
- Get off me, Mom!
- Stop it!
You know something?
You have a lot of nerve!
- I have?
- Yes!
I'm in here trying to move
my stuff around! My stuff!
- Spoiled! That's what you are!
- Fuck you!
Oh. "Fuck." "Fuck." That's great.
That's just great.
Shut up!!!
Okay, fine.
Why do you smoke?! David? Huh?
- Why do you go through my things?
- Why do you smoke?
Why do you fuck Barry
in Dad's bed?!
- I am just trying to do my best.
- Would you move, please?
Can you move?!
You don't even...
you don't even care.
You don't...
Hey.
What's up?
Your parents home?
My mom's taking a bath
or washing her hair.
- Washing her fat rolls?
- Fuck you, man.
- Dude, you still smoking lights?
- Yeah. Why?
- You're a bitch, dude.
- What?
You think you can just
put your cigarettes all over my house
like my mom's not gonna
fucking care?
- How'd she find 'em?
- She finds everything, you dick.
- Fuck. I'm sorry.
- Yeah, thanks. That helps a lot.
Ike.
- Hey.
What's up, hunk?
Uh, Tally, Mouse,
you know my friend David?
- Hey, "my friend David."
- Hey, yeah, we met before.
- You want anything to drink?
- Yes.
- That's cool.
- Thank you.
Follow me.
All right.
No...
I don't know.
Well, I came into the room,
and he was moving...
...Robbie's bed.
Have you guys known each other
for a long time or whatever?
Yeah, actually, I've known her
since grade school.
- Oh, wow.
- Yeah.
You go to St. Anthony's?
Used to.
Hey, was your brother
the one who... um...
Yeah.
I love David. I care...
more than anything.
Hold on.
Ohh.
- What happened to your stomach?
- Oh, uh...
It was this thing I was doin'
on my bike.
There's a park over there,
and there's these steps
I always ride down,
and I kinda ate it. Hard.
Got me this new alarm clock.
Oh, my God, it's so annoying,
it's like... bramp! bramp!
So, um... we should
hang out sometime.
I mean, if... I don't know
if you want to, but if you do...
- Yeah.
Yeah, I... yeah, that'd be cool.
Can I have your number
or something?
- Yeah. Uh, I don't have a pen.
- I have a pen.
I'm thinking I want to transfer
and to go Ridgeline with you.
Ohh, dude.
The girls are so much hotter.
I mean, you said it yourself.
Tally, Mouse.
Yeah, but there's hot girls
in St. Anthony's.
- Not at all.
- Yeah, there is.
Okay,
let's roll on my cue.
And... roll tape.
Ed, whenever you're ready.
I know it's been three years
since the tragedy,
but could you still give us a timeline of
what happened after you arrived?
Yeah, sure. Um...
I got the call at 11:38 in the morning,
and, um, I was alone in my squad car,
I was near Ridgeline.
Shots had been heard,
so I went over there and, um...
as you said,
by the time I got there
the first two kids had already been shot
by Donald and Robert when I arrived.
I notice you make an effort
to call them by their names.
They've been called the "shooters,"
the "killers"...
The killers, yeah.
I just always remembered
that they're kids.
Do you still think about it?
You have a...
you have a good day today?
It was a bad day?
- Learn anything new today?
- Same stuff.
What, you didn't learn anything new
all day?
I guess.
You got something
you want to share with me?
You can talk to me.
You know you can talk to me, right?
Hmm...
Let me hold this bag
for a second.
'Cause, uh...
hold that for a second...
'cause I need to put some color
in my wardrobe.
How's it look?
- It's okay?
- It's a little bit better.
All right? Come on, let's go.
Let's go. You ready?
Gotta do your homework, buddy.
Hey. You guys are home early.
We were just watching cartoons.
Oh.
You talk to him at all?
Yeah, I tried to talk to him.
He didn't have much to say, though.
- No?
- I tried to talk to him about school,
- I tried to talk to him about Jeremy...
- Jimmy.
Yeah, that's what I said. I said Jimmy
when I was talking to him about it.
He knew who I was talking about.
You can't get him to open up to you
by breaking my rules.
What rules did I break?
We were just having some dinner.
- The cartoons, Carter.
- Cartoons?
Yeah. No cartoons during the week.
You know that.
Come on, babe. I mean, my son...
my kid, he likes cartoons,
I love cartoons...
I mean, it's my fault,
'cause I wanted to watch that show,
that really good show,
the Dragonball show.
- Dragonball Z.
- The guy with the funny hair and...
Yeah.
That's my favorite.
You know...
I'm sorry, babe. I'm sorry.
Hey, you're gonna
have to cut the TV off.
That fool took away your gun?
Damn!
- I'm a'ight.
- You're a'ight?
So what, you think
you're Superman now?
All them bullets just gonna be
bouncin' off your chest?
I don't know, man, I'm...
I'm cool.
- I'll just get you another piece, man.
- Nah.
I don't want one.
So you're just gonna
walk around here naked.
I'm good. I'm light on my feet.
Look, I'm gonna find me a girl...
I'm gonna sing some Johnny Cash to her,
some J. Cash.
You know, Johnny Cash
carried a gun.
Yeah, a'ight.
There you are. Clean as a whistle.
You know,
it's a question of safety.
Mm-hm.
- Look here, see...
this is the stock,
and... it's a little shorter
and just a little thinner.
Yeah, I don't know if I like how...
Maryanne, would you
come here for a second?
It's my granddaughter.
Can you put your hand there, please?
Okay, just relax it.
There.
Okay. See?
Mm-hm. I see our hands
are about the same size,
I just, uh, I don't know if I like how...
This is made to fit snug.
This one, the one you've been using,
because it's thicker,
if you were to try and pull it up quickly,
you could lose you grip
and it could slip away.
You could find yourself
in some trouble.
I've gotten used to it, though.
I think I like the weight.
Well, it's heavy, that's for sure.
- You don't find it too heavy?
- Not so much. It's all right.
All right, there you are.
Honey, can you take this back
to the cash register
and ring up that other stuff?
Thanks an awful lot.
I'm gonna keep this aside for you
because, trust me,
it's the best thing for you.
That's his brother.
Can I help you?
Um... yeah.
I actually called earlier.
I just thought maybe I could
learn a little bit about shooting or...
Okay. Have you ever
handled a firearm before?
Yeah. But I haven't shot a gun
since I was a really little kid.
Well, we can start from
the beginning and... and go from there.
This is a 9-millimeter
semi-automatic handgun.
When it's in your hand,
you are smart, you're careful,
and you're always responsible.
All right. So, now with your feet,
you want to spread your feet
apart a little bit,
get one foot in front of the other
like I am.
Your knees are able to bend
so that you're relaxed
- but you're strong.
- Okay.
Does that feel comfortable?
It's the Weaver stance.
It's probably the most
comfortable for you.
Again.
- Uh, I don't...
- Do it again!
Good.
So why you got
all the nerdy classes?
I just got transferred over like that.
I'm gotta get 'em switched.
- I got this weird lunch period now.
- It's 'cause you have pre-calc.
Pre-calc?
I've been in algebra forever.
Yeah, it was just
'cause in my old school,
- I mean...
- You want a ride home?
You know, my... my mom's picking me up.
You want me to wait with you?
Yeah.
- And the other room's upstairs?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, you're looking at...
well, twelve hundred.
Is there any way you could
knock that down just a little bit?
'Cause it's...
Well...
Where's... where's the school?
The school's down a ways...
a few miles.
Go out and head east.
Thanks. That's great.
Your boy play football?
Westland's got one of
the best teams in the state.
Good academics, too.
So, was it weird today?
What, like... going here?
It's whatever.
The classes seem like
they'll be easier.
Yeah.
You ever think about your brother?
No. Not really.
He was a fuckin' idiot anyway.
Can you give me a tattoo?
Down here.
Yeah.
So...
...how many guys have you
kissed in your lifetime? Ever.
Ever?
Um...
Three.
But only one, like, real one.
You're such a liar. You...
you've only kissed one guy?
Yeah. One guy.
How many girls have you kissed?
I like it.
Are you all right?
Thanks for staying with me.
Uh-oh, I think that's my mom.
Uh...
Do you want to come meet her?
- Are they still warm?
- Yeah.
'Cause they were hot
when I bought 'em.
Thanks.
So, I went looking
for some places.
What, like apartments or something?
- What the hell is this?
- Mom, what's goin' on?
What the?
Hey, David,
I want you to go inside.
- Why?
- Honey, just go inside.
Hey. Hey!
I can't believe this.
- Mom.
- David, just go inside the house!
Go on!
Excuse me.
What the hell is this?
Why the hell would you
put this on my lawn?
Huh?
What is your problem with me?
You! I live here!
This is my house!
Where do you get off...
Why would you leave this for me?!
You deserve whatever you get,
Janet.
- Oh, I can't believe...
- Don't complain to them.
How can you...
This is so unreal.
- Go inside the house.
- How dare you talk to me like that?!
- Calm down and go inside.
- Oh, Bob? You have nothing to say to me.
Your kid stands out here
and sells weed like it's lemonade.
- Not my kid.
- Oh, yes. Yes. Yes.
- Don't act like you don't know.
- Your son's a murderer.
- Oh, my son...
- Yeah. What do you have to say to that?
- You know what?
- Your son's a murderer.
People just stand out here
talking about...
If you have a problem with
people putting flags in your yard,
I mean, do you realize
what these flags represent?
I don't have a problem
with flags in my yard...
These flags represent the children,
the children that were murdered
by your son!
So why do you have
a red flag in your yard?
- Because I care, Janet.
- Oh, you care?
I have a problem with
coming home in my car
- with my other son David...
- You are such a slut!
I'm a slut? Oh, excuse me.
And who are you?
I hope you're not the woman
whose husband has come over
like four times and offered
to mow my lawn!
Because it looks like crap.
We feel sorry for you!
- Don't feel sorry for me.
- Why don't you move?!
Because I live here!
You're the reason
those kids were killed!
- I'm not the reason!
- Yes, you are!
I didn't kill your kids, okay?
But I baby-sat them!
How the hell could you not see it?!
Your own kid!
Look, my son is dead!
Hey, you! Stop!
I'm fine. It's okay, I'm fine.
Yeah, I'm fine.
- Why don't you just go inside?
- I'm going inside.
- Mom! Please, come on.
- Why don't you make them go inside?!
Go! What did I say?!
Hey, Don.
Everyone's back in their houses now
except the guy down there
watering his lawn.
Yeah, he's all right.
Jimmy just rolled up
with another car.
Why don't the two of you
get on out of here, okay?
The chief wants me to stick around
and make sure that...
No, I got this covered.
You go home to your family,
all right?
- You sure?
- Yeah. Go on.
- All right. Thanks, Frank.
- Okay. I'll see ya, Don.
'Night, Jimmy.
You want coffee
or tea or something?
No, ma'am, I'm fine, thank you.
I didn't even know you guys
were still here.
If you guys are here to...
There's nothing wrong
with my other son David.
No, ma'am, I know.
I was just...
There's nothing in this house
that you... would interest you anymore.
- Okay?
- I know.
I'm his mother. I would know.
Yes, ma'am.
Uh... thank you.
I, um...
I understand.
I mean, you'd think I don't understand,
but I get it, David gets it.
It makes sense,
with the flags and the banners and...
people are...
I feel bad.
Maybe you could let... someone know
I said that.
Yo, what's up, man. Lemme get
that Old Highlander right there.
How much is it?
- It's twenty-one.
- Twenty-one?
How about that little rum
right there? How much is that?
Um... seventeen.
Seventeen?!
How 'bout the Wild Turkey?
- That's fifteen.
- Fifteen?! Man, fuck that!
Hey!
Hey!!!
Gimme the Wild Turkey!
Look, I'm... I'm'a chill, right?
I'm'a put this away.
Gimme the motherfuckin' Wild Turkey.
Gimme the Wild Turkey!!!
Nigga, I see you!
Gimme the Wild Turkey!
Hey, man, get your ass up, man!
Get your ass up!
Your ass got to come out.
Ima be here waitin'.
Are you concerned at all?
I'm concerned about
all kinds of things, Sara.
About our family? Our home?
I mean, we're not happy
as a family.
I'm not happy, Hakeem's not happy.
And I know...
Sara, I have to go.
- There's some stuff going on outside.
- Cater, you always have to go.
When you were a teacher,
before we moved,
- you talked to the kids, you...
- Sara, come on.
This is my job. It's my job.
Don't make this like it's not
important to me,
- 'cause you know it's important to me.
- I love you.
- And I know you.
Can't you just hear what I'm saying?
Can't you?
This is what I do.
Hey, hey!
You want to hurt him that bad?
Huh?!
- Carter.
- Do you even go to this school?
Do you go to this school?
Hey, Carter.
We're backed up out there.
I got Lisa Ann from yesterday,
- Kwami's back.
- You know...
this stain has been on my ceiling...
for such a long time.
Well, you can just
switch out the panels and...
I have switched 'em.
I switched 'em nine times.
It comes back.
So I switch it again, 'cause that's what
the guy before me told me I should do.
That's probably what I'm gonna
tell the next guy, too.
I don't know why...
if it's just laziness or...
or stupidity or...
I just keep, like,
hitting my head against the...
I just keep changing the...
the panels.
Carter, what did you mean
by "the next guy"?
How many kids you say
we got out there?
Five.
Can you just give me
a couple of seconds,
- then send somebody in?
- Yeah. Yeah, I can do that.
Hello?
Hi. Um... this is David.
I was just calling
'cause I was wondering if
maybe you wanted to hang out tonight.
- Yeah, um, I...
- Yeah?
I would love to.
Do you want to come over?
Or I could go to your house
or something?
Yeah, you could come over here.
That sounds fine.
Yeah, that would be totally fine.
I'll go grab my bike.
Okay.
My address is on Hawthorne.
It's at the end of the block,
last street on the right. It's 236.
All right, I guess I'll be there
in like ten minutes.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- I'm gonna run by the store first.
- Then I'll see you soon.
All right. Bye.
Bye.
Get your notebook too, babe.
Mr. Carter?
Yeah?
We, um... well, I...
I just wanted to say, um...
Thank you for talking to my son.
You, um...
you truly, I believe,
saved his life.
My other son went to this school
before you got here, and, um...
...well, it was different.
Thanks.
Thank you for that.
Do you have to work tonight?
Oh, my God.
What?
- Did you get stitches?
- No.
No, it's...
- You didn't go to the hospital?
- No.
- Is Louise coming over?
- Umm.
Barry?
Barry doesn't come over anymore.
You hungry?
Hmm?
No.
- You should stay home tomorrow.
- What?
You should stay home.
Sit down.
You tired?
Yeah.
Hmm.
Me, too.
- You gettin' out of here?
- Yeah.
- How ya doin'?
- Good.
Finding your way around here okay?
You mean, like...
here in the store, or...
No, here in Charlottesville,
and in the shop too, it's just...
you know, you seem so down
every time you come in here.
You don't smile,
you... hardly talk,
you never even really say good-bye.
I say bye.
Yeah, okay, I was just askin'.
And I smile, too.
Yeah.
You know, it's just...
it's like... it's kinda like
you used to talk more
when you came to visit.
I mean, you were younger, but...
It's just, things are...
different around here.
I mean, some of it's college different,
and some of it's just... Southern or...
East Coast or whatever.
Virginia different.
I don't know, Papa.
It's just that some shit happened, and...
and I just feel like...
...edgy or whatever lately,
and I don't... I know that
doesn't explain how I've been
for the past two months, but...
You know, this place was always
kinda weird for me to walk into.
But I guess around here it's...
...it's just how everybody is.
I don't know.
Boy...
I miss your grandmother
so much sometimes.
I sure wish she was alive right now.
Yeah... me, too.
I mean, maybe you'd talk to her
when you used to come visit,
maybe not to me at all.
It was nice you callin' me Papa,
anyway.
Did your mother tell you
to call me Papa?
- Yeah.
- Oh, shit.
Yeah, but...
Aw, shit.
Hi.
Do you have strawberry soda?
Oh, I see it. Thanks.
- Hi.
- Uh, pack of lights.
That's four seventy-nine.
Hey.
Just take it easy, man.
No, no. No.
Get down!
On your stomach!
Stop moving!
- Stop moving!
- Just let me get my arm out, man.
- Ow! Ow!
- Hey! Shut up.
Mom, I'm home.
Time to go to bed, man, okay?
Oh, hey.
Hey.
What's going on?
What'd you buy?
I got a backpack.
Thank you, Carter.
I quit today.
You what?
I'm done, at the end of the semester.
They're, um, looking...
they're looking...
They're gonna find a replacement.
Oh, baby.
Need some help?
911, please state your emergency.
These guys,
they're shooting people!
Where are you calling from?
Ridgeline...
Ridgeline High!
Stay calm.
What's your name?
My name is Rebecca.
Okay, Rebecca,
are you injured?
No, but there are a lot
of people who aren't moving.
Are you in any danger?
Can you see the shooter?
Not right now,
but they're in the building.
Okay, Rebecca,
stay on the line with me, okay?
Rebecca?
Are you okay? Are you injured?
Rebecca, help is on the way.
Just stay on the line.
Officers will be there soon.
Okay, stay calm.
Stay calm, Rebecca.
Do you see any exits
nearby?
No!
Okay, just stay where you are.
Get down low.
The officers will be there soon.
Stay calm.
Stay calm, Rebecca, okay?
Help is on the way, darling, okay?
Officers are on the way right now.
Do you know how many shooters
there are, Rebecca?
There are two guys with guns.
And what room are you in, Rebecca?
On the second floor
in the science lab.
All right, stay calm, dear.
Oh, God, oh, God.
I think they've killed our teacher.
Rebecca, hold on sweetie, okay?
Help is coming, darling.
Just stay on the line with me,
all right, Rebecca?
Just breathe, sweetie.
Just breathe.
Rebecca,
are you hurt?
Are you injured?
Is anyone injured near you?
Okay, stay calm, stay calm.
Just be calm, Rebecca.
Just stay on the line.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Rebecca? Rebecca?
Rebecca?
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com