Arthur?
where's he gone to this time?
And the dog's disappeared too!
Alfred!?!
Oh yes, you'll see, he be a great guard dog!
Alfred!
I wonder what exactly it is he'll be guarding!
If you could at least answer when I call!
Arthur...?
Arthur?!
Help! An attack!
Men, come to my aid!
Calm down!
It's me! Granny!
Sorry! I was in Africa!
I can tell! Did you have a good trip?
Fantastic...! I was in a tribe with Granpa!
Look!
Grandpa painted a canvas
that he placed in a circle
that way the animals pace round and round it
but can't find us. It's like we're invisible.
Invisible, but not unsmelable!
Did you have your bath this morning?
I was on my way when I found this book!
Hmm hmm!
It's incredible!
It's all the inventions Grandpa made
for the isolated tribes.
Yes. He was more interested in African tribes
than he was his own!
Look! He dug a super deep well
and invented a whole irrigation system
out of bamboo poles.
You know it wasn't Grandpa who invented
that, it was the Romans.
They called them viaducts.
The Romans? I never heard of that tribe!
Oh, it's a very old tribe
the leader was called Caesar.
Like the salad?
Yes, like the salad.
Put that book back where you got it
we have to go shopping!
Granny, please
can I drive on the way back?
I don't know, Arthur, we'll see.
Oh, please, Grandpa would always
Grandpa's not here, and I'm in charge
Goody day, Mrs. Suchot!
Oh, officer, hello!
Always a pleasure to see you in town.
Thank you, Officer
always a pleasure to see you too.
Good day, Officer!
Good day.
Arthur, um, here, here's the shopping list,
and I'm, I'm just gonna run across
the street for five minutes
so I'll meet you at the checkout counter.
Can I buy some straws?
Yeah, as many as you like.
Did he follow you?
I don't think so
Perfect! Perfect!
There! It's all there.
Perfect, this is wonderful thank you so much
What do I owe you?
Are you crazy, nothing! Nothing at all!
Now, get going before he catches you.
I'm speechless, I don't know how thank you!
By letting me participate!
Nothing could make me happier!
Now, get going!
Thanks so much.
I'm counting on you to let me
know how it went?!
I will, I'll call you tomorrow!
Talk to you tomorrow
Bye then.
Bye.
Oh Arthur! Arthur, no no no it's fine.
You go off and play.
Go off while it's still light...!
Sure?
Absolutely.
Thanks Granny!
Sure.
Yes! Yes! World champion!
Alfred!
Watch carefully, Alfred!
You are about to witness the invention
of the largest irrigation system
in the county.
Bigger than Grandpa's
better than Cesar's.
This is Arthur's invention!
Perfect!
By the grace of God!
Alfred, congratulations!
It's a remarkable invention
that'll go down in history!
Believe me!
Arthur! Telephone!
You'll have to excuse me!
Probably the uh
president calling to congratulate me.
Hey! I built an irrigation system like Cesar's!
Now the radishes will grow twice as fast!
Huh? Is this my honey pie?
Who is this Seesher?
One of Grandpa's colleagues...
but I followed Grandpa's blueprints
and it works really well!
I hope you can get here before nighttime
so you can see it...
where are you now?
Um... well, we're still in the city, Arthur.
Huh?! Oh. Well...
I guess you'll see it tomorrow morning then?
Um, No
we're not going to able to make it Arthur
but even though we can't be there,
we wanted to
tell you that we're thinking of you
Because... today is... your birthday!
Happy Birthday son!
Thought we'd forgot, didn't you!
But ten years old is a big deal!
You're a big boy now, aren't you?
(ON) So how did you like the present?
We haven't gotten it yet, you idiot!
What?
No, I fixed it with Granny.
Yes, you can go into town tomorrow
and pick out whatever you like.
Not too expensive!
Just joking, son!
But we'll see you real soon
and uh remember you have yourself a
Happy birthday!
It wasn't the president.
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday dear Arthur!
You know what?
You're the best Granny in the world!
And you're the best grandson!
Go on, blow them out!
Presents first?
Oh, right. This is from Alfred.
I never had a new one before!
Thank you Alfred!
No, ah! If you could wait till
you're outside to throw it
I'd consider that a favor
Oh, yeah, you're right.
And this is from me.
It's beautiful!
How did you manage to bake a cake?
I thought the oven was broken.
Mrs. Kerman from the hardware store
actually made it!
Still like it?
It's fantastic. Just too big for three.
Don't be too hard on them
Arthur! They try their best
I spend my whole year
in boarding school in England,
and when I come back for vacation
they're not even here!
Anyway I'm used to it now
they're never here for my birthday.
Wait! Make a wish.
I wish that, for my next birthday
Grandpa will be here to share it.
Better blow them out quick
you don't wanna eat a wax cake!
Every night this
magnificent sunset was all ours.
It's precisely into this landscape
that your mother came into the world.
While I was having the baby
your grandfather was painting this.
Who are they?
The BOGO-MATASSALAI.
Your grandfather helped build
an irrigation ditch for them
and in return they gave him
a big bag of rubies.
Really?
Really. Oh, I could tell you stories all night long
Great! Tell me.
No, not tonight, Arthur, maybe tomorrow.
Come on!
No, I haven't even cleaned the kitchen.
Please, Granny. Just a little! It's my birthday!
Alright, just one minute.
OK.
The Bogo-Matassalai were very, very tall.
They say that nature always balances itself
with its opposite
and for centuries they searched for them,
in order to find perfect harmony.
And did they find them?
Yes.
It was another tribe living right next to them
and they had this particular trait:
they were small as a tooth...
They called them the Minimoys!
Wow! Did they get along?
Oh, wonderfully! Soon they were inseparable!
The one side very incredibly tall,
the other incredibly small.
And only together could
they have a complete vision of the world.
Who's this?
This is the Princess Selenia.
Daughter of the king of the Minimoys.
She's beautiful! I mean, this is incredible!
Yes and the king himself
gave your grandfather
the secret of
how to find him anytime he wanted!
That's what your grandfather said;
every time he was a little drunk.
I'd like to meet the Minimoys too.
Now, to sleep!
Sweet dreams.
We miss you Archibald. We really do.
No!
How you doing, kid?
Nice shot.
Oh! Mr. Davido! You startled me!
I'm so sorry!'
Spring cleaning? Need a hand?
No, thank you. What do you want this time?
Here it is! Done! Signed
sealed and delivered.
You didn't waste any time!
That was a coincidence really.
I was in church, this morning
You were in church?
I've never seen you there.
Oh, I usually sit in the back. Modesty really.
You really should have been there.
You would have seen the Mayor,
who confirmed the document
which pronounces the expiration
of your ownership
of this property for lack of payment.
The president of the bank,
who transferred your debt to me.
And as amazing as it may seem,
you know who else was there?
The Notary and the Chief of Police
who countersigned the order of eviction.
So you see
there is not a single signature missing,
and if your husband does not sign this paper
within the next 48 hours,
I will be under the obligation to evict you
from this property
whether your laundry is dry or not!
Ah! You should to hang him up to dry as well!
Are we gonna have to leave the house?
I'm afraid so
I won't be able to hold off
that vulture Davido much longer
but what about the treasure?
The rubies that the Matassalais gave Grandpa?
Your grandpa hid them somewhere out
there in the yard.
I dug for weeks!
And I... he hid them so well I haven't been
able to find them.
Where are you going?
You think I'm gonna hang around
twiddling my thumbs for forty eight hours?
I'm gonna find the treasure!
Just like his Grandpa!
You should go and find my car rather
than sitting there watching me.
Can I help you?
Oh! Pardon me!
You came by our house once and left this.
You said if we ever wanted to get rid
of any furniture or knick knacks
Yes?
Well, I, I brought this...
it's from my private collection
I wondered if it was at all valuable.
Ah! What is this? A carnival mask?
No, this is an African mask.
This is... this belonged to the chief
of the Bogo-Matassalai tribe.
Two bucks.
Two dollars?
But this is... of inestimable value
Alright alright, two fifty.
That's the best I can do!
This kind of exotic object
just isn't selling any more.
People want practical
concrete, modern stuff, you know.
I can't believe you'd have hidden the treasure
in the yard
without leaving some sort of clue,
a note, something to help us find it!
Malthazar... the Evil... M
I hope
I have the honor of meeting you one day,
Princess! In the meantime
Permit me to steal a kiss.
Jealous!
I knew it!
to get to the land of the Minimoys
put your trust in Shakespeare.
The house is here... south is that way.
The tree! The elf! The moon!
It's all there!
Alfred! We found it! Yes!
Ah!
Hang on there, young man!
Arthur, how many times do
I have to tell you?
I don't want you playing in this room.
Excuse me, please, go ahead!
Thank you
Granny?!
What?
Who are these guys?
This gentleman is going to evaluate some of
your grandpa's things.
Granny?!
What?
You're not gonna sell grandpa's things?!
I'm afraid I don't have any choice anymore!
Yes we do! Look!
It's the map to get to the Minimoys!
What map?
They're here!
Grandpa brought them back
from Africa with him!
If we can get to them,
I'm sure they can lead us to the treasure!
Arthur you're a big boy now, right?
You don't really believe
there are little elves running around the garden
just waiting for you to visit
so they can slap a bag of rubies in your hand!
Pardon me?
No, nothing...
I... I was chatting with my grandson.
If you have jewels, we are interested
Unfortunately, not a jewel on the horizon.
Go to your room, now
William. 'S' for Socrates?
Shakespeare. William Shakespeare.
Ah! Not too far off!
Yes. Better hurry and make your choice
before I change my mind.
Come on let's go.
Granny
Let's go
Three hundred dollars.
It's not very much for thirty years of memories!
A down payment! If sell them well
you'll have more
thank you.
Mrs. Suchot?
Yes.
Frederic De Saint-Clair.
Process server, Bailiff.
It seems I came at an opportune time.
I have a claim for
debt collection which concerns you,
for non-payment of services rendered
by a certain Mr. Davido,
Ernest, for the amount of
two hundred fifty two dollars,
now with the
six percent late penalty surcharge,
and procedural fees added,
that comes to a total of
two hundred ninety five dollars
and five cents.
May I?
Here's your change.
Hello?
Sweetie it's mom, is everything alright?
Great!
We're cleaning up today!
It's amazing how much old stuff
just piles up around the place...
but, thanks to Granny, we threw it all out!
Arthur! Don't upset your parents!
Did you hang up on your mother?
Of course not! It hung up by itself!
Well, she'll call back in a second!
Granny! They've cut the phone line!
Don't you see what's happening?
We've fallen into their trap,
and it's closing in on us a little bit
more every minute!
But as long as I live and breathe,
they're not gonna get this house!
There you see? That's probably the repairman.
Good evening ma'am!
You came at just the right time!
Our phone's just been cut off
and I really think you should warn people!
I agree, ma'am,
but I'm not from the phone company,
I'm from the electric company.
And I came to tell you
that you're gonna be cut off soon
for nonpayment.
Some words may hide others
Grandpa help me
When am I gonna get cut off?
That's what I call a clear answer...
Don't move, I'll get a candle.
Some words may hide others...! Of course!
My dear Arthur. I was sure
I could count on you to find my riddle.
You must be at least ten to have
become so clever.
I, on the other hand, have not been so clever,
and if you are reading this
I am probably dead.
Therefore, the heavy task of accomplishing
my mission now falls to you.
If you accept it, that is.
I accept, Grandpa.
I knew you would. Bravo.
To get to the land of the Minimoys,
you must know on which day
the next passage will fall.
There's only one per year.
Take the universal calendar from my desk.
The night of the tenth moon,
at precisely midnight
the moonlight-passage will open
If you follow my instructions,
on the twentieth knock, you
will have the world in your hands
That's today!
Night brings good counsel
Arthur. We'll sleep on it
Tomorrow will bring a solution.
Good night, Granny.
Goodnight.
The world in my hands... world in my hands.
On the right side of the chimney,
there's a button
Turn it all the way to the right,
and then turn it back to the left.
Only twenty minutes before midnight.
I've got to do something.
Damn!
Ah! I thought you were in the shower!
No, I was in the living room looking
for my sleeping drops...
And if you don't get back into bed this second
I'm gonna make you drink the whole bottle!
Go!
Go on! Go on!
You know, I don't like to do this.
But I'm gonna lock you in.
I don't want you to do anything stupid tonight.
OK.
OK
Alfred, what're you doing?
Go to sleep.
Is it the full moon or what?
Thank you, Alfred
Aaaah!
Granny!?
Always keeps this key with you
The garden, the tree, the telescope
Oh my god!
I need more light!
I've seen Granny do this a hundred times.
Oh, yeah, the brake... Ah! Oh! No! No!
Perfect!
Sorry, old man!
Now for the dolls.
Ah! Alfred!
Arthur?
Uh, yeah.
Follow me!
Oh, okay
Hi.
Time to go.
You're not coming?
Only one can pass through,
and you seem to us to be the best
choice to combat Evil M
MALTHAZAR?
Oh!
Never, never speak that name.
It brings bad luck.
OK, OK...
Your grandfather went off to defeat him,
and now it's up to you to continue his fight
Thanks for the honor,
but... I think it might be better
if I leave my place to one of you
I mean, you're so much bigger
and stronger than me...!
Your heart is the strongest of weapons.
OK.
The first ring, for the body
three times to the right
The second ring, for the mind
three times to... the left.
And the third ring... one whole turn for the soul
Ah!
There! The door is open!
You can introduce yourself!
Introduce myself?
Yes, and try to be convincing
because you only have five minutes.
Alright! Be convincing! OK! OK!
Euh... There's a... with
Archibald?
No, no... No.
Introduce yourself!
I... I'm his grandson... My name is Arthur...
and you are
Saimono Matrodoy de Betameche
Right...
But you can call me Beta...
Pleased to meet you, Beta
I hope you have a good reason
for using the beam like that,
because the Council has strictly forbidden it
Go on! Go on!
This is a matter of extreme urgency!
In just two days' time
the garden will be destroyed
What are you talking about, young man?
Are you a practical joker
like your grandfather?
This is no joke, Mister Betameche...
A building contractor wants to flatten the land
and build apartment blocks!
Ah...! What are apartment blocks?
Enormous houses built from concrete that
will cover up all the gardens
and stop the flowers from growing!
Ah! But what's awful!
The only way to prevent this is for me
to find the treasure
that my grandfather has hidden somewhere!
Then
I'll be able to pay off the contractor
and none of this will happen!
Well, that's a really good idea!
All's well that ends well!
See ya!
No, no! To do that...
I need to pass into your world
so I can start looking for the treasure!
That's not possible!
You can't make a journey just like that
The council must first be assembled...
then you must explain your problem to them,
they will then deliberate and
And in two days' time the land will be
flattened and you'll all be dead!
This is an extreme emergency.
Yes, and we have to act now
because the future of your people
is in your hands!
Yes, you're right in my hands.
This calls for action!
Ferryman! Ferryman! Wake-up
it's an emergency!
You did well!
I hope it will be enough to convince him!
Betameche? You little good-for-nothing!
Don't you have anything better to do
than go around waking up honest people?
My father sent me. It's for a trip!
What again!?
Why does everyone want to suddenly travel?!
The last one was three years ago...
Exactly, that's what I mean
I was just starting to nod off
Hurry up, the King is losing patience!
The King! The King!
First, the moon...! Is it full now?
Perfect, perfect!
Now for the rings
So... three turns to the right for the body
three turns to the left for the spirit.
and now, one whole turn for the soul.
What's happening to me?!
You are going to join our brothers
the Minimoys!
They will lead you to
Help! the Seven Kingdoms.
Stop!
You only have thirty-six hours!
Granny!
At noon on the day after tomorrow,
the gateway will close again for 1000 days!
Thirty six hours... I'll do my best!
Aaaaaaaah!
Good luck, Arthur.
The key! You have the key!
The key?
Yeah I have the key!
OK. Now go over to the lock.
The lock...? That has to be it.
Good! Good! Now turn the key.
I'm gonna die!
Yes!
No, no, no, no, no! Aaaaah!
Welcome to the Land of the Minimoys!
It's not funny! You really scared me!
I thought I was going to die in that
That's incredible!
What's incredible?
I dunno, just look at my clothes
they've changed!
You can admire yourself later.
The council's waiting for you...
Come on, follow me!
I think I'd like to take a little nap
How far've they got?!
You're joking, they've only just started.
Princess Selenia!
My little girl
Father!
Sorry. Princess Selenia
may the spirits of the Ancients guide you.
Papa!
Yes?
Where are you?
I'm over here!
My son!
You did that on purpose, didn't you?
Couldn't you have waited ten seconds
before playing the clown?
I'm on a mission of great importance!
Aah? Because my mission isn't of great
importance is that it?
You're far too arrogant to
be able to free the sword!
You know you are!
Uh!
Enough! Stop bickering, the two of you!
Betameche!
I hope
you have good reason for daring to
disrupt this important ceremony.
I do father!
The Upperlands Light Beam
was activated today.
Who would dare do this?
His name is Arthur.
He is the grandson of Archibald,
and he says a great misfortune is
about to befall us
Our great misfortune has a name:
The Evil M.
And we have no need of this Arthur person.
As the Princess of royal blood,
the task of protecting our People falls to me.
Hmm!
It's moving! I have it, I have it! I feel it!
Hah!
See, told you so. Way too arrogant.
In view of the circumstances,
the Council agrees to hear this young man.
Cute huh?
Ordinary
My humble respects, Princess Selenia.
Who told him my name?
I'm sure it was you
you're only one that knows this Arthur
You can't keep a secret
My humble respects, your Majesty.
Um... yes... my respects
Oh Arthur, I am delighted to meet you...
I was a good friend
of your grandfather Archibald!
Well, young man... we've all ears!
It's like this...
In just under two days some men
are going to come
and destroy my house, my garden,
my world. And your world.
And you, all two and a half millimeters of you,
you've come to save us, is that it?
The only way to stop these men
is to pay them off!
This is why my grandfather
came to you three years ago.
He was looking for a treasure and...
I've come to complete his mission.
Your grandfather was a remarkable man
He taught us so many things!
He was the one who showed Miro
how to harness image and light.
Then one day he left,
in search of this famous treasure.
And after wandering through the seven lands
which make up our world,
he finally found it
Deep in the Forbidden Lands
in the heart of the city of Necropolis,
where he reigns supreme...
the Evil M. And unfortunately,
no one every returns from the Forbidden Lands
So
Look out! To the central gate!
It's Gondolo, the Juggler of the Great River
That's incredible we thought
he was lost forever in the Forbidden Lands
Stop!
What's wrong, Arthur?
Sire, look over there,
it looks as if a piece is peeling off.
I think it's a trap.
That's a painted canvas,
my grandfather used to do this in Africa to
protect himself from wild animals
Well, we're not wild animals
and we're not going to leave
this unhappy creature to die...
Here, make yourself useful!
Oh! Oh my god! Gondolo
Selenia!
Yes, take it easy, Gondolo.
It's a... trap!
Oh...! oh my god!
Arthur!
Clo... close the gate!
Charge!
Come on!
Ready to fire!
Watch out!
Follow me to the palace!
Hurry, father!
Yes, yes, I'm coming.
Hah! Oh, I am sorry, I'm so clumsy
Ahem, perfect timing...
I rather fancied stretching my legs a little
Father! Go and take cover, quickly!
Out of the question!
It's king's duty to face his destiny...
and if only one person is left standing,
I will be that person
Ah!
Art... we have to go on fighting!
Sure, but with what?!
Take my weapon. I'll find another one!
This is not working.
Gentlemen, it's time to face up to reality.
Watch out... the walls are booby trapped...
fly close to the roof... it's much safer
I couldn't agree with you more
Come on, my lovebirds!
This is your chance to prove you really
love each other
Here you go
Okay, we'll let them have one final kiss
Okay, that's enough now!
When I blow my whistle,
release your Romeo so he
can get back to his Juliet
OK!
Oh no!
Hi! Okay, here we go
Ah! Come on!
Right, this can't be more complicated
than driving a car!
Aah!
Beta! Look out!
Arthur, I'll never forget you!
No, you fool! it's not feeding time!
No... not the gap...! not the gap! Oh! Oh!
Oh! oh! oh!
OK... here we go again...!
That's it, I've got it!
And one mosquito down!
That's better... now let's go for it!
How brave he is,
how heroic!
It's amazing how much he's just like me!
He'd make a good partner!
Father, I'm old enough to look after
myself now
Forget it... Forget it
Oh! So who's next in line?
Oh no!
Oh yes!
Betameche!
Arthur?!
Do something!
Hang on, Arthur, I'm coming!
What a gift he is!
Come to think of it, he does remind me of you.
You OK? Nothing broken?
I'm not sure.
I can't feel anything on my butt!
Just one question...
where did you learn to fly like that!
Umm., driving with my grandfather.
Oh, that makes sense.
Let's rise to the occasion.
Aaah... All's well that ends well.
Mogoth! Let's show them what we're made of!
Selenia... The Master wishes to see you.
Follow us and no harm will come to you!
Come and get me!
Right, go on, grab her!
Why me?
Well, who else?
Well, you for example!
Me? Why me?
Four of you attacking one woman!
Aren't you ashamed of yourselves?
No!
Pick on someone your own size!
With pleasure... With pleasure!
Long live the king!
Oh, my daughter!
My daughter, my child, I must do something!
Cover me!
...thank you.
The sword of power.
It's Miracle!
OK, that's enough now.
Get on your knees
and beg the Princess for forgiveness!
Hmm!
I said, on your knees!
And beg the princess!
Forgive us, Princess Selenia
I don't think we heard that.
Our humblest apologies, Princess Selenia.
Pff, I'll think about it.
That's my daughter, just like her mother
You fought like a prince!
Thanks... This sword seems so light
it all seems so easy!
Of course!
It's magic sword.
It's been embedded in that rock for years
and you're the one who released it
Really?!
Oh yes, my friend... you're a hero now...
Arthur the hero! Arthur the hero!
Arthur the hero!
Long live Arthur the hero!
Father! now that the sword has been freed
from the stone,
we must act fast.
I would like your permission
to continue my mission.
Unfortunately,
I have to agree with you, my child,
but I must insist on one condition
What condition is that?
Arthur is brave and his heart is pure...
He will go with you.
If that is what you wish, father
I know you are going to make a fine team!
The way is clear
Are you sure that you
haven't forgotten anything?
I'm sure, go ahead... let go
Father
do we really have to take Betameche with us?
Even if your brother is still young
one day he will be
Arthur, if you should encounter
a small mole wearing glasses
who answers to the name of Mino
on your travels...
he is my son...
he's been missing for some three months now
You can count on me.
Alright, let's get going.
Thank you, Arthur!
Hey hero, let's go.
Hey... wait for me
You could at least wait for me!
Oh... I do hope they won't fall into any traps.
I slept like a rock
Arthur, time to get up
Selenia, slow down a bit, can't you?
No way! It's your fault for loading yourself up
like a gamallus!
I just packed a little bit of everything
y'know, just in case
Uh... What's a gamallus?
It's like a pachymollet, only much bigger.
And what does a pachymollet look like?
Like that!
Any chance you got something in your bag
for dealing with pachymollets?
Don't worry!
I've got my 300 function pocket knife here
Double knife, multicrab clips,
soap bubbles, music box
and for when things get really hot... a fan!
Hey, that's pretty handy alright!
And then you've got all your classic functions:
like your tulipan, matchet
sunjink, whistler, gullybar
Nothing in there to cut off tongue
by any chance?
No, but that's you specialty, isn't it?
Stay right where you are!
run on my signal... now!
Here we are
Anybody home?
Not many people come through this way
Once you've tried it, you'll understand why!
Anybody home?
Oh no! I... I'm sorry!
I mistook you for a bell.
Um, no, I mean
I didn't realize you were actually... alive!
Hold on, ma que fa, stupido!
What do you think
you're doing knocking
out all o'my customers like that?
It's not as if I got so many to start with.
Hello. I am Princess Selenia.
I know that...
and that is your stupido brother!
So who's the third comedian
who comes around knocking out
all the customers?
My name's Arthur!
And I'm looking for my grandfather!
Ah...?!
I transported a grandfather a few years ago
An old eccentric madman
who absolutely insisted on being
transported deep inside Seides territory... to
That's him! That's my grandfather!
And that's exactly where we wanna go!
Sold out!
Ah!
Necropolis, sure, why not the moon as well
We didn't ask you for the moon,
we asked for three tickets to Necropolis
is that clear enough?
Arthur!
Arthur?! You break my door to steal the key?!
Answer me Arthur! Ah!
Arthur!
Hey...! fasten your safety belts, please
Arrivederci!
Arthur?! Arthur?!
The car...? What's the car doing there?
Ah, here it is!
Wow... That's cool
I got another one just like it in pink...
wanna see it?
Beta, we've got enough light already
Arthur
Where exactly are we heading?
We are here... and we're going here!
Oh my gosh, I know where that is.
That's right under the water tank.
A giant water tank
in the hands of that unspeakable piece of.
Now I'm starting to understand
Who are you talking about?
The most evil of evil
Oh...! MALTHAZAR?!
oops!
Holy humpbacked gamallus!
Didn't anyone ever teach you
to hold your tongue?!
I... I'm really sorry!
Arthur?!
Granny?
And... we're off!
Arthur?
How long is the flight?
It's pretty short as long as we can avoid
any unpleasant encounters
What do you mean by...
unpleasant encounters?
Holy bumblebee!
He smashed the door in and now we're stuck
Whoa!
What is that?
I have no idea, but I don't think
we should hang around to find out!
Wh... what are you doing?
I'm getting out of here... oops
Hold on tight
I like it much better when it stops.
Somebody's going to get hurt with this
I'll hang onto it... it'll be safer that way...
Water!
Do something, Arthur!? Get us out of this!
It looks like you two are going to have
to get me out of this
There's a hole in my boat!
Minimoys... can't swim!
I'm coming to get you, here I come
Arthur! Arthur, please?!
I'm coming... I'm coming. I'm coming.
I know this river.
First there's a bend to the right,
then, there's a sharp bend to the left
so to catch up with them, all I have to do is
cut straight across as the crowflies
Sorry, but as the crowflies is as the crowflies
You see. I didn't abandon you
Oh, great! So instead of the two of us drowning,
now all three of us can drown together!
No one's going to drown, Selenia!
Surely, you're not going to let a li'l ol'
river frighten you, are you?
It's not the river I'm frightened of... It's that!
So, Mr.
got any good ideas before we drown?
Sure, course I have
Beta, any chance there's a rope on
that 300 function pocket knife of yours?
Erm, no, that's only on the smaller model
I've got an idea!
Hey, just because we're going to die
doesn't mean you can start taking liberties!
No, you've got it all wrong!
I need the lace to reach that tree, over there
I'm not so sure about this idea of yours
Well, I'm sure!
Arthur
have you ever thrown a sword like that before?
No, but it can't be much more difficult
than playing darts.
Betameche you go first! Selenia you next!
Yes, sir
Your turn Selenia.
Betameche, hurry up!
I can't, I'm slipping!
Selenia, hold on with both hands!
Absolutely no way!
Whew, we're safe!
Not quite!
Come on, Arthur, hurry up
we haven't got all day
I'm coming.
Selenia, you gotta admit it
the guy is pretty agile.
It's easy when you've got both hands free
Thanks
Arthur, you were fantastic!
Right, maybe Mr.
Fantastic can return my lace now?!
It's already so hard without my husband,
I don't know how I'll survive without Arthur
I'm sure he's just run away for a spell.
All of these events have probably upset him
Yes...
I don't think he could have gotten far,
and we've gonna do everything
we can to find him, ma'am.
okay.
You can count on us
What was that?
Humans.
Really?
Yep, sometime it's like that all day long!
Aw, rats, this map's a total washout
How are we ever going to find our way now?
We'll use the position
of the sun to guide us when it comes up
in the meantime, let's look for a place to sleep
And make sure you find us something comfy
Selenia,
'cause I ache all over
Beta, if you complain once more
you can go sleep under a bullmunch.
What's bullmunch?
It's like a gamallus, only much, much bigger.
Beta, I'm going to need your knife.
Coming right up...!
Ummm... Where did they put the METAGLUE?
Whoops... sorry!
Give that to me, Beta!
Before you end up hurting somebody!
Just hang on, I haven't had it very long!
I just got it for my birthday.
How old are you?
I'm three hundred years old...
only another sixty years
and I will be a grown-up
How old's Selenia then?
Almost a thousand years old.
A thousand years old?
Oh, yes... the age of reason...
It's her birthday in two days.
How is this working? Got it!
Whoa.
What's she up to?
She's making the bed.
Wooh, I'm exhausted
Goodnight!
Well, he certainly doesn't having
any trouble sleeping, does he?
It's normal, he's still young.
Three hundred years young! It's not bad!
Ah... so good.
What about you...
are you really going to
be a thousand years old in two days?
Aaah, yes... and in two days time
I am to succeed my father
and watch over the Minimoy people until
it shall come to pass that my own children
reach the age of one thousand
and succeed me
such is the tradition!
But to have children
you need a... husband.
I know, but I'm not worried,
I still have two whole days to find one...
And now...
Goodnight... Arthur!
Goodnight, princess.
Arthur?
Come on, time to get up boys!
We've got a long journey ahead of us today!
Hello, I said, get up
OK! This calls for a change of tactic!
Argh! Ow!
Come on now, shower time!
That's what I call a rude awakening!
Consider yourself lucky!
She's been waking me up
like that every morning
for the last three hundred years!
Mmm... these are even better
than the other ones!
Here, try some!
Mmum... tastes good!
What is it exactly?
Dragonfly eggs
Hey, come and take a look at this!
Oh...! that's awful!
I suppose... uh, seen from this angle...
it is less attractive
Anybody have an idea what this thing is for?!
It's an irrigation system... It transports water
Water! More water!?
I'm... really sorry, I had absolutely no idea that
Wait wait wait, wait a minute,
you mean that you're the one
who built this monstrosity?!
Yes... But I only wanted to water the radishes...
Granny loves radishes
You mean
you actually eat those disgusting things?
Let's just hope that your invention
doesn't fall into the hands of the Evil M
otherwise... I have a pretty good idea
of what he'll do with it.
My straws, they're stealing my straws!
As long as they're getting rid of those things,
I'd say they're doing us a favor.
Try thinking before you talk, Betameche!
The Evil M. knows only too well that
the Minimoys can't stand water,
and your friend, Arthur here,
just provided him
with the means to transport water
where do you suppose he'll send it to?
Oh...! our village!
Arthur, where are you going?
To repair the damage I've done.
I can't believe that guy
humans are really crazy.
That may be, but I think Arthur's right
they're bound to take the straws to Necropolis
...and us along with them
I never get to decide anything!
It's really nice of you to come with me
I'm just worried you're gonna
do something stupid
if I'm not around
Psst! Beta... hurry up!
Beta, your foot!
Oh no!
Here we go again.
Do you know
at least where this waterway leads to?
No! But, in any case
all rivers and waterways meet up at some point!
You always have such brilliant ideas
don't you?!
Don't worry, I'll take care of it
give me back your lace.
Absolutely NO WAY.
Hold on tight!
I hate public transportation!
He's coming this way... He's coming this way!
Hey-oh! Hey... what you playin' at down there?
Uh... if the Seides find us first
we won't have a chance to tell you.
The Seides?
You got a problem?
Nope, it's nothin',
I was just checkin' that
the accordion part ain't damaged
We don't need that part
we're only interested in the stems!
Oh, yeah, the stems, sure thing
Get a move on, the master is waiting
Oh, yeah, the master, sure thing No problemo!
whatever you do
don't move until I come back
and get you, got it?
No problemo!
So where are these refugees of yours?
I've hidden them in a mega discreet place!
Pretty cool, huh?
Yup, and mega discreet like you said.
Jackfire all 'round!
Yes please! Yes yes yes!
sure thanks
Hey, Jack!? Fill 'em up,
this one's on me!
oh good
Long live the Seven Kingdoms!
Cool!
Aah! Just what I needed.
Oh, yep, that hits the spot!
Ah sorry
To the Seven Kingdoms!
That's refreshing stuff!
As long as you here with me
there's really nothing to fear.
I'm the boss here. My name is Max.
Hiya Max!
And you, young lady, who might you be?
Selenia.
Daughter of Emperor SIFRAT of MATRADOY,
the fifteenth of that name
governor of the First Kingdom.
Wow! Delighted to meet you, baby!
Jack, same again
Hey, yo Easylow!
Yes boss?
let's get this show on the road!
You got it!
May I have the honor of this dance, Princess?
Selenia? We ought to be making a move
we've still got a long way to go!
Certainly.
Pff... she's too old for me anyway!
She's a thousand, I'm only ten!
What would I want with an older woman?
What's a good lookin' kid like you doin'
in front of an empty glass?
well if wasn't empty you couldn't fill it up
could you?
I like your sense of humor, kid...
we're gonna get along just fine... Jack!
Hey hey hey, take it easy
If you want to find a husband in two days
then, there's no time to lose!
But, I can help you out if you like...
That's sweet of you, thanks.
I like to help out,
besides which
things are pretty tame right now.
I only have seven wives.
Wow! Seven wives? That a...
must take a lot out of you!
I like hard work,
I can work night and day seven days a week
and I never get tired.
Ah, ah, ah, Wonderful
So, where do I sign?
Anywhere you like
kid it doesn't make any difference.
Excuse me, but...
he's already signed up elsewhere.
Selenia, it's... are you really gonna
be a thousand years old?
Yes, but we count the years in Selenielle blooms
Selenielle's the royal flower.
Ah! OK, Selenielles.
So, how old does that make me?
about the same age as me!
Wow, that's amazing!
And uh... So, before
were you a little girl like me?
what?
no, uh I mean, I'm a boy of course
but were you a little girl like the other
little girls in my neighborhood?
No, I was born as I am...
and I've never set foot outside
the Seven Kingdoms.
I'd really like to take you to my world one day.
That's Malthazar!?
No, lucky for you, it's only Darkos, his son.
Hey... Darkos this is an honor!
Hey... Great timing, there's quite a vibe
going down here this evening.
I can see that."
Organizing parties without inviting
our friends now are we?
No way, it wasn't planned
Just a little something we improvised...
to impress the newpunters, you know...
New faces?
Warn me if he comes this way
Hey, Darkos... What's up?
Selenia... what's a princess of your rank doing
in a place like this?
I just dropped in for a dance.
Ah, Well then... let's dance!
Darkos, sweetheart
I would rather DIE than dance with you!
Your wish is my command, Princess!
you will dance... for all eternity!
Easylow, get this place rockin
GET THEM!
Arthur! Look out!
Hey, they're putting up a good fight
Let's see if they've got the groove.
Huh-huh-hun-hun
h... I think I'll go get some reinforcements
Hey, I like this kid
Oh! Three against one, huh?
Then I'll just triple the power!
Oh how sweet!
So... You shouldn't have!
Really, it was nothing
Woooh, that's my girl
Holy gullybars! You scared me!
What are you doing here?
I lost my knife, I gotta find something else.
You find anything?
my knife!
Wooh, that's entertainment!
Easylow, closing time I think!
Charge.
CHARGE, MY BUTT.
Got 'em! There they are!
I've got one, I got one!
Let go of me, you idiot!
Ow! One of them bit me!
Sorry, boss!
Somebody turn the lights on!
What's going on?
I'm just following your orders
my Lord, ten o'clock curfew!
and it's ten o'clock! (blows out the smoke)
Late opening authorization granted!
cool, real cool!
Come on man, follow me!
Look, if you go this way, you'll travel safe!
Oh, great!
This is from Max!
it will lead you right to M's quarters.
Oh, I'm sure glad me ain't goin' along!
Get out, move aside!
I... want... them!
What was that unearthly scream?
Oh, just Darkos throwing a little temper tantrum.
Do you think Max will be able to delay him
for long?
Max is a real smooth talker
I think we can count on him. Come on, let's go
Oh yeah right, how can you even think about
trusting a guy like that?
Don't start Betameche!
Just keep walking and shut up, please
Um...! Wh-w-what's that growling noise?!
What growling noise? I don't hear anything
Cut it out, Selenia! I know you're just saying
that to give me the creeps!
Come on, what was it?
Oh, no
he's growling because you woke him up
and now, he's gonna eat you!
I did?
Now what did you say...?
The Yeti?! Really?!
Surprise
Well this is... a... surprise
Where's Arthur?
In the garden
In the... In the garden?
This is it!
Thank you, Betameche! Without you,
we'd be completely lost!
Now, give me your knife!
Okay, but don't break it!
Come on, boys, let's go.
Mmmm, after you, Selenia!
Princesses first.
Men only act like gentlemen when it suits them
huh?
Hmm
Well, uh... princes second
Guess it's my turn,
what do you mean he disappeared?
Every night I told him stories
about his Grandpa's adventures in Africa.
And, last night I told him about the Minimoys
The Mini what?
The Minimoys, and, um...
.he became convinced
that they live in our garden.
In the garden?
These are just fairy tales and legends, Granny
Of course, but then,
since I made the mistake of letting him know
about our money problems,
he got it into his head to
find the treasure that grandpa hid.
what treasure?
Honey
what's the use of finding the treasure
if Arthur isn't here to enjoy it?
Don't worry, Granny.
I'm sure Arthur will be right back.
He, he just took a little time off that's all...
No, in the hole
Sorry!
not the face!
Hurry!
Selenia, it's crawling with Seides!
Duh... what do you think we're hiding for?
What are they doing?
They must be taking food to their Master...
let's follow them
Do you think he's there?
Yes!
Wh-wh-what are we gonna do. Selenia?
I'm gonna spoil his lunch
oh... he's not going to like that!
But
This is where our paths separate, Arthur
I have to deal with this alone
What do you mean?
I thought we were a team?
Well, the team is about to split up!
You're gonna go look for your treasure...
and I'm gonna take care of M...
If I succeed, we'll meet back here
If I should fail...
I bequeath all my powers to you
What do you mean?
Be a good king...!
But, wait... we have to
Sele-
Congratulations, Arthur
it was a wonderful (wedding)..."
really one of the loveliest weddings
I've ever been to! Very moving,
clear, concise and quick...!
Yeah... A little too quick.
Oh, no, you got the most important things,"
her hand and her heart...
what more do you want?
Well, I don't know...
maybe like a party or something?
If you would allow me the pleasure
I would love to be
the one to organize that party!
I spend entire days polishing
that sword to perfection
I'd recognize that sound anywhere...
And who else would have been
able to draw the sword
from the stone besides you, Selenia?
I am delighted to see you, Princess.
Likewise! This way I'll be able
to kill you with my own two hands
Why so much hatred?
Because you betrayed your own people,"
slaughtered entire populations
and bound the rest into slavery...
you're nothing but a monster!
Speak not of monsters...!
Nor of things which you are ignorant!
Back in the time when
I was known as Malthazar the Good,
Malthazar the Bountiful
He who watches and protects
I inspired such trust and confidence...
that when the drought came
one which lasted a thousand years...
I was the one they chose for the crusade
with the task of bringing back water
of course
but also, all the riches I could reap
Malthazar the Conqueror!
How they praised and applauded me when I left
but I faced every hardship quit alone
the hostile lands, the ferocious beasts
the bloodthirsty tribes
lurking in the depths of contaminated plateaus
where even the humans dare not go
But I survived all that.
And having accomplished my mission,"
I returned to my village... Malthazar the Hero!
yet, it was not long
before the diseases and bewitchments
which I had encountered during my voyage began to
disfigure my body
Fear spread through the people...
fear of contamination...
people stopped speaking to me
They crossed the street when I approached...
and very soon
I became Malthazar... the Evil M!
Uh, uh. The version recorded in history books
is slightly different.
It is said that
when you returned from your voyage
you celebrated for months on end
each day sinking a little further into
drinking and debauchery
until you began keeping company
with the worst kinds of insects,
even poisonous ones..."
like a certain pretty, young... uh... weevil
Silence!
You gave your powers to her
she gave her powers to you!
That's enough, I tell you!
I was drunk!
Ah, well, if you can't hold your liquor
you shouldn't indulge.
Yes, I know. I let myself go a bit and..."
it's true, she stole a kiss from me.
One single kiss which has ruined my entire life.
Next time, try being a little more selective
in your choice of partner.
Next time
my partner will be the most beautiful of all
she whom
I have watched blossom like a delicate flower...
and whom I have long dreamt of... picking
Watch yourself...
delicate flowers might have thorns!
Yes... and this lovely flower alone has
the power to release me
from the spell that binds me
and make me look like my old self again.
Only the very first kiss of
a princess has the power
I know, and... if my information is correct...
you are still unmarried
Your information is a little out - of-date.
Master
Who dares disturb me?!
I have news of the utmost urgency
and importance
Speak up!
Well, Selenia...
you're more clever than I thought you were.
Thank you.
You could have saved my life
but you chose not to
Don't count on me to spare yours!
Don't worry, Selenia
you won't die right away
You'll just suffer a little first,"
as you watch the destruction
of your people...
You're a monster, Malthazar!
I know, I get if from my wife
Take her away!
Leave me alone, let me go!
I'm married five minutes,
and I already feel like a widower,
and a jailbird!
We gotta get out of here, Beta..."
we gotta think of something.
I'm thinking, Arthur, I'm thinking...!
The powers...
what about the powers she gave me
when she kissed me?
I don't know!
What do you mean, you don't know!
Strangling him won't do you any good!
And besides, you'd better save your energy
if you want to eat!
What do you mean?
If you want to eat down here,"
you'll have to teach them something new
every day,
otherwise you'll go hungry...
and it makes sense... complete sense...
knowledge is the one true source of wealth
is it not?!
What kinds of things do they want to know?
Pfff... anything will do!
From the elementary laws of physics to
the behavioral patterns of winkles...
even how to cook garden peas.
I taught them to write
And to paint, especially huge canvasses..."
and to harness light using mirrors
And transport water from
one place to another
Yes...
that's true, but how did you know all that?
Because the man who invented all those
wonderful things is my grandfather!
Arthur?!
Grandpa!
Oh my grandson
I'm so happy to see you again!"
Let me look at you... my, how you've grown!
It feels more like I've shrunk!
Yes, that's true.
But how did you manage to get down here?
Well, I found your riddle
Oh, yes, of course! My riddle
oh, you are a true hero!
Hello, Archibald, remember me?
Betameche?! Is that really you?
Oh... I'm so happy to see you again..."
How is your father, that noble king?
Very well indeed, thank you.
and your sister, the charming Princess Selenia?
Selenia!
I failed, Arthur... I'm sorry, all is lost!
No, as long as we're still alive"
and love each other, nothing will ever be lost
You are so full of hope!
You can never give up hope."
Look at me, only yesterday
I was just a small, lonely kid,
and today, well, I married a princess!
a happy princess.
Because she's finally found her prince charming
W-W-Whoa! Time out!
I don't mean to be rude,"
but don't you think you
should maybe respect the tradition...?
Hey, yes, he's right, what was I thinking?
Oh, hey, Archibald...! how are you?
Well, actually... not bad at all, Selenia,"
what a pleasure to see you again
Likewise, likewise!
Selenia, what's this tradition business?
Once the first kiss has been exchanged,
then you have to wait another thousand years,
because then desire
and faith have to be put to the test...
that which is rare is always valued highly
She has a point, you know
And as a Princess,"
it is my duty to follow
the teachings of the Great Book...
besides, you ought to do the same,
instead of trying to steal kisses from me!
Me? It wasn't me, you were the one
Come along now, you two lovebirds
it's showtime!
If you would care to
Gate open, boss.
My God...
When I think that
it was I that taught them all this
and now they are going to use it against us!
And when I think
that I was the one who gave them the straws...!
Look! It's Mino, Miro's son, he's still alive!
the treasure!
Ah, Archibald
what a great pleasure it is to see you again...
The pleasure is all yours.
So, Archibald
aren't you proud of the marvelous use"
I've made of your knowledge?
Looks like a fine structure...
A shame it's only purpose...
is to flood the Minimoys!
Oh, no, not only that..."
we are going to drown them,
pulverize them, and destroy them forever.
They will die in agony
with my name upon their lips
Look... read my lips
Mal-tha-zar
You really are a monster!
Maybe... but I also know how to be noble!
You are free
See?! All you have to do is follow this tunnel
and you'll be home in no time!
As soon as we're inside that tunnel
you'll flood it
My poor Selenia
What a twisted mind you have! Come on
hurry up, before I change my mind
Sire?
What is it now?
May I ask You Highness to grant me
one last favor before I die
I like this kid!
what is this favor?
I would like to leave my only valued possession,
this bracelet, to my friend, Mino.
Granted!
Your father sent me! I'll get you out of here
But you need to signal your
position at noon precisely!
Signal my position, but how?
Using your mirrors, Mino, mirrors...!
Oh? Yes! Mmm... mirrors!
That's enough!
Patience is the only thing for which
I set myself a limit...!
At noon... high noon, on the dot!
I shall allow you a head start of... three minutes.
I hope the burns in hell!
He's already there, Selenia, hurry!
Darkos?
Yes, father?
Prepare to open the floodgates
Is there nothing to nibble?
I do love something to nibble
on during a good show
I can't go on...
and what's the point in running anyway?!
Grandpa... come on, hurry
You go on!
I'm staying here... to await my death...
with a little dignity.
Come on, Grandpa! You can do it
Arthur! What's the point?
you must face up to it,
son, we're done for.
Your Highness, a few tasty tidbits
Mmm, delicious! Bring me more!
There must be a solution!
There's always a solution
The only solution is to pray,"
my children... pray for a miracle
The problem is,"
I've already asked the Great Goddess of
the Forest for so many miracles...
I'm afraid she might get mad!
A miracle!
A miracle, where?!
Right here, Grandpa, you're sitting on it.
Look!
Come and give me a hand...!
Come on... push!
Oh
What is this thing?
It's a car.
It's a Ferrari 250 GTI 12-cylinder...!
It's a birthday present!
Don't tell me you know how to drive that thing?
Of course I do!
If the young lady would care to step this way
Oh God, whatever!
Bingo!
Hurry, Arthur, please get in!
If we want make it the whole way,"
we have to wind it up as far as it will go.
Arthur, the water is coming!
Hurry, Arthur, please.
Got it!
this is the first time I've ever taken
a girl out for a drive, you know!
Well, let's just hope it won't
be the last... Step on it!
We're off!
Faster!
I just hope there aren't any speed
cameras down here,"
or we've had it!
Hey, go to the left!
I'd appreciate a little more warning
next time if that's OK with you?
OK, Turn right.
Which way do I go now, left or right?
Down!
Selenia... I... I don't feel so good!
Just hang in there, the road is smoother now.
Arthur
Honey, do you hear that strange noise?"
It sounds like
there's running water underneath.
Oh great, now you're hearing voice
just like Joan of Arc did?"
Next thing you know you're gonna
be seeing little angels
and great big ghosts
with spears and armor coming after you
Wait wait, you might want to turn around,"
there's, there's large men
with necklaces and feathers
and I don't know... I...
What the...
What time is it?
The time?! sure!
According to our calculations,"
the water should hit the village in three balls time.
What time is it, my dear Miro?
Five to noon, my good king.
Only five minutes left and still... no news.
Have faith in them, my good king..."
I am sure that they will succeed.
May the Gods hear you
Miro, may the gods hear you...
Look, there's the gate!
Yes
We made it!
Arthur
you're not going break down on us now?!
Sorry
I guess we're gonna have to get out and... RUN!
What is that rumbling noise?
I have no idea, Sire
but I have a terrible foreboding
Father, it's me, Selenia!
My daughter... they have returned!
Open the gate!
Open the gate now!
Close the gate immediately!
Open it, close it, make up your mind
All together now!
You did it daddy, you did it!"
You are now the uncontested Master
of all the Kingdoms!
Heaven knows,"
I don't care about titles and honors,
but I must admit that it does feel good
to be Supreme Ruler.
Let us prepare ourselves.
The gate looks as if it will hold.
Not for long!
It will!
Oh, my children!
Papa!
Daddy!
We missed you, Papa
Oh, my children,"
what a joy it is to
have you back safe and sound!
What's wrong?
No, the phone's cut off, it doesn't work."
What is wrong?!
AHHHH... Ou... out there!
What's out there?
Five!
Five what?
Blllllaaaaaack!
What are you talking about?
Huge!
(panicky whispers, then, LOUD)
Where're you going?"
Don't leave me here, no Granny please!
it's noon!
In one minute!
Hurry now, you only have one minute
Arthur, I must confess we'd..."
well we'd pretty much lost all hope,
but you've brought my children back to me!
And the Minimoys
will be eternally grateful to you.
And a second turn of the wheel for the spirit
Thank you for everything,"
my friend. Take good care of my son-in-law.
Sure, and you, you take good care of"
my granddaughter-in-law.
It's going to pretty dull around here
without you!
Come back soon, huh?
At the tenth moon, that's promise.
Ten moons, that gives us plenty
of time to put our desire
to the test and respect the protocol!
To hell with the protocol!
and a third turn of the wheel for the soul.
See you... ten moons!
Thank you! You okay? Yeah, thanks!
Mom?
Mom...! Mom?
Honey, what, get out... what...
oh! Arthur! where have you been?
I was with the Minimoys
The Min... Miniwhat?
The Minimoys!
Oooh... Ha, ha!
Mom?!
Oh Granpa!
Are you okay?
My brothers!
Oh I'm so glad to see you again!
Grandpa! We've got no time left
we gotta go!
You're right
Noon on the dot!
and no one in sight!
I'm afraid
though it is a beautiful Sunday
despite it being the day of our Lord...
there seems to be no miracle! So
You're right Davido
it is a beautiful, beautiful Sunday!
I believe we have some papers to sign
am I right?
Let's go in the living room,
we'll be more comfortable!
While I try to buy time,
you get busy finding the treasure
OK!
Mino, Mino where are you? Mino!
This is not gonna be easy!
Light!
I promised you riches and power
And Malthazar always keeps his promises.
nothing can stop us now!
The Seven Kingdoms are... mine!
I mean, of course, ours
What?
Excuse me,
could you tell me what time it is,
I'm kinda far-sighted
NOON!
Thank you!
My fearless and faithful warriors!
...let the festivities begin.
Now if I do the exact opposite,
the light which reflects downwards should
then reflect... upwards!
Mino! You're the best.
But what is he doing? Darkos!?
That idiot will give our position away!
Make him cut that beam immediately!
Cut the beam!
Huh? Uh, sorry, because I'm far sighted,
but I'm also hard of hearing!
You fool! You will be sorry
that you defied Malthazar!
Oh, it's nothing, really!
Bring him here!
Watch out! I can get really nasty!
Sure you can... come on, show us!
WHAT IS THIS THING?
I know, I know... Oh gracious Lord
it's a kind of
Damn!
Father! What shall I do?
What about me, father?
As for you, my son...
I hereby solemnly appoint you Commander
of the Imperial Forces!
Oh... thank you, father, that's nice
but... you wouldn't have a place left
on that mosquito of yours,
would you?!
A Commander never deserts his post...!
Father... Daddy!?
Mino? Yes!
More coffee?
No! No more coffee! Thank you!
But what I would love is
for you to sign the paper!
Of course, what did I do with my pen?
Oh what a lovely pen!
We have wasted enough time.
Sign!
Of course.
And now... the money!
Hm? Oh the money, yes!
I'd like to see how you're going to
pull one of your tricks now!
Here!
Bravo my boy!
So then...
good accounts make for good friends
isn't that right?
There you are, paid in full!
Sir, I must now be saying goodbye!
Good bye now.
Good bye!
Congratulations!
Nobody move!
I said!
So that's why you
had your sights set on this land?
Of course! The call of greed
now and forever!
One night you had a few too many,
and you told me about this treasure,
and ever since
I have not had a good night's sleep!
But now, it's mine!
Thanks kid! Nice job!
Well, I'll be saying my farewells,
you won't be seeing me ever again!
Because, I am going far, far away!
You're coming with me! C'mon!
Get your hands off me. I know the governor!
Yeah, so do I
I'll take that. I'll take that.
Next time...
please put your gift in a safer place.
That's a promise.
I'll take it. It's much safer with me.
Don't worry Mino,
I'm gonna care of you.
They did it!
Yes, he made it!
Howl would have loved
my little Mino to see this!
I understand Miro,
but our people are safe and sound...
and that is something to be thankful for
Of course. of course.
Wait, I think I know what it is
Hey, it's Mino!
Mino, my son!
Papa!
Well, there you go!
All's well that ends well!
Not quite...
May I?
I think it's ready... Excuse me...
Waited so long for this moment
I propose a toast!
Here, here!
Here it comes!
What's that?
My favorite dish!
African giraffe's neck!
What?
Honey! Honey! Rosie!
Wake up, honey!
Every time she gets a little excited
over she goes!
Where's Arthur?
He, he just went to wash up.
He'll be back in a jiffy!
only ten more moons, Selenia
I will wait for you.
This was a roNy re-encode for
300MBUNiTED.com