- This is complete madness.
- Well... so what?
I'm not going to have a
single penny until springtime.
But Mercedes, they say it's worth it.
You should see it, once in your life...
- It's unforgettable, amazing...
- And cold and expensive...
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Oh fuck, it's cold.
- Are you sure it's here?
- Yes.
It doesn't look like it's open.
They said at the Tourist Office
that it would be fine for the weekend.
- See anything?
- No.
It looks like
it's going to snow again.
Can you tell me once more
what they are again?
Thney are magnetic particles
in the atmosphnere.
- Will you wake me up at 4?
- Sure.
Once in a lifetime...
- Ouch, it's burning!
- Don't be stupid. Catch!
- Did you ask them?
- No.
But they are
from there aren't they?
Ask them yourself!
No,
I'm no good at languages.
Smile!
Go away, clouds!
Who are you Writing to?
Antonio.
Didn't he dump you?
Can I read it?
Okay, here.
We are in the asshole of nowhere,
far north of the polar circle.
We get up at daWn,
have breakkfast until dark, -
- it's a matter of a few hnours.
The night lasts for more
than twenty hours -
- but you can't even
go out for a feW drinks, -
- because the prices
are astronomical hnere.
No wonder the Norwegians have
the world record in suicides.
We haven't seen any
polar bears or reindeers.
Mercedes sends her regards.
A big kiss. Ana.
- Do you think she's his wife?
- Yeah.
Look at that hat,
stylish or what?
Didn't you ask them?
No.
Mercedes! Do We have to
listen to thnat music?
Gimme a break!
Have faith! What if there
is a saint for thne northern lights?
No saints that far north, they don't
believe in those things here.
Listen Ana, you have dragged
me all the Way up here -
- promising me the fireWorks
of the sky, and We've only seen -
- streetlights and snow.
You came of your own free will.
- I'll Wake you up at four!
- Good night.
Look Ana!
The sky is clearing up.
Look at all those stars.
That's Orion. Let's go outside.
A shooting star!
Wish for somethning!
- Where?
- There over the mountain.
It's a satellite, it's orbiting.
What are they doing?
The satellites?
They carry soaps, -
- commercials for shampoo, -
- telephone conversations, -
- the last episode of Friends.
The dreams of the world.
But then they also
carry military secrets, -
- emergency signals, -
- women calling
to scold their husbands, -
- bad Weather forecasts.
The nightmares of the world.
- That's a shooting star.
- Yes.
Now you can
wish for something!
One...
Two...
Three...
To see the northern lights.
Nothing is happening.
Maybe you should wish
for something else.
- And you?
- Me?
A guy With the sexiest body
in the World!
But we have to
prebook the hotel!
Do you remember Lanzarote.
The dirty place we were staying in!
Are you going to stay
there all day? They'll get cold.
Tell them to
come in for supper.
Ragna wants to know if
you'd like some supper.
I'm glad
Anton isn't at sea.
Once in a lifetime...
Forget about that,
you can't expect so much from life.
- Come on, let's forget it?
- One, two, three?
Yeah.
But with concentration.
One.
Two.
Three.
- Anton...
- Yeah, what is it?
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/4jpax
Help other users to choose the best subtitles