"Save the planet."
Whenever I've read that bumper sticker,
I've had to laugh.
"Save the planet."
What for?
And from what, ourselves?
What about God?
Can he help us?
I don't think so.
God gave us what we have
to see how we'll use it.
Shit. Rats in a cage
would've done it better.
"Life's a bitch
and then you die."
Bumper-sticker philosophy.
Yeah, right.
Sometimes...
you get a second chance.
For hundreds of thousands
of people commuting to the Iranian capital...
this morning began
just like any other.
At least 52 people died,
along with four bombers...
and 700 were injured.
If the chief U.S. interest at this point
is in combating terrorism...
as it emanates
from Kazakhstan...
there really isn't anyone
to deal with other than-
Since Kazakhstan's
independence six years ago-
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
Two-two with
the triple fat goose
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat
You, you ain't
never seen a bigger threat
Deuces is wild getting
willy off a bag of ily
Iced out on the sand
like a chilly willy
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
In this world that's been frozen
they come be Achozen
Rising from the dead
Overthrow the opposin'
Forces of evil
controlling our people
Deuces is wild
and their wisdom is lethal
Four twenty-two stomping
through I can see you
Strike a match, light the sun
Watch the preview
Life is a game played once
Don't refuse to
Three is the view
and life we are true to
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
Two-two with the triple fat goose
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat
You, you ain't
never seen a bigger threat
This is how I really talk
Fuck what you really thought
Now I'm really pop
Shit talk silly pot
I'd like to kill the cat
Ice like the polar caps
jawra is ily raw
So fast you kill my rap
Your phantom power
My anthem will strike the power
The truths of which I write
and will be sanctum power
It's how I spit my night
to this very time
An hour with disrespect
A light we shine
Get out here!
Come here!
Get back!
You remember me?
You sold me a gun
that don't work.
It almost got me killed. I paid $20
for this. I want my money back.
Give me that.
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
Two-two with
the triple fat goose
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat
You, you ain't
never seen a bigger threat
Okay.
I owe you.
I'll save you some.
Hey, Toorop. Toorop.
Somebody came by looking for you.
Okay.
If the chief U.S. interest
at this point is in combating terrorism...
that emanates from Kazakhstan-
Boy, what a massacre.
The victims were killed
as they were visiting the factory...
in a northeastern
Kazakhstan province.
The blast went off as the-
At the peak
of the rush hour, bombs were detonated...
in three crowded trains
and aboard a bus.
At least 50-
Toorop.
Karl, is that you?
I thought you were in Sudan,
killing babies.
Remember the last time we met?
I told you if you ever point
that gun at me again...
I'd kill you.
Who would hire
a baby killer to get me-
Who?
No shit, Karl.
If you wanted me dead, you would've
blown up the building. Who?
Gorsky.
Karl, you're a disgrace
to the profession.
You're not a mercenary.
You're a fucking terrorist.
your balls and your word.
You don't have either.
Know the difference
between you and me, Karl?
I still got both.
Take it easy.
That was just personal
between him and me.
Let me get my things.
Amateurs.
Toorop.
- See you, kid.
- Thank you, Toorop.
You are a hard man
to find, Toorop.
I'm not hiding.
Mm-hmm.
You could've knocked.
I needed to be sure
that you were the same idealist...
who worked for me 10 years ago.
So you knew
I was gonna kill Karl.
Hmm.
- I don't like you, Gorsky.
- Hmm.
You can't trust me,
and I can't trust you.
This is not about trust.
This is about, uh,
professionalism...
ethics.
- Ethics?
- Hmm.
If it's about ethics, I should kill you right now.
And you think that would make
the world a better place?
Look at you, still in this shit-hole.
Surviving.
Sleeping with your gun.
No friends,
no family, no future.
We are the same.
You and me.
We're not the same.
What do you want?
I need a smuggler.
I don't
do refugees anymore.
Use your own cargo.
- You own the borders anyway.
- Only on this side.
- This is an overseas delivery?
- A girl.
She needs to be
in America in six days.
Why are you playing with me?
You know I can't get back
into that country.
You know that U.N. passports
are impossible to fake.
This is not a fake.
Inject it in your neck
when you pass the official border.
This is your new life.
Clean credit.
John Doe.
What's the catch?
You have to make a choice.
That's the catch.
I'll do it for half a mil.
I can make you do it for free.
You can't make me do shit, Gorsky.
But you can pay me what I need
so I can get the job done right.
You got yourself
a deal.
A car will
pick you up outside...
to take you
to the rendezvous point.
Cross me, and you'll have
no place to hide anymore...
Toorop.
Hmm?
That goes both ways...
- Gorsky.
- Huh.
Shit.
Good morning.
You must be Toorop.
I am Sister Rebeka.
I just want to bring three simple rules
to your attention...
before we start our journey.
We?
I'm here to pick up one girl.
Wherever she goes, I go.
That is rule number one.
Rule number two:
the less contact she has
with the outside world, the better.
You're here to protect her
from outside influences.
That includes seeing,
hearing and feeling.
You know, it's a harsh world
out there, Sister.
I know. That is
why we live in here.
Ah, shit, okay.
What's your third rule?
No foul language.
Do we have an agreement?
You listen to my one and only rule.
Don't fuck with me...
or I'll leave you standing
in the middle of nowhere...
with nothing but your ass to sell
to get back here.
Your perfect world.
Do we have an agreement?
Obviously,
you are not a gentleman.
Obviously not.
Now that we have an understanding,
pick up the bags.
No.
Shit.
- What's your name?
- My name?
You don't have
to talk to him.
You didn't introduce yourself.
My name's Toorop.
Are you taking us to New York?
Yes. Now, please, get into the car.
Are you a killer, Mr. Toorop?
Look, lady, I'm just a delivery boy.
And to me, you'rejust a package.
I'm not your friend. I'm not your brother.
I'm not your boyfriend.
In six days, I'm gonna deliver you
and never see you again.
Sister Rebeka's right.
We shouldn't even talk.
Come on.
Comfy?
You wouldn't have a light, would you?
Figures.
Are you okay, baby girl?
I've never been this far.
Let's hurry up.
The train's gonna leave soon.
Take your bags.
Are you really going
to need all that?
We could never have
enough firepower, Sister.
In fact-
I've never touched a gun in my life.
Now would be
the perfect moment to start.
No, thank you.
I can defend myself.
Stay close. This is the real world.
There's no mercy for the weak.
Just because we're peaceful,
that doesn't mean we're weak.
It does here.
Take this.
- Hurry.
- Here.
- Change.
- What are you doing?
That's him. We're locked on.
He's a big motherfucker. Look at him.
That won't be a problem.
- And that's Aurora.
- She's cute.
- Put this on.
- Let's stay concentrated, guys.
Come on.
What do we do now?
No need to rush. Let's give it time.
Hang on.
Okay, give me three.
Hey.
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
Come on.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, come here! Hey!
- Hey, something's happening. She's on the run.
- Hey!
Aurora! Toorop!
Aurora!
Don't go. You will die.
- What are you doing?
- She's felt it.
- Don't go that way.
- She's not used to crowds.
- We have to go now. We have no time.
- We have to get away.
What is wrong with you?
Make her walk, or I'll carry her.
- Stop. Don't touch her.
- Don't go that way.
- We're going now.
- We have to get away.
Don't touch her.
Come on.
We'll go to the train.
We need to catch it.
Come on.
Come on. Move. Move.
Get out of the way. Move!
Hey, guys, can I buy
these three seats off you?
Buy some more goats.
For you.
Those tigers in the cage-
they weren't real, right?
Siberian tigers
went extinct in 2017.
The last one died
in the Moscow Zoo.
What is she,
a walking wildlife encyclopedia?
They were clones?
Second-generation clones,
not real tigers.
Copies of copies.
But they're living creatures,
made by God.
No. They were organic
machines made by man.
But God made man
in his image.
So what man creates
is also God's will.
Is this what you
teach her in the convent?
Then God would be pretty
fucked up to make man in his image.
You wanna talk? Tell me what
happened at the marketplace.
If I'm gonna protect you...
I need to know
what's wrong with you.
She was scared.
It's the first time
out of the convent...
and you put us
in that situation.
First time
out of the convent, huh?
So I'm probably delivering you
to some billionaire playboy...
who purchased you
off the Internet.
Stay close.
- What are we doing here?
- Looking for a friend.
Come on. Come on.
Sit over there.
I'll be right there in a minute.
And, you, don't talk to anybody.
Yo, guys.
They're separating.
Don't do anything stupid. Wait.
- Get up, motherfucker.
- Huh?
Hey! Toorop!
How are you?
- How you doing?
- What you doing in this beautiful part of Russia?
Working.
Working for who?
Hey, hey. Two shots.
- Hold your positions. We're gonna move in.
- Gorsky.
He made me an offer
I couldn't refuse.
What can I do for you?
I need three passes
on the boat...
and two snow bikes
on the other side.
- You crossing?
- I'm delivering.
The girl.
Her? Who is she?
I don't know.
- Where you taking her?
- America.
- What America? You're on a terrorist list there.
- Yeah.
You need a passport.
You need an identity.
You're kidding me.
You got a passport?
- Yeah, and I'm not coming back.
- That is a bold move.
I got 50 G's saying
you can help me out.
When?
Now.
You don't have to look.
Who is he?
He's a lost soul.
See you at the landing
at 0600 sharp.
You got it.
- Who was that?
- An old friend. A good smuggler.
- You trust him?
- I don't trust anybody. Come on.
Sorry, kids.
These girls are with me.
- Just let her go, Toorop.
- How do you know my name?
- We know a lot of things you don't know.
- Yeah? Like what?
Like you don't know
what you're doing.
- I'm doing my job.
- Fuck your job.
- What?
- One million, tax free.
Take the money
and walk out without a fight.
Make it easy on yourself, Toorop.
Aurora!
Toorop!
No! Toorop!
No!
Hey.
- Aurora!
- Hey, man, let the girl go.
Just let her go.
Let her go.
Hey, man.
Hey. Hey. I don't-
No!
Get over there!
You wanna fight?
Okay, man.
Come on!
Stop! Stop! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop!
Don't kill him!
He doesn't want to hurt me.
He wanted to protect me!
- Your father sent us.
- My father?
Get away from her.
Get away from her!
It's okay, Aurora.
- I have to know.
- No.
Aurora!
Aurora.
Aurora! Aurora!
Listen to me. Stop!
Toorop! Toorop!
Come on.
Let's go. Hurry up.
Move it.
Come on!
Go! Go!
Stop!
Let her go!
Next one dies!
Come with us.
They're ready to die for you.
I don't want anybody
to die for me.
What do you think
you're doing?
- What's wrong with you?
- You think this is a game?
- Why did you shoot them?
- You trying to get us killed?
- Why didn't you let me go?
- You don't know them!
Well, what are you gonna do,
shoot me in the head?
- Shoot me like an animal?
- Stop it!
I told you I'd take you
to New York, and I will.
This is way too many refugees, man.
The ice is getting
thinner every year.
They're losing cargo
all the time.
We're not gonna all
get on the boat.
Make sure we do.
Ah, this goddamn global warming's
bad for business.
What's happening?
Watch this.
There's not much time.
They don't wanna be
spotted by satellites.
Hurry. Come on!
Come on!
Move!
No!
You can't do this!
They'll die out there!
No!
- You can't do this.
- Get away from the controls.
- What are you doing? Stop it. Stop it.
- No!
- Don't do that. What's wrong?
- Put it down.
- No. Don't.
- Hey, hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Take it easy.
- Hey, take it easy.
We go back up.
Now.
Okay. Okay.
Relax.
- We go back up.
- Easy.
Now.
Relax.
Calm down.
I feel them!
I feel them dying!
The whole Bering Sea is dead!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
What the fuck was that?
I was 17 years old,
living in San Francisco.
My life was a mess.
I met the wrong man.
I was lost in darkness.
But then the high priestess
of our church opened the doors...
that led me
on to the path oflight.
I joined the Noelites...
and I ended up in the convent.
It was a haven for women
who needed to heal.
I worked in the orphanage.
She arrived.
A little baby.
Her father was dead.
Nobody knew anything
about the mother.
I took her as my own.
I fed her. I taught her.
Everything was fine...
until three months ago.
The doctor came.
He gave her a pill.
He was with her
for 10 minutes...
and then she slowly
started to change.
But nothing- nothing as violent
as what you saw today.
But something's not making sense.
How could she know how to operate
a 30-year-old Russian sub?
She's always known things
that she never experienced.
Aurora could speak
when she was two years old.
- A lot of kids speak at two-
- Nineteen different languages.
Who else knows about this?
Nobody but the doctor.
He told me to keep it a secret
to protect her.
He said...
that we would get
the best medical help in America.
She needs help.
Get her ready.
You know, two years ago,
in Uzbekistan...
I saw this viral bomb go off.
It was, uh-
It was incredible.
Everybody died.
She's carrying, ain't she?
Huh?
All the symptoms fit.
All that weird behavior.
I'm telling you, man,
she is carrying a weapon.
You have any idea
how much money she's worth?
If she's carrying a virus...
I'll kill her myself
and burn the body.
- What happened to them?
- Fighter drones.
Anything that moves
is shot on sight.
Now we're in the zone.
It's 10 miles to the D.M.Z.
Then let's make it
10 fast miles. Let's go!
Toorop, they're coming!
Shit. Finn, we're spotted. Hit it!
Break!
Finn, get close to me! Finn, now!
Aurora, jump onto our bike.
I'll draw them off.
You three, hide here.
What are you doing?
Toorop cleared our way out.
We're almost at the border.
Toorop, we need you now!
It's gonna shoot us!
Toorop. Toorop!
Stop!
Toorop!
He's not dead!
Ah, shit!
Hey, stay with me.
He's not reacting.
He's bleeding to death.
I need your help. Okay.
We gotta get outta here now.
It's a small piece of metal.
I'm gonna take it out.
- What do you need?
- Just hold him.
Look, we don't have time for this, okay?
They're gonna send more drones!
Aurora?
- You got it?
- I got it.
- It's okay.
- Give me a bandage.
We should never have turned back.
He knows the rules.
I'll sew it up later.
Hey!
Now you and the passport
are mine.
- What are you doing?
- You, I don't need.
Like I said,
trust no one.
It's good.
Where did you learn to cook?
Rule number one
in the mercenary handbook.
You never had a woman
take care of you?
Ow!
Sorry.
No, not in my line of work.
- Ah!
- Oh- Finished.
She gets pleasure out of this.
- Crybaby.
- Crybaby?
Mmm.
Ooh. What is that?
- Painkiller?
- No, thank you.
- Live a little.
- No.
Aurora, stop!
Spit it out.
Ah!
Yuck! Hmm.
Girls, we made it
across the border.
Here's to survival.
And thank you
for saving my life.
Maybe now
you can trust somebody.
We protected each other,
like family.
We are all going to die
in New York.
Good night.
She's just scared.
Yeah, right.
Go back to sleep.
We still have
a long way ahead of us.
What are you doing?
We go through
customs tomorrow.
I can't take these.
You know, when Sister Rebeka
first held me as a baby...
it was a night like this.
Aurora-
that's where I got my name.
- From the chaos.
- It suits you.
You're risking
your life for me. Why?
I've done my time.
All this killing
and pain and... war-
For what?
I'm tired-
tired of it all.
And you're my only chance
out of this hell.
And go where?
27 Cedar Grove.
Near Canada.
It's upstate New York.
My parents had a farm-
more like a cabin
with a lot of land.
It's probably in ruins,
but I might be able to fix it up.
There is no place like home.
But Kansas ain't
what it used to be.
The Wizard of Oz.
1939.
That's right.
Toorop?
Are you really going to kill me
and burn my body?
I hope I won't have to.
You have reached the limit of your water credit.
To purchase more credit,
enter your room number now.
Thirty minutes.
The bus leaves in 30 minutes.
Last plane to New York
in two hours.
Your Highness,
they've crossed the Canadian border.
She's coming.
Let's pray.
A miracle in the making.
Trust. Invest in our new faith.
Tomorrow is the dawn of our new age.
Right here, girls.
Welcome, Mr.Johnson.
Your multimedia system
is loading.
- We wish you a pleasant stay.
- It's okay.
It's safe here.
Here.
Hey, there's no food.
Guess we're not
gonna be here long.
- What's wrong?
- They are all dead.
Sources report the destruction in Kyrgyzstan...
of a 1 ,000-year-old convent...
one of the oldest continually functioning
convents in Central Asia.
Now occupied by
an ascetic branch of the Noelites...
the convent was struck
by a missile late last night.
There were no survivors.
Here, an initial reaction
from the Noelites.
It is a tragedy
to think that even defenseless women...
who made the choice
to withdraw from society...
and lead a life of purity...
should suffer
the attacks of terrorists...
who have absolutely no respect for
the lives of decent, God-fearing people.
We shall mourn our sisters...
and continue their legacy
for world peace...
through obedience,
purification and hope...
for the miracle
we so desperately need.
Congratulations, my friend.
- You made it safe and sound.
- Gorsky.
Did you destroy that convent?
I'm not a terrorist, Toorop.
I'm a mercenary, like you.
Bullshit.
What the hell is going-
What the hell
is going on over here?
- You didn't leave me a gun.
- You've done yourjob.
A doctor is coming
in a few minutes.
If she's okay,
you're home free...
and the tracking device
in your passport will be deactivated.
Don't make us use it.
Sometimes it's hard to understand...
but I believe God has a reason
for everything that happens.
What reason could there be?
They never hurt anybody.
Maybe it was
an accident.
It was not an accident.
It was destroyed right after
we crossed the border.
Would you like
to pray with me?
I don't feel
like praying anymore.
Toorop said
I'm just a package to him.
Why did you bring me here?
'Cause I couldn't
take care of you anymore.
How is she?
Scared.
Yeah. Well, she should be.
- Who are they?
- To the left...
the Range Rover goons
work for your sect, the Noelites.
To the right,
the bikers work for Gorsky.
They're all here
to make sure I deliver.
And if we don't?
It's gonna be a free-for-all.
Look, Sister...
we traveled
6,000 miles together.
The truth is this has been
a suicide mission from the beginning.
They won't let either one of us
walk out of here alive.
- That's why they destroyed the convent.
- That's the doctor...
that came to the convent
three months ago.
Okay.
- Good evening, Sister.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
- Where is she?
- In the room.
Good.
You're a bad man.
They're more powerful
than we expected.
Thank you, Aurora.
Thank you so much.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
- I have to run some more tests.
- More tests?
- Standard-
- Hey, you just ran your test.
- What's wrong with her?
- Expect a call from-
What is wrong with her?
Toorop. Toorop.
Let him go.
If you please.
Thank you, Sister.
- Get over here!
- What's wrong with you?
- I want to know everything that you know.
- Don't you think...
that if I knew anything
I would tell you?
No, I don't think. You're a Noelite.
You're like him.
- You swore an oath.
- Not to them. To God.
God has nothing to do with it now!
You understand?
If she's carrying a virus,
she could annihilate half the city...
and I'm not gonna
have it on my conscience!
- How can you believe that?
- I don't know what I believe anymore!
I'm pregnant. Twins.
It's not possible.
I've watched over you all your life.
No one's ever touched you.
And nobody has.
Shit.
Toorop,
theyjust want my babies.
Yes.
Mr. Toorop?
- This is the Noelite Church C.E.O.
- I know who you are.
- Thank you for doing such a goodjob, Mr. Toorop.
- You're welcome.
Please bring the girl
to the limousine...
and your mission
is accomplished.
We're on our way out.
All right, guys. Are you ready?
Keep them in sight, guys.
We can't
let her go, Toorop.
Look around.
Do we have a choice?
She's your problem now.
Thank you, Toorop.
We're going in the subway.
What's wrong?
It's a missile
linked to my passport.
- How can you stop it?
- Only by death.
Go to the subway!
Toorop.
Aurora!
Ow!
I need you to live.
He's back to life.
Scars are all gone.
Doctor hasn't lost his touch.
Too bad he can't make him pretty.
Where am I?
In paradise. We'll take you to your maker.
Good evening, Mr. Toorop.
I'm Dr. Darquandier, Aurora's father.
Thought you were dead.
It's sometimes useful to be dead.
It allows one a second chance.
You'll see.
Oh, yes.
You were clinically dead for two hours.
I fixed you up as best I could.
We lost quite a bit of time
getting you from the morgue.
And then you went
into a coma for five days.
Now, Mr. Toorop,
I believe I owe you some explanation.
You see, 20 years ago I was drummed out
of the medical profession...
for trying to implant human babies
with artificial intelligence.
Around that time, the Noelites
came to me with an unusual offer.
They wanted me to do exactly what
the rest of the world was scared of.
That is, to create
a supernatural human being...
with the complete knowledge of
the world imprinted in her memory.
So I built a supercomputer...
to be Aurora's
artificial mother.
As a fetus, Aurora learned
to process information...
just like a computer.
But when she was born...
she became much more
than just an experiment.
You see, she became-
she became my daughter.
She was beautiful. She was unique. And
I couldn't bring myself to give her away.
That's when they hired
Gorsky to kill me.
Well, he almost succeeded.
He took my baby away.
I searched for her for years.
I couldn't find her.
I knew that one day the Noelites
would have to present their miracle...
to the rest of the world.
- What do you want from me?
- I want you to find my daughter.
We think she's alive
and that she planned everything.
She even shot you
with a purpose.
You see,
you died with your eyes open.
But your brain recorded more
than you can actually remember.
We just need to rewind the tape
and fiddle with your memory.
I was dead.
Precisely.
People are starving for any kind of miracle.
We were the provider,
and we had the copyright.
250 million followers today.
Two billion tomorrow.
This is what Aurora represented.
Our stock options were sky high...
and the whole world
was waiting for a revelation.
But not anymore.
Aurora was our trademark.
But now our trademark has disappeared
in a ball of fire like a cheap magic trick!
And you morons can't even find
a single D.N.A. string to rebuild her.
We are finally on the verge
of becoming a bona fide religion...
and your incompetence has thrown
20 years of careful planning down the tubes.
Who gave the order
to use guns to retrieve her?
You left Gorsky no choice!
What were you thinking?
Try not to get upset, Your Highness.
It's bad for your blood pressure.
Stop fussing. Well?
Does anyone
have any suggestions?
What should we do?
Your Highness,
we want to launch a campaign...
to inform the people that
we were targets of a terrorist attack.
We need to be proactive,
not victims!
In six months, we can offer a closer look
at God through our new space module.
We need a miracle,
not another gadget!
What?
The body stolen from the morgue
was Toorop's.
The police found the van
that transported him in New Jersey.
Who would want to abduct
the body of a dead man?
What am I looking for?
What you missed the first time.
We'll guide your memory
with our computer.
Are you ready,
Mr. Toorop?
I hope so.
Fast forward. Fast forward.
Not too fast.
Those are his wars.
Don't bring him too far back.
- We're losing control. He's going back too far.
- Kill!
That's his childhood. Bring him back.
Don't lead him there.
Bring him forward.
Not on the Noelites. On the bikers. On the bikers.
All right.
He's way past
the danger threshold.
Everyone, slow down.
Slow him down now!
Slow down!
Let's wait.
Let's wait. Let's wait!
I need you to live.
He's dead.
Wait.
Don't bring him back yet.
Go home.
It's all right. It's all right, Toorop.
You're back. You're safe.
"Go home."
What does it mean?
How'd she survive the blast?
It's the babies, you see.
They're gaining power.
They're the ones
guiding her.
Her capacity for survival is greater than
anything we could ever have imagined.
Survival of the fittest.
We're
a pathetic race, really.
We stopped evolving
at a critical point.
Machines have evolved infinitely further
in the past 200 years.
And that's what
I tried to correct with Aurora.
Her babies are our future.
They are the real miracle.
You tried to correct mankind
by creating a Virgin Mary.
The Noelites have found us.
They'll be here in two minutes.
Find my daughter.
You're the only one now.
Mr. Gorsky.
I hoped I wouldn't have to see you again.
Where is my money?
You still haven't paid me.
- You have an odd way of killing people.
- What are you talking about?
I'm on my way to see our old friend-
Darquandier.
Impossible!
I made his car explode myself.
Mr. Gorsky, when I kill,
I kill for good.
- Are you threatening me?
- Bless your soul.
You need a nuke to kill me!
Bitch.
Our satellites have spotted two vehicles
leaving the compound.
- It's too late to intercept them.
- I'm sick and tired of your damn excuses.
Hello, my dear.
It's lovely to see you.
- Where's my daughter?
- I see you haven't found her.
And you never will.
You selfish bastard.
Twenty years ago I gave you
the opportunity you wanted.
Now it's my moment.
- Where is my daughter?
- She's not your daughter.
- She comes from me!
- I designed her!
For me!
She's my miracle!
She belongs to my church!
Your church is a lie!
You're peddling miracles for your own profit!
Are you willing to die for her?
Yes.
Why?
For a reason
you will never understand.
Love?
I understand love.
Find Toorop.
He knows where she is.
Wait here.
Toorop.
You're finally home.
What's left of it.
But I came back for you.
Have a little faith.
I thought I had saved her.
But I was wrong.
Aurora was designed to breed.
The perfect holy virgin
can't live in flesh.
She was just a vessel...
a prototype
that wasn't built to last.
She was programmed
to create new life...
and disappear.
They say she won't wake up
before she gives birth.
But I'm here...
waiting.
Toorop.
Thank you...
for protecting us.
You're their father now.
Aurora.
That's the first time
you've said my name.
Save the planet...
one child at a time.
Ain't that a bitch.
Take me home to where I'm from
Take me home away from Babylon
Take me back to where I'm from
Take me back away from Babylon
Don't be afraid of destiny or paradise
Your path is right above
if you don't compromise
These are blessed in space
and, hey, you decide
So real to you but still we realize
Oh, take me home to where I'm from
Seems so far from where I've gone
Take me home to where I'm from
It takes a man to be alone
My mind is the mother ship
I can solve space because of it
The more further I fly
the deeper my subjects get
Sun eclipsed, stars align
I see Mars when I rhyme
Knowledge is mine
I got bars to burn
The pen is the tank
The fuel is the ink
Souls that think
just like my mind move from the blink
Call the pages my runway
The book is my launchpad
Soon as the sun blazes
Renaissance on glass
Virgin ears question
all perception
The Achozen, resurrectin'
the resurrection
Paradigm shifts
Indirection
Sharp swords slice
the immaculate deception
So fate propels us
through that open door
That heart for show
and so much more room to grow
Human connection illuminates our mission
Mission
The past is after death
So never look back
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
Two-two with
the triple fat goose
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat
Deuces is wild getting
willy off a bag of ily
Iced out on the sand
like a chilly willy
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
In this world that's been frozen
they come be Achozen
Rising from the dead
Overthrow the opposin'
Forces of evil
controlling our people
Deuces is wild
and their wisdom is lethal
Four twenty-two stomping
through I can see you
Strike a match, light the sun
Watch the preview
Life is a game played once
Don't refuse to
Three is the view
and life we are true to
Deuces is wild
It's a triple threat
Two-two with
the triple fat goose
You, you ain't never
seen a bigger threat