I put a spell on you
Because you're mine
You better stop
the thing that you do
I said watch out
I ain't lyin.
Yeah
I ain't gonna take
none of your
Foolin' around
I ain't gonna take
none of your
Puttin' me down
I put a spell on you
- I see a rabbit.
- Where?
Up there. One that's got big,
droopy ears.
That's a shoe.
- It's more of a... It's a boot. A lace-up
boot. - It's a boot, like your boot.
Now what is it?
I put a spell on you
Cos you're mine
You better stop the
thing that you're doin'
I said watch out
I ain't lyin.
Yeah
I ain't gonna take
none of your
Foolin' around
Ain't gonna take
none of your
Puttin' me down
I put a spell on you
Cos you're mine
Oh, you're mine
They're all moving into
these houses, Rosie.
A whole nation.
A whole fucking world of plastic houses.
It's like a rash. It's eating up
this island like a case of bad acne.
In 30 years, there won't be
anything left that isn't suburbia...
...or the ghettos.
Cos they all want to live in places
with people exactly like themselves.
They have their own police forces,
some of them,
to keep their greedy
little children safe.
And they have the vanity to call this
place a community. Look at this crap!
That's not a house.
It's a thing to keep the TV dry.
I wish we had a TV.
No, you don't.
I swear, I solemnly believe
that humanity is now
officially descending
the ladder of evolution.
In a thousand years,
human beings will be the size of gerbils
and they'll have one
thought a year...
...in December.
They'll think about what
they want for Christmas.
Decline and rot, my angel,
that's the way of the world...
...except for you.
You're exempt.
Remember that.
Jack Slavin for Marty Rance.
Hey, Marty.
Me again.
That's government land
that you're eating into.
50 yards of nature preserve.
That is a wetland, as I'm sure you know.
You can call the cops if you want to.
I'll call them myself.
I look forward to
seeing the outcome.
We needed a doorstop.
What are you thinking about?
I'm going to plant the bell flowers
in front of the house today.
At least leave me
a place to walk.
- You're getting freckles.
- I always had those.
No, there's nothin'
you can send me
My own true love
There's nothing I'm
wishin' to be ownin'
Just carry yourself
back to me unspoiled
From across that
lonesome ocean
Oh, but I just thought
you might want something fine
Made of silver
or of golden
Either from the
mountains of Madrid
Or from the
coast of Barcelona
If I had the stars
of the darkest night
And the diamonds from
the deepest ocean
I'd forsake them all
for your sweet kiss
For that's all I'm
wishin' to be ownin'
Rosie, Rosie.
That's a sweet little bridge,
but I wouldn't want to drive across it.
Well, seeing as we
never go anywhere...
You still don't understand
weight-stress ratios.
I understand them enough.
- Enough for what?
- Everyday needs.
The Latin name for "buttercup"
will only get you so far.
Let me write that again.
One more time...
...with feeling!
What is the Latin
name for "buttercup"?
Ranunculus Bulbosus.
What?
I'm glad I got to know
you for such a long time.
Don't say stuff like that.
- I have to face up to it.
- Shut up, OK?
Do you not think we should
get somebody in to help?
Who, a maid?
Don't go off, Rosie.
Go away.
What is it?
You're going to leave me soon.
You're the one that's
going to leave soon.
You're getting too big for me.
Look at the size
of that hand.
No, you're going to die.
It's just the way it is.
I mean, this thing may be...
pumping away for
some while to come.
When you die,
I'm going to die.
- What on earth are you
talking about? - I am.
What are you going to die of?
When you go, I'm going.
If you die,
there's no point to my life.
Tough luck.
Don't you ever say that again.
Do you hear me?
You never say that again.
Tell me a story.
Come on.
Once...
there was a girl...
and she lived in
a little tiny house.
And one day an ox came by.
And the girl was so polite,
she said,
"Ox, would you care to join me for tea?"
The ox wasn't used to being spoken to
very much. He was flattered.
He said,
"Thank you, yes. "
And he proceeded to put
his nose through the door.
His nose had a big ring in it.
The girl pulled as hard
as she could on the ring
to try to get the
ox through the door.
The ox pushed and pushed.
The girl pulled and pulled.
Cracks started to appear
around the walls.
Then the ox gave one
great almighty push.
The whole house
collapsed around them.
So she climbed up
on the ox's back
and they rode away together.
In the course of time,
they were married.
Let me look at you.
I'm never going to leave you,
you know.
I have to go to
town tonight, Rosie.
There's some stuff I've got to do there.
I may not be back until the morning.
- Will you be all right?
- Yeah.
- I'll see you later, Rosie.
- OK.
Seen a shooting star tonight
And I thought of you
You were trying to
break into another world
A world I never knew
I always kind of wondered
If you ever made it through
Seen a shooting star tonight
And I thought of you
And I thought of me
If I was still the same
If I ever became what
you wanted me to be
Did I miss the mark
Or overstep the line
That only you could see?
Seen a shooting star tonight
And I thought of me
- Is she here?
- She's downstairs.
You got thinner.
Hi, by the way.
I was thinking maybe
you'd come live with me.
- What?
- You heard.
You've never even
invited me out there.
- You like me that much, huh?
- Yep.
What about my kids?
Well, that goes without saying.
What about Rose?
- Have you thought this through?
- Through?
I've thought about it,
but I'm not clairvoyant.
- You know what I mean, Jack.
- Come live with me.
Quit your job.
Quit your jobs.
I can make life easier for you.
Just to prove that...
I'm in earnest...
Call that an early-retirement
package.
Er...
It's not coming out right, is it?
No.
I'm sorry.
Look, come live with me.
Give it a try.
I'll take care of you or you
take care of me. Whatever.
My kid needs a woman
around the place and... so do I.
I need you.
How's that?
What are you thinking?
I'm wondering if you're
crazy or not.
That's a waste of time, honey.
My poor tree house.
We can rebuild it. That's not a problem.
Do you really use it any more?
It's my house.
- Rose...
- Yes?
There's some people coming
that I've invited. Guests.
- Guests?
- People...
just come to stay for a while.
It's an experiment.
OK?
New chapter.
Hey!
Welcome, strangers.
- I see you er...
- Yeah. A couple of things.
So glad to finally meet you, Rose.
- I'm Jack.
- Yeah, I'm Thaddius.
Thaddius. Right.
You must be Rodney. Welcome.
These are my boys.
That's Thaddius...
Rodney...
This is Rose.
Oh, I'm Kathleen.
Wow!
Does anybody else live out here?
Er... used to be a commune.
There was 60 people living here,
give or take, at one time.
Engineers, farmers, carpenters,
a couple of scientists...
We were trying to...
Well, it wasn't what you see in the movies.
We weren't painting ourselves
orange and shaking tambourines
and whatever else
they got up to then.
We were trying to...
rebuild society on a small scale.
We were trying to figure out a way people
could live without destroying the planet,
with virtually no waste
or private property and...
I'll take that.
It was an experiment.
It looks like it didn't go too well.
- No, we learnt some stuff.
- Watch it.
- This is it.
- Oh, Jack...
Just put all your stuff down there for now.
Bring the rest in later on.
Where do you really live?
In my aunt's basement.
How long are you
going to stay here?
Not very long, personally,
but I have a feeling that my mother will
be embedded here for quite some time.
You get a lot of postcards.
My mother used to send them.
- Uh-huh.
- She left when I was five.
She might be coming back.
- Oh, dear.
- Rose?
Would you like to help me set the table? I'm
just going to make some cheese sandwiches.
- No, no... - Oh, that's cooked
food for the chickens
and that's raw food for the compost and
the big one... metal and plastic, paper.
- You'll get the hang of it.
- Yeah. OK.
Any questions about
the house, ask Rose.
One of you can sleep in
here for the time being,
and the other one's on the couch until
we get one of the outbuildings fixed up.
- That's fine.
- Is that all right with you?
- Mm-hm.
- It's so quiet in here.
It's like the inside of a can.
Hey, where's the TV?
No TV.
Are you working at
the moment, Rodney?
I've been studying to be
a women's hairdresser.
What brought you to that?
Erm...
I always wanted to be a barber,
but men don't get enough
pleasure out of their hair.
Did you do er...?
Kathleen.
- Yeah. Her hair?
- No, I didn't do Kathy's hair.
My mother likes to think of
herself as being 16 years old.
- Oh, Rodney!
- I'm sure if I cut her hair off,
she would have a
breakdown of some kind.
How do you make your money?
I inherited the family business
when my father died, so I sold it.
- Oh. So you're loaded? - I don't think
you need to worry about that.
- Mom said you were an engineer.
- That's what I studied.
- Er... alternative energy.
- You got your degree in England?
Scotland, but I've been
an American since 1972.
Naturalised citizen,
God help me.
Why did you do it, then?
Because I fell in love with this country,
or... what I thought it was going to become.
You've got one more year
of school left, is that right?
- Yeah, I guess so. - I was expelled
in the last year of high school.
Why?
For defecating in the thirteenth
hole of the school golf course.
- Your school had a golf course?
- He's doing real well in school.
- Is that for me?
- Yeah, sweetie. It's a cheese sandwich.
I haven't seen one
like that since 1953.
- I'll be right back.
- OK.
Sorry.
Rose...
Don't make me bloody
well chase after you!
They're not guests.
They're moving in!
They're guests, until we see.
Just see how it works out.
- They brought everything!
- Everything?
They brought their lamps!
I've got to admit,
those lamps were shocking.
Look, it's just an
experiment, Rosie.
Let's just try it for a while
to see how it works out.
God forbid, you might even
end up wanting them to stay!
- You tricked me!
- It was a spur-of-the-moment decision.
She's so regular.
Kathleen, her name is,
by the way.
That's the whole point.
She'll take care of things.
- I took care of things!
- We took care of things. Now I'm sick.
How long have you
been lying to me?
How could you
not have told me?
I didn't think you'd understand.
I don't.
Hey, little freak.
Ever eaten a snake before?
No.
I know these kind of woods.
You got copperheads in there,
don't you?
There's a few that live under
a dead tree in the woods.
Show me where the tree is.
I used to trap snakes for this evangelist.
- What did he do with them?
- Put on a show.
Said he had the power of God
cos he didn't get bitten.
Did he have the power of God?
He died of a snakebite.
There.
So does your dad know
about this place?
Maybe.
Does he know
everything about you?
Wild thing.
I'll give you a bedtime story
you won't forget.
- What are you doing?
- I want you to do it to me.
- Huh! Oh, my God.
- I never did it before.
Not even partly.
And erm... what made you select
tonight for your initiation?
Cos I have to do it right away.
Er, my brother is out
at the moment...
probably doing something
along these lines,
so if you want to take a seat in his
room I'm sure he'll be happy to oblige.
I don't like him.
That's funny.
I don't like him, either.
Look, it's not funny.
OK?
This is tragic.
It's...
It's not exactly tragic.
It's er... it's ridiculous.
OK?
No.
OK, no, look.
Look, wait.
I wasn't aware that,
on top of being trapped in retro world
due to my mother's saviour complex,
I myself was to become
a sort of sex toy...
...for my angelic,
possibly disturbed,
certainly odd new sister.
OK?
Let's...
Let's not forget that part.
Huh!
Who are you people?
- But I like you.
- Christ...
Just...
I'm just er...
I'm not ready to unpeel my nylon
at this particular point in time.
Not for anybody.
It's nothing personal.
Hey...
I got an idea.
It's...
It's kind of a compromise.
Do you mind if it's radical?
I put a spell on you
Cos you're mine
You'd better stop
the things you do
I ain't lyin.
No I ain't lyin.
You know I can't stand it
Your running around
You know better, Daddy
I can't stand it cos
you put me down
Yeah, yeah
I put a spell on you
Because you're mine
You're mine
Oh, yeah
I love you, I love you
I love you
I love you anyhow
And I don't care if
you don't want me
I'm yours right now
Jesus Christ!
Come on.
Oh, God...
Are you out of your
fucking mind?
Rodney did it for me.
I was referring to
the loaded gun.
You're a bloody little hooligan.
What are you doing?
Look what he did to you.
Do you love me?
Is she all right?
Good night, my little dove.
What was Rose's mother like?
What was your wife like?
Just about the opposite of you.
- What does that mean?
- Well, you know. You.
Imagine the opposite of you.
Thin hair, dark eyes, big tits?
- Go a little deeper.
- Rich?
She was inscrutable,
dreamy, capricious,
deceitful and totally selfish.
Oh.
So it was a compliment.
Everything from me to you is a compliment,
no matter what it sounds like.
- That's a mean game.
- Come here and I'll show you a mean game.
- Has Rose ever talked to a psychologist?
- Like your son, maybe?
The psychology of hair?
Jesus!
No, I'm just...
I'm wondering.
- Is she still in school?
- I took her out when she was 11.
How could you not
send her to school?
Don't believe in factory farming.
I teach her here.
Well, Rose is the
way you made her.
What are you getting at,
Kathleen?
Well, you raised her,
so she couldn't love anybody else.
She's not used to having
anybody around.
We come along and she
gets a little upset.
What are you going to do when
it's time for her to get a job?
Listen, there are wonderful schools for
children with problems. My cousin Vera...
Shut your bloody mouth!
Did you hear that?
There's nothing wrong with Rose.
- If you don't think things will work
out here, fine. - I don't. I...
Jack, I didn't mean it that way.
I'm just...
Look, it's not, you know,
that easy for me.
I mean, I just, you know, I...
I'm sorry, OK? I'm not judging you.
It's just like, you know, we see
each other... I'm not, you know.
We see each other for four months,
you don't tell her about me
and I'm supposed to move in here.
I don't...
- What?
- I don't... I don't understand.
Understanding, whatever the hell that means,
doesn't make a blind bit of difference.
Look, believe me, Kathleen,
I've...
...I've made a mess of a lot
of things in my life.
I don't have time
to pay for them.
So I'm just trying to live
a different way now.
- I'm sorry.
That's what I need you for.
Are you equal to it or not?
- Yeah.
- Good.
OK.
I'm going to take really
good care of you. OK?
I believe it.
Careful.
I'm a sick man.
Good morning, Rose.
- How are you feeling today?
- Fine.
Breakfast in a minute, Rodney.
Don't look so droopy.
Thaddius!
Morning, Rodney.
Interesting job
on Rose last night.
- Thank you.
- I think it looks great, honey.
I didn't mean for it
to be so explosive.
You sure scared
us last night, Rose.
You know, you shouldn't walk around
with guns, even when you're kidding.
- I wasn't kidding.
- Excuse me?
What are you wearing?
Huh?
Well, that's half the
day's electricity gone!
Oh, no food again.
Thank God!
You've already lost 16lb, honey.
Let's just keep it up.
- Thaddius! Breakfast.
- Hey...
Now!
I love my life.
Excuse me.
- What are you doing today?
- I don't know.
Maybe I'll go find a job mowing
some other rich people's lawns.
Are there any other people
on this island, or what?
Soon you won't be able to take
a piss without 15 people clapping.
May I be excused?
Turn the light on, at least. You'll ruin
your eyes always reading in the dark.
You know, Thaddius used
to work in a garage.
I was just thinking, you know,
it's amazing your skin stayed so clear
after working in that grime for so long.
- Pancake, Rose?
- Sure.
- What are you on about?
- He's gorgeous.
He probably already has a date
lined up for tonight. Right, Thaddius?
He has been known to date farm
animals under extreme duress.
Rodney, are you ever going to take
that jacket off so I can wash it?
- Yeah, Linus, maybe you'd
get a date too. - Hey...
Can I come with you
to look for your job?
You're not going anywhere.
You've got work to do.
And you can start by
putting some clothes on.
I see that I'm on toilet duty again today.
- It's a rotating schedule.
- Mm.
- Another man, another programme.
- Would you please shut your mouth?
If this one ever gives you anything,
I'd like a commission.
Well, what do you know?
You're interested in make-up.
Oh, don't worry about it.
Let me help you.
Do you want to sit down?
You're such a pretty girl,
you should learn how to use it.
I was only a couple of
years older than you...
...when I had Rodney.
It's hard to believe.
You seem like a little girl.
Do you want to
be my dad's wife?
Er...
Well, one step at a time.
With your dad's heart as weak as it is,
I'm just trying to keep him alive.
It would help if he ate
a little meat occasionally.
This... you need to learn
to do without a mirror.
Mm.
Do you ever want to
have kids some day?
Do you want to work?
Have a career?
Do you ever want
to leave the island?
- Aah! - Why do you
always wear that jacket?
- Just scrub your tub, Miss Muffet. - You
know what? It's too hot, so take it off.
- You're all sweaty. I'm going to
get that off you! - Help, help!
No! That's not funny!
You're a sadist.
- You're a sadist! Stop it!
- Jesse?
Jesse!
Come here, boy!
Hey!
What happened to you?
Mom's got me
cleaning the latrines.
- Who's Mom?
- Ask Jack.
- You've brought everything?
- Yep.
That's great.
Thanks.
Hi.
- Hi.
- I'm Kathleen.
- I deliver flowers for Rose
every now and then. - Oh.
- Well, you must have a name.
- Gray.
That's a nice name.
Rose certainly is a passionate gardener.
Er, yes, she's... got the touch.
Yeah. It's probably
good for her, too.
All right. Well, go on with your day.
It's nice to meet you.
If you want any lemonade,
I've got some in the kitchen.
OK.
Hi.
I didn't see you there.
- Could you do me a favour?
- Sure, what?
Could you teach me how to kiss?
- What?
- Please.
What happened to you?
You used to be so shy.
I just have to.
You don't want to
do that with me.
Why?
Well, because your first kiss
is supposed to be romantic...
...and, like, an accident.
It's not like learning to swim.
Well, can't we be romantic?
I just... I don't think
of you that way.
Bye.
Jesse!
Come here, boy!
I hope you don't think I'll
be frying that up for supper!
We're not really in
much of a rush.
It's OK.
- Have you ever thought of suicide?
- Yeah.
But I'd like to do it myself,
if you don't mind.
I'm going to,
when my dad dies.
Is that a definite plan?
Yeah.
- Rodney!
- Oh, she's with child.
What's up?
Ooh, watch the baby!
This is... my friend Rose.
Rose, Red Berry.
Hello.
It's nice to meet you.
- Shall we?
- Shall we, indeed.
So I'm totally excited
about seeing this commune.
- How's the baby? - Heavy.
It's going to be a big boy, just like you.
- Hey, Gray.
- Picked up your mail on the way in.
- That old Ferenzie working you pretty hard?
- Oh, not too bad.
When is he going to
make you manager?
Er... I don't know.
Maybe this summer.
You must have been working there, what?
Five years?
Seven.
That's too long to work by the hour.
He's exploiting you.
You know more about his
business than he does.
Well, he... owns the place.
Thanks for the cheque.
Could have used you here
when it was up and running.
Let me know when you're ready
to build something of your own.
We'll talk about a loan.
Thanks, Jack, but...
I... I wouldn't be able to do that.
If you don't like your situation, change it.
If you can't change it, leave it.
It's your fucking life, man!
I appreciate it.
So see you on Saturday.
Saturday, was it?
- Yeah, thanks.
- All right. Thanks, Gray.
- On.
- Yeah.
Oh, my God!
- This is awesome! What is this place?
- It used to be an acid pad.
Aha! I bet you guys
do a lot of drugs.
Hey, Rose, I wanna show you something, OK?
Just stand back for a second.
All right, are you ready?
Oh, you had the baby.
Fantastic.
Hey, Rose, do you think
I could see your palm?
Wow! There is, like, hardly
any lines in your hand.
Oh, well. I guess some people just
make themselves up as they go.
I made up my name
when I ran away.
- You did?
- Yeah, it just came to me. I was, like...
I was standing outside of my mom's
house and it was snowing
and I just saw this little bush
with these hard,
shiny red berries on it
just growing out of the snow,
you know?
Next time someone asked me what
my name was, I just sort of said
- "Red Berry" and it just kind of stuck.
- Why did you run away?
The important thing is,
you have to forgive everybody.
I forgave everybody after I left,
even my mom and my brother.
Oh, my goodness!
That's perfect.
We have a genuine and authentic, I'm sure,
wedding-and-engagement-ring set.
And I think you
shall have them.
Thank you.
Red Berry, you don't seem
the marrying type. Sorry.
What? I'm definitely
going to get married...
...to a big, fat man
with a tiny wiener
I can barely find.
- Not you, Rodney.
- Oh, thank God.
He has to be really old,
though, you know?
So do you think that Kathleen
is going to marry your dad?
- She wants to.
- Yeah.
Yeah, Mom is a sucker
for a sick man.
My father was a diabetic.
What was Thaddius's father like?
He's er...
He was just an idiot.
I got a bee sting.
Hey, Rosie.
I didn't squash him.
I was just out by the compost.
Rodney,
come here for a second.
Let's have a look.
Hold still.
The only person you're
hurting is yourself.
I have a feeling I'll be living off
guilt-burgers for a couple of weeks.
- They're quite thinning. - All I want is
to help you get down to a normal size.
Ow! Shit!
Easy.
Bloody fuss.
Why am I always the monster? Huh?
Will you please tell me that?
- It's a question only you can answer.
- Oh, OK!
I give up.
Just eat, eat.
Be disgusting.
I'm signing off!
What was that?
Which God are you praying to?
- Where have you been?
- Up in the dome.
What were you hiding
in there for?
Nothing.
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
That was quite a fit
that Kathleen had today.
Sort of... surprising aspect
to her personality.
OK.
Are you sure you're all right?
You're acting a wee bit strangely.
Tired.
Who's the lucky guy?
Well, sleep well.
If there's something bothering you,
we can just, you know, talk about it.
OK.
I'll be back, OK?
Ow.
Go ahead.
- Ow...
- Shh!
Thanks.
I'm just hoping that's
your idea of a joke.
New chapter.
What's that?
You've been ruined by
that fucking scumbag!
- Jack! Jack!
- What?
Oh, my God!
I'll deal with this later on.
Oh, God!
Jack!
- What?
- Oh, my God!
I just saw a copperhead.
It went behind that
dresser and disappeared.
Probably wasn't a copperhead.
Don't get hysterical.
I know a fucking copperhead
when I see one!
- Oh, shit. Oh, God!
- Right, everybody out of the room.
Did I invite you to stay?
Oh, God...
Who were you planning on killing?
I just wanted to scare her.
Fuck...
What are you hanging around
the door for, faggot?
- Hi!
- Hi.
- I'm Marty Rance.
- Oh, hi. I'm Kathleen.
- I'm looking for Jack Slavin.
- Oh, he's in the house.
There's a snake in there.
Copperhead.
That's why I'm...
Er...
Well, thanks.
Hello.
I'm Marty Rance.
I'm developing that land over
on the other side of the field.
I'm just... making the rounds with
the neighbours, trying to get acquainted.
Looking for Jack Slavin.
- I'm Jack Slavin.
- Jack Slavin?
Marty Rance.
Great timing, Marty.
How's your day so far?
Oh, I'm just spending
the afternoon
kinda making the acquaintance,
you know, just saying hi.
- I know that. You just said that.
- So, I did.
How are thing going
down at the site?
You know how it is when you try
to build something. You get setbacks.
Trespassers, vandalism...
It's hard to keep things tidy.
I agree with you on that one.
Trespassing and vandalism,
- I can't abide by. Never could.
- It's nice to hear you say that.
The reason you can't build
on a wetland, see, Marty,
is that all that shite that goes
into your sewer system over there
will end up running into
the island's water supply.
The grounds too soft, quite apart
from the wildlife that you're poisoning.
That may not be a
wetland any more.
How did you work that out?
I'm making an appeal.
We have excellent sewers.
- I'm sure you do.
- Yeah. Er...
You're bribing someone on
the Corps of Engineers, is that it?
I know you've got the Housing Board
in your pocket already.
You know, I really came here
to try and make peace,
to forget about anything either one of
us might have done to upset the other,
but by the same token, one of my men
gave a pretty accurate description
of a person who shot up our
work site a little while ago.
- Yeah, that was me.
- Mm! Mm-hm.
If you don't tell on me, I don't
tell on you. Is that how it works?
Here's the thing. You're slinging
up houses on a wetland, right?
I just want you to...
take down one of them.
Pick a house.
I'll leave it up to you.
- Of course, that's out of the question.
- See you, Marty,
if you don't destroy
one of those houses,
I'm going to have to kill you.
I hope you're kidding,
for your sake.
You know, I tell you,
from top to toe,
I couldn't make any improvements.
You're perfect.
You too, my friend.
I stuffed down most of the holes
in the house, so we should be all right.
I'd prefer it if you didn't smoke
near the house, please.
- Since when? - Since I fucking told you,
you little rodent.
- You're the boss.
- That's right. I am the boss,
and you're moving out.
I don't want you sleeping
in my house any more.
You've got one more night...
for your mother's sake.
If it weren't for her,
you'd be out on your arse tonight.
I got you back.
- Got me back for what?
- For Kathleen.
Now we're even.
That's insane.
You think I'm crazy too, now?
We're tripping!
- Who is?
- Thaddius and I. Isn't that perfect?
You all came.
I was hoping.
OK, let's learn a little
American history.
This is a genuine imitation acid
pad that was built in 1971.
- This is so cool!
- It was built as a meeting house.
Right.
Sorry.
See, there was an
idea that all this stuff,
all these images and sounds
you'll be hearing, with a little luck,
would break down the psyche
of the people that were tripping.
A person could smash past themselves and
become part of the other people in the room.
Am I getting this right, Jack?
I'm just here as an observer.
See, acid was just
a tiny part of it.
Jack wanted this commune
to be a pure place...
full of people who
re-invented themselves,
hardworking people who
weren't greedy or petty or selfish,
people who could actually share
property because they weren't
enslaved by the patterns they
inherited from their moms and dads.
It was going to
be total freedom.
Total freedom.
See, Jack forgot how to believe
in communal life a long time ago.
How the hell would you know
what I believed in, sweetheart?
But anyway,
seeing as we have guests,
I thought we'd have a little...
educational/nostalgic
experience.
Give up, boy!
You want to kiss me?
You rich fuck!
You think you can buy yourself an
instant family? Well, you can't buy me!
Oh, my God!
Shit!
What happened?
Call an ambulance!
Thaddius?
Baby?
Thaddius...
What happened?
Rose...
Rose planted...
Rose planted the snake to kill you.
You crazy little bitch!
Get out of here!
Jack!
I was bad.
I'm sorry.
You're not bad.
You're innocent.
Innocent people are just er...
dangerous, I guess.
I don't think I've even
really met one before.
You have to get out of here.
OK? I'm going to stay with Red Berry.
Please come with us.
I just can't leave him.
Well, if I'm not going
to see you again, erm...
...you might as well know
that you're pretty spectacular.
Are you getting on or not?
Here we go.
Make secure, guys.
Was that you who put
the snake in the house?
Look, I'm about that far away
from my next heart attack,
so, I mean, what the
hell's going on with you?
Have you nothing to
say about all of this?
Your problem is,
you're scared.
If you had any courage,
we wouldn't be in this mess.
- Who gives a shit what other people think?
- What are you talking about?
You know what
I'm talking about.
No.
Don't go off like this,
for Christ's sake, Rosie!
Rosie!
Rose!
Somebody broke your wings
Little bird you can't fly
Somebody hurt you bad
Feeling down
And the price
you have to pay
You'll be paying,
years of your life
Yeah?
Both legs and one
arm are broken.
Oh, Christ.
He has to stay in hospital
for a couple of days.
What are you going to do?
I guess I'll have to go back
and forth for a while.
My sister will stay with him when
I'm not here. I'll be home tomorrow.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
OK.
Bye.
And the price
you have to pay
You'll be paying
Years of your life
- Shouldn't you be in bed?
- What for?
Well, sit down.
Breakfast is ready.
I'm taking good
care of my guy.
She's got to come back
on her own, Jack.
She will.
I know kids.
Could you get
an ashtray, please?
Sure.
You just need to let her cool
off for a while, you know?
Somebody gotta help you
I believe I love you so
Somebody's gonna
touch you
I don't believe
I'll let you go
Rosie, open the door!
I'm sorry.
You were right.
I was scared.
We should never
have let the world in.
I wish it could just be us,
like it was before.
The happiest man in
the whole wide world.
I was the happiest man, Rosie.
I was.
I can't go back.
I can't see her again.
- Where are you going? - I'm going
to go try and make a transaction.
Can you move out for that?
What about fifteen?
Twenty.
Tomorrow night, OK?
Thank you.
She's leaving by
tomorrow night.
Really?
We'll have to stay in this
godforsaken place for tonight.
- Take off your shoes.
- You've got to be kidding me.
Off.
Yeah.
- Lie down.
- I don't want to lie down in here.
This place gives
me the creeps.
I like it.
It's going to be fun.
Remember how we
used to camp out?
Yeah, but...
...not in housing developments.
What are you
feeding me here?
Beans.
I want you to
promise me something.
That thing that you
said a while back,
that when I die,
you were going to die,
I want you to
take that back.
Take it back.
I promise I'll try.
Little flower.
I'm so happy.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, forgive me.
No, no...
Oh, God...
Oh, my God...
We've got a whole day to kill.
We may as well go to the mainland.
Why do people want
everything to be so ugly?
I was thinking of paying Marty Rance
a visit. You can ask him yourself.
Got it.
That's it.
Hello.
Where did you say
that you lived?
We're on the south side
of Marsh island, by the tip.
- I didn't think that was developed yet.
- There's an old commune out there.
We live on that.
Oh, yes.
- Jack Slavin. Of course.
- Jack Slavin!
- Marty, man!
- This is a surprise.
I'm making the rounds,
getting to know my neighbours.
I'm glad you came by.
This is Rose.
- Rose.
- Would you like some coffee?
Er...
I'll take some coffee, sure.
- Rose?
- No, thanks.
Well, nice!
How's that appeal coming?
As a matter of fact,
I was going to give you a call.
That isn't a wetland any more.
As a matter of fact, that isn't
a house any more. Mind if I er...
- What do you mean?
- Go see for yourself.
I'm just going to build it again,
you know.
If you build it again,
I'll have to knock it down again.
- I don't want to have to call the police.
- Call them. I don't mind.
Listen, Jack...
I realise you and I have
had our differences,
but by the same token,
you can't stop progress.
You can't stop the
future from happening.
People have a right to build.
Laws change all the time
pertaining to the environment,
as the community's
needs change.
I believe in putting people first.
That's just my personal belief.
But I want you to feel
comfortable with the situation,
so you need to tell me
how that can happen.
What the hell do you mean,
"comfortable"?
Well, it occurs to me that
I haven't ever expressed...
my interest in
your land to you.
There you are.
You didn't have to.
I want you to know that if the day
comes where you want to move on...
to, say, a less-developed
part of the world...
We all have our dreams
of how we want to retire.
Anyhow, if that day
ever comes, call me.
I think you'd be surprised at how
much your place is worth now.
When did you purchase
the property?
1967.
Oh, you're looking...
I'd guesstimate
you're looking at...
a 200% profit on
your investment,
and that's conservative.
- Is that so?
- Think about it.
You know,
I have to say, er...
...with our history, Jack,
I would never
have dreamed...
that you'd end up at
my breakfast table.
Why?
Mm?
We're not so... We're not so very different
from each other, you and me.
Well, I gotta hear this.
Well, we both do whatever
the fuck we want. Right?
And we... We both turn a blind
eye to the consequences, us.
That's the way
of the future, right?
I'm a businessman.
I'm not... I'm not a...
I know what you are.
I'm just seeing it now for
the first time, right now.
This minute, I'm seeing it.
You have a vision, too.
Right?
My land is like a blot...
...on your perfect universe.
When you see all these...
these box houses,
these imitation colonial homes,
you get... you get
a feeling of what?
Of everything being in its place,
of accomplishment.
Right, well,
when I see them...
When I see them, I want to punch a hole
through the walls and set fire to them.
So...
...the main difference between
you and me, really, is that...
is that you, you...
love those little houses,
and I hate those
little houses and...
...it all boils down to...
to taste.
And I ruined her out of
some kind of snobbery.
- Ruined whom?
- Dad, let's go home.
It was about something different.
I...
I know it was, but I can't remember,
God forgive me.
- I can't remember.
- I remember.
Do you need a doctor?
Does he need a doctor?
Oh, God...
All right, Marty, you win.
I'll sell.
- It's my land still. I want to sell it.
- Great, but... just think about it.
- I'll come by tomorrow. - I don't need to.
I just want to get rid of it.
- No! - We'll talk about it in
the morning. I'll come by...
No!
Write me out a fucking check,
you imbecile.
- Let me drive you. Let me help you.
- Please, don't. Don't.
Turns out Marty's
a decent guy.
Didn't want to take
advantage of me.
What are you doing?
You know what I'm doing.
You'll be free of this whole...
thing.
Get an education,
you know, try and...
You've got to make
a life for yourself.
I have a life!
I mean, you can't just
give up like this.
Sweetheart, I gave up a long time ago.
I just didn't realise it.
I mean, how can he tell you,
"You can't stop the future from happening"?
- Who made him the future?
- It's not his fault. It's just...
That's...
That's the way things are. He's...
Everything's for sale.
Everything.
Please don't sell it.
Please don't give up.
Your daddy he's an outlaw
And a wanderer by trade
He'll teach you how
to pick and choose
And how to throw the blade
He oversees his kingdom
So no stranger does intrude
His voice it trembles
as he calls out
For another plate of food
One more cup of
coffee for the road
coffee 'fore I go
To the valley below
I'm chilly.
Thanks.
I... I think I'll just
go up for a while.
I'll be up in a minute, OK?
Thanks, sweetheart.
That's better.
We've got work to do.
Forgive me.
Go to sleep.
Dad?
Looking back,
O beloved
I remember things,
you said to me
In the garden
Before the black sun rose
Things you said
To... me
Things you said,
O beloved
And the promise that,
you took from me
Now I see you
Standing next to me
Standing next
To
Me
Saying;
"Promise
Me"
Looking back,
O beloved
I remember things,
you said to me
In the garden
Before the black sun rose
Standing next
To
Me
Saying;
"Promise
Me"
Saying;
"Promise
Me"
Subtitle:
sync, fix: titler