Battle in Heaven
Shit! How did it happen?
Okay, goodbye.
l'll be right there.
Yeah, bye.
Okay, goodbye.
So the baby didn't even cry?
Just a little scream.
What a fuck-up.
Yeah, too bad about the money.
l'm not talking about that.
You're right. Poor Viky.
Poor Viky? The baby died, not its mother.
Understand?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. You and your '' yeahs.''
Ma'am?
Ma'am!
-What's for sale?
-Everything there.
How much are the clocks?
Depends which one.
How many hands do they have?
Four.
Are these ''made in Taiwan''?
They were shipped from Paris.
ls the jelly free?
No, you have to pay for it.
How much is it?
Depends, there are water ones
and milk ones.
What flavours?
Strawberry, eggnog, toffee, coconut,
anise seed, lemon, cherry...
Hurry up, you brat, l'm late!
l'm going to the airport to pick up
the General's daughter.
l'll see you tonight.
What's in the cakes?
One moment, please.
As usual.
Sorry, what is it you wanted?
-What's in the cakes?
-Sugus.
-How much are they?
-40 pesos.
l'll have one.
Here's 50.
Here's your change.
-Thank you.
Your jacket, mister!
ls he drunk or what?
Excuse me, please.
Stop it, you pervert!
What are you looking at?
Thank you.
Hello, Marcos.
Hello?
They sent you to Cancun?
What a pain in the ass.
The thing is, l wanted to see you so bad,
so l came back early.
To see you.
Fine.
What are you talking about?
Well, if you interrogate me,
l might become suspicious.
Well, we'll see.
l'll stay at your place for the weekend, okay?
l'll call my parents and tell them
l'm not coming until Sunday.
You won't be back before noon?
ln that case, l'm going to work tonight.
And in the morning,
l'll come sleep at your place.
Wake me up when you arrive.
Yes, l really want to see you.
That sounds good.
Of course, Jaime.
l won't hang up, darling, but don't be long.
Remember, Marcos?
Of course, Ana. That was for many years.
How could l forget?
Yeah, but wasn't it much better
when l was there?
-Yes, Ana--
-You're back, love?
lt's just that we went past my old school,
and l asked Marcos
if he remembered driving me there.
What a pain.
l hope you will.
Really?
Let's see how you talk in bed, then.
Yeah?
See you tomorrow.
Listen...
l love you.
Let's go to the boutique instead, Marcos.
l'll turn at the corner, Ana.
Jaime's ice skates are fixed, Ana.
Did they do a good job?
Great, Ana, l took them to a digital engineer.
Here they are.
Razor-sharp.
Pardon?
Nothing, just turn the music on, Marcos.
Wake up, you fucking piece of shit.
And go fuck your mother, you faggot!
Get moving, damn it!
Now turn off the music, Marcos.
Are you all right, Marcos?
lt's just my mother. Her body's very swollen.
ls that all?
Yes, Ana.
Well, l've never seen you so absent-minded.
No, Ana.
Well, at the boutique, you're coming in
so l can set you up with one of my friends.
Can we do it another day, Ana?
Don't tell me you're faithful to your wife.
Yes, Ana.
But sometimes l go out with other women.
You've always wanted
to see the boutique, right?
Yeah, whatever you say, Ana.
Lie down.
Ana!
The fatso can't get it up.
He says he only wants it with you.
What are you doing, Marcos?
l was just taking the condom off.
You've worked for my dad for 15 years.
You've known me since l was a child.
You're the only one who knows
about this place.
And l finally invite you here,
and you go telling my friends
you want to screw me?
What's up with that?
All l said was that
you told me to come here, Ana.
You think l didn't notice
how you stared at me at the airport?
What's wrong?
Tell me.
The thing is, my wife and l kidnapped
a baby, and he died this morning.
lt was an accident.
Why are you telling me this, Marcos?
You asked me.
You shouldn't talk about things like that.
Take my bags to Jaime's.
The maid will open the door for you.
Take the car with you as well.
See you on Monday.
Now leave, Marcos.
Just don't tell anyone.
MEXlCO ClTY
Welcome to Cuajimalpa
Fill it up?
Pardon? Yes.
Mexico loves you
We are never sad
Because the heart is inflamed
Upon mentioning your name
The world knows that
Your name is our lullaby
You are our pride
Mexico is yours
And you hold the key
Long live the Queen of the Mexicans
Who planted beautiful roses
With her own hands
What do you think?
They're all sheep.
How many are there?
The pilgrims have been coming
for three days and nights.
But l was talking about the car...
and the engine is fine.
We're almost there.
Careful, careful.
What's this music, son?
Don't worry, Grandma.
Mister!
Put in 200 pesos, please!
And change that music now!
lrving, lrving.
Wake up, your dad's here.
lrving.
Sorry about this morning.
We've got to talk.
Did you lose your glasses, love?
They were all scratched anyway.
l've got your old pair here.
l told Ana.
Your boss's daughter?
Are you fucking crazy or what?
l feel better.
You're not well, are you, love?
l understand.
Now you'll have to make sure
she keeps her mouth shut.
We can't have the princess talking.
You better leave her out of this.
You fucked up, you idiot!
That fucking Viky came crying to me today.
She said she's had no news
from the kidnappers for three days.
l'm afraid that if we don't call her tonight,
she'll go to the police.
lf her husband were still alive,
he'd have broken both our necks.
Should we go to Sunday's pilgrimage?
Where do you get
these fucking stupid ideas?
After all the shit we've done,
don't you get it?
He's not big enough to come by himself?
Why don't you ask him?
Stop it, Dad!
Your pet is waiting for you.
l brought your car, Ana.
Go prove you're a man, Son.
-Bye, handsome.
-Thank you.
-Wait for me outside.
-Yes, Ana.
Fuck off, you faggots!
l gave her some back door action!
Tona, Juanita, come get our stuff
from the trunk.
What's ''back door action''?
Back door action?
You'll learn soon enough, my dear.
Watch out!
Good morning, Juanito.
-How are you, Tonita?
-Good, good.
-Hello, Tonita.
-Hello.
Get inside, lnes.
What time is this to come home?
-l'll tell your parents.
-Come on, Tonita.
Good morning, fatso.
What do you want, Marcos?
l told you l'd see you Monday, Marcos.
l wanted to tell you something, Ana.
Good morning.
He likes to listen to the birds.
What you really want is to fuck me,
right, Marcos?
No, Ana.
Where's the car?
Up the road.
We just came that way.
You didn't ask me before.
Calm down, Marcos!
You'll have to turn yourself in, Marcos.
You have to go now, Marcos.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Twenty seconds from now,
the Pumas will once again
be crowned champions of Mexico.
This is one of the most prestigious squads
in the country,
and it has been an endless source of talent.
An institution that loves football
more than anything
and is allergic to showboating.
There's no room for ball hogs on the Pumas.
The Pumas are home
to artists and imagination.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Pumas are champions.
The champions of Mexico.
How our league has changed
since it's moved to just one championship.
Now we have established a general league,
the ridiculous sale of franchises
has stopped,
reason has prevailed
and we've seen the end of speculators
who think this is the NBA.
lt's good for Mexican football
and it's good for Mexico.
And now over to Andre,
on the field with Vignatti.
Here is the great Argentine keeper, Vignatti.
Finally a champion with the Pumas.
How do you feel?
As they would say
in your country, ''super cool''.
This is really an exciting moment
in my career.
This is a fantasy.
This is the best thing
that has happened to Vignatti in 10 years.
l want to thank my family,
who convinced me to come to Mexico.
This is a huge league,
the Pumas are a major team.
Now we'll go and celebrate
with our families in Argentina,
with our wives and friends...
This is a fantasy.
The best thing
that ever happened to Vignatti.
The best thing.
Dad! Dad!
Hurry up. We're going to the countryside!
Marcos, my love, don't make the family wait.
What are you doing, Dad?
Stop crying, Viky.
You'll see your baby very soon.
And everything will be fine. Just calm down.
Tomorrow's the pilgrimage.
Tomorrow l'm turning myself in
to the police.
Forgive me.
We'll be separated,
but you'll always be in my heart.
l couldn't live without you.
Please wait one more day.
Wait for the pilgrimage.
l feel something's going to happen there.
Something's going to change.
What's one more day, for God's sake?
Okay. Now promise.
Swear on our love.
Thanks, love.
Are you raising the flag tomorrow?
Yeah, l have to go twice.
Well, after you've raised it at dawn,
come pick me up at home
so we can go together on the pilgrimage.
Then at sunset l'll go with you
to bring the flag down.
l haven't seen you in action for a long time.
Okay.
The changing light is making my eyes itch.
Children, stop playing around!
You're going to get dirty.
Who do you think does the washing?
Give it to your mother,
or l'll give you a smack.
l'm looking for a stick now. You'll be sorry.
Come here. Do you hear me?
Come over here, children! l can't see you!
lt's dangerous to play like that!
Didn't you hear your mother?
Marcos, get in the car!
Good job, Marcos. See you tomorrow.
-Yes, General.
-Thank you, lads.
Have a good morning.
-Hi, Marcos.
-Good morning, Jaime.
You've come to see Ana?
-Just for a minute.
-Come in.
Thank you.
Did you wake up on top or underneath
this morning?
On top.
Come into the living room. Don't be stupid!
l'll let Ana know.
Hello, Marcos.
Jaime is going to buy the newspaper.
Yes, Marcos.
l'll be right back.
l'm turning myself in to the police now, Ana.
Sit down then.
You won't mind us being separated, Ana?
No, Marcos.
l'll keep you in my heart.
Goodbye.
You forgot your jacket, Marcos.
Take care, Marcos.
Yes.
What do you mean, ''naked''?
Yes, thank you for letting me know.
Goodbye.
The suspect's mobile phone
was found, lnspector.
He was seen in Polanco five minutes ago
and he was headed to the Basilica.
Some pilgrims found him
and sent him by bus because
they thought he was mentally handicapped.
Ma'am, you're coming with us.
We're going to find that son of a bitch.
And your child stays here
with the lieutenant.
Station calling Blue Wolf.
We have some information from the house.
The kidnapper's son
just led us to a baby's body.
Ask for backup, damn it.
Jesus will help you change!
This is the way of the light! Save yourself!
l have the key to salvation!
Forever and ever!
They renounced sex.
Think of the women who left prostitution.
There you are again, brother!
We will help you resist the temptation
that you have been lost in all these years.
God loves you. God protects you.
God loves you.
Take this. Save yourself, brother! Hallelujah!
You are saved! You are saved!
Yes, brothers! This is the proof!
The only proof!
You have your medicine now! Go forward!
No more drugs! No more alcohol!
No more women! No more tits!
No more tits!
We're here, lnspector.
lnspector, how are you doing?
l must inform you, lnspector...
lnspector, l must inform you
that the girl who was stabbed has just died.
lt's disgusting, Chief.
Attention, headquarters.
Yes, Officer. We have information.
The suspect has been located
near the Basilica.
Beware, he's likely to be armed.
We bring these gifts for you
Oh, father! This is our song
l've tried to live by your light
We love justice and peace
We know you will come
On your feet
And bring peace to the poor
We know you will come
AM l NOT HERE, l WHO AM YOUR MOTHER?
Please. Let me go in first.
We've been waiting so long.
l love you so, Ana.
l love you too, Marcos.
in memory of Alejandro Ferretis