Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
SLON Studio
Film Studio SOL
supported by the Ministry
of the Culture of Russian Federation
Sabina Eremeeva
presents
a film by Kirill Serebrennikov
BETRAYAL
Here you go.
Please take off your clothes.
- All of them?
- Above your waist.
Have you ever had a
prophylactic examination?
No.
Have you been here before?
What for? I'm OK.
Lay down, please.
Keep still,
the charge is very weak.
- I just don't like to be...
- Touched by a stranger?
Many people don't like that.
Any complaints?
No.
Your heart?
It's OK.
I haven't been feeling
too good lately...
Why?
My husband has been
cheating on me.
I'm sorry to hear that.
He cheats on me with your wife.
I don't get it. Why?
What do you mean?
Why tell me?
Because you came here.
I came for a checkup.
That's how it usually is.
Someone lives a peaceful life,
thinks he's healthy.
Then he comes in for
a routine checkup and...
That's not true.
I'm glad I met you.
Good-bye.
Easy, easy.
Are you OK, man?
I'm OK.
Somebody call 911!
Call 911!
Does it hurt?
Will somebody call 911?
- Yes?
- It's me. I've lost my keys.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I can tell something's wrong.
- Where were you?
- We had a medical checkup.
And?
Have they found something?
What is it?
Nothing.
You scared me.
Are you going to eat?
We're out of white bread.
Is that all right?
A woman in our office is
selling a parcel of land.
The foundations already done.
And it's cheap too.
You want to build a cottage?
You told me yourself it would
be great to have a country house.
Have you changed your mind?
We could go there on weekends
to get some fresh air.
- But you work on weekends.
- Not every weekend.
I know the soil there is good,
I've made inquiries...
I could plant cherry trees,
some raspberry bushes.
My grandmother used
to grow raspberries...
Could you help me for once today?
- I saw an accident today.
- What?
An accident.
A SUV crashed
into a bus stop full of people.
That's terrible.
Have you washed your hands?
I left the bus stop
a minute before it happened.
Really?
Yes, only a minute before.
Now I see why I've had an eerie
premonition all day long...
Can you stop grabbing food?
That's terrible.
Any victims?
Yes.
Three people
have died, I think.
Give me a hand please.
I can't stop thinking
about that crash.
How awful.
Somebody is not going
home tonight.
I need to tell you something.
Promise me
you won't fly off the handle.
Go ahead.
Promise?
He got five F's this term.
He's been flunking school.
He's flunked
about two months.
I've no idea why. He won't tell me.
Maybe you could talk to him?
Stop it! Please don't!
Hush now...
Don't cry.
Daddy loves you.
You shouldn't have.
You didn't even ask him why.
Are you OK?
What is it?
What's the matter?
- Everything's OK.
- I'm not crying.
- What?
- Nothing.
Why aren't you sleeping?
I see.
Good night.
It's stuffy in here.
Open the window.
Wort help.
Please wait outside.
You lied to me.
Why are you doing this?
Please have a look.
It's not her.
OK, it's not her.
You can go now.
I have a busy day today.
Could you give me something
for my heart?
I feel pressure.
It's the weather.
I have a son.
He's started flunking school.
- I lost my temper yesterday and...
- I'm not interested.
Why?
Not interested, and that's all.
I'm too busy.
Do you have kids?
- No.
- No?
Why?
Your husband can't...
Let me guess. He's impotent.
Your wife cheats on you!
She's with him now!
- They... They have switched off
their phones!  - Quiet!
He never used to switch it off!
She's with him now!
They're both naked!
Your heart is fine.
It's the weather.
What do you want from me?
Nothing.
This is where they usually meet.
Their bench.
Last time,
they sat here for two hours.
My husband usually orders tea.
Your wife takes a double espresso.
They share a cheese plate
and a bottle of wine.
She likes strong coffee.
Isn't it bad for the heart?
Womers hearts are stronger.
They are surrounded by fat,
and they beat faster than mers.
Why?
We bear children.
Our hearts have got to be stronger.
You should go home,
you don't look too good.
I don't want to.
They take this room every time.
Seventh floor, nice view.
If the room's taken, they
never rent a different one.
They take a walk instead.
Once, they were downstairs, in the sauna,
then were swimming in the pool.
What are you doing here?
And you?
We're discussing the real estate.
Husband?
How did you find me?
I... Came here to find out
how much the room costs.
A friend asked me to.
- What for?
- What can I get you?
- Green tea, please.
- I'll have juice.
- Coffee, please.
- Double espresso?
He seems to be aware
of how you like your coffee.
Let us finish, OK?
We were in the middle of something.
- Tell me about that property.
- It's quite big, the location is quiet.
Nice neighbors. Faces the forest, some
nice lakes are 5 minutes' walk away.
I'm just interested what
you were doing there.
I've already told you.
Why couldn't your friend
find out for himself?
By the way, who is it?
I can't tell you.
He's having an affair.
With a married woman.
They have no place to meet.
And you are helping him?
They really love each other.
Why can't you tell me his name?
Do I know him?
No, you don't.
Tell me, in all honesty.
Are you seeing someone?
Are you serious?
Yes.
No, I'm not.
Are you?
Am I?
- Sorry, I didn't mean it.
- You really hurt my feelings.
Listen.
I didn't mean it.
I work all day. I look after the kid.
I never blame you for anything.
And this is what I get.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry.
- Have you ever had an affair?
- No. Have you?
No.
Should I turn off the lights?
I'll switch the night light on.
As you wish.
Can I kiss you?
Why ask?
My wife always says that too.
What has it got to do with your wife?
Sorry.
Not like this. Softer.
What?
Did I hurt you?
Turn it off!
I'm sorry.
Are you feeling better?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
Smoke?
No.
Teach me how.
Just inale it. It's easy.
Not too much,
or you'll get sick.
I can't...
Two bodies, heads pointing east
and feet south-west.
Both naked.
Cause of death: Fall.
Suspecting multiple bone breakage.
The man: Caucasian, no
distinguishing marks.
Mars body on top of the womars.
Two idiots were making love
on the balcony.
Two idiots
less in the world, huh?
Put it away.
Take a look and tell us
if you know these people.
You first.
This is my wife.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Your turn.
Yes, it's him.
You barely looked at him.
We cannot include such an answer
in our report. Take a better look.
- Can I do it later?
- Later?
His body tissues
will start changing.
- It's him.
- Him?
We can't record
the body as "him".
My husband.
You can go.
But we'll meet again soon.
Why?
You'll need a burial
permit from me.
Is whiskey OK?
Why not?
Thanks.
- Want more?
- Yes.
Why are you laughing?
Just because.
By the way, what do you do?
Doesn't matter.
Are you cold?
I'm OK.
Let's have more.
A thunderstorm.
Great.
We need to find cover.
Are you scared?
I'm scared for you.
We're not that close.
I have to go.
I've got a son waiting.
- Go.
- Let's go.
- Don't yell!
- Let's go!
Go!
Everyone's scared.
Did you get caught in the rain?
No. You?
I did.
The flowers?
I threw them out. They died.
Not too much salt I hope?
No...
It's great.
Did you cook it?
Yes.
I never told you before,
but I like to cook.
Of course, mom does it better...
Are you OK?
- I don't know how to tell you.
- Tell me what?
It's mom.
Try to understand...
How do I say it...
She's no longer with us.
She died.
In an accident.
She fell from a great height.
I don't get it.
She died.
She's gone.
Where is she?
Why?
No.
There was a balcony.
A piece of it went loose.
She leaned against
the railing and fell.
A balcony? Where?
At a hotel.
What was she doing there?
- Where is she now?
- In the morgue.
You're here?
Come in!
Both of you.
We came for the burial permit.
You think I'll give you one?
Why not?
There's something...
I don't get.
How could...
they fall like this?
By accident.
- By accident?
- Well, yes.
It was an accident.
What were you doing at the hotel?
Sorry, we should have told you at once.
We're lovers.
You, too?
That's interesting.
Why didn't you tell me then?
We thought it didn't matter.
That you are lovers?
Yes.
And that you
were there that night?
It's a coincidence.
You know.
I'm not giving you
the burial permit
until the investigation is over.
Are they going
to stay in the morgue?
They're not the only ones to stay in there.
You think they're somewhat special?
Why did you say we're lovers?
Would the truth be better?
I think it would.
You could have told her, then.
Is your wife beautiful?
Ask your husband.
Sorry, it's the stress.
Are you going to give
him a church funeral?
Do you think it's necessary?
I guess.
A church funeral?
- Why would you need a church funeral?
- Laugh one more time, and I'll hit you.
Thank you.
I feel better now.
I decided I will do without
a church funeral.
I think it won't help them.
Why didn't you come earlier?
I killed them.
Alone?
Yes. She's innocent.
It was me.
I detached the railing
from the wall.
It was loose to start with.
She's innocent.
Write down your statement.
Here's your permit.
Go.
This is for your girlfriend.
She's not my girlfriend.
Doesn't matter.
Can I go?
Kiss me.
I beg your pardon?
On the lips.
Go.
You were so outgoing.
Always nice and cheerful,
generous and giving.
Thank you for the joy
you've given us.
You left us
so young and beautiful,
and that's how we'll
always remember you.
Good-bye.
You have always been an example
of discipline and high moral values.
You always had our
sincere admiration.
We grieve for you deeply,
and will always remember you.
Time to say good-bye.
Here?
What do you want?
I wanted to talk.
About what?
I can't stop thinking of you.
Are you crazy?
I want to go on seeing you.
Please don't call me anymore.
I don't ever want
to hear from you again.
Stay away from me.
I thought you got lost.
The forest here is too thin. I had to
walk quite far away from the road.
Give me the map.
Or you could just follow us.
All right, thanks.
Why are we following them?
They're going in
the same direction.
Is this really necessary?
It's late. We need
to stop for the night.
I am falling asleep...
We could swim in the pool
tomorrow morning...
They have a pool here?
Yeah.
I thought you were sleepy...
Ionized water.
It has a rejuvenating effect.
Please put out the lights
before leaving.
The water's nice.
Ionized. They say it's rejuvenating.
Was that your husband?
Yes.
How long has it been?
No idea.
You look great.
You mean I'm well preserved?
No, I mean you look terrific.
You too.
You never moved?
No.
- How's life?
- Good. For you?
Not bad.
How old is your boy?
Five. Do you have kids?
I can't have children.
Sorry.
Really, you do look amazing.
Thank you.
I think
I'm going to go now.
- Did you sleep well?
- Very well, thanks.
Good morning!
Did you enjoy the pool?
Yes, thanks.
Did you go swimming? When?
This morning. I couldn't sleep.
It's small, and not too clean.
- Did you sleep well?
- Yes, and you?
Very well.
When are you leaving?
Around ten.
Same time as us.
I think we won't get lost now.
Thank you.
Look how well you eat.
Good boy.
- Coffee?
- No, thanks.
Coffee, please.
Two more, please.
It's stuffy in here.
Yes.
Can you describe the pain?
- No.
- You told me you had stabbing pain.
It's different.
Does it hurt more at
any specific time of day?
In the morning, or in the evening?
It used to hurt more after PE at school.
Now, it hurts all the time.
What's that knife for? Tell the
doctor why you always carry a knife.
Why do you carry it?
To protect myself.
All right, get undressed.
I'll listen to your heart.
Am I going to die?
No.
Your condition is often
linked to fear of death.
- I don't want to die.
- Oh, stop it already!
I'm sick of hearing it. All she
ever talks about is death!
- I'm not interested in talking about
anything else! - Really?
Keep still. Sit on the couch.
Could you wait outside, please?
Do you want to talk about death?
Go ahead.
It's intimidating.
What else?
Look,
death is beautiful.
The most beautiful thing that
can ever happen to you.
Really?
Yes.
You have a strong heart.
You will live a very long life.
Can I do sports?
Yes. But don't strain yourself.
Next!
Hello.
I thought you moved.
I did. I'm here for a visit.
Any complaints?
Well... I just don't
feel very good.
Take off your clothes.
I'll listen to your heart.
All of them?
From the waist up.
Too cold?
I can't live without you.
I can't.
OK.
Now, get dressed
and lay on the couch.
Your heartbeat is a little
faster than normal.
No reason to worry, though.
I'm staying at the same place.
Where have you been?
I've sent you a message.
But you didn't say you'd
be home at 2 a.m.
I didn't realize it was so late.
I was worried something had
happened to you.
Like what?
Come on, go to bed.
I'll be there in a minute.
I think she knows.
So what?
She's suffering.
She will get used to it.
It's always like that.
I need to stop, of course...
But I can't. I've been thinking
about you all this time.
Do you think of your
first wife sometimes?
Let's not talk of them.
They're dead.
Yes.
Do they always come together?
Sometimes they do.
Which room again?
769.
Excuse me.
I locked my card inside the room.
- There you go.
- Thanks a lot.
I'm so sweaty.
Do you want to go
swimming once again?
No.
I'm going to the shower.
I'll go.
I can't stay any longer.
Where have you been?
Why are you smoking?
I was at the office.
I was worried.
What could happen to me?
I'll be a minute.
Why aren't you sleeping?
I can't. Sorry.
It's cold here...
Do you want me to get
you something?
No, thank you. Go to bed.
What about you?
I'll join you soon.
You promised me
you'd stop smoking.
I will.
Do you love me?
Yes. Why?
Just asking.
I love you.
Hello!
Excuse me, has the guest
from room 769 checked out already?
Sorry, we can't disclose
this kind of information.
How can we help you?
He's a friend of mine. He's
not answering his phone.
I'm worried something
might have happened to him.
No answer.
Thank you.
Open it.
Nobody here.
Go check there...
I need to talk to you.
Go ahead.
I'd like to ask
if he was murdered.
Yeah.
Someone came in,
forced him
to have a heart attack,
then locked the door
from the inside...
A heart attack?
Yes. A common heart attack.
What they used to call
a "burst heart".
What do you mean?
You don't believe it?
I understand.
People don't like boring deaths.
Boring deaths... Keep it down!
Boring lives...
You'd prefer a murder.
People are strange.
I tried to go in the room, but
there was the sign "Don't disturb".
I couldn't do anything.
Franziska Petri
Dejan Lilic
Albina Dzhanabaeva
Arturs Skrastins
Andrei Shchetinin
Guna Zarina
Director
Kirill Serebrennikov
Scriptwriters: Natalia Nazarova,
Director of Photography
Oleg Lukichev
Set Design
Irina Grazhdankina
Costume
Ulyana Polyanskaya
Sound
Boris Voit
Editing
Sergei Ivanov
Producer
Sabina Eremeeva
Studio SLON, 2012
www.moviesubtitles.org
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/6md27
Help other users to choose the best subtitles