Hey!
Hey! Move it! Come on!
It's a green light!
Let's go!
Come on!
Come on! Move it!
Sir? Open your window, sir.
Okay! Okay!
Wait a minute.
Sir?
I'm blind.
Sir, open the window, please.
Stay calm. Stay where you are
and tell me. What happened?
I'm blind. I'm blind!
It's like something's flooding my eyes.
I didn't do anything!
Right. It's probably nerves.
Should someone call
an ambulance?
Please, just take me to my apartment,
and my wife can help me.
I can take him.
I can drive him home.
Are you sure, sir?
Yes. Of course. We got to
get him off the street.
Okay.
Okay, sir. I'll take
you to the other side.
It's.. It's just a blind guy.
Ooh! Careful, take care of him.
Watch him. He can't see.
He's blind.
- If he's blind, why is he driving?
- I know.
Here. Careful.
Here we go, give me your hand.
Watch your head, please. Easy.
Okay. So, you can hear me, right?
Yeah.
Right. So just say
something if you need it,
and we'll have you
home in no time. Okay?
Any questions?
Why aren't we moving?
- Oh, it's a red light.
- Oh.
There's a movement to it.
Like light particles.
Like light shining through a sea of
white. It feels like I'm swimming in milk.
Really? Well, one good thing is
I've never heard blindness
described as white. It's black, right?
It's the absence of light.
- So that's a good thing.
- I guess.
Yeah, sure it is.
It means it's not real blindness.
Anyway, it's too fast.
Blindness is slow, right?
What you have is some
kind of psychosomatic,
some kind of nervous thing.
Just a second here, is
this where we're going?
Okay, so.. Why don't
you just get out here.
Okay. Walk to the curb.
All right.
- I got it.
- Walk to your left. Right there.
Hey! Hey!
Help!
Don't worry.
- I got you. You okay?
- Oh! Yeah.
This your building? It's nice.
He's blind. Can't see.
Just put your hand on that.. Careful.
Remember stairs, right?
What floor? I got it. I got it.
14th.
So, what are your problems?
- Sorry?
- What are you worried about?
Nothing unusual.
No? Any other symptoms,
like nervous symptoms?
No. My life is pretty
regular these days.
Not a care in the world?
Life of leisure, huh?
I don't know.
Here we go.
Is anyone going to be at home,
or are you going to be alone?
There you go.
Honey, I'm home.
- Thank you for everything..
- Nice place.
Hey. Hey.
Did your wife design it here?
No. Listen, thank you
for everything.
I'm so fine for now.
Okay. Do you want me to stay here
and take care of you
until your wife gets home?
No, no, no, no. I'm fine.
- Sure? It would make me feel better.
- I'm fine. Thank you.
- You sure? You want me to stay?
- I'm sure.
- No, thank you.
- All right.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Oh.. Wonderful!
I liked it so much..
Ouch!
Look at this..
You couldn't have cleaned it
up before you lay down?
Are you even listening?
I'm not your maid.
You're bleeding..
Are you okay?
I'm blind.
Eye doctors, eye doctors..
Do we know any?
Let's just go to the hospital.
No way, they'll keep us
waiting for hours.
We're going to a specialist.
I'd rather die
than stay like this!
Shut up!
You're confusing me..
My apologies..
- Honey?
- What?
So?
So what?
Can you see anything?
Anything at all?
I see nothing.
- Try harder..
- What?
Where are the car keys?
Take your keys.
You can look for mine later.
Taxi!
Are you sure you
looked everywhere?
Sure!
There's nothing
wrong with my eyes.
What kind of a person
steals from a blind man?
He should go blind.
You can come with me now, sir.
The doctor will see you.
Excuse me, but I've been waiting here
for over an hour. I'm with a child.
Sorry. Doctor's orders.
Yeah, but my appointment
was at 6:00. It's now 7:00.
- We'll get to you as soon as we can.
- And it's not..
Miss, Miss, let him go.
He's worse off than we are.
Nothing. Nothing in your lenses
and nothing in the retina.
Somebody just turned out the lights.
No, no, it's more like all
the lights were turned on.
Your eyes look perfect.
You see? I told you.
Except I cannot see anything.
Yes, and if this is true,
then we're going to have
to run some more tests.
Unfortunately we're not going
to be able to do that today.
What do you mean, if it's true?
You think I'm lying?
No, not at all.
But I have to be honest with you,
I've never experienced
anything like this before.
So, is that a prescription?
No, I'm actually writing
directions for the hospital.
I know how to get
to the hospital.
I don't need directions.
They're not for you.
They're for the staff.
So they know what to do
with your husband when he arrives.
Okay.
- So that's it?
- That's it for now.
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay.
We're going to find out what it is.
There's nothing else
we can do right now.
- And I just need a signature right there.
- Okay.
I'm sorry. Not you, him.
- Oh!
- Me?
- Parking stand?
- We don't have a car.
Shit!
Hey, hey, hey! What are
you doing? The road's closed!
What was that?
Fuck!
This is so fucking stupid.
All right, we're gonna do this guy.
Remember this guy, the crab?
Okay.
All right, we're gonna test this eye first.
- Do you prefer this lens or this lens?
- The other one.
- This one?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
All right, put your glasses on.
This is for you.
Show your mom. Good boy.
I'm gonna ask you to take the drops
for at least five days.
And maybe,
should I keep wearing the glasses?
Would you like me to
order you to wear them?
Okay.
I order you to wear your sunglasses,
unless you're bathing or sleeping.
All right, I'll give you a try tomorrow.
I just wanted to get your take
on a bizarre case I saw today. Okay.
So, it appeared to be, kind of, what
we call an amaurosis, which is a..
- Which is a kind of a..
- Oh! Oh, sorry.
- Are you done?
- Sorry.
- Sure, do you want to hear this or no?
- Yeah.
Except with an amaurosis,
everything goes dark,
and with him, everything was white.
Well, how do you know what he saw?
Exactly. I don't know what he saw,
but I guess I have to take
his word for it, don't I?
It could be something neurological
like, something we call agnosia
which is an inability to
recognize familiar objects.
- Agnosia?
- That's right.
It's as if a man sees, I don't know,
a fork, he looks at it, he says,
"What is this thing? I've never seen
anything like this before."
Ta-Da!
Is that related to agnosticism?
In what way?
You know, "Agnosia."
"Agnosticism."
- Etymologically speaking?
- Yeah. Didn't you take Latin?
It's actually Greek, dear.
Well, I bet it has something to do
with ignorance or lack of belief.
- Hmm.
- There's a lot of judgment in that word.
Never mind. Never mind.
You want some more wine?
- No, but are you sure you do?
- Yeah.
- I'm going to bed.
- Okay.
Wait, hold on, hold on.
I..
What was I gonna ask you?
What was I gonna say?
- How are you?
- Something about dinner?
No.
Diseases?
No. That's a nice sweater.
Thanks. I can't help you,
sweetheart, sorry.
- Okay. Good night.
- Good night.
I'm sorry, I'm a little distracted.
I know. I know. I'm sorry.
Could you set the alarm
back for half an hour?
I need to make a couple of calls
in the morning.
Yeah, of course. Good night.
- Good night. Thank you for the tart.
- Mmm-hmm.
- It was tiramisu.
- Yeah, tiramisu.
- Hi.
- Well, well. What's the big secret?
Hmm?
What are you hiding from?
Jerks like you.
That'll be $11 even.
Thank you.
Taxi!
Hi. Hotel Emiliano, please.
Do you have the time?
Yeah, you still have 20 minutes.
- Hi.
The guy said you might be late.
You're pretty.
Nice to meet you.
I can't take my glasses off.
Is that a problem?
Are you serious?
- Doctor's orders.
- Really?
I can call another girl.
Fuck, yeah.
That was wild.
I mean it.
Really weird.
I still see everything white.
- Just ring the bell.
- I've been ringing the bell.
Can I help you?
Ma'am, this man says
he's your husband.
He can't see.
I don't fucking care what he's done.
You can just turn around..
Just open the fucking door!
- Officer, I don't know this man.
- Forget he's a cop, let me in!
All right.
Get out! Fucker!
Thanks a lot!
- Nice and easy..
- Thanks!
Hey! Hey!
Come on, come on. Let's go.
I'll get you some help. Wait here.
I'll get you some help.
Just wait right here.
You don't understand. I can't see!
Jesus.
- Hello? Hello?
- I need security at 18, right away.
- Hi.
We have a disturbance up on 18,
we need somebody up there..
Yeah, I'm up on 18 already.
I'm going to grab your purse.
All right. It's okay. It's okay.
Where's your clothes?
Jesus Christ!
Hey, hey, hey, slow down.
Everything's going to be all right.
Don't push me!
Shut the hell up!
Take your hands off me.
Where's my dress?
I need to call my parents.
You're up before the alarm.
Good morning.
Yeah, I doubt it's going to be
all that good.
What's the matter?
I can't see.
What?
Somehow that patient I saw yesterday
must have infected me.
That's impossible. Let me look. Here.
I don't see anything. Nothing.
Nobody goes blind like that. That's..
Well, there's at least two of us now.
Oh, no! No, go out! Oh, God, no,
you touched! No, it's infectious!
- No, no, no!
- I'm telling you, it's infectious!
He gave it to me! It's contagious!
- It's all right. I'm not gonna get sick.
- Honey, get out!
- I'm not gonna get sick.
- What am I thinking?
Jesus, I spent the night
in bed with you!
It's all right, it's all right!
We'll take care of it. It's all right.
It's all right. Shh. It's okay.
It's all right.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's all right.
What time is it?
- It's almost 8:30.
- Okay, let's call the hospital.
With no visible signs of trauma,
no extenuating symptoms, I'm not
about to barricade the streets.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
All right, I'll see
you soon. No problem.
That's a risk I can take.
All right.
- What seems to be the problem?
- It's a boy, he's blind.
Hey, sport. It's okay, everything is fine.
Don't be nervous.
Somebody, help!
Ministry of Health.
It's a little bit early.
I would suggest that you call
sometime after 9:00.
Yes, 9:00.
Morning, Minister, some
strange calls this morning.
Oh. Thank you.
God! He was here at 6:00, I think.
Or 6:30. Who else was here?
The waiting room was
crowded, I remember.
- Ma'am.
- Excuse me.
I have all the contact numbers here.
Do you want me to..
Ma'am. I'm gonna have to ask you
to close up shop
and come with us, as
quickly as possible.
May I have those files, please?
They're gonna be
here any minute.
I know. That's why
I want you to relax.
I'll take care of everything
when they come. I promise.
Okay, I'll be fine. If I need anything,
I'll have them call you.
- Or I'll call you myself.
- Okay.
They can't keep us apart
for too long, now, can they?
- Are you coming?
- I'm right behind you.
- Don't lock yourself out, now.
- Don't worry. I've got the keys.
- Morning, sir.
- Morning.
Please approach the vehicle.
Do you have a cell phone, sir?
- Yes.
- Put it in the bag, please.
What for?
- Thank you, this way.
- I got it, thank you.
- Thank you.
- Mmm-hmm.
No, no, step down, ma'am.
I'm asking you to step down.
- No, I'm gonna go..
- My orders are only to take the man.
This vehicle is for the infected, okay?
Well, then you'll have to take me,
because I've just gone blind.
I've just gone blind.
Fine, have it your way.
Jesus.
Attention!
Attention! Attention!
The government regrets having been
forced to exercise with all urgency,
what it considers to
be its rightful duty
to protect the population
by all possible means.
We are in a state of crisis.
An epidemic of blindness has
broken out, provisionally known as
the White Sickness. And we are
relying on the public spirit
and cooperation of all citizens
to stem any future contagion.
The decision to temporarily quarantine
all those infected
was not taken without
careful consideration.
Be assured that the isolation
in which you find yourselves
represents, above any
personal considerations,
an act of solidarity with
the rest of the nation.
You'll never believe
where they've brought us.
Let me guess. This guy's voice
is already driving me crazy.
You're lucky you can't see it.
It's a video? Well, that's scary.
Makes you question what kind
of an idiot would play a video
in a quarantine for the blind.
Each ward is equipped with a phone
for communication with the outside.
The phone is for
emergency purposes only.
We've got to get you out of here.
- I'm gonna tell them that you can see.
- No. They'll never believe it.
You'll never get near
enough to tell them.
I want you to go home,
please go home.
Honey, I know you think you have
to say that, but I'm fine!
- It's what I want.
- Really. All right.
- I want it.
- All right.
Anyway, it's too late now.
But we shouldn't tell
anyone that I can see.
You're right.
With that spirit of
cooperation in mind,
we ask that everyone pay attention
to the following simple instructions.
Are you with me?
Number one.
Each patient shall
choose his own bed.
It's a corridor.
Number two. Each ward shall elect
a captain or a ward representative
for communication with
the outside world.
Four? Three?
Row two, number three.
Five.
Doctor, how many wards are there?
Yes, sorry.
There's two other wards on this floor
and then another ward on
the lower floor for people who..
How do you know that?
We explored a little
before you came in.
We chose this ward because
it's closest to the entrance,
- where the food comes in.
- Well, someone's thinking.
That's the asshole who's
responsible for all this.
If I had my fucking eyes, I'd kill him!
- He's responsible for stealing my car.
- What? Are you serious?
Damn, yeah!
If I hadn't been decent
and stopped to help you..
You know, I'm gonna
go to another room,
as far away as possible
from this son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch who can
steal from a blind man!
- Honey, they're fighting.
- They're fighting.
Stop it now! Stop that! Stop this!
- Over here.
- Stop this!
Stop it, you're acting like children!
Stop it, please!
We're obviously all alone here, okay?
We're on our own!
So if you want to
make this place a hell,
you're going about it
in absolutely the right way.
He stole my car!
It doesn't matter!
What are you gonna do with a car?
You can't drive anyway!
- He stole my sight!
- Okay, stop that now!
Look, Doc, whoever the fuck you are.
We're all equal here, right?
There's been no proper election.
So, don't start ordering people around
with that tone of voice.
I am not ordering anybody,
I'm simply asking you to..
I'm simply asking you
to leave this man alone.
- Okay, fine!
- Come on.
Just be aware that I don't respond well
to that voice of authority.
What I do respond to,
in case you're wondering,
is flattery and people sucking up to me.
Everyone, close your eyes, ladies.
I'm gonna take off my clothes now.
And try out this bed here.
Number three.
Are you okay?
If you need anything in the night,
I'm right here.
I gotta go pee.
Doorway. So try to remember the route.
How many doors.
How many steps.
I counted them when I first got here.
And straight.
Stop that!
- Doorway. Right turn. I think.
- Right turn.
Straight.
Another doorway.
Ow!
- Jesus!
- What happened?
Ow! What are you wearing
for shoes, bitch?
- Where's the wound?
- Here?
- Oh, fuck!
- Okay.
Crazy bitch stuck her heel in me.
I tripped, and watch your mouth.
- I gotta go pee.
- Just hold it a little while.
Everyone, stay put.
We'll be right back.
Okay, okay.
I really gotta go pee!
Ow! Jesus! A piece
of skin or something.
I found some dish towels but
I don't know if they're clean.
Okay. Keep pressure on it.
It's too dirty, I think.
It's really bleeding!
It's really pouring out.
What are you wearing?
Give me your shirt.
Quickly.
Thank God we have a real
doctor here. Seriously.
I was only fooling around
what I was saying back there.
- Relax. Relax. Relax now..
- Ow!
- Careful!
- Here, here, let me!
- Let me do it. Let me do it.
Careful with that. It's expensive.
Expensive shirt of mine.
Once, twice, three times.
All right?
- That's fine.
- That's good.
I'm afraid it's gonna be infected.
Doesn't surprise me.
The filth from the street on that shoe.
What time is it?
1:30.
You can't be responsible for everyone.
You need to get some sleep.
Are you afraid to close your eyes?
No. I'm afraid to open them.
Afraid I'll go blind in my sleep.
I'm gonna take a walk.
Opening the gate.
Pull right up to the door.
Closing the gate!
Locking up!
Only the infected
are permitted within these doors.
Once inside, follow the corridor until
you find the wards. All right, let's go.
Four, three, two, one.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Hello?
Hello, can anyone hear us? Door.
- Door.
- Door?
- Hello? Hello?
- Hello?
- Honey, wake up.
- Hello? Hello?
- Hello? Hello? Hello?
- New people.
- How many?
- Not many.
Do you have any beds
available in here?
Yeah. We should.
How many of you are there?
- We don't know.
- Okay.
Maybe you could count off,
one by one, and introduce yourselves.
- I'm Number One, I'm a police officer.
- Okay.
I'm Number Two. I'm a taxi driver.
Number Three.
A pharmacist's assistant.
Four. I'm a hotel maid.
- Five. Financial advisor.
- Okay.
That's my wife!
- Honey?
- It's me.
Honey?
- Where are you?
- Here.
Say something.
Keep talking.
That's great!
Is my mom here?
She'll be here, don't worry. Okay?
Get off.
That's them. I wanna catch them.
Quickly.
It's occupied. Move on.
Okay, everyone, try getting
yourselves settled in.
We'll be right back.
Who was that guy talking?
That guy is our ward
representative. All right?
Please!
Go.
Please! Stop!
- Stop! Stop!
- Stop!
Hey, someone's coming.
Please wait!
Excuse me! Wait!
Halt, turn back!
- Wait? Where is he?
- I'm sorry. You gotta get back.
Excuse me, listen! We have
a man here with an injured leg
and he needs serious
medical attention.
He has an infection, he needs
antibiotics. I'm a doctor.
I can't let you leave.
So please turn back.
Okay. I'm not asking to leave.
I'm simply trying to ask
for some help here.
Get the fuck back!
Another step and I'm gonna shoot.
This is ridiculous. Now.
I have a sick man here.
- This isn't gonna work.
- All right, listen!
I'm gonna count to three
and if you don't turn back,
I'm gonna shoot you!
Can you talk to your superior, please?
- One!
- You gotta be kidding me!
- Two!
- This is insanity!
Will you talk to your supervisors?
This is not going to work!
- Three! I'm gonna fucking shoot you!
- Let's go.
Thank God.
This is ridiculous!
Just forget it.
They're not..
I can't believe this is happening.
- Three.
- Stop.
Each ward is equipped with a phone
for communication with the outside.
The phone is for
emergency purposes only.
Would you like a drink?
Coffee?
Is there any
coffee here?
Is there any extra food
at the end there?
I don't know.
The other table needs one.
I think I have one.
An extra fruit cup.
Does anybody need that?
Anybody has a knife?
Or a fork?
I have a knife.
Do you want to borrow mine?
I'll wait, what about you?
- We can share it.
- No problem.
I'm still curious about
what happened to that girl, though.
What?
There was this girl in 1806,
screaming, naked, except
for these sunglasses.
Naked?
She'd gone blind?
Yeah. She was the
one that infected me.
- Is it good, your food?
- Yeah.
Yes, I'll leave a message, my message
is why is there an emergency number
if there's no one there to answer it?
We have a situation
here in the blind ward.
Apparently you missed that
because we don't have enough food.
Also, there's still my request
from yesterday
for an emergency medical supply kit.
I hope you get this
message before dinner.
- Pull it up!
- Six more coming!
Number Five, security guard at a hotel.
Number six, engineer.
I'm a receptionist
at an ophthalmologist.
I know your voice.
Oh, my God, where are you?
Here. Here.
I'm Seven, I forgot to say Seven.
Are you all right? I've got you, okay.
Left, left, make a left and straight.
Straight. Keep going.
- Do you need a hand?
- No. I got it.
That's it.
First of all, welcome
to the newcomers.
We're Ward One.
There's a few things I want to discuss.
We have a guide line now that
connects all the wards to each other.
It's an innovation made by my wife.
We can thank her for that.
There's another point. The toilets.
They're absolutely disgusting.
I'm going to need a team of people
to go and see what's going on in there.
I like the warm feeling on my face
The smell too.
You used to like it..
Remember that New Year's
when we went to the shrine?
There were so many
people waiting in line.
It was cold.
The ceremonial fire
was near the line.
When we got close to it
our bodies were warmed on one side..
It felt good.
We didn't even know
each other that well..
I don't want to listen.
Why?
I can't pretend.
There's no..
There's no soap.
I guess it's better than nothing.
You hear that?
What?
Hello.
Would you happen to have an
extra bed in your dorm?
I have a radio.
There's not as many stations
as there used to be.
But I guess if you insist,
I can give you an update.
At least we could
save on the batteries.
Please.
In the first 24 hours there
were hundreds of cases,
or so the rumor says.
All the same. No pain.
A sea of white.
The government's response,
as you know, was decisive.
The first of the make-shift quarantines.
But this decommissioned sanitarium
didn't make for ideal public relations.
Let's organize a massive
international medical conference of
ophthalmologists and neurologists.
We don't yet know if this is..
And so, for days and days
the helpless viewing public
was subjected to seminars
and endless roundtables
with specialists from around the world
proclaiming their general ignorance.
That was published in
Infectious Disease International.
How premature it was to talk of cures.
How more research was
needed, and more funding.
A point that was at least once
dramatically illustrated.
I'm blind! Oh, my God,
I've gone blind! Oh, my God!
Help me! Help me! Help me!
Someone please! Please help me!
Somebody!
Shit! Shit!
Shit. No, no, no!
Weeks passed, and with time
and the constant coverage,
the city was bored back to work,
oblivious to the evidence
all around them
that the disease was
immune to bureaucracy.
What about the roads and traffic?
Chaos, as usual. But then reports
came of a bus crash with 23 casualties.
That same day, two planes collided.
No one could really say if the disease
was the cause of the accidents.
But people were terrified.
And either the panic spread
the blindness,
or the blindness spread the panic.
Casualties multiplied,
people decided to stay home.
And the traffic problems were solved.
My fellow citizens,
friends, supporters.
Like so many of you,
I have gone blind.
Maybe we need some music after all.
Leave it there.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I need you to follow my voice.
Come towards my voice, and as
you do, please watch your step.
Hold on to the person in front of you.
Do not push.
To the right!
Number twelve.
Anyone attempting to leave the
premises will be forcibly corrected.
- Hello?
- Stay in line!
Excuse me! Sir.
We have permission
to shoot! I repeat.
Can we have some guidance, please?
Sir?
We have orders to shoot.
Stay in line.
Please?
Stay in line, little man.
Hello? Excuse me, sir? Someone?
- We need some guidance, please.
- Stay in line.
Fuck!
Okay, all right, all right.
Attention.
The shovel you requested
is waiting in the yard.
Choose one person to
come and collect it.
One person!
Where is it?
Straight ahead!
Just come, come this way.
Okay, good. You're fine.
Next one's the ground, that's okay.
Okay, keep coming.
Warmer. Warmer. Keep coming!
Colder. Stop. Okay.
Turn to your right.
Good, now keep going forward. Okay.
Warmer. Warmer, colder!
Stop. Now turn right again.
Yeah. That's it, okay, good!
Very good, now keep going forward.
Go forward! Good, warmer,
colder, colder, colder!
Stop, stop, stop!
Colder! Colder!
Whoa! Did you see that?
Sarge!
Did you see that?
The blind adapt quickly.
Hello, Ward Three?
Today, three of the newcomers
were gunned down by the guards.
So, I think that the best solution
would be that
each ward takes one body, takes turns
with the shovel that we have
and they bury their own
share of the bodies.
Fuck you.
What do you mean "our share"?
They're not ours.
Well, yes, but some of them
would have probably come to this ward.
After they were turned away
from yours, like I was.
Our ward is full.
Same here.
Okay, so then we're all
in the same position, right?
Listen, I don't wanna argue about this.
I just simply wanna have these people
buried, and I think the fair thing to do
is that each ward takes a body,
and then the job is quickly done!
All right?
Good.
Now, there's the matter
of food rationing.
It seems that one of the wards is
taking more than their fair share.
So I'm proposing that we put together
some sort of a committee
with a representative
from each ward and..
Who the fuck are you?
Yeah, who the fuck are you?
Excuse me?
Yeah! Yeah, who do you
think you are, giving all these orders?
I'm the chosen representative
from Ward One,
and I suggest that you people
choose your own representative.
Otherwise, we're gonna be at
each other's throats constantly.
So you wanna talk
to our leader, then?
That's right.
Yeah, yeah. Like in a diplomatic
mission, negotiate? Yeah?
Well, here we have
a monarchy system,
and I hereby declare myself
the King of Ward Three.
- Long live the king!
- Long live the King of Ward Three!
Any objections?
Long live the king!
Get the fuck out of here!
And for my first pronouncement
I declare that
everyone in Ward Three will eat dinner
before we think about
getting or burying any dead.
So, eat, eat, eat. Come on, eat.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
You can't sleep like that. You're filthy.
Give me your clothes.
I'll wash them tomorrow.
Go to sleep.
How are you?
You don't know what it's like.
You gotta see it to believe it.
If you want something done,
you gotta do it yourself.
Okay, okay. Just try to get some sleep.
You're so hot.
I know you can see.
No, I can't.
I don't know why you think that.
- Don't lie to me. You trust me?
- Uh-huh.
You trust me, then why don't
you tell me the truth?
You can't trust a thief, right?
I got a secret, too, you know what?
I'm smart. And when I went blind
it made me think better.
I got a lot to contribute!
Okay.
I'm sorry for being such a burden!
I can't take this!
Come here and lie down.
Get some sleep.
What time is it?
What? What?
What's the matter?
Have you lost your sight?
I forgot to wind my watch.
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Look at me!
Did you hear that?
I'm gonna check it out.
Hey, fuckers!
What the fuck song is that? It sucks.
- You suck.
- Whatever.
Fuck!
Did you get him? Blood!
There's blood, man, step back!
It could be infected, step back!
Sarge is gonna
fucking kill me!
Is this the right way to go?
Yeah.
You know, he told me
he knew I could see.
- Shh!
- He told me that, and I did nothing!
What else could you possibly do?
You did everything you could.
- I think I have to tell them, and then..
- And then what?
- And maybe..
- Become their slave?
- ..I could help. I could help.
- It's bad enough as it is.
I can handle it!
No. I'm not talking about you,
I'm talking about us! Us!
What?
You dressing me, bathing me,
wiping my ass, for Christ sakes!
It's hard enough to think of you as..
As? As what?
As a wife.
Instead of my mother or a nurse!
Well, you'll just have to
get used to it, won't you?
Because I don't have any choice.
Okay, you're right, I'll get used to it.
I guess I just have to get used to it.
Do not tell a soul.
Come on!
Attention! Attention!
The government regrets
having been forced to exercise..
Fuck you!
Hello! Hello. Hello. Hello.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hello. Hello.
Attention! Attention! Attention!
That's the last we're gonna
hear from that asshole.
We are taking over this shit hole now.
I'm the King of Ward Three.
And there's gonna be
a lot of changes around here!
What the fuck is that?
Number one. If you wanna eat,
you'll have to pay for it.
And that's pretty much it, I guess.
Okay, and now for our grand finale,
a little song that comes
from the bottom of my heart.
And it goes something like this.
I just called to say I love you
Yeah, come on.
I just called to say I'm on my..
I'm turning it off.
Hey, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay. Okay.
I just called to
say how much I care
I just called to say I love you
Hey! Stop it!
Don't push. Stop it.
Shut up! Shut up!
Or I'll just keep on shooting straight
till somebody gets hit. Okay?
God, you blind people are stupid.
Screaming and crying like babies.
Makes me ashamed to be one of you.
Listen up!
Ward Three is going to take
charge of the food right now.
- What?
- Like in a store.
And like the real world,
we're gonna guard our store!
So don't even think
of breaking in, okay?
So how do we pay for it?
Excuse me, did I ask
for any questions?
He means explain your rules.
What do you want us to do?
Do you want us to come one at
a time or all together, what?
- What do you want?
- He said shut up!
Okay, okay, okay.
I'll tell you what.
We're gonna pile up the food and we'll
let you know the rules later, okay?
Now go back to your wards and
get your money ready, okay!
You know we don't have any money!
Well, then whatever you got, lady!
Shoot her right now.
One less mouth to feed.
If I had eyes, she'd be
dead already, I tell you.
Now. Jewelry, lady.
For example, watches.
Electronic shit, anything.
Anything you think we might like.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, yes.
How much is it for a meal?
Well, man, it's.. I don't know!
You know? Just get your stuff together
and we'll let you know
what you deserve, okay?
Hey! And by the way,
don't hide anything.
All right? Understood?
Go, go! Oh, lady, lady! Lady!
I'll never forget your voice.
And I won't forget your face.
What the fuck! Fuck.
This is wrong, man.
It's wrong, but what else can we do?
We can stick together, we can
stick together and just tell them no.
We're going to stick together.
I'm not giving my stuff up
because a nigger says I have to.
We don't know what race he is, man.
I can tell, I can tell by
the sound of his voice!
Fuck you.
Who the hell are these people?
This is absolute bullshit!
We don't have to do
whatever the fuck they say!
Just because they
make an announcement!
Forget it! We don't have to back down!
We can stand up to these guys!
You're right!
Absolutely!
We don't have a choice.
We have no choice!
What?
They have a weapon.
They have a gun!
But the point is, they can't shoot us all!
Yeah, exactly!
Yes, but if they kill one of us,
then it's too many!
I'm going to collect the valuables!
No one has to give
if they don't want to.
But don't expect to be fed at
the expense of the rest of us.
- Here.
- I don't have anything.
Don't worry. I'll be like your mom,
okay? I'll pay for us both.
What if you don't have anything?
It's just jewelry, everybody, what
can we do with it in here, anyway?
Each give according to
what they have and all that.
Thank you.
Well, they better come
through with the food.
This is what, plastic?
So much junk.
You know, I thought I told
someone to just tell them
not to even bother putting the plastic in
because it's just a waste of my time.
I'll tell them.
These have some weight.
These are rings.
That's gold.
Two rings, possibly a diamond.
Yeah? That's good.
Oh, no. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Got something here.
We're fine with these people.
Okay, good. That was close.
- It was actually, but it's okay.
- All right.
- All right, one.
- One.
- Two.
- And three.
- Three.
- That's it.
- Three?
We normally get four
when we go by ourselves.
Well, now you get three. You keep
whining, you'll get two! Next!
We're coming!
- Next! All right.
- We're here.
We're from Ward One.
- Ward One.
- Don't handle me!
Okay.
We're not gonna hurt you here.
Want your food?
Watch your manners.
All right, it's here, it's here.
I wonder. Can I touch this?
Is that okay?
Shit. Fell down.
Fuck! Nail polish, nail polish.
Fuck.
We got some good stuff here.
- Yeah?
- Looking pretty good so far.
Yeah? Yeah, we're good.
All right. Take it, take it.
You're blind.
Oh, thank you, professor.
You're using a Braille writer.
You're a normal blind person.
- Yeah.
- No, he's not normal.
He was born blind. That makes
him some kind of superhero
in a world like this.
So you better watch out.
You of all people, born blind,
should understand
empathy and human decency.
Shut up! Shut up!
He's blind! That's all.
That doesn't make him good or bad.
That just makes him blind.
And now he's blind with a purpose,
'cause he's looking out for the sick
and the hungry of his own ward.
That's right.
How do you sleep with yourself?
That's all we get, is two boxes?
Yeah, that's it.
But the others got a third box!
How are we supposed to
survive on only two boxes?
That's it! That's it, no more.
It's immoral! A blind man..
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
- Shut up.
- Okay.
Fuck off with the sermon. Okay?
Okay! Get your food! Get out.
And say thank you for what you got!
Understand?
Understand? Understand?
I understand.
Okay, okay. Now say thank you.
Thank you.
Okay.
- All right.
- Out. Out!
Don't let them get to you.
No, it's fine, it's fine!
This fucking guy, you know?
He wants more.
How many people are
in Ward One now?
35.
We only have 24 meals, so
everyone is gonna have to share.
What!
I'm sorry, this is all they gave us.
Quit shoving, everybody!
Relax!
Just find a partner!
Find a partner!
Two people to a meal.
Please!
Just don't push, okay?
Just wait in line, okay?
Guys! Guys, stop pushing!
And he put you, our own
doctor, to be our leader.
Perhaps he wants to
get a second opinion.
- You wanna eat something?
- Stop.
You have to eat something.
You have to eat a little something.
Stop it!
Do you have any pepper?
Doctor.
- Are you here?
- Yes, I'm here.
Here.
I brought you some food.
No. Jesus Christ, no.
This place is a toilet.
It's not your fault.
You did everything you could.
No, no, I didn't. The son of a bitch,
he had his gun right in my throat.
Exactly.
No. I could've reached
and taken it, but..
And then what? And then what?
I don't know.
If you'd have killed him,
it would've been way worse.
You would've started a war for sure.
A real war.
You're right.
Yeah, you're right. I'll pretend like
I thought that one through.
And it's not easy knowing
that you've killed someone.
Like I did.
Oh, God.
Oh, no.
- Hello?
- Don't say anything.
It'll be easier for me to understand.
I'm sorry, it's my fault.
I wanted..
Oh, Jesus!
Let's be quiet.
Let's all be quiet.
I can see.
I knew that. At least,
I think I knew.
Shh. It's a secret.
So, it's been like a week or so, and
you people have nothing left to offer.
So at Ward Three we came
up with a new plan.
Bring us your women.
Women for food.
Have a good day.
What's going on?
We haven't eaten in three days.
We gave you all the food we have.
It's up to you to ration it.
Distribution is your problem.
Asshole!
Forget it! Fuck that!
We're not doing that!
I'm not. I'm not. I'm not going!
I'm not gonna go! No!
Bullshit!
No one's asking you to go.
What?
Certainly not the men from this
ward, so you can't blame us.
I think she brings up a good point.
And I think we should ask
if there are any volunteers.
Volunteers?
What are you talking about?
Most ridiculous thing
I've ever heard!
Look, if there are
any volunteers,
I think they should say so now.
I wonder how many volunteers would
we have if he said send us your men?
It's not the same.
- Like, it's obviously not the same.
- Oh, really? And why's that?
'Cause it's just not.
- 'Cause there's no fags here!
- Yeah, well there's no whores, either!
Yeah. That's debatable.
I gave myself to you out of pity,
and now you think I'm
some sort of goddamn whore?
Doctor.
What? Are you asking me
for a deliberation here?
I mean, my God! Of course I would
rather that my wife didn't go.
But what I want really doesn't matter.
It's completely up to her.
My male pride, of course,
is gonna be hurt.
But if that even exists in here,
what does it matter anyway?
We're all starving to death.
So I just think that people should
do whatever they feel like doing
according to whatever morality
it is that they have left.
- There's nobody, forget it!
- Just anybody.
I'll go.
No. Oh, my God.
- No.
- I'll go with her.
Me, too.
- All right. I'll go, too.
- I'll go, too.
Well, you do whatever you like,
but my wife is going nowhere.
Dignity has no price.
No one knows how
many women are here.
You can do what you like,
and we'll feed you both.
And then you can talk
to me about dignity.
- No, that's not the point. I just want..
- I'm no different than the rest.
- What?
- I'll do what they do.
You'll do what I tell you to do!
Don't order me!
There's nothing worse.
No. It's disgusting!
From now on, you don't eat.
How long do we wait before
they come and get us?
Get out of the way!
- Good evening!
- How many ladies?
Eight.
- Nine.
- Nine, only nine?
Well, you nine will have
to do double duty tonight.
If any of you is on the
rag, we don't want you.
We will get you some other time.
No one's on the rag.
Well then, get yourselves
all gussied up
and come over at your leisure.
We'll be waiting.
And the food will follow,
if we're happy.
In the meantime, I have brought you
a little bit of bread to tide you over.
I think I have one more.
There you go.
Let's go.
There's no point in trying to run.
They have guards.
At least it would be faster.
We'd be dead by now.
No one's gonna die,
come on.
They're coming!
Hey, welcome.
Girls, okay, don't be afraid!
We're here to love you!
We're not going to hurt you, all right?
Guys, don't get too excited, all right?
Everyone's gonna get
their own girl, okay?
If we don't, well, we share!
That's how we do things here, all right?
Okay. I want you all in
order from hot to cold, okay.
The hottest come here and the coldest
go to the back of the line.
What's wrong with you?
She's a bit of a dead fish.
Take care of her, yeah.
Give her some life.
Oh, man, where have
you been all my life?
Do I know you?
Okay. Yeah, take your turn.
Why are you trembling? Why are you
trembling? Why are you trembling?
No, easy, okay.
You two are coming with me.
Are you blonde?
Okay. All right.
All right. Okay, a bit
on the mature side,
but that's more like it.
You like this?
That's my gun.
- You like it?
- No, I don't.
Lady. Lady.
Now, that's a surprise, lady.
All right, you're coming with me.
And if you let go,
I'll bite your nipples off, all right?
- Come on. Now suck! Come on.
- No.
I'm not asking, all right?
Come on! Come on!
- I could bite it off.
- Try it!
I'll blow your fucking head off!
You and your friend!
All right? Or I'll tear you to pieces.
Come on!
All right, lady! Hey! Wait!
All right! All right, way to go!
Okay, okay.
Okay, let's just take
your time, now. There you go.
It's okay, don't worry.
You're so tense. Please sit down.
Get the fuck out of here!
Little bit tense, there we go!
May I suck on your nipples?
No.
Just a little bit. Here we go.
There we go. That wasn't so bad.
Just a little tickle. Tickle, tickle.
Come on, dead fish!
Move for me!
Come on!
Move now!
Will someone
go get the food?
What happened? What happened?
- Are you okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
You want another story?
The women of Ward Two.
Tonight is the big night.
- How many ladies?
- Seven.
Seven? You sure that's it?
Count them again.
- Seven!
- All right, well, if you've got seven..
How about,
"The boy with the magic powers"?
- You like that one, don't you?
- Yeah.
Okay, so where did we leave off?
Do you remember?
- This boy wasn't ordinary.
- No.
He could turn invisible,
he had special powers.
And he turned invisible
when they weren't looking.
- Right.
- 'Cause when they looked,
he wasn't there
and they thought he got away.
Good afternoon, ladies.
I just wanted to make sure that
you've all recovered
from the fun that
we had the other night.
Seriously, I just wanted to touch base
with any of you who might be feeling
a little bit of jealousy.
I know that tonight is not
your night, but I assure you
that our hearts are still with you.
You men folk should be
very proud of your ladies.
Very proud! Well, one of them
was kind of a dead fish,
but the other ones
performed like real pros.
There are only eight of us now.
- What happened, did someone die?
- Yeah.
It's not a big deal, though.
She was kind of a dead fish.
I'm gonna finish the story later, okay?
- Aw..
- No, I promise, I'll finish it later.
Okay.
Who's that? Where you going?
It's you, isn't it?
What happened?
Hey, hey, hey!
What the fuck is going on?
Hey!
I know you're here!
You don't even know my name.
No. I know your voice!
Just say one more word. I dare you!
Your dead friend said the same thing!
Don't let them leave!
Do not let them leave! You idiots!
Come this way.
Come this way. Go!
Do not let them leave!
You fucking jerks, stop them!
Come back! Get back here!
That's it! That's it for you!
Ladies, no more food for you!
Every day we go without food,
one of your men will die!
We collect from now on.
You missed!
He's dead! He's dead!
What's going on?
Where are you? Where are you?
- Are you okay?
- Go get the food.
They told me a man was killed.
I killed him.
Now there's gonna be a war.
They're going to want revenge.
We're gonna have to
barricade our doors.
- We'll use our beds like they did.
- Whatever you say. I'll get the food.
Oh, shit.
- Barricade it! Barricade it!
- You got the door?
Two beds!
So fucking what if we send
the women there twice a month?
We'll get fucking fed!
Stand it up!
Barricade the thing!
Come on.
What I suggest we do is we
find out who killed their leader
and offer them up like a peace offering.
No, not now!
We don't know what kind of thing
they're gonna do!
In exchange for food!
They have a stockpile.
We're in a state of war.
And we started it.
Yeah. Exactly.
And I suggest we find out
who killed their leader and..
Look! Look.
If they won't give us food,
I say let's get it ourselves!
Yeah, let's do it!
I agree.
Then let's go!
Okay, I think he's right.
If anyone's willing to go,
I think you should raise your hand.
What? What?
That's about the most ridiculous thing
I've ever suggested.
How about, whoever doesn't wanna
fight, simply slip away right now.
And no one will know you were here!
And for those of us that are left,
gather around me,
and we'll make a plan.
Here.
Okay, how many of us are there?
One, two, three..
12. I can see 12 of us.
What?
Don't touch my fucking bed!
Do it! Come on. Do it!
Hey!
- I heard something!
- Someone's here!
Who's there?
I heard somebody.
I heard somebody!
I have a chair over here.
Let's go, come on!
Grab the person in front of you!
Stay in a tight group.
All right.
Straight ahead.
If we go back!
We can't go back! Come on!
Let's move!
What's that?
Smoke.
Fire!
Help!
Don't push!
Fire!
It's okay!
It's okay! It's okay.
Stay there! I'm gonna come get you.
- Here I am. Hold on to him.
- They're gonna shoot us.
Guards! Guards!
Do you see?
Do you see what's going on?
Guards!
We're free!
Hello! Hello!
We're here!
- It's empty.
- Okay.
Go on in. Step up.
We're in a shop.
Now everyone, please stay together,
I don't wanna lose anybody else.
Step up.
All right, I'm gonna go look for food.
I'll go with you.
No, it's something I can do better
on my own.
You stay here
and look after each other.
Right here. It's right here.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Get out. This place is occupied.
There are other groups out there.
Do not leave this spot.
I know you can do it.
But how can you carry the food back
on your own?
Is there anything,
is there running water?
I'll look for bottles.
I wouldn't guess there's any electricity.
No.
Are there any signs
that people can still see?
What's happening?
Don't! No!
I miss you. I miss you so much.
Here's a supermarket.
- I'll go in.
- Okay.
Step up.
I'll stay here. I know my place.
Stay off my fucking spot!
Don't touch me!
I'm coming back!
I'll fucking kill you!
You stay off my fucking spot!
That's mine!
Give it to me, you thief! You thief!
You thief! Give it back!
Give it to me!
Hey! Hey!
I can hear you near
my fucking spot!
What do you have there?
Hey! Hey!
What are you eating?
Smells like meat!
She's got meat?
No! No! No! No!
Let go! Get back!
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Let go!
No! No! No!
Get away!
It's me! Go! Go! Go!
Okay.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay!
You all right? You okay?
- Oh!
- Okay.
- I have to stop. Stairs.
- Stop, stop.
All right. You're all right.
It's all right. You're safe.
- Thank you.
- You're okay.
I have to go back and get those clothes
before I forget where they are.
Here, eat something.
That God is punishing
us. This is not what is happening.
This is not God's way.
What is happening to us
reminds me of what happened
to Saint Paul.
Paul used to kill Christians,
used to persecute them.
But the Lord came to him
and converted him.
And not only converted him,
but blinded him.
Is this what is happening to us?
- Here!
- Here.
- Here I am!
Here! Here, I have a jacket.
- Where's the food?
- Right here.
It's terrible. Who would do that?
Someone who went blind.
And then he went crazy.
Since he couldn't see,
he didn't want his statue to see.
I don't think so, little man.
I don't know if it'd be
possible for a blind man
to paint the painting like that.
Yes, they could.
More likely a priest
who saw what happened
and had a crisis of faith.
No, but seriously,
all those people made me think
of how lucky we are that we have
a leader with vision.
So I think it's up to you to
decide what we should do next.
Well, I think we should
stay here tonight.
Try to get some sleep.
And then tomorrow,
I was thinking we
could go to our house.
It's pretty near here and it's big,
so it can accommodate everybody.
Where are you, dog?
Still there?
No, no, no. Don't follow that dog.
He'll lead you to a fire hydrant.
Too proud to be a seeing-eye dog.
27. Five-four. Black hair. Brown eyes.
I don't wanna know what you look like.
Well, how can we know each other?
I know that part inside
of you with no name.
And that's who we are, right?
When you went to look for food,
we talked to this man
that was part of a group
that moved around together
trying to find food and shelter.
Each night they slept
in a different place.
I asked him why he didn't
sleep in his own home.
And he said he didn't know
where it was anymore.
He lost it.
They're welcome to it,
if they can find their way
to my little room.
I think it's okay!
Here we are. Here we are.
Looks fine. Come in. Come in.
Come in. I can't believe it.
Okay, careful.
Just because the door was locked,
doesn't mean that no one's here.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
Maybe we should take
our shoes off. Right?
That's a good idea.
We can leave them by the door.
We don't wanna mess the place up,
we just arrived.
If you want, take off your clothes, too.
We have plenty of clean ones upstairs.
Are you talking to me?
No, to everyone.
Our clothes are just
as dirty as our shoes.
Here? All together?
Come on. She's the
only one who can see.
If it makes you feel better,
it's getting pretty dark.
All right. If you insist.
I'm sure you've seen worse sights
than this old body.
I want you to feel at home here
because this is your home now, too.
Thank you both.
We're all flattered that
you would offer your home.
It's our pleasure.
Kick us out when you've had enough.
Or when I become too
much of a burden,
just tell me, and I'll just
wander off like an elephant.
You're not an elephant.
I'm not a man, either.
You're plenty of a man, babe.
I don't know.
I haven't seen myself in so long.
- I must look ridiculous.
- No, no.
- Dirty and skinny.
- But not ridiculous.
Not at all.
- And what about me?
- You're beautiful.
Yeah. Not like you.
You've never seen me.
But in my dreams you're
always beautiful.
How come you never
appeared in my dreams
but I know you're beautiful?
Well, that's why
blindness is a gift to the ugly.
Come on, you're not serious.
No, but I suppose I was
more beautiful before.
- We were all more beautiful before.
- I know.
Is anyone cold? It feels so good!
I'm having a great time.
- Hello?
- Hey.
- Hi.
- It's me.
I brought you some hot water.
Oh, thank you.
- I'm gonna pour it down, okay?
- Okay.
- Feels good?
- Feels good.
I hope we can find the boy's parents.
What do you hope for?
Nothing is more ridiculous than
the desires of an old man.
Tell me. I wanna know.
You wouldn't understand.
- Why that tone of voice?
- What tone?
That one.
What I hope is that
we can go on living together.
As we are. Like this.
Blind?
For me nothing has been better.
I'd want us to live together.
Together with me or with everyone?
Don't make me say.
I wanna know.
Are we alone?
Is anyone listening?
Good. Good. I wanna live with you.
I remember that New Year's.
It was cold, but I didn't mind.
All right. At this end of the table,
we have peas and carrots.
At the center we have olives in a bowl
and some crackers on a small plate.
And at the far end of the table
we have anchovies.
- Mmm..
- Anchovies!
A special bottle of something
sparkling for our guests.
There's nothing like water.
Clean water.
I'd like to propose a toast.
To our family.
- To our human family.
- And the dog!
Much better than any champagne.
I see you.
When I touch you like this,
I see your face.
So beautiful.
It's all I need to remember.
Tell me, is this working?
Let's see. Take another one.
Take another of me in the face.
Blind inspiration.
There's coffee, if anybody wants some.
- I'll have some, please.
- I want some, too.
I need to wake up.
Honey, honey,
I think we should
get everybody together
and talk about what we need to do.
There's not much food left,
and I'm worried about security.
Okay.
I can pour it for you.
Careful.
It's hot, okay?
- I can see you.
- Mmm-hmm.
I can see you.
Oh, my God!
I can see everything!
- What?
- I can see you.
What are you saying?
- What?
- Yeah.
- Everything is beautiful.
- What are you talking about?
- What?
- Oh, my God!
What do you mean, you can see?
I can see you. I got back my sight.
- What is it?
- Come here.
I can see.
I can see!
You're lying.
Really?
What? You have your sight?
Yeah, hi!
- You're kidding! Your eyes! Just now?
- Nice to meet you.
- Oh, my God!
- He can see.
I can't believe it!
He sees! He sees!
I know.
I thought he was kidding!
Oh, my God!
What does this mean?
I can see everybody's face!
I know.
I can't believe it.
I can see. I love you guys.
You guys are so beautiful!
- Oh, my God. You're so beautiful.
- It's wonderful.
It's wonderful.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326