Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
The triple-nine call
was logged at 9.40.
Isn't this a bit of a fuss
over a probable suicide?
Her boxer died, now she's dead.
I don't like coincidences.
Recording a nasal temperature
of 32 centigrade.
When did it happen?
The man opposite heard something
about 9.30. 9.30 could be right.
OK. I'd like a picture
taken from this angle.
Get all the ammunition.
..Anything else?
Bag the head and hands.
Get her over to the mortuary.
Yep. ..Geoff.
We'll need to recover as much skull
and brain as we can off that wall.
Make sure we get the shot. I'd like
the shot's spread pattern plotted.
Suicide?
I couldn't say without a proper
examination. You mean, you won't.
That's right. ..Ah! Wait, thank you.
What?
If Terence needed his daughter,
why would she kill herself? Despair.
It doesn't add up.
Suicide's linked to low self-esteem.
How could she lack that if her
father relied on her? It's selfish.
Heartless. But not a reason
to rule out suicide.
She isn't selfish OR heartless.
Ask the boys in the gym.
If she didn't kill herself,
somebody killed her.
Prove it.
Hello, Mr Reeve. Can you spare us
five minutes afterwards, please?
Lift up the tape, son. Thank you.
Oh, Peter. This is a crime scene.
Police on this side, public on that.
Ex-superintendents go on that side.
I'm here in an official capacity.
As? The Boxing Board has an
interest. When I find something the
Board should know, I'll tell you.
How did you know she was dead? Is
she doing your job now? YOU'RE not.
Over here, Mr Reeve. So, what's
the Boxing Board's view, Mr Reeve?
It's a tragedy. Terri's been under
pressure since her father's injury.
It would seem she took her own life
as a last desperate response
to this pressure.
Just go for it. Yeah...
Absolutely. Morning.
I heard you on the radio.
It was a result.
The licence
is as good as in the bag.
MEN TALK IN UNDERTONES, AND LAUGH
No, I wouldn't.
Where is DC Gladwin? Dunno. I asked
to see Cross's shotgun certificate.
He hasn't got one. Really?
He never had one.
Did SHE? No. That's interesting.
So it might not be their gun.
I made a few enquiries.
It's a Wilkes. Handmade.
How do you know?
I asked Perks, the gun dealer.
I'd rather you asked me first.
What? How's that?
We should stick
to police firearms experts.
So what did Mr Perks say?
What do you reckon it's worth?
Dunno.
How about 15,000 quid?
Normally we can't trace shotguns.
But one worth 15 grand...
This is the contract
for the sale of your mother's house.
If you just sign here...
and here.
How much will be left
from the sale?
About ã20,000, after fees and taxes.
I'll divide the proceeds
and send you a cheque each.
There's no need. Just send it to Sam.
As you wish. Why?
My sister paid all my mother's care
expenses. Nothing but the best.
It cost a lot more than ten thousand.
You'll have to put that
in a letter.
Well, let's do it now. Just lend me
your pen again, will you?
HORN BEEPS
You frightened me! Sorry. I thought
it was you. You know about Terri?
What can I say?
I feel useless. I don't know
how to help. Be a success.
That's all they wanted.
The gym's nothing without a prospect.
That's YOU. Well, you can rely on me,
Mr Jones. I'm not going nowhere.
Good. Good... Hey...
head up.
I wish you hadn't done that. What?
The money. Oh, that. What's money?
I won't take it. You need it.
What are you living on? The dole.
No Attendance Allowance, or Child
Benefit since Ricky left school...
I manage. I'm after a little job
and I've seen a little flat,
easier to manage.
What sort of job? How do I know?
I haven't actually found it yet.
Look, you have to take
that money, Sam. Have my half
and buy a little flat.
"Hello, Mr Bank Manager, I'm forty,
on the dole, I've got ã20,000 and
I'd like a mortgage." No, take it.
It makes sense. I haven't finished
with this. I have. Want a lift?
No, thanks. I have to go
to the Post Office. It's giro day.
Mr Cross.
Mr Cross, can you hear me?
I want to ask you about last night.
Do you remember anything
from last night?
Do you remember the gunshot?
Mr Cross...
could you give me some sign
that you can hear me?
He can't. I know he can't. Detective
Inspector Selway. You are...?
Keith Jones. Friend of the family.
How well did you know the family?
VERY well. Work and personal, both.
Young Theresa's a great loss.
Did you know they owned a shotgun?
I gave it to them. When?
It was a year ago.
It was a business gift,
to cement our working relationship.
That's a big gift.
I'm told it's worth 15,000.
It was an important relationship.
I'm a promotor, Terence is a trainer.
Was.
They had no shotgun certificate.
I leave that to you.
I just gave them a present.
But you DO have a certificate?
Yes, of course.
Shooting...
It's a good way to entertain people.
We'll need a statement. Come to
the station today or tomorrow. OK.
Rigor is established
in all major muscle groups.
Hypostasis in the back of the body,
further marked in the lower back,
buttocks and lower thighs.
This is Dr Stewart. He has
an interest in brain injuries.
If you pull the ragged edges
of the wound back together,
you can see where the impact was.
The injury to the head is massive
and ragged
and appears to have been caused...
by gunshot entering the face
at about the level of the lower lip.
There are no contact marks
on the skin,
indicating that the weapon
was not pressed against the flesh.
The entry wound is about...
Thanks, Fred.
..ten centimetres across.
Part of the head has been destroyed.
There's a quantity of shot
inside the skull.
I can't find any wadding.
What's wadding?
Shotgun cartridges have a cap
to stop the lead shot falling out
before the cartridge is fired.
Nowadays it's plastic. You find it
where the gun has been fired,
or in the wound. We picked up
everything at the scene. OK. Thanks.
CHILDREN CHEERING
Hey! That's my car!
HEY...!
Not any more it isn't.
I don't believe this.
Cause of death? Massive trauma
to the brain caused by a shotgun.
Not definitely self-inflicted.
Well, I think it WASN'T,
but I've no proof. I'll tell
Superintendent Ross.
When can we expect a report?
I need to see a ballistics expert.
Anything else outstanding?
Finding that wadding. The SOCOs
are back at the cottage now, but
I doubt they'll find anything new.
OK.
Is there a problem? No, no...
I worked for Peter Ross
for some time in London.
Yeah, he said.
You must know him very well.
He is... He's very thorough.
I know. And he has great respect
for your profession.
Is this something you've discussed?
We don't need to.
But...? We're going to need
something concrete soon to continue
pursuing this as a suspicious death.
I know that too.
See? It's all in the block.
It's quite scientific.
Amazing. Do it again.
OHH!
Sorry!
Speedy.
Sorry...!
It's all yours. Huh... Why?
Well, we can't have you going
in raggedy-arsed cars, Charlie.
This is my promise.
I will do at least as well for you
as Terri could have. Better.
That's the least I can do for her.
What will I do for YOU?
Me...? Nothing.
For Terri, for her dad, you can be
a success. Be a success for us.
So you're taking over? We'll
get someone to hold the trainer's
licence. But you're gonna be my star.
Er... "We"? The Board.
I can't have this. It's not right.
I only earned ã11,000 last year.
The car is a gift.
This is your breakthrough year,
Charlie. There's a TV deal
on the table. The sky's the limit.
The car's only the start of it.
You sign with me.
Who's gonna train me? We're getting
someone in. You know him. Who?
Tony Kennedy. Tony K...?
Terence wouldn't have him! They had
harsh words. We're putting all that
behind us. Tony's a good trainer.
So I get to keep the car
if I sign with you and Tony? Yes.
What about Terence? We've organised
accommodation for him. He'll be well
cared for. This is the right thing.
Enjoy!
There really is no evidence of
anyone else being involved. She's
right. But you don't believe it?
You aren't identifying with Terri?
Helpless parent...
Of course I am. You and Wyn
did everything you could for
your mother. That's just my point.
And Selway's message?
Ross doesn't agree that a dedicated
carer is unlikely to commit suicide.
He's entitled to disagree.
It's not just that. I'll let him
down, it'll go to court...
His promotions will go on hold...
This has to change.
I tried the dinner and black frock.
It wasn't really me.
OK. How DO you want to approach it?
I don't.
He's a policeman with his job to do.
I'm a scientist with mine. Right.
So, first scientific question?
Where's the wadding
from that shotgun cartridge?
I need to see a firearms expert.
Will Rider.
Retired Royal Army Ordnance Corps.
Lives in Cambridge.
Is he available now?
He owes me a favour or two.
KNOCK AT DOOR
It's open.
Dr Ryan? Captain Rider?
Thanks for coming.
It's very good. Very good.
You should have been a detective.
I am, in a way. Of course.
I can see two problems.
One is, how did she fire the gun?
Presumably she tied the string
around the chairback
and pulled the trigger. Possible...
But the firing mechanism
is very positive. If she pulled hard,
she risked spoiling the aim.
Is that conclusive?
Unfortunately, no.
Just likely.
I need something physical.
Tangible.
What was the bore of the gun?
Twelve gauge...I'm told.
I'm no expert.
And the area marked in red
represents the damage.
Roughly the right angle on the head.
I'm bothered by the stuff down there.
What does it mean? I don't know.
There's an awful lot of damage.
What does that mean? I don't know.
What sort of shot was it? Um...
I got that out of her skull.
Buckshot!
Why would people use buckshot
around here? I don't know. It's for
shooting big animals. Deer. Bucks.
Hence the damage to her skull.
Not necessarily. Where is this shot?
At the forensic lab.
How much was there? Um...
There. And there's the the stuff
the SOCOs got out of the wall.
How much is that?
About an ounce and a half.
There's your answer! That's miles
too much shot for one cartridge!
There was more than one shot!
That's why the spread pattern
is a little bit wrong. That's why
there's so much damage to her head.
Ballistics will say the gun
was fired twice down the same barrel.
He backed her into the room
with a shotgun...
He sat her down...
Then pulled the trigger. PCHOO!
Then he thinks about it. He's
intelligent and he knows about guns.
He puts himself
in the mind of the police.
Nobody commits suicide with a gun
held at right angles to their head!
If he leaves things as they are,
the stupidest detective
will know it's murder. What to do?
Your murderer
sets up a sophisticated suicide.
He brings over a chair...
He ties the gun to it, attaches
a string to look like the victim has
fired it, lines it up carefully...
pulls the trigger...
Presto! The scene is obliterated.
Or almost.
What about the cartridge wadding?
Why didn't I find any in the wound?
You wouldn't with buckshot.
It's big and powerful enough
to blow the wadding to smithereens.
It's very clever. The only thing
your gunman failed to account for
was the extra shot.
Where did you acquire the gun?
I told you. A country-house sale.
Where? Herefordshire.
There's the auctioneer's receipt.
ã14,700.
Guineas. It's a great deal of money
for a gun. It's a very good gun.
Anything else?
Yes, Mr Jones. Such as?
You gave the gun to Terence Cross.
When? 12 months ago. On a shoot.
Were you aware of whether he held
a shotgun certificate? No.
Did you try to find out?
We talked about this yesterday.
If you're going to charge me with
anything, shouldn't you caution me?
This is a general talk.
But you're taking a statement.
To establish the facts.
Nevertheless, I would like my lawyer
present if we're going to continue.
As you wish.
15,000 guineas is a lot of gun.
Yes.
It's a huge gift.
That's business.
It's the way it works.
You must have had something in mind
for a return.
Must I?
Yes.
- What did Terence Cross have that
was worth a fifteen grand bauble?
- Well... Nothing.
It's much vaguer than that.
It's more "feelgood".
Did you hear that, Inspector?
How much feelgood would 15 grand
buy in this nick? Loads.
Are you going to charge me
over this gun?
- Stuff the gun.
Cross had something you wanted!
- I don't think I like your tone.
I don't care if you like my tone!
- Someone is dead because of this
gun and I'm asking you about it!
- Am I under arrest?
KNOCKING
Sorry. Dr Ryan's outside.
Oh. Bring her in.
Cross had a stable of fighters,
several championship prospects. They
must glitter like jewels to Jones.
So, you don't think Kevin Sharma
was murdered? No.
They needed him alive and kicking.
Punching? Quite. Alive and punching.
Terri Cross was murdered.
Two shots were fired into her head,
the one to cover the other wound.
It's very rare to shoot yourself
in the head twice. True.
No defence marks on her body.
She let the murderer come in.
She knew and trusted him. Jones?
He's a cool one if it was. Then...?
Reeve and Jones. They're like that,
yeah? Get Reeve in here.
Ask him? Arrest him? Tell him!
He hangs around here
like Banquo's bloody ghost,
burbling about when he ran CID...
He can tell us about his mate Jones.
..Thanks, Sam.
I'm sorry. It's time.
DOORBELL BUZZES
Wyn!
Wyn?
Did you not hear me
at the front door?
I didn't know it was you. I didn't
want to answer the door like this.
What happened?
Is it Mammy's clothes?
It had to be dealt with.
I just thought,
"I'll have a tidy up and that'll be
that. It's just a practical matter."
Of course it's not "just practical".
I'm so useless, bawling like this.
I've the rest of the house to do
before I go. How will I manage?
Don't manage. What do you mean?
I'm all alone in that new place.
Why don't you come and stay with me
until you get yourself straight? No.
You'd be doing me a favour. No.
How would I? I'm not going soft.
I was sortin' out Mammy's stuff
and got upset.
I'll be fine. It'd be nice for me
to have someone there sometimes.
And not others! It won't work. We'll
fight like cats and dogs. You're the
sort of person that polishes spoons!
How would you cope with me
slumped on your sofa?
You won't be slumped on my sofa!
No. Thanks, but no thanks.
I'll get a flat of my own
and slump on my own sofa.
How are you going to get that stuff
down to Oxfam?
I hadn't figured that out yet.
Will I come back later
and give you a hand?
EASY-LISTENING MUSIC PLAYS
What the frigging...?
What? ..WHAT?
Mr Reeve, as a former policeman, you
know the importance of co-operation.
Go on.
Who has to gain from Theresa Cross's
death? You think she was murdered?
I KNOW she was. Who would benefit?
Not me, if that's what you think.
You're a pain in the arse! You're in
and out of this nick as if you own
it, but you're not a suspect! Thanks.
Could it be Jones? I suppose Jones
COULD benefit from Theresa's death.
Would he do it? It's unlikely. Why?
He plays mind games with people.
He's a game player, a businessman.
You wouldn't call him strong.
You don't have to be strong
to pull a trigger.
That's twice.
Next time make an appointment.
Do you want a coffee?
Kevin told me he had a fight
on the building site. When?
About six weeks before he died.
So, that's where he got
his injuries to his hands? Yes.
And it's where he got
his blood clot on the brain.
Did he have headaches?
Dunno. He wouldn't talk about it.
But you could see the injuries
to him? He was all beat up.
That was why he avoided Terri.
He didn't want her
to see his bruises. Is that all?
No. ..I imagine he didn't want
to face her, knowing what he knew.
What did he know?
Why did he have a fight
on a building site?
Who did he fight?
Tony Kennedy, an ex-boxer, bit of a
throwback. He thinks you fight with
your chin out and the toughest wins.
Jones knows so little about boxing,
he actually hired Kennedy
to be my trainer. KENNEDY!
I mean, the man is an animal.
How? He's a disgrace. When
he couldn't get a boxing licence,
he did bare-knuckles
in the backs of pubs.
Terence wouldn't have him
in the gym!
And Jones had me sign a contract
and gave me a car as a sweetie.
What happened to Terence?
He got put in a wheelchair
by a hit and run. Only,
the hit and run wasn't an accident.
Kennedy knocked him down.
How do you know?
I DON'T know!
Kevin told me. He went off to kill
Kennedy! He wanted to rip him apart
with his bare hands!
He fought Kennedy bare-knuckle?
In a skip.
So, Jones had Kennedy
try to kill Terence Cross
for control of his boxers.
When Kevin found out what Kennedy
did, he tried to settle it with him.
Who killed Theresa?
I told her.
Dr Ryan, I told her...all I know.
I told her that Kennedy drove
the van that ran down her dad.
What did she say?
I should have...
I should have looked after her.
I-I...
CHARLIE SOBS
KNOCK AT DOOR
Yeah.
Sir, could you...?
Yeah, sure.
What was all that about, then?
DOOR OPENS
Do you have an address
for someone called Anthony Kennedy?
Yes. I'd have to go to my records
to get it. Why?
Can you get some big lads and a car?
..Why?
Well, he hasn't won the Lottery!
Did he shoot the girl? Follow!
What IS this?! DS Speed is going to
play snooker with you. For how long?
Till I say different. Tell me why.
I'm off to arrest someone. The few
that know are coming too, except you.
If he runs, you could be accused of
tipping him off. You're arresting me.
I'm offering you a game of snooker.
Billiards.
Heads or tails?
Heads. ..Ha. Chalk?
SIREN WAILS
Charlie, if you get in there
with DI Selway. The boys will be
in the car behind. ..Thanks, Sam.
He wants to do it for Terri.
His evidence only mentions Kevin.
We need something concrete
to take to court on her.
This is the first time I've been
in the back of a police car without
any handcuffs on. How does it feel?
Naked.
Who's this?
That's him. That's him.
SIRENS WAIL
Shit!
You do not have to say anything,
but it may harm your defence if
you omit something you use in court.
So, Tony, you're in a bit of a jam.
Murder.
I killed no-one. Kevin Sharma died
of injuries he got fighting you.
Double jam.
Double? You know why he fought you.
You ran down Terence Cross.
I want a brief to be present.
Good idea.
Yeah, keep mum till the brief turns
up. Do you think he killed Theresa?
I never.
Yeah.
I never!
He's never coming out. They're all
eligible after 15 years for parole.
It depends on the Home Secretary.
Which way do YOU vote, Tony?
No, they're all tough on crime now.
You're nicked for murder
and attempted murder! You'll be in
prison well into the next century.
Look, the old man was an accident.
He stumbled in front of the van.
I only meant to frighten him.
Kevin was pickin' a fight.
I was only defending meself.
How's that murder?
When you get that lawyer, get him
to explain the law on murder to you,
cos if he gets that down to
manslaughter, he's your best friend!
Except, YOU could be.
Me? How?
Keith Jones shot
Theresa Cross, didn't he?
I don't know.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Oh, Trevor. Come in.
Sam asked me to give you a hand.
She's busy.
Where have I heard that before?
Sorry.
It's not YOUR fault.
All this to go?
I hear you've got a new flat.
What's it like?
Small.
Sam said she'd asked you
to move in with her for a bit.
She did, yeah.
Do you think you will?
Guv, Jones is here with a brief.
What, for him?
He hasn't said. They want to see you,
and Dr Ryan's on the phone, too.
Ask DI Selway to see Jones, yeah?
Yeah.
OFFICER:
Right, you, sit down and shut up!
Sam? 'Get your man?' You make
me sound like a Mountie. We did.
I think I can prove who murdered
Terri. I examined her body again.
On her arm I found a hair pulled
out by the root, like in a struggle.
So? 'It's not Terri's.
'My bet is it's Jones's.' Mine, too.
If you can get a sample of Jones's
hair, a DNA test will confirm it.
Superintendent Ross,
this is my lawyer, Joe Feeney.
Hello. Hello.
Mr Jones thinks we're accusing him.
We didn't call you.
I came here to confront this farrago.
Charlie vandalised my home today!
- Is that a complaint?
- Yes, official!
- I'm here to face my accusers.
I don't run scared!
- Answer me one question.
- Any!
- Can we have a sample of your hair?
Hello, Sam. Hello.
Did you get the hair sample?
Yeah, well, he could hardly refuse.
The one I got from Terri's body's
in the fridge. I'll get it tomorrow.
Did you arrest Jones? Yeah, but
his lawyer reckons we've nothing.
You don't agree?
On its own, he might be right,
but he knew about the gun, he stood
to gain from her death. The gym?
Exactly. That's a powerful reason
to murder her.
Let's hope the jury thinks so.
Fancy another go at dinner? I know
somewhere that stays opens late.
Well, I'll need to go home
and change.
I'll come with you.
You have a drink
while I get changed, and I'll drive.
Why don't we both have a drink
and call a cab?
FOOD SIZZLES
Sam? Sam, is that you?
You came, then.
Yes. Trevor brought me. Very nice.
I've cooked supper for us.
Smells good. Wyn, this is
Superintendent Peter Ross. Wyn.
Hello, Peter. I'm sure we can
make it stretch round four. Four?
Hi.
♪ Testator Silens
♪ Costestes e Spiritum
♪ Silentium
♪ Angeli Silens... ♪
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org