I am announcing today my candidacy
for the presidency
of the United States.
I do not run for the presidency
merely to oppose any man,
but to propose new policies.
I run because I am convinced
that this country is
on a perilous course
and because I have
such strong feelings
about what must be done,
and I feel that I'm obliged
to do all that I can.
Hell, no, we
won't go! Hell, no, we won't go!
There's a time when
the operation of the machine
becomes so odious...
I shall not seek
and I will not accept
the nomination of my party
for another term
as your president.
Some very sad news for all of you,
and, I think, uh, sad news
for all of our fellow citizens
and people who love peace
all over the world,
and that is that, uh,
Martin Luther King was shot
and was killed tonight
in Memphis, Tennessee.
We're gonna say to the whole
damn government:
"Stick 'em up, mother. "
Bobby Kennedy's the only
white man in America I trust.
If I have reason to believe
that there's gonna be a riot
started, and somebody tells me
that there's gonna be trouble
if you don't stop them,
then it's my duty to stop them.
Then you go out and arrest them?
Oh, absolutely.
How can you go arrest somebody
if they haven't violated the law?
They're ready to violate the law.
In other words...
Could I suggest
in the luncheon period of time
that the sheriff
and the district attorney
read the Constitution
of the United States?
I don't want to be part
of the United States,
of the American people,
and have them write of us
as they wrote of Rome:
"They made a desert,
and they called it peace. "
Your generation, this generation,
cannot afford to waste
its substance and its hope
in the struggles of the past.
For beyond these walls
is a world to be helped and improved
and made safe
for the welfare of mankind.
Do we know anything yet?
We got men on the sixth floor
going from room to room.
You the manager?
Paul Ebbers.
And the bungalows?
We're checking them now.
5574.
Roger that.
- It's a false alarm.
- False alarm.
I wouldn't want to be you today.
Occupational hazard.
We'll open the cafe.
You or your men want
coffee, a hot breakfast,
- it's on the house.
- Thanks.
It'll take us a little while
to wrap this up,
but I'll let the boys know.
We're gonna need to
open a lane here for traffic.
False alarm.
Yeah. I didn't know
you were in this early.
Are you kidding?
Have you seen my schedule for today?
Hey, Paul.
What the heck's going on here?
There's a hook and ladder keeping me
from my first cup of coffee
and crosswords.
Don't you have a home, John?
Well, this is my home, you know that.
Retirement doesn't suit you, does it?
No, sir.
This is not the muscle tone
of a retired man.
If it were up to me,
John, you'd still be
in uniform, still at that door.
Oh, that's great. Hold it.
Okay, one more.
Everybody smile.
Thank you.
You guys can put out my fire anytime.
And how are you, my baby?
We're gonna go back up
to bed, aren't we?
Ladies and gentlemen,
if I may have your attention,
please, ladies and gentlemen.
We are very sorry.
This has been a false alarm.
Yes. Uh...
you are free to return
to your rooms at this time
or join us in one of our cafes
for a complimentary breakfast.
And once again, on behalf of the...
Jack?
Welcome to Los Angeles.
Sir.
The polls are open
in South Dakota, fellas.
Let's go.
How long has it been
since you've slept?
We bring home California,
we'll all sleep
a hell of a lot better.
Timmons.
Damn it. Damn it.
- Good morning, my brown brother.
- Hey.
You know you're working
a double, right?
How come everybody knows but me?
And that's the third time this week.
For once, I'd like to
be asked, "Hey, Jose,
would you mind working
a double shift today?"
- That'll never happen.
- Why not?
Because you're Mexican, that's why.
I'm Latino.
Latino?
Jose, you're a fuckin' Mexican, okay?
Call yourself what you will;
You're no different
than the rest of us.
If you don't like the double shift,
there's a hundred guys
out there on the other side
of that door
that'll take your place like this.
And if it makes you feel any better...
I'm working a double shift, too, so...
we'll both be here until midnight.
I got tickets to see Drysdale pitch
against Pittsburgh tonight.
- Is that right?
- He's on a streak.
You know?
Field level.
These are good tickets.
I was gonna take my dad.
He's never been to a game.
Well, he ain't going to one tonight.
So, if I were you,
I'd sell those tickets.
I can help you with that.
Son of a bitch.
Timmons, he doesn't show me
the decency of the respect.
- Yeah, you know why?
- Why?
Because you're Mexican.
And a busboy.
Hey, we're the new niggers, brother.
Get used to it.
Shit.
"Latino."
Well...
I missed all the excitement, I see.
Oh, it's not much to speak of.
Well, it's the Ambassador Hotel.
People coming, people going.
Nothing ever happens.
Grand Hotel.
What about it?
It's a line from the old
Greta Garbo movie, Grand Hotel.
Okay, John.
Ever seen Grand Hotel, Henry?
- No, I haven't, Mr. Casey.
- No, of course you didn't.
I have seen Bonnie and Clyde, though.
Ah, that's a good film.
Have you seen
Bonnie and Clyde, Nelson?
I saw it with you.
Thank you, Henry.
Have a good day.
Thank you, Mr. Casey.
You know, I stood at that door
from the first day
the Ambassador opened back in 1921,
and I greeted everyone:
FDR, Truman, Eisenhower,
Jack Kennedy, Johnson,
Premier Khrushchev,
the Shah of Iran,
King of Sweden, all of them.
Madame Chiang Kai-Shek... she
rented the entire fifth floor.
I personally delivered the
Oriental furniture to her suite.
It was antiques, mostly.
Oh, yes, and one night, I, uh,
I caught Will Rogers having a pee.
He was taking a piss
in the greenhouse.
He tried to convince me
it was good for the plants.
He said, "Good
for the shrubbery, boy."
I said, "Don't do it again,
sir."
And I also danced at the Grove
when I was off duty
with, uh, Barbara Stanwyck,
believe it or not,
and Dolores del Rio and Rita Hayworth.
I was quite a dancer.
She was a beautiful woman, mind you.
And I heard Bing Crosby
sing at the Grove, too.
Yeah, and Sinatra, too,
of course, and Rudy Vallee.
Sophie Tucker, Ruby Keeler.
Yeah, and Cab Calloway, I think.
Yes, sir. All good
things in this hotel.
Yeah.
Can I see the sports section?
Her boobs.
I read about it somewhere.
Anne Bancroft is not
gonna show her breasts in a film.
She's a good-looking lady, Coop.
I'm not saying she's not
a good-looking lady.
Oh, like you wouldn't,
if you had the chance?
Anne Bancroft has too much class
to show her breasts in a film.
That's it.
That's the facts.
It's not just a film, Coop.
It's The Graduate.
Mm, I love that movie.
- More coffee?
- Yes, please.
Okay, so I have a question for you.
What do you think,
Bancroft or body double?
- The nude scenes?
- Mm-hmm.
Flashes.
They're not even scenes.
Body double.
For sure.
Wait. You know this for a fact?
Well, no, but it's what I would do.
That is, if I ever actually got hired
- for a movie I auditioned for.
- You will. You will.
Plus, you're my favorite ingenue.
And you got a great smile,
and you're nice to us,
and you know
how to pour coffee so well.
You know what?
He actually thinks
he knows what he's doing
with that thing.
I do know what I'm doing
with this thing.
- No, you don't.
- You look like a movie star.
Really? Who put it on 13 frames?
- There you go.
- Well, say a prayer for me,
'cause tomorrow
I'm interviewing for Schwab's.
Oh, wow, good for you.
Schwabs, is that a director
or producer or something?
No, moron, Schwab's on Sunset.
Lana Turner was discovered there.
Oh, Schwab's.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, every
out-of-work actress
in Hollywood is trying
to get a gig there
waiting the lunch counter.
- Well, good luck.
- Thank you.
Hey, I guarantee you,
if Hitchcock asked her
to show her tits in a film,
she'd do it in a heartbeat.
Daryl.
I'll call you back.
I do everything I can
to make sure that
the employees of this hotel
are treated equally and fairly.
I'm getting complaints
that you're not allowing
the kitchen staff off work
to vote today.
We're understaffed this week.
I've got six workers with the flu.
I've had to deny sick leave, too.
Did you tell them they couldn't leave?
This is no small thing
we're doing tonight.
I need every staffer
with a pulse on duty.
Did you tell them that they
couldn't leave to vote?
They're not gonna vote.
Half of them are illegal;
They can't vote.
Why give them the time off
for something they can't do anyway?
You'll post a memo informing
all employees of their right
to vote.
They can't put two words
of English together.
Put up a memo
in English and in Spanish
informing all employees
of their right to vote
and allowing them
the privilege to do so.
Additionally, you will inform
them that they will be paid
for their time off for this privilege.
And...
because I'm an equal-opportunity
kind of guy,
you've got till the end of the week
to clear out your desk and leave.
You're fired, Daryl.
Good morning. Ambassador Hotel.
How may I direct your call?
Please hold.
Good morning.
Ambassador Hotel.
How may I connect your call?
Please hold.
One moment, please.
Good morning.
Ambassador Hotel.
Good morning. Ambassador Hotel.
How may I direct your call?
I'm sorry, but I can't
give out that information.
Please hold for the reservation desk.
It's the policy of the hotel.
Yes, it is.
Well, if you are his wife,
then you should have
his room number, now, shouldn't you?
What a bitch.
Husband's playing around,
and she wants to take it out on me.
No, no, no. Not today.
No, thank you.
- Speaking of...
- Don't start.
Ambassador Hotel.
How may I direct your call?
It's gonna bring you
nothing but trouble,
Angela, you don't end that.
Hey, do you have plans tonight?
Yeah. I got a hot date
with my Magnavox.
Do you want to go
to the party with me?
For Kennedy?
I didn't think employees were
allowed at hotel functions.
Well, screwing the boss
does have its advantages.
Oh, God.
Look, I know it ain't easy.
I know it's damn near impossible
to find a good man out there.
Seems like
all the good ones are taken.
But a married one?
I'm not good at being alone.
You stay with a married man
who ain't gonna leave his wife,
and you're looking at a lifetime
of being alone.
Honey, don't kid yourself.
Ambassador Hotel.
How may I connect you?
America was a great force in the world
with immense prestige
long before we became
a great military power.
And that power has come to us,
and we cannot renounce it.
But neither can we afford to forget
that the real constructive force
in this world
comes not from tanks or not from bombs
but from the imaginative ideas,
the warm sympathies
and the generous spirit of a people.
One thing is clear
in this year of 1968,
I believe, in this country
as I've traveled across,
and that is that the American
people want no more Vietnam.
California can make the difference.
Test one, two. Test one, two.
Miss, uh, Jan... Jana...
Janacek.
Yes. Perhaps I need to
remind you, Miss, uh...?
- Janacek.
- Exactly.
That there is a law against loitering.
I've been in this lobby
for the past two days
waiting for my interview
with Senator Kennedy.
Miss...
there are no rooms available
at the hotel,
and no records of your credentials
with regards to the senator's
press corps.
What does this look like?
I write for an
international publication.
Rude Pravo.
Well, it's not exactly
the Washington Post, now, is it?
Excuse me.
Hi, um, I have an appointment
for a manicure-pedicure.
Oh.
Yup. And you are...
our lovely bride-to-be.
Yes, ma'am.
Well, let me see 'em.
Excuse me?
Oh.
Oh...
You know he's gonna
break it tonight, man.
What?
Drysdale, consecutive shutouts,
it's gonna happen tonight.
Yeah, maybe.
You don't know
how important this is, Miguel.
Jose, it's one baseball game.
You can buy tickets to another night.
What?!
No, no, no, no.
It's not just a game, okay?
Don Drysdale has pitched
five consecutive shutouts.
That's a record
that has stood since 1904
by Doc White of the Chicago White Sox.
He's gonna break it tonight, man.
I know he is.
Who, Drysdale?
Yeah.
You got money on the game, Jose?
No, I'm-I'm just a fan.
Well, then, go Dodgers.
Yeah.
I need to see you in my office.
I'm supposed to tell the staff
to go to their polling place
today and vote.
I'm not old enough to vote.
I'm a felon.
You're a felon?
Nah, I'm just kidding, brother.
'Course I'm gonna vote today.
Now, listen, a lot of people,
a lot of people are
gonna be intimidated
by this thing because it's new,
all right?
So I'm counting on all of you
to reassure them
that it's perfectly legitimate,
it's easy...
Just-just for one minute,
please.
It's easy, and it makes voting
simpler and quicker, all right?
All you have to do is
turn the plastic pages.
Names and offices appear on the left.
Simply make your choice and push
down firmly in the proper place
with the steel stylus
attached to the vote recorder.
All right? Now, when
you're finished with that,
take out the paper ballot.
And I want you all to check,
check the back of it,
all right, to make sure
that there are no stray bits
of punched-out paper called
"card-hole-aggregate debris."
Or what the, uh, what the folks
down at IBM
like to call "chads."
If I'd have worked
this hard in school,
I'd be on the honor roll.
Hey, you think your brother
will loan us his car again?
Ah, I don't know.
He was cool with it
the first couple times,
but now, I don't know.
I can't do another day
on this awful bus, Coop.
- Me neither.
- I hate it.
Maybe if I was stoned.
Well, yeah, stoned would be good
whether we're on the bus or not.
- Fellas.
- Wade. -Wade.
You guys are on
the Glendale-Pasadena bus today.
Well, no, uh, we were actually
gonna come over here to tell you,
we got a car today, Wade.
Uh, Coop's brother
comes through again.
Really?
Um, just think of
the number of elderly
we can help get
to the polls with a car.
I think we're much more
valuable on our own.
Yeah.
Well, that's great.
Maybe you can persuade them
to go along with you.
Every little bit counts, right?
Uh, what precincts
are you guys covering?
Actually, Dwayne and I
won't be in the field today.
We're gonna stay here
at campaign headquarters.
That way, we can take care
of any problems that come up.
Yeah, we already received a call
about stolen voting machines
down in Precinct 180.
I'm not familiar with that area.
It's a black neighborhood.
Oh, is it?
Yeah, I guess busing
doesn't really agree
with you fellas, huh?
I guess we got more in
common than you think.
Good luck.
Ladies and gentlemen,
if we could get...
Now all we have to do
is actually get a car.
Well, first things first.
First things first.
Mr. Buckley.
Please, Mr. Buckley.
Mr. Buckley, please.
Yes, Miss...?
- Janacek.
- Yes, Miss Janacek.
You told me on Sunday
that I would have my interview
with Senator Kennedy,
but no interview.
Then you said Monday.
Monday, no interview.
Five minutes, Mr. Buckley,
that's all I'm asking...
Miss Janacek, I believe
I also told you
that you have to call
his press secretary.
I left 20 messages
for Mr. Mankiewicz.
Well, perhaps you'd like to
join the volunteers today,
hop on one of the buses.
The only thing I want is five minutes
with Senator Kennedy.
Does he have any idea what's happening
in Czechoslovakia right now?
The censorship law has been repealed.
The people are energized.
Bobby Kennedy is an inspiration
to the Czech people.
Miss Janacek, you are
a Communist writer
for a Communist paper in a country
that is an ally of the Soviet Union.
I mean... do you have any idea
how that would look for the senator?
"Be informed."
"Informados importante. "
"Informados...
importante. "
"Importante. "
It's almost like you just add an "E"
to the end of every
English word. Huh.
Almost.
All right, let's keep going here.
"Employees must be informed
of their right to vote."
"Los empleados deben estar
informados
de derecho de votar. "
I might need some help spelling that.
L-O-S...
Love or money?
Pardon me?
The reason you're getting married.
Love or money?
I'm saving a life,
marrying a boy from my school.
There's a lot of that
going on these days.
The government sends a check
to the spouse for $135 a month.
Mm.
It's definitely not for money.
Well, I married for love.
He was
the most handsome man I had ever seen.
He looked like a movie star.
He could have had any woman
he wanted, and he picked me.
You picked him, too.
Yeah.
Suppose I did.
What color is your dress?
Lavender.
Maybe a bit lighter.
We have polish to match
that, if you like.
Sure.
Yeah?
Big wedding?
No.
No, my father refuses to go.
He calls the shots.
My father's a veteran.
Uh, he thinks William, my groom,
should take whatever tour
they give him.
You see, if he's married,
he goes to Germany.
If not, then, um,
he's more likely to go
straight to the front lines.
My father thinks he's a coward.
What do you think?
You know, more and more
young men keep coming back
in body bags.
Two last week
from my graduating class.
And if I could've married them
and kept them from getting
killed, then I would've.
So, until someone in charge tells me
why it is that we're over there,
then...
I don't know.
You are gonna be the prettiest
June bride in this hotel today, dear.
English and Spanish.
Great.
I've given six years
of my life to this place.
It means everything to me.
I'll give you a fine recommendation.
You're not gonna have any
problems finding another job.
I don't want
another goddamn job, Paul.
Hello.
I don't know if I have
that portfolio with me.
You know, we're three hours
behind you.
Say again.
No, I'm saying
we're three hours in time
behind New York.
I can't say for sure.
Oh, damn.
What is it?
It's nothing.
- What is...?
- It's stupid.
No, no, I'm listening.
You know those black shoes?
What?
I told you it was stupid.
Let me call you back.
I bought this dress to go with
the black shoes I forgot to pack.
I did pack six other pair,
none of them black.
And I have two pair of tennis shoes,
so if you're up
for a little game later...
You see, women have to pack
for every occasion,
making it virtually impossible
to travel light.
Like tonight, it's a formal event,
so I brought formal wear.
But... God has a sense of humor.
So I... I bring backup.
However, I'm doubly screwed.
Two dresses, both black,
and no black shoes.
I know you're probably thinking,
"Who the hell cares what
color shoes she's wearing?"
Believe me, Jack, women notice.
So, basically, you're saying
you need to go shopping.
For shoes.
Black shoes.
At least I don't have to get up
three times a night to go have a pee.
Well, at least I get
out of bed to have one.
Checkmate.
See, when you make a move
out of frustration or anger,
it always ends in catastrophe.
Ah, to beat you just once, Casey.
I'd like to die knowing
that I've beaten you just once.
It's all I pray for, Lord.
Keep praying.
Hey, Paul.
Gentlemen.
Would you like to replace
an elderly gentleman
while he goes off to
take his afternoon nap?
Nelson, if I may...
you could have held
your rook in reserve,
given up one of your pawns
and turned this game
back around in your favor.
Now you tell me.
Hey, Mr. Fallon.
Hey, puppy, come here.
Beautiful girl.
Come here.
She's a beautiful
little thing. Oh, yeah.
How's your wife?
She's perfect.
- We're a sold-out show tonight.
- Yeah?
You and Mrs. Fallon getting
everything you need from my staff?
We are, Paul, thank you.
Jefferson once said
about the United States
that we were the last best hope
for mankind.
That's what I want
the United States to be.
This is a generous
and compassionate country.
That's what I want
this country to stand for.
Not violence, not lawlessness,
not disorder,
but compassion and love and peace.
That's what this country
should stand for.
And that's what I intend to do,
if I'm elected president.
"And that's what I intend to do
if I'm elected president."
- Hey.
Yes?
We were here yesterday.
We...
We purchased some, uh...
Goods.
Goods from you yesterday.
Floor?
Um... four.
Mm. That's where I'm going.
I know you, right?
You, uh, you work here, don't you?
Uh, switchboard.
And you?
Kitchen.
Food and beverage.
Huh. That's got
to beat the pants off
of sitting at the switchboard all day.
Not that I'm complaining.
It's just got to be
more stimulating than:
"Good morning.
Ambassador Hotel.
How may I direct
your call?"
Grass is always greener.
Your job certainly sounds
more exciting than mine.
Well, be my guest.
Today, our brilliant general
manager wants me to let
all the wetbacks know they
can have time off to go vote.
After you.
See you around.
Sure.
Mm...
Anybody see you?
No.
What are you fellas looking for?
We just wanted to get
another joint from you. Um...
Well, what are you...
looking for?
Uh...
Oh, that's my camera.
Just what I said, just another joint.
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
- Oh, okay.
- No.
- Maybe we should split, man...
We could come back tomorr...
What are you looking for?
Um...
I don't...
I don't understand.
You don't understand
because you're not
listening to the words.
You're not listening to the words
in the question, my friend.
Well... if we could just
get our, uh, the joint...
- Okay, why, why?
- Then we could I...
Why?
Why...?
Why do you want a joint?
Why do I want a joint?
- To-to get stoned, man.
- To get stoned.
What's with all your questions?
- Um...
- Okay, okay, okay.
Now...
why do you want to get stoned?
We want to get stoned
because it feels good, man.
Because it feels good?
Bingo! Because it feels good.
Right.
You want to get stoned
because it feels good!
- Right?! Right!
- Right.
- Wrong!
W-What?
Wh... Wr...
Why is that wrong?
Because it's a cop-out, man.
Okay, then can you explain to us
why, for what other reason
than the fact that it feels good
do we want to get stoned, man?
Because...
it's our way...
of getting closer...
to God.
And that is what you're looking for.
Except for you didn't know it...
Yeah.
Until this moment.
I had no idea.
Well, I knew.
Thank God for me, huh?
Absolutely.
So, if we could
just get the joint and...
Are you fellas familiar with
lysergic acid diethylamide?
Hey.
William.
I couldn't sleep last night
and I had to get out of the house.
My folks are driving me nuts.
You gonna invite me in?
Of course.
That dress looks great on you.
You know it's bad luck.
What is?
Well, for the groom to see
the bride in her dress
before the wedding.
Oh. Is that better?
You silly.
Any chance of getting this in earlier?
9:00.
Seems late for a wedding.
Chapel sure is busy for a Tuesday.
It's summertime... June brides.
You didn't have to get me
this room, by the way.
My brother...
my family really appreciates
what you're doing, Diane.
It means a lot to all of us.
To me.
You know, I always thought
my wedding would be
the most exciting day of my life.
Every little girl's fantasy.
A white dress, cake taller than me,
hundreds of guests.
It's just a certificate, Diane.
You can still have all of that.
Yeah.
If marrying you tonight
keeps you from going to Vietnam,
then it's worth it.
Yeah.
Chef's Special, Edward?
Miguel, you know if I could, I would.
Bullshit, man.
I see you serving the brothers
the good stuff.
White folks, too.
You don't see them
eating this dog food.
Lord, today.
Do we have to do this
every day, Miguel?
Every day you keep putting
the brown man down, Edward.
Keeping the brown man down.
I'm putting the brown man down.
That's right.
Let's keep the brown man down.
Let's send the brown man
back across the border
to his sweet senoritas
and his refried beans.
First of all, we didn't
cross the border.
The border crossed us.
And our senoritas are better than
your fried-chicken-eating mama
with the big backyard.
Hey, you smell that?
Look at that... my very own
special berry cobbler,
fresh out of the oven.
But since you had to put
my mama in it, excuse me.
Here you go, Jose, enjoy.
Come on, man.
"Come on, man."
You Mexican boys
can't play the dozens.
I don't know why you keep on, Miguel.
Yeah, man.
Man, what do you know
about the dozens?
I know that I got some
cobbler and you don't.
You're a sellout, man.
- You know.
- Hey.
It's good, ain't it, Jose?
Mm-hmm.
That recipe was handed down
by my great-grandmother.
Mm...
Hey, let me have some of that.
Come on, brother.
We ain't brothers, amigo.
And we ain't amigos,
"bruh-thuh."
Go ahead.
- You, um...
- Mm...
You working a double shift
like the rest of us?
I most certainly am not.
You must be the only one.
Yeah, and you know why.
Why?
Too good-looking for that mess.
You ain't working a double
'cause whitey's afraid
of your black ass, man.
They're afraid you're gonna go
all Huey Newton on them, all violent.
See, they ain't afraid
of us yet, Jose.
Not yet, man, but one day,
one day they will be, man.
We're gonna get the respect
that we deserve.
We're gonna take back California,
take back our land, man.
I want you to park that anger
in my kitchen, young man.
I want you to get your hand
off my shoulder, Negro.
All right, keep it up.
See, the first few times,
I tried to make this dessert,
couldn't get it right.
Too much sugar one time,
not enough sugar the next time,
couldn't find the balance.
I realized I was forcing it.
You know, trying to make it taste
like my mama's or her mama's.
Mine didn't have any poetry,
didn't have any light.
And then I realized
I was trying to force it
to taste like my mother's,
taste like her mother's.
Mm-hmm.
See, it had to be Edward's creation.
It had to come from me.
Now, you, Miguel,
you've got... shit to offer.
You've got no poetry.
You've got no light.
You've got no one
looking at you and saying,
"Damn.
"Look at that Miguel.
I want some of what he's got."
All you got is your anger.
I ain't angry.
I'm sorry, I didn't hear you.
- Come on. Speak up...
- I said I'm not angry!
All right.
You know, I used to be just like you.
I had anger.
And then, after Dr. King
was killed...
well, anger like you
can't even imagine.
White folks ain't trying
to keep you down, Miguel.
White folks just don't like
to be pushed into a corner.
They'll come around.
You just got to make it
look like it was their idea,
like they're the ones
that thought of it.
They need to feel like
they're the great emancipators.
Like it was theirs to give
in the first place.
Let 'em have it.
I mean, if that's all it takes,
let them have it.
Can you dig it?
I know my man Jose
can dig it, can't you?
Yeah.
Hmm.
Edward.
Is that your famous cobbler
I'm smelling down in my office?
Yes, sir, Mr. Timmons.
I just pulled a fresh batch
out of the oven.
I'll make sure some gets
to your office
directly, sir.
"I'll get some sent
to your office directly, sir."
Step-and-fetch-it motherfucker.
Hey.
I'm not working a double shift
today, though, am I... amigo?
LSD was first discovered in 1938.
She can be beautiful.
She can be terrifying.
The difference between
a good trip and a bad trip
is completely contingent upon
your willingness to let go.
Turn yourself over to her completely.
Are you ready to have
a personal relationship with God?
Very well. Open.
Under the tongue.
You figure out what to do
with those Dodger tickets?
I know a few guys
might like to buy them.
I'm not selling them, Miguel.
How many times I got to tell you that?
Hey, what's the face value?
I don't know...
$4.50 apiece.
$4.50? I can get you
ten bucks easy.
I'm not selling them.
I want this whole place
filled with balloons.
I want people having to fight
their way through the balloons
just to get in here.
Balloons don't translate
into more votes, Wade.
But they look better on TV.
McCarthy's not going to want to give
a concession speech after
the big win in Oregon.
They're gonna turn those cameras on
before the polls close,
so we got to look
like we got the thing already won.
It sends a stronger message.
Why are we still standing here?
Let's go!
Dwayne, we need you
upstairs right away.
Socialist.
What's that?
You said I write
for a Communist paper
in a Communist country.
It's a Socialist paper
in a Socialist country.
Red is red, Miss Janacek.
The reforms in my country
are working to put a human face
on Socialism.
See the room we're
standing in right now?
In a few hours,
it's going to be filled
with hundreds of people who are here
either to celebrate a victory
or lament a defeat
because of something
that we have in America
called the democratic process.
Now, if you can tell me
the last time that happened
in your country, I'll give
you your five minutes
with the senator.
Damn right I'm threatening you!
We're not just talking
about a few stolen
voting machines this time!
Do we understand each other?!
Damn it.
What is it?
There's a police checkpoint
outside of a polling place in Watts.
The system's not working
for us... again.
I was watching
the local news yesterday...
and what-what I saw happen
on that motorcade
just gave me hope.
I mean, it's Negroes and Mexicans
by the tens of thousands just
leaping in front of his car,
tearing at his clothes,
ripping at his shoes.
They loved him.
Now that Dr. King is gone...
no one left but Bobby.
No one.
And how did it seem to you
when the senator came
through Prestonsburg?
Oh, it, uh, it's one
of the greatest days
we've ever had in this town...
especially the young people.
They're all crazy about him.
Do you feel any
differently after seeing him?
I feel a little prouder
being an American.
Did you get to see the senator?.
Yes, sir, I did.
How did you feel about it?
Whew. I was very pleased.
I'd just loved to have got
to laid my hand on him.
Senator, you've just about completed
the second day now.
Is there anything significant
that you've learned on this trip?
Well, people, uh, are still having
a very, very difficult time.
There is hunger, considerable hunger
in this part of the country.
There's no real hope for the future
amongst many of these people
who, uh, worked hard
in the coal mines, and now
that the coal mines shut down,
uh, they have no place to go.
There's no hope for the future.
There's no industry moving in.
The men are trained
in government programs
and there's no jobs at the end
of the training program
because of the cutback,
because of the demands
on our federal budget
in Washington and the war
in Vietnam there...
even these training programs
are being cut back,
and so people are being cut off
and they have no place to turn,
and so they're, uh, desperate and...
and filled with despair.
It seems to me that, uh, this country,
as wealthy as we are, that
this is an intolerable condition
that reflects on all of us.
We can do things
all over the rest of the world,
but I think we should do
something for our people here
in our own country.
It's over.
You okay?
You want to talk about it?
Not really.
Sometimes it helps.
Not right now, not this time.
Good afternoon.
Ambassador Hotel.
How may I direct your call?
Connecting to his room, sir.
Have a nice day.
Good afternoon.
Ambassador Hotel.
How may I direct your call?
Please hold.
Come on, girl.
Come on.
It's our summer clearance sale.
Everything must go!
Everything!
That shit, this shit for...
this shit, for sure.
Hey, man, it's okay.
I want you to look at me.
I am.
Through my eyes.
No.
This is painful.
Shut up.
You shut up.
No, you shut up.
See, it comes and it goes.
I can't see.
Okay.
What were you saying?
Hi.
I realized I hadn't prayed
in a long time.
Thought it might be
a good idea, you know?
Well, what are we praying for?
I suppose, whatever you like:
World peace, sick grandparent,
better job.
Do you really believe that
our prayers get answered?
Some do.
I prayed for my brother to come
back from Vietnam in one piece,
and he did.
I guess when a prayer is answered,
it's called a miracle.
Well, in that case, I'm going to pray
that my mother and father
show up tonight.
Now, that would be a miracle.
Mm-hmm.
I remember you saying something
something about a friendly game, John.
Yeah, well, I think that, uh,
chess is a little bit like life.
It scares people, intimidates them,
and that's why they invented checkers.
Hm.
You're still in check.
Story of my life.
What exactly is that story, sir?
Well, it's not what you read
in the gossip mags,
that's for sure.
Mm. Well,
I'm glad of that, then.
I mean, we have our moments,
like any married couple,
but, you know...
Mm-hmm.
But you stay, huh?
Real men stay.
They-they fight the good fight.
They don't leave.
- Yeah.
Your wife?
Oh, she's gone.
She died last year.
Any regrets?
Well, I suppose I could've
spent more time with my kids.
I've got three of them
and eight grandchildren,
and, um...
I suppose I missed out quite a bit,
being here all the time, working here,
I mean.
You know, it has to be said,
in those days, your job was your life
because your-your life
depended on it.
I remember my wife said to me once,
she said, "You know, John,
I think you-you love that hotel
more than you love me."
Perhaps she was right.
And you're still in check.
Oh, hi.
-I think, after five years,
the entire staff knows
we're married, Paul.
-I guess.
So it would probably be safe
to steal a little kiss
now and then.
And you have to eat lunch
more than once every two weeks.
Salad?
Is that all I get?
Yes.
Well, you had a heck of a morning.
Which you slept through.
Hey! My name tag
does not say "manager" on it.
Hey, I'll switch with you.
I'll be the stylist of the stars.
Oh!
And you can start
with Virginia Fallon.
-Okay.
-So sad...
-That woman.
-Tonight's her last show.
She's not booked here
at the Grove until next fall.
Can we go on vacation that week?
Hey, did you vote?
I tried, but the line was too long.
I've got some, um...
it's "yes" on Proposition 1.
That's the Veterans' Bond Act.
"No" on 2.
Mills for supervisor, not Hahn.
Cranston, Sheinbaum.
Of course Bobby.
Also, on the, um...
What?
What? What is it?
Your hair, your suit...
you know, it might say 1968,
but your attitude is pure 1920.
Well, look,
if they don't close the deal
by the end of the day,
then we're out...
Uh, he just came in.
Aw, you're the best.
Thank you.
Good afternoon, Mr. Fallon.
Afternoon, Mario.
Tim, did you know
that Mario's family's from Portofino?
We spent two weeks there last summer.
Tim simply adores it.
He adores...
I had to drag him off the beaches
to go to work.
Can I get you anything
else, Mrs. Fallon?
No, we're fine, Mario.
Thank you.
Oh, Tim, can you give Mario...?
Very well.
Have a nice night
and a wonderful show,
Mrs. Fallon.
Thank you, Mario.
Hello, Tim.
Phil.
Virginia woke up, couldn't find you.
We were nervous.
We were, huh?
Phil has lots to tell you
about Vegas next month, baby.
- That's right.
- Oh, yeah?
Has it changed since
the last time we were there?
Lots of hotels and casinos
in the middle of the desert,
as I remember it.
What, they get rid of gambling?
We booked the Flamingo, Tim.
Four weeks in July!
I booked the Flamingo.
Guys, four weeks in Vegas
in the middle of summer?
That's not a booking.
That's a sentence, Phil.
Tim, come on.
No, no, no, you come on.
Who the hell wants to spend
four weeks in Vegas in July?
I'll tell you who: nobody.
What happened to that picture
that you promised us?
Things are slow at the studios, Tim.
The Vegas deal is a good deal.
Good for who?
Tim, give it a rest.
It's not like you have to perform.
What the hell is this, Virginia?
Well, from the looks of it,
a very fine single malt Scotch, Tim.
Thought we had an agreement.
I haven't had a drink all day.
You've been sleeping all day.
Tim, there is a time and a place...
Hey, you know,
believe it or not, Virginia,
people do eat food
every now and again.
Take your fucking judgment
and check it at the door.
I don't need you to babysit.
You don't want to go to Vegas?
It's too hot?
Well, then, get out.
I'm the reason we have all this,
not you.
- Nobody's saying that you...
- Phil, shut the fuck up!
People come to see me.
People love me.
They love me.
So if I want to have
one fucking drink,
I'm going to have one fucking drink,
because I deserve it.
That's the new agreement, sweetheart.
You have a 5:00
hair appointment.
You're on stage at 9:00 sharp.
You'll have a 45-minute break,
then you're introducing Senator
Kennedy in the Embassy Ballroom.
Try and stay sober enough
to not embarrass us
in front of the next president.
I've heard a rumor
that someone's trying to unload
tickets for tonight's Dodgers game.
It's Drysdale's night.
Tell me about it.
Six consecutive.
He's gonna do it tonight.
Not since 1904... 64 years.
Yeah, I know.
They're yours, man.
But we haven't discussed a price.
There is no price.
Enjoy the game.
You could've just gone, Jose.
And tomorrow... then what?
I would've been out on the
street looking for another job.
That's you.
Little man...
that's you.
The story of King Arthur.
Knights of the Round Table,
Merlin the magician.
You have heard of it, of course.
Yeah.
We read the stories in school.
Then you know that Arthur
wasn't always a king.
He was a young man once, like you.
You, Jose, are a young king.
Kind, caring, humble.
Eager for adventure.
And so... I thank you, humbly,
for these tickets, my young
brother, my young king.
A chivalrous act.
Chivalrous act, indeed.
Hey, Edward.
Hey, save a... save a ticket
stub for me, okay?
You bet I will.
Go, Dodgers.
Yeah.
Ah...
Nice shot.
It's 40-love.
All right.
How come we only play tennis
when we come to Los Angeles?
That was... that was...
I'm s... Bring it in.
We-We gotta discuss.
- Let's talk. Okay.
- We gotta talk.
How long does this stuff last?
I don't know, man.
I am freakin' out right now.
Me, too.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
Play-Play tennis.
14-love.
What's wrong?
Good.
What's the matter, Nelson?
I don't know if it's because of my age
or that I simply can't remember.
I, uh... I keep
losing track of things...
my keys, my cane, my socks.
I don't even know in
what drawer I put my underwear.
I got lost on the way home today.
That's never happened to me before.
No.
Well...
You know, perhaps it's just a phase.
No.
This is no phase, Casey.
It's about growing old.
Old bones, old face, old man.
I hate it.
I hate retirement.
Yeah.
Makes me... feel useless.
Hey, how 'bout a nice cup of tea?
Tea?
Yeah.
Tea is a drink for old white folks.
How 'bout a Scotch?
Well, a Scotch.
I don't know; could be arranged.
Make it a double.
On the rocks.
30% of the precincts in South Dakota
have McCarthy and
Senator Kennedy in a dead heat.
Large gallery,
including several FBI agents...
How long has it been
since you've slept?
I'm tellin' you, man,
there better be some Cabinet
positions in this for us.
I got dibs on Secretary of State.
Hey, you can have it.
I want something with
a little lower profile.
Like Secretary of Transportation.
Sounds a little boring,
but if that's what you want,
you can ask the man yourself.
Okay, I will.
He specifically asked to meet you.
He wants to thank you for all
your help on the campaign.
You're... kidding, right?
He sent word with the advance team.
He asked to meet you.
Yeah, you're okay.
Robert Kennedy and some people
who aren't registered this year.
In ten years,
these Americans will inherit
the problems we don't solve today.
It's suggested that, in
the next several decades,
that people are gonna start
having to wear gas masks
in New York City because, uh,
the air's becoming so polluted.
750 pounds of refuse, uh,
you breathe every year.
And the same thing is true,
to a lesser degree, in cities
all across the United States.
That will spread
to the rural areas, as well,
unless we stop it.
There are things
we can do about automobiles;
There are laws that we can pass
about, uh, dumping
and, uh, throwing refuse
in lakes and streams,
and into the air.
Industry must do something,
and then individual citizens.
And then the demand,
the interest that all of you
might take in it.
And I think that's
what's going to make
the difference in this country.
Mm. I look fat.
You're not fat, I'm fat.
Well, I feel fat.
Maybe it's your swimsuit.
So you do think I look fat.
I didn't say that.
You're being
passive-aggressive.
Please don't do that.
- Don't do what?
- I mean it.
All that headshrinker gibberish.
I never thought you needed to be
fixed in the first place.
It was your idea for me to go.
Because you were sad.
It's called depression, Sam.
Would you keep
your voice down, please.
It's called depression.
I don't understand what you
have to be depressed about.
What do you talk about
in there, anyway?
Well, most of the time, my depression.
Is it me?
Samantha, sweetheart, no.
It's me.
How's your personal relationship
with God comin' along?
It's beautiful.
You?
Me and the Big G
are solid, my brother.
We have to get more of this stuff.
I know.
Planet of the Apes.
Planet of the Apes
on acid would be cool.
Look...
I'm having trouble with...
I'm not sure about this.
About what we're doing.
William.
No, l-I can't help feeling
that I'm taking
something away from you.
Something sacred.
I mean, you should only get
married once, like our parents.
It's not frivolous.
It's not disposable.
Look, I'm okay with this.
I'm okay with it
in my heart and in my head.
And you're not taking
anything away from me.
This is my choice, William.
Christ, Diane,
l-I created a rift
between you and your father.
My father has a problem
with you, not with me.
Well, that makes me feel better.
He's a stubborn man.
Well, look on the bright side...
be getting 135 bucks a month
until the annulment.
What if I don't want an annulment?
What?
Excuse me, miss.
We do have 24-hour room service.
So where are you from?
Czechoslovakia.
That's near the Soviet Union, right?
Have you got a map?
This is a kitchen, not a library.
Man, when was the last time
you had something to eat?
I don't remember.
Slow down.
You're making me nervous.
Czechoslovakia, that's a, um...
Communist country, right?
Socialist.
Socialist, Communist.
I really don't know too
much about that stuff.
Maybe you should pick up
a newspaper sometime,
you wouldn't need a map
to find Czechoslovakia.
Well, wherever it is...
I don't understand why you kill
so many of your own people.
Really?
So, what do you think
you are doing in Vietnam?
So, you want the same as last night,
or something a little special
for the senator?
Ah, you know, I don't care, as
long as it stays out of my face.
Okay.
I have something in mind.
I suppose you're past
getting nervous for a show.
You know, the only thing
that I get nervous about...
is whether anybody's
gonna show up or not.
You're Virginia Fallon.
Of course they'll show.
Yeah, but, you know,
I'm getting older...
and...
people don't care about you
as much when you get older.
Look at you.
You look terrific.
Yeah.
But you know how they call women
"tootsie" or...
"cupcake"?
Anyone ever call you "Twinkie"?
No.
That's right.
And I guarantee you
no one will ever call you Twinkie.
You know why?
Because we don't have
the same shelf life as a Twinkie.
We're like melting...
ice cream cones.
You know what?
I was wondering, like, exactly,
I was thinking,
"When did I grow
that flat spot on my ass?"
Very nice, fellas.
Hey, you want to sit in,
Mr. Fallon?
No, no, no.
I don't play anymore.
Come on, once a drummer...
Come play some music with us.
- Come on up, Tim.
- Come on, man. Go with it, man.
- Come on. Let's hear it.
- Get up here.
What do the guys got up?
I think we have, uh,
"Don't Jive Me Now."
I know that one.
All right!
A-one, two, three, four.
So you can listen to the game tonight.
Oh-ho...
Miguel.
Eh, just don't let Timmons
catch you with it, all right?
Thank you.
Thank you, man.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey.
You know, I never could sing.
- Couldn't carry a tune.
- Ah...
Not even a Christmas carol.
That's fantastic.
My husband was always
trying to get me to sing.
Make a little joke.
Mm-hmm.
At my expense, I suppose.
You know, we're all whores.
All of us.
Just some of us get paid.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
No, that wasn't very nice.
That's fine.
Yeah.
I'm a drunk.
I'm an awful drunk.
I really am.
And I'm an awful person sometimes.
And you seem like a really...
You seem like a really nice lady.
You know, you've been
really nice to me, too.
You have, you've been
really nice with me.
And I'm sorry.
You don't deserve that.
Hey.
I try to do better.
I do.
I try to do better, and...
somehow I just don't do better.
Tonight's a big night.
I'm introducing the senator.
Tim's very excited about that.
That I'm introducing the senator.
-I can't decide.
Those shoes are beautiful,
sir, and they fit her well.
Fine. I'll take those.
Do you want to put 'em on first,
walk around a little bit?
You don't need to know how they feel?
It's not about how they feel,
Jack, it's about how they look.
And they look fabulous.
Okay.
I'll ring 'em up, sir.
What have we done?
What do you mean?
What if Dwayne
is right and Kennedy loses?
We can all forget it, man.
I'm 19, Jimmy.
I don't want to go to Vietnam.
Do you?
No.
I mean, 'cause we fucked off
today, Jim.
You know, we fucked off.
We should've done
what we were supposed to do.
Coop, it's okay.
It's just two guys knocking on doors.
No, it isn't.
McCarthy in New Hampshire
came within 230 votes of Johnson.
230 votes.
We could've knocked
on 230 doors today.
I've knocked on well over
a hundred by myself!
Okay. You know what,
if it makes you feel better,
we can go out, and the polls
will be open for...
It's too late now.
It's too goddamn late.
Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
We can't do anything
anymore. It's too late!
I feel like we should personally
apologize to the man.
We should apologize
for not doing our part.
What if we cost him
the election, man?!
Calm down, man.
You're freakin' me out.
- He's fine.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Are you still high from the acid?
No.
Maybe a little.
We didn't order this.
You guys got to eat something.
Why's that?
Is this the first
time you two have turned on?
Oh, come on, fellas,
your pupils are like saucers.
Wh-What do you know?
You're from Iowa.
Ohio.
What, you think California's
the only place people drop acid?
Was I that obvious?
Got to break her in.
Okay.
Daryl.
What can I do for you?
Kennedy says
if he doesn't win California,
he will drop out of the race
for president.
Oregon voters have given...
Jack?
What?
Do you think I'm more
Jackie or more Ethel?
What do you mean?
If you had to pick one,
who would I be more
like, style-wise:
Jackie Bouvier or Ethel?
Are you serious?
Play along.
And you have to pick one.
Samantha.
What?
When do you feel like Samantha?
Oh, I don't know.
Oh, Jack, it was just a little game.
Come on, it was a game.
What?
Can't keep track.
Of what?
I can't keep track of you.
I'm right here.
You are now.
Samantha.
You're more than the shoes
on your feet
or the designer dress on your back.
You're more than the purse you carry
or the money inside.
You and I are more
than the stuff, more than
the things in our lives.
Somewhere between our things
and our stuff is us.
I don't want to lose us.
I don't want to lose us either.
Knock, knock, knock.
Hello.
So do you work here, young lady?
Well, somebody has to
bring home the bacon.
Aha! You finally admit it.
I am underpaid and undervalued.
Gilliam even with the bag at third.
Parker doing a little housecleaning
down there at first base.
And Drysdale looks in to Haller.
Don into his windup,
the pitch to Pena.
Bunt attempt is missed.
Oh and one.
Shit.
Larry Jackson on deck.
No balls and one strike,
the count to Roberto Pena.
Don working quickly.
What inning?
And the strike one pitch.
Breaking ball over the outside...
Bottom of the fourth.
No hits for Pittsburgh so far.
It took so long
to come to this moment.
May 14: a rather uneventful
one-to-nothing score.
May 18: a one-to-nothing score.
May 22: people started to talk;
A two-to-nothing score.
May 26: they began
to think about it seriously.
And there's a ground ball up
along the first-base line, foul.
Still oh and...
Did you fire Daryl Timmons today?
Yep. He's a racist,
among other things.
What's she like, Paul?
Pardon me?
The woman that you're sleeping with.
What's she like?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
We don't do this.
Other people do this, Paul,
but we don't do this.
You know, people tell me all the time
how... lucky I am
to be married to you.
How wonderful you are.
And I agree.
I say, "Yes...
"he's wonderful.
"Yes...
I am lucky."
Not because I have to.
Because I want to.
'Cause you are wonderful.
And...
And so much more.
You're...
You're strong.
You're a wonderful
father to those kids.
Oh, God.
- Oh, whoa!
- Whoa, whoa!
- Ebbers, you son of a bitch!
- Come on.
- Put 'em up!
- Calm down!
Stop it.
You don't have to wait
till the end of the week!
I wasn't planning on it!
- All right.
Easy. Easy!
Calm down.
All right, back to work.
I wish I could stay.
No, you cherish the fact
there's still someone at home
who worries about you
and, uh, cares about you.
- Cheers for the Scotch.
- Oh, good.
We'll do that more often.
Yeah.
Makes me feel like
I still have a pair.
Of course, our game is another matter.
Yeah, well, you know,
perhaps tomorrow will be
more forgiving.
You've always...
always beat me at chess, John,
- Yeah.
- And you always will.
That's why you play me.
Perhaps you're right.
And tomorrow and tomorrow
and tomorrow.
Good night.
Sleep well.
Say hello to Dorothy.
Yes, I will.
Good night.
Evening, Mr. Casey.
Hey, Morris, how 'bout a coffee
and a bite to eat in the cafe?
Ah, I've-I've got
cats to feed.
Don't you have a home to go to, John?
- See you tomorrow.
- Good night.
- He stepped out.
- Get a picture right there.
- I got it. I got it.
- He's there?
- Senator Kennedy?
- Senator! Senator!
- Senator Kennedy, this way.
- Please, stand back.
- Oh, that's him!
- Hello, sir.
Nice to meet you.
Senator Kennedy.
Welcome to the Ambassador Hotel, sir.
Thank you very much.
- Senator, this way!
- Please, right this way, sir!
Follow us, sir.
Right this way.
- Sir...
- Senator, this way.
This is a CBS News special report
on the California primary.
Here is Walter Cronkite.
Well, as we said a moment ago,
the count may be rather slow
from California tonight.
The voting out there
offers unusual complexities,
not only in the manner
of counting this year
for the first time, but in
the very process of balloting.
CBS News correspondent Mike
Wallace, at our studios here,
can perhaps give us
a little explanation
of that voting and the way
it's being tallied. Mike?
The actual, uh,
vote tabulation, Walter,
is going to be extremely slow,
tonight, in California.
A large part of the state,
including the 7,000 precincts
in Los Angeles County
are using new automated
voting equipment,
where the ballots
are counted by computers.
Now, although on the face of it,
that would seem to indicate
a faster count,
the fact is that the new voting
system is going to be slower
in the count.
Hello, David.
Hey, Wade.
So, Dwayne...
you ready to meet the next
President of the United States?
Come on, he's not gonna bite ya.
Oh, I wouldn't be so sure about that.
Okay.
Go get him.
You'll be fine.
Sample of 89 precincts,
which, together, represent closely
to where the state votes and polls.
As soon as returns are
available from those 89...
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Coconut Grove
proudly presents the lovely,
the talented, the incomparable
Virginia Fallon.
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, yeah.
Swung on, a ground ball wide of third.
It's Blair, has the chance.
-He's done it!
Spring, 1946.
The last free election in my country.
And yet the Communists
still took power.
That's not what
you asked, Mr. Buckley!
The Iron Curtain is coming down.
Dubcek favors greater relations
with the West.
He's the man of the people,
like Senator Kennedy.
I am not going to write
a propaganda piece.
After the senator's speech
in the Embassy Ballroom,
there will be a private press
conference in the Colonial Room.
I will see to it that you
have the proper credentials.
You have your five
minutes, Miss Janacek.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Buckley!
Thank you so much!
Please slow down.
I can barely walk
in these silly shoes.
But they look fabulous.
I don't know your birthday.
August 3.
I don't know a lot about you, Diane.
Your favorite food,
your favorite color.
I don't know
your favorite book or movie.
I don't even know if your belly button
is an innie or an outie.
An innie.
But I'm surprised
you didn't know that.
-Whew!
- Apurate! Apurate!
-Man!
- Chingale, man, you think
they could use the same
glasses more than once?
It is packed in there.
There's got to be over
a thousand people.
Rapido, rapido!
Gentlemen.
How was it out there?
It was fantastic.
Yeah, we dropped acid
and went to the movies.
Planet of the Apes on acid?
You got to try it, it's...
Tidings of great joy.
Test one, two. Test one, two.
Ladies and gentlemen, could
I have your attention, please?
Please, ladies and gentlemen,
could I have your attention?
We have an announcement
that we would like to make.
With 16% of precincts now reporting...
Why don't you go ahead and read this?
Future Secretary of Transportation,
Dwayne Clark, ladies and gentlemen.
With over 16% of the precincts
now reporting...
I recognize his voice.
He's cute.
Hey... my love life is the one
that needs some attention.
Of the United States,
Senator Robert F. Kennedy.
You look wonderful.
Thank you.
Let's see 'em.
- Good girl.
- Thanks.
This must be the...
the lucky man.
Miriam, meet my husband, William.
- Nice to meet you.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Excuse me...
Aren't you a little young to be
Secretary of Transportation?
I'm gonna strangle him.
I recognize your voice.
Really.
Do you work for the FBI?
You're the young brother
from 506 that's always
yelling and always angry.
I'd recognize it anywhere.
So you do work for the FBI.
I'm a switchboard operator
for the hotel.
Patricia.
What's your name, angry young brother?
Dwayne.
I'm not always angry.
I need another box.
Jose, come on with the box.
I'm-I'm coming.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I'm coming.
How in the hell
are we supposed to work
with all these people here?
I don't know, but I ain't never seen
so many white people
in the kitchen before.
- Hey, Susan.
- Hey.
How are my little drug addicts?
I don't think I have ever
seen you out of your uniform.
But we've both fantasized
about it before.
He's still high.
- He's still high.
- No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
You're the one who's still high.
I'm a stockbroker.
I'm an artist.
As well as a patron of the arts.
She bought a painting
of a can of soup last month.
A can of soup.
Mm-hmm. I think it
was Campbell's tomato.
- Yes.
- No, onion.
Tomato.
She says tomato, I say onion.
It's an original Warhol.
Do you know he was shot yesterday?
And probably by someone
who sobered up and realized
they paid a fortune for
a picture of a can of soup.
You're terrible.
May I ask you a personal question?
How personal you want to get?
I'm not asking to embarrass you
or anything, but...
how much do you make a week?
These folks ain't interested
in eating.
Besides, they gonna
throw it away anyway.
Yeah.
I'm not proud, Dwayne.
I'm just another sister
trying to survive in the world.
No, you're much more than that.
This one looks pretty good.
The board behind me shows
the story from
the California primary tonight.
There's still just
a scattering of votes in,
but our vote-profile
analysis of, uh,
key precincts through the state,
representative "key-cincts"...
precincts... indicate
that Senator Kennedy
is going to come out with a wide lead,
probably 52 to 38 percent
over Senator McCarthy.
RFK! RFK!
RFK! RFK! RFK! RFK!
Ladies and gentlemen...
RFK! RFK!
Senator Robert F. Kennedy.
RFK! RFK! RFK! RFK! RFK!
We want Kennedy!
I want to, uh, first, uh,
express my, uh, high regard
to, uh, Don Drysdale...
who pitched his, uh,
sixth straight shutout tonight.
And I hope that we have his
good fortune in our campaign.
What I think is quite clear
is that we can work together,
in the last analysis,
and that what has been going on
within the United States
over the period
of the last three years...
the divisions, the violence, the
disenchantment with our society,
the divisions, whether it's
between blacks and whites,
between the poor and the more
affluent or between age groups
or on the war in Vietnam... that
we can start to work together.
We are a great country,
and a selfless country,
and a compassionate country.
And I intend to make that
my basis for running,
then, over the period
of the next few months.
Bobby! Yeah!
So, uh, my thanks to all of you.
And now it's on to Chicago
and let's win there.
Thank you very much.
Whoo!
It's impossible to hear tonight.
Robert Kennedy's victory is
setting up a possible showdown
in the general election
with Richard Nixon,
who his brother defeated
eight years ago.
We want Bobby!
We want Bobby! We want Bobby!
- Bobby!
Bobby!
We want Bobby.
We want Bobby. We want Bobby.
- Hey, Bobby!
- Bobby!
- Bobby! Bobby!
- Where you going?
I wanna shake his hand.
You don't wanna shake his hand?
Bobby!
Senator, this way,
through the kitchen.
Senator, follow me.
No, no, wait, Senator.
- Bobby!
- Hey!
William! William!
-Hey!
We want Bobby.
We want Bobby. We want Bobby.
Please, right this way, sir.
Follow us, sir.
This way.
This way, through the kitchen.
Bobby! Bobby!
Bobby! Bobby! Bobby!
Bobby!
Bobby! Bobby!
- Bobby!
Kennedy, you son of a bitch.
Get the gun.
Get the gun. Get the gun.
Stay away from the gun.
- Stay away from the gun.
- Get a doctor!
Keep them out!
His hand is frozen.
Take ahold of his thumb
and break it if you have to!
Get his thumb!
Excuse me. Excuse me!
Hold him! Hold him! Hold him!
Get a doctor for the senator!
We don't want another Oswald!
Senator!
Wade! Wade! Excuse me, Wade!
Excuse me! Sir, move!
He's been shot!
-What?! What?!
Excuse me.
Wade! What happened?
-Someone shot him!
What?
Excuse me!
Excuse me! I'm with...
Ladies and gentlemen, could I
have your attention please?
Ladies and gentlemen, can I
ask you please to be calm?
We need a doctor to come
to the podium right now.
- Please, everybody...
- Bobby's shot?
- Please, just be calm.
And if you can,
please leave the ballroom.
We need a doctor to the podium
right now!
Please. Is there a doctor
in the house? We need you...
It is not a day for politics.
I have saved this one opportunity...
I've been shot!
My only event of today...
To speak briefly to you
about the mindless menace
of violence in America,
- which again stains our land
-Can you help me?!
- and every one of our lives.
-Can you help me? Please.
It is not the concern of any one race.
-Doctor! Anyone!
- The victims of the violence
are black and white, rich and poor,
young and old, famous and unknown.
They are, most important
of all, human beings
whom other human beings
loved and needed.
- What happened, do you know?
- Somebody said he's been shot.
No one, no matter where he lives
- or what he does...
-Get a doctor, please!
Can be certain who next will suffer
from some senseless act of bloodshed.
And yet it goes on and on
and on in this country of ours.
It's okay. It's okay. Plea...!
Why?
-You'll be okay.
What has violence ever accomplished?
What has it ever created?
Oh! Oh. Oh, my God!
Dear.
Help!
Whenever any American's life
is taken by another American
unnecessarily...
William, come on!
Whether it is done
in the name of the law
or in defiance of the law,
by one man or by a gang,
in cold blood or in passion...
I've been shot.
In an attack of violence
or in response to violence,
whenever we tear at the fabric
of our lives
which another man has painfully
and clumsily
woven for himself and his children,
whenever we do this, then
the whole nation is degraded.
Yet we seemingly tolerate
a rising level of violence
that ignores our common humanity
and our claims to civilization alike.
Hey, Donny, what the heck's going on?
Senator Kennedy's been shot.
Too often, we honor swagger
and bluster and the wielders of force.
Too often, we excuse those
who are willing
to build their own lives
on the shattered dreams
of other human beings.
But this much is clear:
Violence breeds violence,
repression breeds retaliation,
and only a cleansing
of our whole society
can remove this sickness
from our souls.
For when you teach a man to
hate and to fear his brother,
when you teach that he is a lesser man
because of his color or his beliefs
or the policies that he pursues...
when you teach
that those who differ from you
threaten your freedom or your job
or your home or your family,
then you also learn
to confront others,
-All right, Captain...
- Not as fellow citizens,
but as enemies.
To be met not with cooperation,
but with conquest.
To be subjugated and to be mastered.
We learn, at the last, to look
at our brothers as aliens.
Alien men with whom we share
a city, but not a community.
Men bound to us in common dwelling,
but not in a common effort.
Is impossible to believe...
We learn to share only a common fear,
only a common desire
to retreat from each other.
Only a common impulse to meet
disagreement with force.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, baby.
You're gonna be okay.
Do you hear me?
You're gonna be okay, sweetie.
Our lives on this planet
- are too short.
-Jimmy! Look at me.
- The work to be done
-Cooper!
Is too great
to let this spirit flourish
any longer in this land of ours.
Of course, we cannot
banish it with a program
nor with a resolution...
but we can perhaps remember,
if only for a time,
that those who live with us
are our brothers,
that they share with us
the same short moment of life,
that they seek, as do we,
nothing but the chance
to live out their lives
in purpose and in happiness,
winning what satisfaction
and fulfillment that they can.
Surely, this bond of common fate,
surely, this bond of common goals
can begin to teach us something.
Surely, we can learn, at the least,
to look around at those of us,
of our fellow men,
and surely, we can begin
to work a little harder
to bind up the wounds among us
and to become, in our hearts,
brothers and countrymen once again.