What follows is a movie and
if it seems strange already...
...you'll have to wait,
cause everyone can see that.
You may only see my reflection,
but believe me...
...this movie is not worth
the reflection of a moment.
This fiw is a comedy, therefore harmless.
No preaching, no teaching.
Just a fun way to spend time.
Why not be playfull with art?
Here we have an efficient
unemployed actor
...who miraculously got a job.
A very special job.
“We finally meet.
I’m the president of the company”.
“ I’m the president of the company”.
“I authorized Mr Ravn
to close the deal”.
“Hello again”...
Optional.
-Kristoffer? Are you nervous?
-No
Let’s get it over with it.
Sign that you wont reveal a thing.
You said you’ve never wrote a play?
May I ask why? Your prose is
well formed and strong.
-But it says too much.
-Really?
I hoped you’d say as little as possible.
The penalty is heavy but
that’s the law for you..
The most important thing
is to keep it a secret.
-A Secret?
-You must be used to it.
You do not shot someone on stage
and say “it’s not for real” to the audience.
I’m not so sure.
This phrase would easily fit
a non-character created by Gambini.
-I’m your man Ravn.
-Perfect. You’d be the boss.
I’m a bit pushy...
...because no one
can see the real boss.
We have to act now.
Icelanders are really pressing.
It wont take too long...
...and you’ll make a bundle...
...a good thing since you’re
out of work. Sign here.
I’m not taking the job just to work.
-It’s nothing illegal.
-I don’t care if it is or not.
I’m an actor.
The character is my law
and the script my courtroom
Courtroom?
Let’s hope we won’t end up there.
Perfect...
Here’s your pay.
-What’s on your forehead?
-Ash.
I always rely on Gambini.
Never fails.
“The Hanged Cat?”
The chimney sweepers monologue…
...from “City Without Chimneys”.
-Do you know it?
-I know only the  “First Cat”.
“Reluctantly I made
a long journey to this town”
Our president cannot
have ash on his forehead.
A character is formed
by the elements he lacks.
Theatre unfolds beyond
the point where a play ends.
Don’t make me nervous Kristoffer.
Lets keep things simple.
I endow my character
with a tribute to Gambini.
It doesn’t matter.
You’ll be my boss only for a second.
Then there are the pauses.
Pivotal to our comprehension of the play.
He even could speak no words at all.
You have to say what’s on the page.
Otherwise what’s the point.
Only what’s on the page.
We finally meet.
I’m the company president.
I finally found him.
-This is Finnur...
-Finner... Finor...
We finally meet.
I’m the company president.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
We finally meet.
I’m the company president.
You’re both company presidents.
But for two different companies.
Why Danish people talk so much?
That’s why the country is at an
intellectual dead-end for 200 years.
They either talk too much
or are way too sentimental.
The rest of the time they
just laugh idiotically.
For God’s sake, let’s begin Mr Ravn.
Dear Mr. president...
...and I’m referring to our own president...
We’re happy to at least have one.
I want to say this...
Our president asked to be
excluded from the negotiations.
Did I understand that right?
Price is our priority
and we have already agreed on that.
And we have already agreed on that.
.
I have...
...authorized...
...Mr...
...Ravn.
Excuse me...
I didn’t got that.
The pauses got me confused.
Could you repeat it a bit faster?
I authorized Mr. Ravn.
When the president decides something,
you can’t change his mind .
Mr president...
Way too many presidents.
Should we call ours the Dane president?
Icelander or Dane, it’s the same thing
-400 years of Icelandic occupation .
-It was the other way round.
It didn’t feltl like that to us.
I’d better return to the USA.
Just because I’m signing on the 12th...
...it doesn’t mean that I can’t have fun.
Fucking Danes!
You wont get away that easy!
You’re all talk.
Thankfully our sagas
taught us those words.
He who negotiates with straw men...
...negotiates with nobody.
Goodbye.
I insist that your president ..
...should meet me on the 12th.
Not his straw man.
He has to be here that week…
... or there’s no deal.
My lawyers will contact you.
Goodbye then... Optional.
We finally meet.
I’m the company’s president.
Damn!
They shouldn’t have seen you!
-The news will travel.
-They know I’m fake.
-They didn’t tell Finnur ...
-That’s not thw problem. .
They were shocked because
they believed you were the president.
I played the part good.
Even though you gave me no clues.
It’s the interpretation that matters.
Likeness doesn’t play that big a part.
They’ve never seen him.
-They’ve never seen him?
-No.
-I do not understand.
-If I wasn’t that scared...
A company needs a president.
But I didn’t had it in me.
I couldn’t see myself like that.
When I started the company
I told them I was just an employee.
That the president had many companies
and that he lived in the states.
It sounds strange and suspicious.
A boss I invented.
Everything was perfect till the moment
that someone wanted to talk to him.
And now it’s this fucking Icelander.
He trusts nobody.
Absurd...
They called Gambini absurd as well.
Listen... I told you I’m your man.
I’m not just anybody.
I’m an actor.
That’s what you need
so that this thing will work out.
It’s only a week.
I’ll make a contract..
-There’s no need for it.
-I’m doing it as a hobby.
This deal is vital for the company.
Even the slightest doubt...
I can sense doubt in my audiences mind.
-You’ll meet the staff.
-It’s all part of the job.
-If you tell anyone, you’re dead!
-Stop making a fuss.
Heidi A.?
Could you call the managers?
I want you to meet someone.
These are the six people I started with.
He’s here finally...
The boss of it all.
He’ll spend a week with us in Denmark.
Maybe because, deep down he’s still a Dane.
And maybe he feels
that he has…if not “abandon”…
...surely neglected our firm.
Yes that’s understandable.
It’s understandable.
Yes,  that  is understandable.
So you have a lot to talk about.
I think I’ll just retreat…
...and crawl back to my desk.
Any questions
What is your name?
-My name?
-Yes
Everybody calls you
The boss of it all”.
Some of the girls had the hounour...
...to receive a mail with specific instructions.
I want to make clear
that I randomly chose…
... the people I was contacting with
all these years.
I have no preferenaces.
My god ... You have to be very carefull.
-His name is Svend.
-Svend E.
That was the name on the e-mails.
What does  Å  stands for?
I didn’t write it?
Didn’t Ravn tell you what it is?
In all these ten years?
Never?
Thatt’ good news because it means...
...that I can say I have a name I like...
...and I’m proud of it.
Eker....
Ekersberg.
Svend Ekersberg
-How should we address you?
-Gorm would like to call you Svend.
Gorm can calls me by any name he likes.
He can even call me Kristoffer.
Why call you Kristoffer?
Why should he do that?
Why on earth he should do that?
-Please call me Svend.
-Ok Svend.
I would like to say one thing.
Autumn in the country is gloomy.
Really gloomy!
I want you to know that.
People believe that autumn is refreshing.
No, Gorm!
-Are you done?
-Everything’s ok?
-Yes. Sorry.
Everything’s fine
Stop!
That was a strong hit!
I’m afraid that you’ll have to apologize.
Apologize to him?
Don’t forget the tech meeting tomorrow.
Tech meeting...
Ravn...
They’re all completely crazy
-We have to speak.
-On neutral ground!
If my character’s name is Svend for instance…
...that’s something I would like to know.
-I want to be informed.
-Of course.
Name do not really matter.
Gorm is from the country.
Sometimes he’s suffering from depression
-But he’s very good with Brooker.
-What the hell is that?
It’s our flagship.
Our best seller.
That’s what got us started.
The hero doesn’t like
crying, shouting, or hitting.
My private space was violated.
I’ll insist on gaining control.
They have to respect me.
The Six Managers
can become a pain.
They’re the creative team
of our company.
I’ve no idea from actor’s psychology
but it must be the same thing more or less.
So things are really that bad?
I love them a lot although
they can be really hard to deal with.
It’s not that bad as in Slagelsi in 1992.
I had to speak to the women
in the audience after the show.
I had no idea they knew
their theatre in Slagelsi.
-What’s Wrong?
-It’s my distant look.
-It must be scary.
-Yes it’s effective.
The Six are far more hostile
than what expected.
Tech meeting sounds like trouble.
Tell me what you do, so I can have an idea.
IT .
I cant understand those stuff!
No way!
Thank god you’re
such a good actor then.
Now you’re ready.
Take control.
O?k
It’s quite a shock when the
copying machine starts working.
Luckily it doesn’t happen often.
Only 1 .000 ötimes per day.
How’s the weather in the country today?
Lets suppose...
...it’s wintry like all over the land.
Are you looking for your office?
It’ll be safer here than walking around.
Safe?
What do you mean?
To find me, since I visit so rarely.
You want to see them?  I told them to wait.
I’ll let them know.
-Thanks.
- Jokumsen is waiting outside.
I don’t know how he found out you’re here.
He has filed a complained since a long time.
I’m not sure if anyone ever spoke
with him after that.
Should we schedule him after the meeting?
Sorry. It had the boss’ role when you were not here.
Lets start with the directors vision.
I would like to hear more
about our goals.
I studied the philosophy of the company.
Some strategic and technical measures
are not clear..
Transactions hierarchy. Why not?
Rule 8020: direct development.
It’s just a small part of necessary conditions.
...to provide IT support
on an adequate level .
Apart form these fucking terms...
...how does the boss determine
the hierarchy of the transactions?
And rule 8020? I may have missed
something, but what it is exactly?
”Direct development”
can be defined in 7 or 8 ways .
How do you define it?
Define... I’m tempted to say “dictate”.
There’s a tenuous difference
between the two.
And it all ends on the boss’ will to dictate.
Or the boss’s knowledge of what this company is about.
-Of course I do.
-What is it then?
-What
-What do we do in this company then?
Haven’t you prepared a presentation?
What do we do?
-This and that. Stuff..
-Like?
Hi there.
I have an announcement to make.
Nalle, why the long face?
Come on...
Smile a little...
And a little hug...
What is the nature of your announcement Ravn?
Our trip to Kullen is cancelled.
We were to go since we didn’t go last year.
-Quiet Spencer.
-Make it so we can go.
I’m afraid the order comes from high above.
I know it shows a
strict attitude against staff
I’m sure there must be a reason.
We don’t go because the Boss of it All said no.
“The Boss of it All said no”.
What’s new?
Why don’t we pick up and just go?
-Be good Gorm.
-You’re not good with us.
We all agree we would be better off without the boss.
Let’s not spoil the good atmosphere.
It’s my fault.
The point is not if the boss is strict or not.
Let’s here what Svend has to say.
Svend?
C’mon Svend.
We study sales reports. Usually not
at tech meetings though.
Can you tell us if you saw the sales reports?
-Of course I did.
-And what do you think?
They’re shit.
Finally it’s out in the open.
They’re shit..
They’re crap.
Turds and feces.
We should change the course of this ship.
These numbers should better improve.
-Finally it’s out in the open...
-Come on Mette…
The numbers look fine on your e-mails.
Did Mette say they’re good?
All that I can say mette...
...is that they’re not good enough.
They’re very far from good.
-Mette is crying again.
-Relax Mette
They’re only numbers.
They’re Outside. You want to see Lise and Spencer
or  Jokumsen
Everybody, apart from Jokumsen.
His complaint is just.  .
-Lise is our HR representative.
- Of course why not?
Spencer has something to say...
-No more.
-No more...
We won’t tolerate no more...
-These ...
-Working Conditions.
It’s easier for me to say it since you can’t.
He means “working conditions”.
Our working conditions are terrible
as well as policy.
Other companies have perks, bonuses.
Here’s a list.
Would you mind going Heidi?
Out of the office.
So you relate to other companies as well?
I would be naive to believe...
...that the market is made
from small businesses only.
With “Hell’s Rangers” on your shoulder...
...your needs demand special care.
But you don’t have to talk about that..
HR...
Human Resources.
You’ve been away so long..
...you can’t remember the meaning of it.
I’ll check the translation in english.
You can tell me.
You can spit it all out.
I talked it over with the others
You’ re not reliable.
Your personality betrays you.
You’ re not the one you pretend to be.
I think you should say the truth.
You believe it’s the right move at this point?
You really believe that?
It wouldn’t make a difference.
It’s obvious.
Your lines show no reliability.
You’re a bad actor from beginning to end.
“My lines show no reliability”
You’re overdoing it.
You called me “a bad actor”
Then the audience is convulsed.
They don’t understand
that the point in comedy today...
...it’s the revelation of it.
Destruction stroke.
We’re close to the end.
People today want everything
to be reliable and normal.
Well things are not really like that, now!
-Yoy have a reliability problem
-I don’t.
-You do
-I don’t
I don’t know a lot about you,
but I know what you’re not.
So tell me what I’m not damn it!
A faggot.
-A faggot?
-Yew faggot.
It’s not as much that you’re trying
to convince me that you’re a fag
...as that you’re pretending you
don’t remember what IT means..
...or, management or HR.
“Hell’s Rangers”!
Come on now!
Of course you’re an expert.
How else you would have managed?
-I’m I right?
-Yes.
Why would you believe
that I’m a fag?
You were sending me e-mails
To drive me apart.
-Ravn made me realize it.
-What would I win that way?
The same thing you win by acting
Stupid in you business.
To look interesting or
to make us feel pitty for you.
You got that last thing right.
You pretended you didn’t know what IT is.
I admit that was a bit far fetched.
-But I am a fag.
-You don’t look like one.
Some of us are this way.
I’m not trying to convince you.
I’m sorry about that
I’m a fag since the day I was born.
You cant explain something like that.
Better to be a fag than to be unlaoved.
I can tell you why you like men.
You haven’t met the right woman yet.
On neutral ground.
Now!
I’m tired of walking in the dark.
I have no control over things.
It would have been much easier if I knew
What I said or wrote in the past.
Faggot?
You could have told me!
-Damn it Ravn
-You’re right
Only Lise’s president is a fag.
You’ve told each other different stuff?
I know...
-You told them different things?
-I understood the question.
Are you completely stupid?
I was creating positive energy.
Everybody feels you close to them.
That’s what I mean
-And the IT thing? I really can’t get what it is.
-Me neither
-You’re doing great.
-You really thing so?
Keep it up for a few more days.
Listen to my advise.
Don’t take it so seriously.
All those stuff about taking control, are ok…
...but it would be easier if you didn’t try.
Let the audience do the hard work.
You wont stress yourself that way.
Say “yes”. When they come to you,
Say “yes”
It may not be that artistic but it works.
Say “yes”? That’ improvisational theatre.
Just like when some jerk wants
to put on a dress…
...and we all have to cheer.
Gambini didn’t believe in that.
For him improvisation was a bow to drama.
He was the first to understand Ibsen.
Ibsen was an idiot.
Incapable to grab disaster by the throat.
Why don’t you go straight to soap operas?
With their sentimentality and all the fucking cliches?
“It’s au revoir, not goodbye” and bullshit like these.
-these are bullshit
-definitely.
Relax.
Sorry. You should know.
Its your role. Your idea.
And ideas are god.
Even Hitler’s ideas
If you want improvisation
and acting you got it.
I’ll say yes till you’re sick of it.
But not to Jokumsen.
He has a just complaint for six years now..
Why didn’t he came six years ago?
He did, but the Boss of it all
Was away that day
-Ok
-And what about the IT terminology?
When they say “exhaust our resources”
they mean “outsourcing”.
Easy as a pie.
The results of our structural unit...
...are better than what we expected.
We have to slow down the process.
We have to add more authentications.
Exhausting are resources seems like a great idea...
Excuse me...
You mean outsourcing...
You said exaust our resources
but you meant outsourcing.
Of cource.
Thank you Svend
So what does the boss say?
Do we have thegreen light?
-Yes or no?
-I can answer that.
We all do. “If it’s cheaper by 1/3 we go ahead”.
Is Nalle right?
The Boss of it all spoke.
You had to sabotage Nalle.
Disgrace him in front of everybody
You’re a bastard
I am.
Lets get up.
And a big hug
00So sweet. Like a baby.
But no, babies mean reproduction..
...and that requires fucking people
of the opposite sex. .
If you have a question
or want to ask something…
...then the answer may be “yes” .
May I say something?
Me or anyone else?
They can say “yes”...
...or yes, or yes, or yes.
-That’s enough Svend. Got it?
-Yes.
You’d better!
Enough with your faggoty shit.
I know when somebody likes me.
-You are a big tease.
-Yes.
Those e-mails... “Be good with Ravn, take care of him”
-was to make me fall for you..
-Yes
Fun is nice but there are
bigger fishes to fry.
-I don’t care.
-Yes.
-As long as you’re in control?
-Yes
Here and now.
The sooner the better.
Chauvinist pig.
You won’t fuck me till
I blow you good first.
An now on the desk..
That s how things are.
-Yes
-Right?
You like it better
when I’m like that?.
Don’t get confused there are two holes..
-Yes
-Right.
That’s why the call you
big boss then.
You’re a bastard.
Is that all you can say?
You know Gambini?
Who?
You look tired.
I told Yokumsen that
he couldn’t see you today
I told him to try again next week.
Is that okay.
-of course because I wont be here then.
-You’re leaving again?
Thanks from the letters from all over the world.
They meant a lot to me.
And I answered all of them.
Except from one.
Yes right.
There was one you didn’t answer.
Why didn’t you?
-You want to talk about it now?
-I’m here aren’t i?
That’s true.
You always joke about stuff
Sometimes I get confused.
I don’t know if you’re joking
Why you believe I was joking.
I couldn’t have been something else.
If it wasn t a joke what would you tell me.
I think you know.
No I don’t.
That’s why I ask
-if it wasn’t a joke?
-Yes.
I’d say “yes”
It’s absurd.
We don’t know each other at all.
You don’t seem very thrilled with my “yes”.
Sorry. Its stupid of me.
I’m ashamed.
That’s why I didn’t wrote back.
Naturally ... it was a joke.
Yes and a funny one.
I’m so stupid.
I thought it was for real.
Sorry. I’m blushing
I think that...
...the fact that you would say “yes” its perfect. .
Not many people would.
I respect you for that
Perfect…
Can we forget about it now/
I cant believe that I was so vague
that you were doubting me.
I don’t do those things.
Its not my character.
Sometimes we ask just for fun..
...in case that one day we’ll have to ask for real..
I thought there was real romance here.
Come now!
You think that I’m hiding my intentions...
...and fishing for answers out of fear?
You think the big boss would do something like that?
A man is a man, a word is a word...
...and a boss is a boss.
I didn’t built an empire by running away..
Heidi A.! I remember this e-mail clearly.
You ask me if I meant it
and the answer is “yes”
And the question still stands.
Gasping is right.
-I’m happy.
-If you’re happy, I’m happy too.
You didn’t do it for stopping from resigning?
Of course not. What does it have to do with this?
And I didn’t resign. I stayed with you.
-That’s what you did.
-Because of your e-mail
It’s time for the boss to go home.
I’m glad we resolved this matter happily.
You seem as if something is bothering you.
-Everything will be alright.
-I’m glad you meant it.
Especially since you know so little about me.
Isn’t something you would like to know?
Of course there is Heidi A.
What does the “A” stands for?
Not that it matters.
Because now it will become Heidi E.
Heide Ekersberg
Okay then...
No! When everything was going fine.
An intermission. Why?
And don’t get me started
on that vulgar, awkward zoom
Here’s a statement.
There is no comedy without an intermission.
We have to supply vitamins,
even if we are reluctant.
Who wants to be the doctor who with
A syringe at hand....
...will disrupt a childs play?
Well, that would be me.
I feel obliged to introduce a new hero.
The boss is horny.
There might still exist a bit of ...
...homosexuality
On this dick.
The boss will be right there.
How are the returns today honey?
Not bad at all honey.
-You don’t work for this company
-Neither do you.
I don’t remember ever seeing you
That happy..
But we’ve only been married 5 years.
Or was it 50?
Were you ever happy?
Only when you spoke about Gambini.
This phony that no one has ever heard of.
A phony wouldn’t stage plays
in seven big theaters.
With a Gambini play,
fiasco is unavoidable.
Who have heard of an one act play
That lasts 3 hours?
The Chimney Sweepers Monologue.
Too Christmassy for my taste.
-That’s why I couldn’t stand you.
-I couldn’t stand you either.
-Why not?
-Peanuts.
Yu ate them with the husk
I’ve only seen such a thing in cartoons.
It used to drive me crazy.
I bet you want something from me.
-You came to win me back?
-I don’t want you back
You came for something else then.
You’re very lively.
You must have got a promotion.
I’m Finnur Sigurdson’s lawyer.
Capitalism!
Weren’t you supposed to use your degree
to fight guys like him?
Yeah that was the plan.
Finnur mentioned me,
You didn’t notice.
Life is like a Dogma film.
It’s hard to hear what they say,
But the words remain important.
I don’t think that the president
will be present tomorrow…
... to meet with my client.
I had my doubts, but I know
Yoy’re not the president.
Couldn’t I be the big boss?
Like the chimney sweeper
in a town without chimneys.
-Always with ashes on the forehead.
-you could be wrong.
I have much more inside me
That what you’ve ever saw.
-But you haven’t have you?
-No
Not according to what
they teach you in law school.
What we learn there
were more tangible.
So are you the real president
or not.
Okay, I’m just an impersonator.
But I can’t talk. I signed a cotract
not to reveal anything.
With Ravn?
He has were he wants you.
He’s an expert on contracts.
Would you tell on me?
I would ten years ago, when you
were just staring as an actor
-But I see you like the part.
-I’m good at it.
That’s what it looks like.
And you don’t have the luxury to deny a role..
It’s against your beliefs to control things
-You only want some attention.
-I control the company.
So the real owner can do his job.
As the lawyers say “acquitted
due to stupidity”.
And you are stupid if you believe Ravn
Ravn is okay.
We go along fine.
He likes the job but
hasn’t got the will to be the boss
He’s a pussy but he’s not meen.
He abuses the system to work
everybody to the bone.
By blaming someone else
you get to be the nice guy.
-And what’s it to you?
-Nothing
But I saw a spark of dignity in you.
You’re not as bad as youwould like Kristoffer.
For a moment I thought that
you considered the moral aspects.
Ravn’s deals are good for the company
And the people.
This is a good opportunity for his work.
So since you like Ravn so much...
...i guess that he has informed his people...
...that their jobs is the subject
of tomorrows meeting.
-Ravn is selling the company?
-Yes. It’s that simple.
You didn’t do it .
You didn’t manipulated me.
You were a gentleman.
Even when I left the company
For a competitor.
You put pressure o Ravn a few times..
He was really sad
after one of your phonecalls.
I’ve got to go downstairs…
...to make some photocopies.
Do you feel that somebody else
Has been manipulated?
Not me, but Gorm does.
It was a big hit for him.
The fact that you didn’t had him work
on the Brooker platform.
He was working for to years on the other platform..
How can you talk about brooker?
It’s ours.
It’s not me who talks but Nalle.
You weren’t fair.
You told him he was unprepaired...
...you knew he wouldn’t take it nicely
Can I ask you a question in English
Danish...
No, danish.
You stopped his Danish lessons...
...so he couldn’t chit chat around.
-he could do it in English
-yes but he didn’t wanted to.
And me... You had me answer to Ravn.
But it dint do you any good..
-And Ravn?
-Our sweet teddy bear?
You cant but love him, even though he’s pathetic.
I shouldn’t mention his economic state..
-How do you Know?
-he told us.
We decided to lend him 25.000 each.
Not that it helped.
-Why not?
-he hasn’t paid us back
And then there’s poor Mette.
You know what happened
After you fire her husband.
-No I don’t
-He hang himself
With the printer’s cord.
He couldn’t stand not being a part of it.
He was begging to come back.
Ravn told us about the letters he sent you.
There was no place for him really.
That’s life I guess.
-And now Mette is in that state.
-Where is she?
At the photocopies room I guess.
Elizabette, is the printer working?
There you are?.
All lies.
There’s rumors in every workplace.
I deserve some credit
for starting the company.
There 150.000 was not a part of it
Of course they were.
They all lent you money,
and you started the company.
-You make it sound bad.
-You can say that again!
I run the company, you’re the actor.
Ask your part if the pieces fit.
I did it and I’m afraid they do.
If I’m such an asshole...
...they better sell and get rid of me. .
We’ll have to sign an authorization.
I’ll guarantee the lowest price
so you’ll sell for less.
Kristoffer shouldn’t sell for nothing.
-Don’t I get a copy?
-If you insist...
I’m no better or worse
than anybody else
-I’m not sure.
-I feel misunderstood.
I give and give but what do I get back?
Almost nothing.
Not exactly peanuts.
Strindberg was misunderstood too.
People talked behind his back
all the time.
They were saying he pushed
his wife down the stairs.
-And he didn’t?
-Of Course he did.
But that doesn’t make him
a bad writer.
Here’s my account number.
You’ll find it usefull.
The Norwegians wont be carrying
Money on them.
It’s not an account number. It’s the price.
It’s right for you.
That’s the vale of your company sir.
Should we sign?
Here…
I caution you...
...in two points in the text.
The ones that refer to the personnel. .
Allright .
I trust you completely.
The personnel will stay right?
We didn’t agree that.
We won’t inherit a bunch of fucking Danes.
Mr Ravn is the only one that will stay.
I also edited out some parts...
...regarding selling the Brooker 5
patent by mr Ravn
What are the other stockholders getting?
Nothing
Mr Ravn has the exclusive rights.
The Six believe they also have rights.
Emotionally yes, by law no.
They worked to make it
but that was part of their job..
Excuse me for a second.
Some fresh air is always good.
It’s moving really, but
you can’t really do anything.
If I don’t sell to Finnur I’ll find someone else..
You wont win by selling cheap.
Come...
-Mr President...
-Lets close the deal.
It was about time.
It’s sad to have to part it.
But Ravn knows
I’m a businessman at heart
Lets talk business.
I had started to like this place.
It was my stage for all these years.
Nice thoughts but get it over with.
We have to sign.
Thanks Ravn. Always helpful.
At your service. Sign here.
I’ll take my finger
so you can sign.
Wouldn’t you agree mr Finnur.
Mr Ravn always helps.
I do not share your Danish sentimentality.
All is left is my signature.
Just one note for the person who
drafted this contact.
The numbering does not go
in the middle of the page.
I don’t know how you do things in Iceland.
It’s not the page number, it’s the price.
My copy says 245 million.
That’s what we agreed on.
I can’t sell a life’s work at that price.
You understand.
How much more
would the president want?
-More.
-How Much?
50 cents
It’s just a symbolic amount.
As a businessman I need to feel
like I made a profit.
We speak of free will,
but we need the machine.
The machine that wants gold..
Sometimes just a crumb can fill you up.
We’ll have to draft the contracts again..
We can do it by hand..
I know it’s a professional disagreement.
But if I can get
50 cents more…
...i can get 50 million more as well.
Mr Finnur?
Finnur?
There it is
“The town Without Chimneys”
It was always here.
All fit together at this moment...
...to be blown apart
by a Gambinian explosion.
Unfortunately Gambini
didn’t write our little comedy.
His contempt would have made
the genre unrecgnisable.
No I adhere to to rules of the genre.
As beautiful as may be
the sight of two men...
...who ask nothing of each other...
...we know tey’re men with demands..
These demands have to be satisfied
before we leave this room..
An with clear conscience
we’ll forget what we saw..
Why the hell didn’t you sign?
I understand your question.
Really?
The amount was huge.
You’re getting on my nerves.
-I’m bored of your changing moods.
-You’re firing them
You didn’t mention that.
You’re robbing them blind.
Brooker 5, whatever it is...
You’re getting on my nerves.
You’re the company’s lawyer
and their friend.
You should have told them
to draft contracts.
The don’t even suspect
they will be losing their jobs.
-It’s very hard..
-You don’t say!
Lets do this deal.
That’s what I wanted to do
But I’m willing to make a trade.
Confess! Admit you’re
sucking their blood..
-I promise you.
-I don’t trust you.
All that you did was to fool me.
Sign the promise that you will confess...
...stealing their money and firing them.
I did my best.
I’m not happy signing something
Idea is god.
You said it.
Even if the writer was Hitler.
I didn’t know then that Hitler
Was indeed a writer..
If you mean it that
you’re confessing sign.
At the highest price
so no more tricks.
Shut up over there!
Today is a very hard day.
I decided to tell you something...
...that I should have told you long ago..
I cant do that...
-You don’t have to say it.
-let him finish.
I have to say it..
Who’s never letting us down?
Ravn.
In whose arms we sink?
Ravn’s
Who owns the crown?
Ravn
You’re all so tender.
This makes it worse.
If it’s so important, get it over with..
-You’ll be angry.
-Even more so if you don’t say it.
I had a plan.
What plan?
To fire all six of you.
Excuse me?
I would fire you without
compensating you for Brooker 5.
Nice Plan
Damn it Rvan
Damn!
Can I ask something
before we all attack him?
Why did you plan this?
Why fire us?
-Why steel Brooker?
-Because...
Yes?
Because...
...That’s what the Boss of it all said.
We should have known it.
He haven’t got the guts
to tell us himself.
-Autumn is gloomy...
-Gorm...
-Autumn is gloomy.
-Stop it!
Aytumn is fucking gloomy!
Gorm. Stop it!
I haven’t got the guts
They have a memory...
...just like...
An elephant’s?
Yes. I lay at night and see their eyes..
You talk of forgiveness!
They’ll never forgive me.
Pour Mette is the worst. .
Nothing of what I’ll say
Will be good enough for that girl.
I’m such a pussy!
They will not forgive you
If you don’t confess.
We have a contract.
“I promise to confess”.
-Who signed it?
-I confessed my plan.
And said it was mine.
That’s not a confession.
-I didn’t mean that.
-Why it’s not on the contarct?
Unfirunately for you,
law is an exact science.
Therefore I demand...
...to honour your contract and sell.
I’ll arrange a last meeting with Finnur.
I wouldn’t want you at work.
I told them you’re in the states…
...till the day of the signing.
It’s me . We have to meet on neutral ground.
Legally you can’t touch him.
You have to sell.
-It will be a disaster.
-Yes.
But he almost confessed right?
Being hard befits you .
You’re right.
I’m better at making people nervous.
What is biggest fear?
Not being loved.
That what all this is about.
He wants to be papa bear, or
he’s not functioning properly.
So you’ll became papa bear.
Do what Ravn did, only better.
Morning.
Do you have space for little me?
Ravn!
Sit with us.
The more the merrier.
We thought you were in the states.
I cans see my friends there all the time..
But with my most precious friends...
...can only spend two more days.
-Right Ravn?
-Yes..
Two more days in our family’s bosom.
Autumn is a time bomb.
Speaking of bombs
I have a confession to make.
Things got excited the last time.
If I tell you why I came back
you’ll see that you were wrong about me.
-You’re a bastard.
-Possibly
But not in the way you think
I’ve been hiding things from you.
Now everything is better, thanks.
I wasn’t alone in doing so.
Someone else was at the helm.
This person should step forward.
He’s someone above me. My boss..
-This is getting complicated.
-And who’s this guy?
He’s...
...the boss of the Boss of it all.
This is really getting complex.
Can someone tell me
what does this all means?
No.
So where’s the boss of the big boss?
In the states.
No surprise here.
So you’re not the one taking the decisions.
I’ll have to disappoint Jokumsen here..
All his anger, as well as your anger...
... is finding another target now.
I’m glad to hear that.
You’re a good guy. I knew it from the start.
We should have known about these things.
As the boss’s representative ...
...i apologize for the Brooker thing.
Because you were right from the beginning.
You can’t but love this guy, right?
And to cheer you up even more...
...our staff trip to Kullen
Will take place tommorrow.
Perfect!
Lets spend a nice day togeher.
How about a group hug? Come Ravn
What are you expecting to succeed?
Nothing. Just to have some fun.
Here we are.
Palnatoke was saying to Harald, how good a skier he is.
“iI you’re that good ski all the way to Kullen”
-And he did. From here.
-And then?
-I haven’t read further.
-Human Mistake. You’re evolving
And now Palnatoke
will do a demonstration…
...of his unique style..
What happened to your hand?
It’s my wrist.
It went numb.
I’m afraid it will relapse.
We’ll fix it soon.
To the kindest of all men.
To Svend.
To our new best friend.
To he who gets 11 out of 10..
More brandy please..
I cant take it anymore.
They’re all parasites!
I’ll say it to the boss of the big boss.
Look how you spend his money!
You mane me sick.
You found a way out..
You’re extremely insipid. To put it mildly.
You need insipid theatre
You can sink lower.
Chamber realism, sentimentalism…
...and cliches all around.
Will you come?
It’s time. Come on.
-Why did you come to the meeting?
-Because the boss of it all...
Because the boss told you to come.
In five minutes we’ll be in our cars.
-Do we have an agreement this time/
-Yes
-Both on the price and the conditions?
-Yes.
-Lets sign.
-yes.
Now that it’s all settled...
...let me send a message...
These dates are all wrong. Shame!
I’ll correct them. Sorry..
...a message.
On the anniversary of aunt Titi
and uncle karl
...they set aside money in an old sock.
They’ve been saving every day of their lives.
In here...
...we’ve been saving every day for 10 years.
It’s the day for aunt Titi and unkle Karl...
...as it will come to us once this party is over..
We’ll wake up one day, well reach out…
...and there, there will be nothing but air.
And you...
...and you...
...and both of us...
...and this three people we’re only a saga.
You that you were once my whole life...
...and me that once I was your’s...
...we’ll never hold hands again.
And for whom is this message?
For hir who curses himself for his
wrongdoings before anyone else does so.
And who always forgives
our errors first..
-Who do I mean?
-Ravn...
-Louder!
-Ravn.
You carried us in your heart Ravn.
You brought us close.
You spread your love..
And now you go...
...like a bubble in the water...
...to move on to great things.
We can promise you one thing.
By begging or biting
faraway or close...
...you’ll always have a place in our hearts...
...on this happy and green earth.
Always.
You were always there for us.
But who was there for you?
But learn this,
just like the swallows on the roofs,
...this is not goodbye,
but au revoir.
Thanks for your words.
Let them be the last.
Thanks for the sentimentality,
That was so hideous…
...that no one would take it seriously.
You have something to say Mr Ravn
Is there something we didn’t notice?
Tell us Mr Ravn
II a the boss of it all.
Its my company.
I make the decisions
Gorm is right.
He’s right.
Autumn is gloomy.
Really gloomy.
Unbearably so.
I’m sorry.
Thanks Ravn.
Was that so hard to say?
I always knew that you were the boss.
You should have been stupid
not to know.
I forgive you Ravn
Come on.
Get up.
All the way.
So what about this signature.?
You’re selling or what?
There is a problem here.
How can Kristoffer sell
something that doesn’t belong to him?
Mr Sigursdon, there can be no selling.
The company is more united than ever.
Even more now that all belong to the past..
I have to start outsourcing.
Exhausting our resources.
You said outsourcing, the right
expression is exhaust the resources.
What you’re doing now
is even more irritating.
You forget the actor.
Right. Sorry.
I have to acknowledge
that he made me confess..
-Everything happened thanks to you..
-It’s all good...
...but things don’t work like this..
You don’t jump from hell to “...happily ever after”.
A certain procedure must be followed..
You’re right!
Let’s cancel the contracts right now.
And you resign from your right to sell.
-No.
-What?
No. No. No.
There are restrictions you cannot nullify.
We are not interested in the deal anymore...
...since the one signing it is not the boss.
Having read our Sagas my client knows
...that he who negotiates with straw men...
...negotiates with nobody.
My client remembered some newer scriptures...
...that indicate a new understanding.
The right translation would be ...
He who negotiates with someone not authorised...
...negotiates with nobody.
My client believes that the man with the pen...
...has the authorization, so he is okay with it.
What’s going on Kristoffer?
Everything’s happening just like you wanted.
More or less.
-You’re not going to sign?
-This is above me.
I’m just an actor.
If I sign or not is up to my character.
I’ll have to ask him.
It’s your character whose to blame for all this.
It will probably a quick affair.
I need time and space to consult my character.
After all he’s the Boss of it All.
What is happening?
His feelings are conflicted. He’s an actor.
He couldn’t have Rvan get all the attention.
He’s putting on a show now that everybody’s looking.
I hope so…
No! Wait a sec.
I cant make contact.
I hear the boss saying something.
And then it can be something else.
Quiet back there!
You have to put life in your material.
What are your character’s values?
Its exciting.
And to be absolutely true...
... I have no idea.
Likes and dislikes go hand in hand.
I’ll listen some more.
I got it!
Almost there, but my sympathies...
...seem to lie with Ravn and his staff..
Shitty Danes !
Our damn babbling made us
suffer for 400 years.
Is this idiot going to sign or not.
I hate Danish people!
What was that last thing?
He said the whole thing was absurd.
Absurd like...
Gambini.
Gambini?
Antonio Stavro Gambini
“The Hanged Cat”.
One act play, 1969
Some say late 1968…
Shit!
Forget about it it’s Gambini’s fault.
The chimney sweepers monologue.
And here we are at the point were we reach...
...the end of our comedy.
Just like you, I would like to go home...
...but I would like to apologize...
...to those who wanted more and to those who wanted less.
They who got what they wanted,
got what they deserved…
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/4q7ff
Help other users to choose the best subtitles