MEZHRABPOMRUS 1927
THE GIRL WITH THE HAT BOX
Natasha Korostelyova and her grandfather
lived in a small house in Moscow's suburb.
Natasha and her grandfather
made hats at home.
I'm afraid, Natashenka,
that you'll soon fly away from me!
You mean marriage?
Don't be afraid!...
Every morning Natasha brought
the ordered hats to Moscow...
From his remote village
Ilya Snegiryov was coming
to Moscow dreaming to enter
the worker's faculty.
MADAME IRENE, HATS, was the shop
for which Natasha worked.
Marfushka, the shop owner's servant.
Madam, the house committee is here!
One of the apartment's rooms of Mrs Irene
was registered under Natasha's name but
it was in fact occupied by Nikolay
Matveevich Trager, Irene's husband.
And where's Natalya Korostelyova,
the tenant registered here?
Darling, you should spend
the night here sometimes!
The house committee
is bothering us again!
I'd like to know your turnover.
I'm the tax assessor.
Idiot! It's the tax assessor!
In search of housing.
Excuse me, is there a room
for rent anywhere?
Ilya Snegiryov spent all nights
at the railway stations.
For heaven's sake,
what do you want from me?
Excuse me, I...
Incidentally...  dropped a rouble...
searched... I have nowhere to sleep...
What were you dreaming of, Natasha?
Poor boy,
he has no place to sleep.
In search of another meeting.
Madame Irene's home
was preparing to receive guests.
I can get you a room if you want.
Ilya Snegiryov. small farmer.
Single...
...Married.
Natalya Korostelyova. Milliner.
Single...
...Married.
You asked, I got it fixed : here is
my husband!  He's gonna live in my room.
I'll let nobody in! Though you're registered
in this room, it is not yours!
You'd better not offend my wife!
Is it her room or not?
Where is it?
Well, here's our tenant...
and she's just got married!...
May I ask you to go
into the next room!
It's falling.
Good-bye "husband"!
I'll visit you some day...
The first night went perfectly.
Mr and Mrs Trager declare war.
I declare that tenant Natasha Korostelyova,
de facto, doesn't intend to inhabit her room.
On the basis of all above mentioned
it is obvious that Ilya Snegiryov,
inhabiting the room, turns out to be
her so-called husband and, thereby,
is entitled to be evicted from the apartment
that I'm responsible for.    N. Trager
Nothing, but lottery bond...
Irene darling! give me some money...
I'm broke! heads and tails...
You're still indebted to me
for my work.
Pay this trollop!
STATE LOTTERY LOAN
Stop singing!
Madame, the house committee
has come to see the new tenant!
And where is your, so to speak, wife?
I'm here!
Lend me 30 kopecks for the return ticket
till tomorrow...
Fogelev still hoped that
Natasha would come with the last train.
I'm late for the last train!
...The last train swept
his last hope away...
Aren't you sleeping?
Yes, I am!
I'm afraid! A mouse is running!
My God! A rat!
In the morning...
Let's listen now to the first winning numbers
of the state lottery loan...
10.000 roubles prize goes to
the bond 7219, serial number 05...
25.000 roubles prize...
goes to the bond n° 1419963,
serial number 03...
Natasha's address! Quick!
She won 25.000 roubles
with my lottery bond!
Natasha's address!!
Working with a round jack.
Going to the station for a newspaper...
I love you!
Natashka, marry me!
Give me back the bond!
It is a dear souvenir to me...
I left it in Ilya's room.
Here's your bond!
You won 25.000 roubles!
Farewell...
I wanted to say...
I agree, I'll...
... be your wife!
Now I don't agree!...
Farewell!
I request to dissolve my marriage
with citizen N. P. Korostelyova,
she won 25.000 roubles
and people could consider
that I'd married her for money.
Ilya Snegiryov
I agree - - - -
Your wife wanted money instead of bond...
It's for me the uttermost pleasure!
The lottery bond is in her hands!
Give me back the bond!
Before it's too late, Fogelev decided
to make an offer to Natasha.
Sign the divorce petition...
I DO NOT agree - - -
Why are you making fun of me?
- - - N. Korostelyova
Here's your bond!
Idiot! Go and buy one hundred bonds!
THE END