Marriage Affairs.
Do not touch
It all started 20 years ago,
in the Plaza hotel in the month of June
Two mothers were with
their daughters, Liv and Emma
here for a cup of tea
That afternoon was
a wedding instead
There was something blue, something borrowed
and something completely magical.
And two little girls from New Jersey
had a new dream
Once they discover that a
person on their side would ...
whatever happened.
And when the time comes ...
they will also get married in the Plaza
Thank you
And yes, Your Honor,
this neglected man
I knew my marriage is the most beautiful
day of my life
Now I want a creature until we have
six children and a house
They allow pets in the Plaza?
It is not that we marry
until we are sixteen, at least six times
- Can I be the bride?
- Emma, you know I always play the bride
- Not too shabbily,
- Cocktails, cigars, operation with white apron
- dancers and video recordings
- Great DJ
So we give them
that ? it is beautiful
- But ...
- Is this the work of Marion St. Claire?
Marion has one vision
- If my marriage was ...
- Say it
- It is not June
- And not the Plaza
- It is the elephant in the room
- Yes
- And here are you
- Check it out
A duck made of ice, is not
great? You know what else is great?
We asked to go home
and look to your TiVo
Am I so predictable?
Another dance, then give
I give you my piece of cake
- If you let me go.
- Very funny.
- Come on.
- You know I always go.
Hello girls
Are you ready for this
bridal bouquet to catch?
- I gotta go.
- I'm so glad you all ...
- On the other hand, I always won.
- I know, we take it so seriously.
My work, my friends around
My friends from school
My heavens, Emma Allen,
is that the same dress ...
you contributed to the gamma delta benefit
presentation one trillion years ago?
- Yes
- What does it matter?
Because it is a classic piece,
which you've worked hard.
Look, this is love and faith.
Friends for coming together, I like that
Keep it up
- Anyway, are you ready?
- Yes!
Remember just feel it and catch it.
One ...
Two ...
Three.
I would have seen the signs,
as I had been.
It was all there.
Look at Emma's eyes.
As a hunter and Liv her hand,
how does it feel around your throat?
Not that they can imagine
that they are hurting right now.
Why should they?
- 20 years are inseparable .
- Okay, just slow down.
- I walk better with iPods .
- You can not run with iPods ...
because iPods are for people who
not have their own thoughts.
I literally walk circles around you
The only thing I can think about
is how I am a disaster
- Did you like this kind of conversation, I am hurt .
- I gotta go.
- Bye, I love you .
- Tell me how the meeting went
The energy increase
- Hey, you have the changes been?
- I read it in the taxi
It seems that the whole town is mad at Liv
A bold approach to dezwakheden use of ...
the affairs of our clients
I think we legally strong,
especially when we have a verdict sheets
Thanks, Liv.
Our best partner
Maybe your approach to brutal?
If we strike,
they will not bite soon
You know me not,
but I know you
You just know
how hard you want to win
Because if we do not
You're right, she is perfect
- Miss Allen.
- Robert, how are you?
- I think Miss Delgado you are looking for.
- Is that so? Was she in the neighborhood?
She is in the room
- There you are, Emma.
- My God, hello.
Is not it beautiful?
I feel so good in this body.
- No, I'm already too late.
- No, no, you gotta help me.
Remember the debate team.
I can not go to finals.
Children who talk about their problems
- You should be in my place.
- I do buscontrole late already and ...
cheerleaders and nablijvers.
You're the debate Adviser
and I do not think I ...
I do so much, I wish
the minimum I could do.
- I admire you so.
- Thanks
Anyway,
this is how we do
I appreciate the debate team and ...
You take all my study guidance on
on Tuesday, for the rest of the year
- You know that ...
- No
Well then, you owe me 't chalk
From the road, children!
You know why they do.
You are the best teacher there ...
therefore gives you a lot of work.
Your school is a jungle.
I do not know, she's quite sad.
She has been divorced three times.
It is far for us,
where our divorce?
I must first get married.
I hate Daniel.
No, Kevin, I have an emergency.
- What is your emergency?
- Code Name 'I talk to you later. "
- So, I understand what you do with me.
- Watch, Sun.
- They fit perfectly with you.
- Is not it too tight?
No, not at all. But this ...
Yellow is not your color.
Really.
But try this
Because you know what,
love it.
It was not me.
Of course not, because it is
my size and it is new
This is the subject of
I see you last week said
- Liv, I can not ...
- Bought in the sale.
- I have actually removed money.
- It is too much.
Thank me, Emma.
Thanks, it's beautiful.
I like it.
Well, and now this. Emma her stuff.
Let's disposal.
You look like hundred years ago.
- Daniel's pull, right?
- Yes, love it.
- A square box.
- You become engaged.
We are engaged!
- My heavens, Emma.
- No, stop it.
No, stop.
Excuse me.
But you should see your face,
if you ring for the first time see.
Good thought.
You always think of others.
This is not even to me.
Sometimes, but ...
I am very happy for you.
Promise me that no one tells you,
before he makes his proposal.
I would never do.
I am not crazy.
Engaged!
- We get four Tequila Shots?
- No.
No, not me.
I have enough.
Acapulco 2006, Emma and Fletcher,
great.
We 're not
talk about that weekend?
That is so romantic,
confused and very thirsty.
- Please.
- Well, stop, please.
- A dean at Liv.
- Congratulations, friend.
And sympathy for Emma
Liv's bridesmaid.
They will certainly the best 'nightmare
bride' who ever lived
- It is my burden and ...
- I give you a favor back.
- Why are you here?
- I married.
- You are kidding?
- Yes.
My sister is married.
Where is the groom?
- He is not here.
- He has not really asked.
A dean at Daniel.
That late in his own world, but in
Livs world did not offer.
Let God bless him.
That he is in life
my sister is living ...
in any world.
Yes, I love you.
- He has a lot of luck.
- Yes, the biggest day of your life.
- Should I go?
- I do it.
I mean they could not see
how I graduated.
Law, or the first story
in the journal read.
And I can not
with them.
I wish your parents
also allowed to them
Whatever, it's good
I'm fine.
You're only human,
you should not have for each other ...
every minute of the day.
Former fat girls, just like me.
Fortunately we survived.
You were not fat.
Yes, you survived.
- Thank you, Em.
- Sure, Liv.
- You will be a good bridesmaid.
- Yeah, right.
- But I am first.
- First?
You may have first
get a proposal?
- You really have an eye for detail.
- Really? I know.
Honey, I think the fortune cookies not.
Wait, I have them here.
Good.
pleaze
I take it out. This guy must really go.
Sorry, I know how much he may.
- He is very vague.
- This is not real.
Vague. say you
someone you can not.
You are vague.
That was me.
- Please?
- You really choose?
- Yes, he was on my side.
- That is not very ...
- Yours is better than mine, which I take.
- I do not think so.
Are you ready?
A ...
- Two ...
- Three.
What is this?
I have long thought, how I
this was done.
And I wanted to do here,
this is our home.
And when I'm 99 years, and we
doing the same here at home.
Television, chinese food ...
Then that is good enough.
- Emma Allen, will you marry me?
- Yes.
It did not happen, but I
not worried because Daniel ...
I'm engaged.
Fletcher made his proposal ...
about two minutes ago.
- I'm engaged.
- Color?
- Colorless.
- Sliced?
- Brilliant.
- Brightness?
- Slightly shiny.
- Carat?
Almost or just under ...
More than he could pay.
Engaged?
Liv is engaged.
Both engaged ...
This is ...
I gotta go.
What do you mean, that Emma is engaged?
No, why would not I be happy?
That is great.
No, you should not come.
I'm okay, I do not eat.
And I have the perfect wedding gift.
You have to live
by Emma and Fletcher.
You annoys me.
I can not believe it,
so weird that I got him.
- The glistening even in the rain.
- Dazzle.
I think I want  DJ Humple on my party
But is not that weird?
- No, you do.
- I'm not as for large groups.
- Well, it's your wedding.
- My mother can not organize the wedding.
She is too busy.
I got you, right?
- Yes, I'm so excited.
- You coming to meet her?
- Sorry, what? Who?
- Marion St. Claire.
Have you not heard?
I have an appointment on Friday.
You already made an appointment?
You're just yesterday engaged.
I know, but I am
already behind.
You must book early,
Plaza if you want.
The Plaza? Unbelievable.
What is wrong?
Why are you angry?
I'm not mad at you. I just said
why is there until about Daniel.
Heaven, I'm sorry.
I had not ...
- We do not need to talk.
- Do not worry about me.
Do not worry about Daniel,
we are so engaged.
- I'll call you later.
- What do you do? Let him do.
Excuse me.
- Honey, faith now agree with me.
- Good.
- Will you not married?
- Can we talk later?
You changed mind,
I saw the Tiffany box in the closet.
Yeah, right
My heaven ...
It is not a ring?
If the chain is, usually I
suicide and I take you.
Can you tell me now,
it is something you want?
- Wil you marry?
- You know what I will say?
I've never been so unpleasant,
complex, dominant ...
beautiful, smart, sexy
woman in my life and ...
you only had to wait
this evening ...
Well, I'm in love with a woman,
who has no patience ...
Keep you a little while?
- Yes.
What all is good,
as long as I my whole life ...
may seek to keep.
Wil you marry me?
You will make a proposal?
Really?
Honey, that is so unexpected.
- Shut up, yes or no?
Yes!
If I had not planned.
- Are you serious?
I love "make you hot
women to work 'day.
Complete.
And that brought these two brides
at my house that afternoon.
No, not now.
Forward.
I'm back in order.
I'm Marion St. Claire,
the most famous wedding planner in Manhattan.
Hi, we have an appointment for an hour.
We both married and
each other bridesmaid.
You are kidding,
that is incredible.
Ms. St. Claire can you
now received.
I'm Emma Allen.
- What an honor!
Put yours.
- Roger.
A wedding marks the first day,
for the rest of your life.
You were dead, until now.
You realized that?
You are now dead.
I understand.
- For example, Angela ...
will guarantee death.
I read the letter that they
you wrote about.
Two wedding in the Plaza.
Is there not a small possibility?
- If you went somewhere else ...
no chance.
But you're here.
Call me Dreamcatcher, I reply.
Dreamcatcher.
I happened to have
three options in the Plaza ...
in June.
Two first Saturday.
And last Saturday,
the sixth and 27th.
My parents their wedding anniversary
the sixth, it must.
My heaven.
- Yes.
Then I take the 27th.
- Fantastic.
Wil you discuss with your bruidegommen?
- No.
Okay, sign here and put
the date here.
This feels very good.
We need to discuss themes.
- Very little text.
And trendy fusion.
I am impressed.
- Really?
We love you.
Busted.
Your next customer is here.
- Thanks.
Very much.
- There are still front brochures for you.
Bride to bride, there is still
a room in June, at the Plaza.
Thank you, you are so sweet.
Mrs. St. Claire, first,
I'm obsessed by you
It is an honor ...
- Get down.
Yes.
- In June!
Watch them go, so blissful ignorance
of the difficulties ...
their marriage appointment.
June was three and
a half months removed.
A simple nod in marriage time.
My dear!
Miss Wang.
A corselet, ten layers of tulle ...
You have to adapt.
- No.
I am wearing my mother's dress.
- Emma, are you sure?
This is nice, but
her or your dream?
It is mine,
I want to surprise her.
But it is your day, send her
a box of chocolate on Mother.
And buy the dress you want?
- She is really beautiful.
And I love strapless.
It is as if I dress
my mother fraudulent.
I can not do
I think my decision.
Hang it back.
But if you want
you must apply again.
No, you saw him first.
- A terrible reason.
We apply this, right?
- I am fit.
It is perfect.
I know. Right?
I must continue to search.
- If there is a better than Vera Wang?
Hang it there, in addition to what
better than chocolate?
Buy the dress simply.
- What if you change your mind?
You must be careful with weight gain
for a wedding ...
you change so that he no Vera you fit
you change yourself into a Vera them.
Now seriously, I lost control?
See these eyes?
You know what that is?
Focus.
That's right.
Well, lenses and focus.
I buy it.
- Fantastic.
I get you some champagne.
Marion.
There is a terrible mistake.
A mistake never to
Marion St. Claire happened.
Your marriage has been made on the same day.
Say that again?
What?
Your wedding is booked for the same day.
Fl ...
- Are you crazy?
The Plaza is our life dream.
Angela confused the dates.
You are both on June 6 and
the other bride on June 27.
The next date is June 15.
- Well, that take me.
Within three years.
This is ...
- I can not ...
It is not a problem.
I consultations.
Production is my work, I rule that
the bride of date changes.
Believe me, you can not no
at that face.
Yes, but by trust obligation
I can not say who she is.
Which of you two choose
another date?
I am leaving now, Miss St. Claire.
- Good advice to you ...
use me as reference.
Hello, Angela.
- Tell us any other bride who is ...
and nobody touched injured.
How are you?
- You look beautiful.
You have been covered.
- You want me to adjust my date?
Yes.
- No.
You take the sixth,
give me the 27th ...
and it is your marriage partner.
- I have your fun, really.
Do not touch me.
- Let's talk.
Each marriage has a cost,
what is yours?
You can not buy.
- So again a thousand times no.
Good luck, ladies.
There is something wrong with you.
You is not leaving,
you until your ...
Only just the date.
Are you crazy?
- I think you're crazy.
You do not want to date once you adjust.
This is unnecessary.
- Will you.
Come on, a pleasant day.
We can sue.
We can sue them all,
the Plaza, the Marriott, all, and Angela.
That is not good.
It is up to us.
I want you on my marriage,
how this uitdraait ...
should any of us
take a different date.
Definitely.
I want you on my wedding, of course.
If we find no other way,
will any of us need to be flexible.
Someone of us should date change.
Right, that's a possibility.
Perhaps not one of us,
already ten years earn ...
because they compared with others
a hunger loontje deserves.
Where.
If the other of us,
not so desperate at the Plaza would ...
because the Plaza is the only pleasant
memory of her youth.
That is ...
- True.
Someone of us should date his herzetten.
- It will for sure.
And until one of us decided
we can not make concrete plans.
Agreed, there is some time
before we conclude.
Let's just do nothing.
Until someone's date herzet.
Talk to you soon.
Someone we call the other.
She has not called me.
They must date it.
She was always flexible, though as a child,
you know not?
Yes, she sounds not so flexible
I think.
Fletch I called and they took on.
He does my taxes tomorrow.
- You can not best friends.
Not now. Daniel can you
taxes yet do?
He is in finance.
- It is a 'hedge fund', honey.
We do not financially together.
- He is my accountant ...
for six years already, I will.
Do not be ridiculous.
Just do a double wedding.
- We are no 41-year-old twins.
Honey, a double wedding.
This is a great idea.
A great party.
No, I have my whole
life shared with Liv ...
I wish for once a date alone.
I know. Is this all the guest list?
- They are on the shoebox, no idea.
It is my dream
in the Plaza to marry.
I have been saving for my 16th.
I have only a few days,
so I find another dream.
It has better reasons than me.
- It's like 'American Idol' ...
Liv is the Simon ...
I mean nothing.
But you are Paula.
Even if they can not sing ...
give them a compliment about their clothes.
That is good.
But anyone listening to Simon.
- I would not marry Simon.
Give me Paula.
That is beautiful.
- Choose something ...
and find something. - Therefore, I
a bridesmaid. You may not care.
If you want to compete,
you know what to do.
The sooner the better.
We must let our guests know.
Exactly, so I kept the date back.
You do not worry.
- There is not.
Well, take your phone on it.
- Hello.
Men.
- Hey, Fletch.
No, not much. Only our
invitations to the rescue.
Is tomorrow still?
- Yes, you have some progress?
Liv is already there?
- No, she does not really admit.
They have a week more.
This is a century in the women's world.
What do they do with weddings?
- I have no idea.
Just the wrong time for your husband
to know that you are crazy.
Do you?
So I would not tackle.
She is here, I see you tomorrow?
Hi.
- Hello, darling.
How did the cheerleaders?
- I hate it.
I hate for teenage girls
insist on anything.
Aggressive, as if nothing else.
I call Liv.
Really?
- Yes.
Amie and Marissa will jointly
that party for us, and ...
it will be good for everything
behind us to have.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
Yes, I agree.
I spoke to Daniel, she is alone.
You can call her, they are
their invitations to save or something.
What?
Call her.
You must know real date ...
for you to send invitations.
We would wait.
And she ...
I believe it hardly.
Can you not believe?
It is Liv hear.
She wants to be the first.
- No, not this time.
I am also a bride.
I am also number one.
You're my number one.
If I think about it.
What are you doing?
Subject: Emergency,
this is not spam.
I go get married, six in June.
- You should not push so hard.
The Plaza hotel.
Be there ... XOXOKJA, SD
Address book. To everyone,
no, not you Liv. And send.
Emergency,
this is not spam.
I go get married, six in June.
KJA?
What is KJA, Emma?
'Great, Emma's wedding is
better than ours are, Glenn.
Perhaps our marriage
even better.
Not filled with loneliness and sorrow.
I hope you understand in
position Amy and I are.
We choose no side.
- Relax.
We plan not until
we have fish.
You go so well with it.
- Why not?
Without a way to choose is Emma's red
the day 'e-mail is not a bit tasteless.
I mean, the sixth in the June
Plaza and a smiley?
What next? A heart over the i.
What do they not?
That is so tasteless.
Is it not amazing.
Elizabeth, I think my ring great.
You sent your invitations?
- Yes, actually.
Surprised?
So both of us ...
moved its date?
You really surprised me, Liv.
You never asked me what I wanted,
you did just what you deemed best.
Emma is saying this ...
Well, Emma is the most tired.
Do not think that I have not noticed,
I fully panikeerde ...
since I first
dared to be engaged.
First and foremost, Daniel bought
the ring in December.
So officially, I was first.
- Pathetic.
Secondly, people can still
things you do not want.
As if you have no backbone.
Oh right, you have no backbone.
I do not accuse you of weakness.
You took the first date in June,
without me even asking.
I'm at least not as
afraid to be alone ...
people that I should order
through life to come.
Emma, you take pleasure.
- Say you, I take pleasure in Fletcher?
I thought not Fletcher.
Since you started on.
Herzet your date, Liv.
- Do you think it.
That has happened. You lose.
Your wedding can better be careful.
What did you just now?
I said that your wedding now
be very afraid.
If I was your wedding, then
I would sleep with one eye open.
Why do you
threats for Daniel?
Do you have his proposal
not removed, anyway?
So I did.
- Your wedding in the pot.
What you just said about my wedding?
Your wedding can ...
I mean ...
can not ...
Please say.
Bye, ladies.
- Hey, Liv.
Yes?
Your wedding will be huge.
Just like your ass on the prom
of school.
It is enough.
Emma and Fletcher, ...
On Saturday, the sixth of June, five hours ...
Olivia and Daniel ...
Sixth of June at five o'clock.
Agreed.
Well, now only a
other bridesmaid.
And soon as you spend more
time with her than with the group.
Friends choose no party.
- Why should a friend?
No, no, just a bridesmaid.
Yes, eredame.
Yes, we were so close to the law school.
Honey, you are my second
best friend of my cousin ...
Of course, you first on my list.
Really.
Carla, Kaitlin?
Erin, no, I did not
he slept.
Okay, anyway.
Actually once.
Twice.
What is that?
He was a layabout.
He was lazy.
Is that so?
Really, I did not ...
Two children?
That must have been handsome.
Yes, tell him hello from me.
I'm actually in a taxi,
so I gotta go.
Kevin?
Yes.
I want you graduate.
Until erebruidsman.
Word you have paid?
It's just an honor.
I have a design for the classroom.
I think it is a great idea.
Because if you class something designed ...
Thankfully, you read on.
Read it for yourself.
Did you receive my note?
Can you take my late buscontrole?
Sure.
Deb ...
- Yes?
We are not really friends but ...
- Are we not?
Why I am proof you favor?
- That you do not.
Forget it.
Wil you be my bridesmaid?
- Can I choose my own dress?
All eyes are focused on me,
it must be good.
Absolutely.
I suggest something natural.
- I have a lot of help though.
What is the bride, do you think?
For the bridesmaid to help, right?
Come on, please?
- Okay.
Because you begged.
I'm your bridesmaid.
It is great.
May I propose something?
Have you ever heard of Pinot Grigio?
This is a really good white wine,
very elegant.
Your music is still around.
DJ Humple is not available to date.
But I had an appointment with him.
In principle.
One of my other brides
gave a higher bid.
I can not say who, of course.
- The slut.
Not you, another.
The person.
She is frightening.
You do not think Liv ...
- Yes it is.
She knows what that meant for me.
It is too cruel.
Typically something for her.
Hey, I know.
Did you not think they would wear Vera Wang?
Yes.
I read that they are quite tight.
She was formerly quite thick?
No.
No, she is ...
This is good.
Great.
Just cream cheese.
It is cream, I test it.
Emma has her cake already chosen?
- Let us to remain.
As for the flowers ...
'U-Floria has ...
I do not have the same pie. And I want
white chocolate cake with seven layers.
Covered with marzipan.
With curls and flowers.
Then you're safe. Emma has a
smaller pie chosen.
And she wants people to
see how much they can spend.
I just checked my even ice sculptures.
My heaven.
That was a pitch to me.
Emma thinks that I want to show off.
I thought I had to show
how much money I earn.
Really, I did not understand.
- Marriott, eat it.
She Emma prefer.
Emma getting the sympathy vote.
I will never, right?
Maybe it takes too much of people.
- I was worried about cake.
In my chocolate
monticule with whipped cream.
Stop, what's that?
Dance lessons?
She is damn competitive.
Her dance will be better than ours.
Do just once canaries singing.
Lark, canary.
Why is there nothing in between?
Serve as a canary burnt.
- Video of their lives?
Really?
That must be Fletcher's idea.
Perhaps baby pictures of Emma ...
with a tooth or Fletcher
in a superheldenpak.
Tasteless.
Can I help you?
- Yes, order for Liv Lerner.
This is chocolate.
Admit it.
It is good.
You deserve this more, Liv.
Daniel Is not the sweetest?
I assume there is only one.
These.
Was she present?
- Yes.
And it is impossible to
of retrieval?
She has already eaten half the box.
That is 45 dollars.
That is what we had agreed.
But you do know ...
If you knew what is really going on,
would you my side.
Please do not tip?
- I thought that there Saturday
Anyway, I give you,
because I am a Paula.
Suppose you really Emma
its beginning to peddle dance.
Then there are ways.
Tell me more.
I do not know, maybe dance?
We know how to dance,
it is a slow. Just like in school.
It is a rod,
that should just accurate.
Anyway, Marion says that our
beginning of our relationship style dance shows.
Well, I am very concerned
on our relationship style.
Place.
I'm Rick Coo.
The Doctor of Dance. "
I get your emotion and rhythm.
I get your sex.
Put you please
on your feet and dance.
Are you ready for this?
Perhaps the Coo Rick Marion
'Doctor of Dance' is not so recommend.
That Ricky.
Well done, you warm up.
I received your voice-mail,
you of a lesson to four wanted.
How long are you here?
My heaven.
What?
- Liv.
Give us a minute.
Who does that?
She is completely crazy, not surprising.
That is they always have been.
- I know.
And they are worthless to our relationship style,
I do not let that happen.
Good.
I think it is bad for Daniel.
He can even his own wife
not in place.
What?
I say that Liv behind it,
because they never think about ...
I go inside.
- What?
Last month
for the big day ...
is a test for couples
how they work ...
Troubleshooting
and communicate.
The happy time is over,
and overcome nerves.
Some couples will
this conflicts with them.
For the lucky among the flocks,
This brings the harmony above.
But even they must have something
order to respond.
For me?
'Jolly Wallis cake bouquet.
Will I, or not?
- Be careful.
Miss Wang is a strict mistress.
- A video.
There are photographs,
and videos?
Yes, at least one short film.
- I am not even ...
I do not know how I want it
We must get.
This is for you by a courier.
- I can not wait to view it.
Hr. Simmons has already called to ask
to an update on the agreement.
Rutherford Press, which is
my birth place.
I will say that you
in a crisis is?
They have continued engagement -
to announce.
Just that I am a celebrity
or something ...
girl from the neighborhood made it.
Dear people.
Girls from the village to marry both
in the Plaza Hotel
That is you, do you?
Emma looks beautiful from.
But not within, that is ...
This is the best thing they can do, right?
As meaningless.
Want to play dirty? I can do.
- I see you do.
I have studied law, people.
I am beginning to think that
30 border.
This is the last time, that men want
with women their own age.
And man, 30, assumes
with a girl of 30 ...
but a man of 35 would
one of thirty.
And a man of forty would
someone of 32.
Or 28.
It is a horrible planet.
- I know.
You know what I asked?
What is the real cause of Emma and Fletcher
that stick to that date ...
why can they date
be done.
Think about it.
She is pregnant.
Emma is pregnant.
No!
- Liv, are you okay with you?
What the fuck is going on?
Let me in there.
I am 5 pounds arrived. 5 pounds.
It could just as well be 50.
The dress does not fit, and if
the dress does not fit ...
my wedding will be a black hole are
in the history of the Plaza.
A, it is our wedding, baby.
And B, so what, let it make widespread.
You change Vera Wang not to apply
you change yourself to adapt to Vera.
What guys learn in school?
- Sorry.
It is not the end of the world.
Really.
What can I do that
you feel better?
Stop what you're doing.
This is all your fault.
It is that you love me sweets
sent, but ...
What kind of candy?
You know, the sweets,
who Truffle appels.
This dish with truffles.
The 'Jolly Wallis cake bouquet?
The international club butter?
- Honey ...
I have sent you nothing.
- My God, Emma.
They try to make me fat, so I
my dress is no longer useful. What is that?
What is that?
The international club butter?
You've really eaten pieces of butter
from different countries?
The last week before the wedding is
come, it's all or nothing.
I expect that my brides
perfect.
Great hair, skin, nails, everything.
Hello there. I have to go back very quickly.
Very fast. I have just yesterday
forgotten, and that is very important.
That may me not care.
Go back.
Miss Ellen.
- Hello.
Honingwit today, since what I like.
- Yes, but ...
with a little touch for the wedding.
Of course.
- Good, thanks.
What happened to you?
You look like a traffic spy.
Blurs that?
- Iet or whatever, I'm really nervous.
Is it so bad?
Fletch said that it was not so bad.
Fletch is your fiance. He said
probably also that you had good hair.
If a wedding is not just something.
- That's for sure.
I am surprised that I not
my therapist about.
I have heard. 'TUFF'.
I was talking by phone with
boy verperst had my table decorations.
It is unbelievable.
One thing after another.
Snowballs.
- Can I have some more 'lowlights' get?
Yes here, remember what you wanted to say, I
suit your color, right?
Make sure that it is not so ...
More like gold beige.
Maybe I should turn to 'chanting' go
do. It is perhaps necessary.
My God.
- My God?
Is it good?
I can ...
I do not know what happened ...
I let it sit for two days, maybe
I can increase it to white ...
My hair is blue!
It is blue!
I have blue hair.
I married in a week.
- Congratulations.
About a week!
I know you are in it.
Here is the video.
Yeah, sure.
Should you tell me something?
Are we a small orange baby?
Apparently we were registered
at 'Babies'R'Us.
Is not that nice?
Marissa, where are you?
I can hardly means.
I can not believe you
to Emma told.
Whatever.
Do not get too attached to the dancers, they
be paid to be nice to you.
A little birdie has just told me ...
that an arriving here tonight
wedding present.
But it has been a very naughty bride.
Agent not your man 'is here
for you to arrest.
You are arrested because
you are sexy.
It is time to be searched.
Oh.
Great.
There are two brides present tonight.
Yes, but this party is only
on invitation.
I am also married, baby.
We invite you altogether. DJ Jazz
Calls bride on stage two to come.
Come here girl.
We want to see how you move.
That meant I
go ahead, girl.
Can I not even my own
bachelor party have?
DJ Humple I could not have?
That was a rock passed.
Besides, I'm not pregnant, right?
I say its time for dancing.
Let me see girls.
Come on, future brides,
I know that you can do better.
Most sexy bride gets
first prize, let me see.
Let us begin.
Showtime.
Look at bride number two.
Bride number two, you are
the most sexy bride tonight, baby.
Applause for wedding number two, everybody.
Sorry bride number one, you
can not win everything, girl.
That is weird, losses ...
I must say that I
not love.
You were both so good.
Yes, you've gone over there,
and you've really tried.
Forget it.
It's my bachelor party, right?
Yes.
Well done girl, here.
- As if you read my mind.
My God.
Taxi!
Kevin, I need coffee.
Sorry, I need coffee,
3 Advil ...
four bottles of water, and look to the designation
of that lawyer, who may be.
Hi Ilana, you work too hard,
I invite you to lunch, okay?
Where are you Kev? In the office?
K..K
My God, completely forgotten.
I had an appointment at seven.
You'll love it.
If we are on the short preparation
may refer ...
I have a few key
highlighted.
My discovery process, and statements
documents and request ...
it has important results
returned.
Wait, I look at a letter
two weeks ago ...
where is the last one?
- I am sure that I've updated.
Your hair?
- Yes, my hair is blue.
My hair is blue, my wedding is over
a week, and I pay my bridesmaid.
And Hr. Colson, maybe I
The letter incorrectly stored ...
and perhaps hate my best friend
of the whole world to me.
Hate me.
My God.
I am a barren bride.
This is not ideal.
This is who we represent.
- Not anymore.
Mrs. Lerner looks at the case more
I take over.
Calm down, I let it appeared.
Ms. Lerner, you can go.
I'm not this girl.
I ruined not all,
I will be demoted.
Like I have nobody, I feel
me alone.
Honey, I'm here.
You miss your girlfriend.
Especially now.
They know exactly what they say.
I am also mad at her,
they went for my hair.
Friends do not.
We make it. And if you do not
you, I love it.
I really do, you are like so
a long, very sexy smurf.
Honey.
It is not only about her.
I am angry because they may
right.
You got out of there all the time
want to be perfect.
So I did
since I was a kid.
I thought that if I get everything and everyone
for was that nothing would happen naars.
Life is not perfect, huh?
It is a mess.
You're right.
I mean, I would be perfect for you ...
but now you say that this is impossible ...
You do not have to be perfect.
I always wanted a human woman.
Those others are just too difficult
to blow.
Almost back to normal.
- I know.
I got a skin layer about
but ...
that should be good enough for our wedding
, so, sorry Liv ...
I wish I had photos.
When I was there, and there were
the spotlight, and when I grabbed the rope ...
My God.
- Enough.
I did that story already ten thousand
once heard, Emma.
You do a little game
the last time, right?
I am tired of, so keep it on there.
You are very angry lately, and
tense and excited, and ...
and I do not know how I
to deal with.
I wonder whether that has anything to do
with the wedding ...
or that this is permanent.
- Well, Fletcher, this is permanent.
It may be possible that I am evil
or am tense ...
or excited for the next 40 years.
- Is that really so?
You do it again.
- What?
You are not hateful, but ...
I did not hateful, but you are
nearby.
You would have to take taxi
and make a U turn ...
and you let off on the corner
of fun and nice.
Fletcher, are you angry because stuff
with Liv ...
Absolutely.
- It is difficult for you to understand.
My God, I'm angry because you
have feelings, right in the bull's-eye.
In other words do not so much
feelings, as if I have ...
let them not see. I would not so much ...
- I can not even talk to you.
You have not tried.
You realize you ...
you know how difficult it is for me, you
I even tried to ask ...
how I feel.
I am so confused.
I recognize you no more.
Well, I want to talk.
It is a tense time, a lot of fun,
whatever, I go to the gym
Goodbye.
The office of Liv Lerner.
- Hi, Kevin. With Emma.
Liv Is there?
Can you wait. A moment.
- Thank you.
Sorry.
- Beautiful eyes.
Sorry, Liv has a crisis,
can call them back?
Well, I understand.
Sorry, with whom I speak?
Hello.
How are you?
- Long ago, huh?
I know. My fault, I am
very busy.
Yes, pressure. This has nothing to do
the fact ...
I am the brother of your best enemy?
I mean your best friend.
I need a tuxedo rentals, you
with me.
Come on.
Well, I am a bit surprised ...
I thought that a large magazine writer
his smoking would have.
How are you, Em?
How do you feel?
I feel good.
Good is not really a feeling.
That is a feeling.
I feel good. That you can say.
People say that.
Yes, of course. That you can say.
Well, it's like ...
It's a mad house with the wedding,
and ...
all these details, and ...
I have this idea of what it would be
in my head ...
and ...
it's not so fun.
And I do not know why.
But most time I feel good.
Let your das good. To
as a tie, I can not see.
That does not look good.
- Change the subject.
Das.
How about that tie-pin,
I can not.
You just have no patience.
- Really.
I think I've waited too long.
Go you drink coffee?
I'm already late ...
But I call you.
But ...
You look ...
you look ...
You will be a great ...
'bruidweggever are.
Thank you.
And Em, you are really a beautiful bride.
Yes?
- Yes, I have always thought.
Thank you. Day.
Despite everything, when the morning dawned
that the sixth June ...
it was the perfect day
for a wedding.
Right. Two weddings.
Three hours people, monitor your
camps, enter your work ...
and we might come alive.
- Incoming, people.
Roses for Lerner, peonies for Allen.
Has the pastor of Allen has been reported?
- Yes.
Tablecloths for Lerner. - Yes.
Excellent.
Hurry up people, this is
no rehearsal.
Liv, my God, you're the most beautiful bride
I have ever seen.
Thank you.
Excuse me a minute.
It is so strange.
I'm so nervous.
I do not know why.
Is that not to go?
- Yes. Why?
I do not know.
You look good.
Honestly, the pressure that we are on the brides
submit today ...
you look perfect.
Just ridiculous.
You do not look your best
on your wedding day ...
good everyone? Mama?
If you want my opinion ...
- No, I do not want your opinion.
What?
Deb, I have my whole life
versions of you, and ...
I tell you something that I long
ago against me had to say.
Sometimes it is about me. Good?
Not all the time.
But once in a while, it is
my time. Like today.
If you do not mind, it is your
free to go.
But if you stay, then you
your work.
And that means laugh and talk about
my beauty as a bride ...
and most importantly, ensure
that it is not your run.
Good? Can you do that?
Yes, I would like to.
Then everything is good.
- Harp Player for Allen, quartet for Lerner.
How often should I repeat myself yet.
Check the status of the bride,
and take your battle positions.
If you get back from one wedding,
let other members know, so ...
because we can rotate,
- Well, I go to ...
the ceremony of Liv, and
the reception of Emma.
I go see the bachelor,
and snacks.
Hello, Paul.
- Allen Lerner.
Hello, Hr. Allen. How are you?
I 'm good. How are you?
- Great day, huh?
Yes, it is.
- I have a blink of Emma absorbed.
When I was the enemy camp
to the viewing.
She is beautiful, sir.
Thank you, Nathan.
Can I talk with your sister? No
that row, but about something else.
Yes, of course.
Hello, Hr. Allen.
Your father and mother will be so proud.
- Thank you
On both of you.
Thank you
- I want you to give a blessing ...
of our generation.
Not myself, but ...
My dear friends, that everything
would have had to be here ...
today.
Good luck, honey.
Nathan.
- Hr. Allen, thank you.
Good to see you.
- You too.
Such a good man.
Dad looks so much like him.
According to Miss St. Claire ...
can you take a sip
the wedding ...
to the nerves under restraints.
So we have Scotch ...
Scotch is good.
Vodka and tequila.
- Tequilla!
Kevin! Tequila, no.
Bring it to you
Marion, I say that the DVD's have changed.
He needs to play Emma. Go.
I know. Go.
Come on.
One day you'll thank me.
I'm open.
- That is very helpful.
Thank you.
My God, your parents. Come inside.
Is not it a beauty of a bride?
That she is sure. Oh.
My God, this is my dress?
Are you happy?
- I'm happy when you are happy ...
honey, you can in a brown paper bag
married, that I would not care to.
This is your day.
I needed a handkerchief.
My God, I cry.
- You ruined your makeup, darling.
I found this when we
Bocca moved.
I have kept.
I knew that one day came that I
that you would give.
Go ahead. Make it open.
Because you need something old,
and blue.
It is actually Liv.
- Something borrowed, then.
Daddy, I must see her.
I think they also feel.
I'm open.
It is Marion.
At your place of people.
We are about two minutes to start.
Marion, I briefly go into the hallway?
Emma, you're the most beautiful bride
I have ever seen.
Ready? We walk.
A bride runs.
Time.
Madam?
Well.
- My God. I am married.
Are you happy?
If I give the confirmation that one bride
to walk ...
video shows five start recording.
And ready.
Walk.
I am in Acapulco, baby.
I'm here.
I want to dance.
Let see what, Emma.
I just want to dance.
We are caught,
I repeat, caught.
Emma!
Let me tell you something ...
This mess,
I would never do.
Let them do it.
Come on.
Liv, I would tell you what ..
Let me tell you something.
- I do not want to fight.
It is done.
I can not anymore.
Thank God.
It is all right.
Emma, what are you doing now?
Are not you crazy?
You just ruined our marriage,
are you happy now?
Your girlfriend is past, because she has always
a bad influence on you.
This DVD assess you to
more than I thought of her.
Good I hope.
- What?
Fletcher, you're already
ten years my friend.
And you must also now
and tell me the truth.
You are in love with a girl
Your ten years ago met.
What is wrong with that?
It is not there anymore.
I do not want my whole
life squabble.
We dig us.
And you want that.
We are different.
We want different things.
You know it's true or not?
I know.
Goodbye.
I'm fine.
This is all my fault.
That video had never happened.
But really ...
I had been terminated
I wish you that.
Emma, you're my best friend.
- Our fight is so crazy.
Excuse me so.
Excuse me.
I am so sorry
If I've ruined it for you,
I do not anymore.
If Fletcher and I perfectly
for each other ...
than we are now married.
Did you now?
- Yes, a whole new me.
I did all the time.
God knows who ...
- No ...
Excuse me.
- No, you're right.
I should not constant
one another.
It resembles a giant
'wake up call. "
I turned it around a bit, but ...
I am awake.
Wil je vanvoor are together?
- Where else would I say?
What do you think?
Back from zero.
I almost forgot something.
- My God, Em.
Where have you found?
- Two little girls kept it for us.
Forward.
Are you single?
- Yes.
Are you straight?
- I do not like labels.
Excuse me if you divorce.
- Why? It is only my first.
And next time faith
I certainly in the Plaza.
Let's go dancing.
- Yes, good.
No honey, let it happen.
I made a big mistake,
by someone smarter to marry?
This was a wedding.
And when I looked, I realized something
I have long forgotten.
you make me so very happy
Sometimes the
life forging links ...
which can never be broken.
Sometimes you can really find that person,
which, whatever, to your side.
Maybe you feel that a partner,
and you'll celebrate your dream wedding.
But there is also the opportunity
that the person ...
life you can count ...
That person you better
familiar than you know yourself ...
same person to you
side, quite the time.
One year later.
You look great.
- You look great.
How was the holiday?
- It was amazing.
I would like everything about this.
Actually not.
Really, you married my brother.
That is strange.
So I would never know.
Shall we toast?
On the marriage?
I do not drink.
Me neither.
Are you pregnant?
- Are you pregnant?
Where ...?
- When did you calculated?
The third of March.
- The third of March.
THE END
Subtitles by: