Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
There will come a time when No.
know what to call what unites us.
Your name will be fading gradually
Our memory.
And soon, it will disappear altogether.
Margaritta Duras
"Hiroshima Mon Amour."
I remember you
by Morning...
... From you.
In the afternoon...
and by night...
... Always you.
Aristophanes said that true love
were among the only similar.
And he uses to explain the mythology.
At first there were men
and women
and a species called "androgens.
These androgens were two men in one,
or two women or a man...
... And a woman. At one point found themselves
very strong and decided to defy the gods.
But do not count on
austúcia to Zeus, who ordered Apollo to...
undo these "wounds". Apollo decides to share them
the chest and belly and just leaves a hole
which is the navel, as a souvenir
Dessen recklessness.
Thus, Aristophanes said that man
will always get that
half of which was divided
in the beginning, and when...
... You then find that other half,
true love and true happiness.
Jonas!
Come on!
Can you imagine?
I do not know...
I'm afraid
They have the opportunity to live a
unfailing love
and will perhaps die
a day for him.
- Oi
- A beer
Jonas can not stop crying...
It is a long time to look
spot where he disappeared...
And cry...
Want to see it again
Why cry...
Do not know, but is certain
that he was who had always hoped.
The saw by chance
and now wants to see him again, whatever the cost.
Gerardo, do not understand.
Not understand.
Remains alien
to this story.
"Heaven divided"
Caption by:
Zhen KIREL
Their bodies are in the same place
Enclosed within themselves.
Sleep always comes first to Jonas.
Sleep well at night because it leads
forgetfulness of life that leads to Gerardo...
... And who wants to leave.
It was after those awakening
Gerardo died when Jonas
He lost his eyes, his voice...
Her eyes closed against his mouth,
soon his lips against his...
His hands too...
but, above all, his eyes closed.
Others say that people are
hiding to penetrate to
TOGETHER and they enjoy
Not knowing is not love yourself.
... Almost without seeing.
These tears hurt the body of Gerardo
as heavenly sword,
cross your heart without stopping
no trace, nothing.
only one certainty,
A scar that burns
as an open wounds:
Had ceased to exist
in the life of Jonah.
There already exist ever.
Gerard turned to Sergio
She looked at him with attention so intense
and deeper, not the saw.
Soon the idea of its existence
came upon his spirit.
She looked at him
how to love him.
Had started
happening.
Comes
No, really, I can not.
Come!
Have loved you long ago.
Until then enter Jonas
Dessen existence of another sense
It took a long time
until he came to his conscience
Suddenly everything changes
around you.
And Jonas wonders
Why?
Can not imagine another love
what Gerardo was living with him.
Can not support it or understand it
Now only thing left to chance
to live with the memory of a Kiss,
of a word,
a hug
a single glance
for an entire love.
Changes that face
You will see that
Nothing happened.
I said I do not know.
Really?
Sure.
For this bullshit!
Sergio!
Sergio embraced
against his chest.
And told him I loved him
but nothing in the world.
Gerardo turned
for him
And the first saw.
He said he believed him.
Me too!
Long after Jonah
called him.
"I am",
I told him.
Gerardo recognized his voice.
Jonas said:
"Just wanted to hear his voice"
I am.
Were silent
Jonas said that every day, somewhere
moment, not wanting
His image returned
his memory.
His voice trembled.
Gerardo then recalled
voice and felt sorry.
Then we did not know
what to say.
And then Jonas told him
I was sorry.
they still loved him.
I could never
stop loving him.
that would love to death
Jonas then listen to the cry
Gerardo by phone.
And wept.
Gerardo stayed in bed
continued crying
Recalling him as the
oblivion of love itself.
... As the terror of forgetting.
Here is the result of all this
time I mean
I loved you,
scream it.
That is all.
December 2005.
Caption by:
Zhen KIREL
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com