Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
If you pair of deuces
are lookin’ for work,
I suggest you get your
scrawny asses in here, pronto.
Now, up on Brokeback
the Forest Service has got designated campsites
on the allotments.
Them camps can be three our four miles
from where we pasture the woollies.
Bad predator loss, ’cause nobody’s
lookin’ after ’em at night.
Now, what I want
is a camp tender
to stay at the main camp
where the Forest Service says.
But the herder, he’s gonna
pitch a pup tent on the q.t. with the sheep,
and he’s gonna sleep there.
You eat your supper and breakfast at camp.
But you sleep with the sheep.
A hundred percent.
No fire, don’t leave no sign.
You roll up that tent very morning
in case the Forest Service snoops around.
Yeah?
No.
No!
Not on your fuckin’ life.
You got your dogs, a .30-.30.
You sleep there.
Last summer I had a goddam near 25% loss.
I don’t want that again.
You...
Fridays at noon to by down by the bridge,
with a grocery list and mules.
Somebody with supplies,
will be there at the pick-up.
Tomorrow morning we’ll truck you up
to the jump off.
Jack Twist.
Ennis.
Your folks just stopped at Ennis?
Del Mar.
Nice to know you, Ennis Del Mar.
My second year up here.
Last year, one storm,
the lightning killed 42 sheep.
I thought I’d asphyxiate from the smell.
Aguirre got all over my ass,
like I was supposed to control the weather.
It beats working for my old man.
Can’t please my old man, no way.
That’s why I took the rodeo.
You ever rodeo?
Yeah... well... I mean once in a while.
When I got the entry fee in my pocket.
Yeah.
Are you from ranch people?
Yeah, I was.
Did your folks run you off?
No, they run themselves off.
There was, uh, one curve in the road in 43 miles...
and they missed it.
So, uh...
the bank took the ranch, and
my brother and sister, they raised me mostly.
Shit!
That’s hard.
Can I?
One thing...
don’t ever order soup.
Them soup boxes are hard to pack.
I don’t eat soup.
Well, watch it there.
That horse has a low startle point.
Don’t think there’s a filly that can throw me.
When you get in this damn saddle it’s kinda not so bad.
Shit.
Can’t wait till I get my own spread
and won’t have to put up with Joe Aguirre’s crap no more.
I’m savin’ for a place myself.
Alma and me, we’ll be getting married
when I come down off this mountain.
That stay with the sheep,
no fire bullshit,...
Aguirre got no right makin’ us do
something against the rules.
No more beans.
Something wrong?
Yeah.
Why didn’t we get the powdered milk and the spuds?
It’s all we got.
Well here’s next week’s.
I thought you didn’t eat soup.
Yeah, well, I’m sick of beans.
Too early in the summer to be sick of beans.
Come on.
Whoa there, whoa, whoa!
Where the hell you been?
I been up with the sheep all day,
I’m hungry as hell and all I find is beans.
What in the hell happened, Ennis?
Come upon a bear, is what happened.
Goddam horse spooked, and the mules took off
and scattered food everywhere.
Beans is about all we got left.
Got whisky or something?
Dumbass mule!
God-damn!
Let me see.
(Shit)
Well, we gotta do something about
this food situation.
Maybe I’ll shoot one of the sheep.
Yeah, what if Aguirre finds out, huh?
Supposed to guard the sheep, not eat ’em.
What’s the matter with you?
There are thousands of ’em.
Sick of beans.
Well, I won’t.
Whoo-wee!  Yeah!
Was getting’ tired of your dumbass missin’!
Then we won’t.
Ain’t nothing you can do with fish
that can’t do with no elk!
Hey, I’m commutin’ four hours a day.
I come in for breakfast.
I go back to the sheep.
Evening get ’em bedded down,
come in for supper,
go back to the sheep.
I spend half the night checking for damn coyotes.
Aguirre got no right making me do this.
If you wanna switch,
I wouldn’t mind sleepin’ out there.
That ain’t the point.
Point is we both oughta be in this camp.
Goddam pup tent smells like cat piss, or worse.
I wouldn’t mind bein’ out there.
Well, I’m happy to switch with you, but...
I warn you, I can’t cook worth a damn.
I am pretty good with a can opener, though.
Well you can’t be no worse than me, then.
You don’t get much sleep, I tell you that.
Yeah.  Come on
I saw a coyote up there.
A big son of a bitch.
Balls on him the size of apples.
Looked like he could eat himself a camel.
You want some of this hot water.
It’s all yours.
I don’t rodeo much myself.
What’s the point of riding
some piece of stock for 8 seconds?
Money’s a good point.
Uh-huh.
If you don’t get stomped winnin’ it.
Yeah.
Well, my old man,
he’s a bull rider.
Thanks.
Pretty well-known in his day.
Though he kept his secrets to himself.
Never taught me a thing,
never once come to see me ride.
There.
Your brother and sister do right by you?
The did the best they could
after my folks was gone.
Considerin’ they didn’t leave us nothin’ but
$24 and a coffee can.
They got me a year of high school.
That was before the transmission went on the pick-up.
Then my sis left,
met a rough-neck and moved to Casper.
Me and my brother, we...
we went and got ourselves some work
on a ranch up near Worland...
... till I was 19.
Then he got married, and uh...
No more room for me.
That’s how come...
...you end up here.
What?
That’s more words than
you spoke in the past 2 weeks.
Hell, that’s the most I spoke in a year!
My dad, he was a farm roper.
Didn’t rodeo much, though.
He thought rodeo cowboys was all fuck-ups.
The hell we are.
Well...
- Yeehaw.
- There you go.
Burn his guts out.
Wavin’ to the girls in the stands!
He’s kickin’ me to high heaven!
I think my dad was right.
Tent don’t look right.
It ain’t goin’ nowhere.
Let it be.
That harmonica don’t sound quite right either.
That’s ’cause it got kinda flat,
when my mare threw me.
Oh yeah?
I thought you said that mare couldn’t throw you.
Oh, she got lucky.
Yeah well, if I’d to listen to that harmonica,
I woulda broke it, too.
#I know I shall meet you
on that final day.#
#Water-walkin’ Jesus.#
#Take me away!#
My mama, she believes in the Pentecost.
Yeah?
What exactly is the Pentecost?
I mean, my folks they was Methodists.
The Pentecost... I don’t know.
I don’t know what the Pentecost is.
No-one ever explained it to me.
I guess, when the world ends,...
fellows like you and me
we march off to Hell.
Speak for yourself.
You may be a sinner,
but I ain’t yet had the opportunity.
Thank you.
I’m gonna go up to the sheep now.
Damn, it’s too late to go to them sheep.
You got an extra blanket?
I’ll just roll up out here.
Catch forty winks.
I’ll ride out first light.
You’ll freeze your ass of
when that fire dies down.
That’s good enough.
Ennis!
What?
Quit your hammerin’ and get in here.
What’re we doin’?
See you for supper.
Come on.
This is a one-shot thing we got goin’ on here.
It’s nobody’s business but ours.
You know I ain’t queer.
Me neither.
Twist.
Your Uncle Harold’s in the hospital
with pneumonia.
Doctors don’t expect he’ll make it.
Your ma sent me to tell you,
so... here I am.
Bad news.
There ain’t nothing I can do about it up here, I guess.
There’s not much you can do about it there, neither.
Unless you can cure pneumonia.
Jesus.
Them sheep’ll drift if I don’t get back up there tonight.
You’ll get pissed in a storm like this.
And we sure ain’t tryin’.
Close it up.
Well, what are we supposed to do now, huh?
Get on in there and untangle
them sheep out of ours, I guess.
...where is it..?
Maybe the Goddam sheep rachers were off.
We’ve gotta try.
The least we can do is get...
...the count right for Aguirre.
Fuck Aguirre.
Oh yeah, fuck Aguirre.
What if we need work next year?
You ever figure about that?
We gotta stick this out, Jack.
You’ll run them sheep off, if you don’t quiet down.
What are you doin’?
Aguirre came by again.
Said my uncle didn’t die after all.
Said to bring ’em down.
Bring ’em down?  Why?
It’s the middle of August.
Said there’s a storm comin’.
Comin’ in from the Pacific.
Worse than this one.
But that snow barely stuck an hour.
That son-of-a-bitch, he’s cuttin’ us out
of a whole month’s pay.
It ain’t right.
Well, I’d spare you a loan but
I’m short on cash.
I can give it to you when we get to Signal.
I don’t need your money.
I ain’t in the poorhouse.
Shit.
All right...
Time to get goin’, cowboy.
This ain’t no rodeo, cowboy.
Ennis... Ennis.
Come here.
Some of these never went up there with you.
The count ain’t what I’d hoped for, neither.
You ranch stiffs,
you ain’t ever no good.
You wanna give it some gas?
I can’t believe I left
my damn shirt up there.
You gonna do this again next summer?
Well, maybe not.  Like I said,
me and Alma’s gettin’ married in November.
So... I’ll try to get something on a ranch, I guess.
You?
Might go up to my daddy’s place.
Give him a hand during winter.
I might be back.
If the army don’t get me.
Well, I guess I’ll see you around, huh?
Right.
What the fuck are you lookin’ at?
Huh?
...forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us,
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For Thine is the kingdom, the power and the glory,
for ever and ever.  Amen.
Under the powers vested in me, I now
pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
And if you don’t, I will.
You all right?
Stop!
No, you stop!
My old lady’s tryin’ to get me to quit this job.
She says I get too old breaking my back
shovellin’ asphalt.
I told her, strong backs
and weak mind runs in the family!
I told her it keeps me fit.
Yeah!
Well look what the wind blew in.
Hi Mr Aguirre.
Wonderin’ if you was needin’ any help this summer.
Wastin’ your time here.
What, you ain’t got nothin’?
Nothin’ up on Brokeback.
I ain’t got no work for you.
Ennis del Mar ain’t been around, has he?
You boys sure found a way
to make the time pass up there.
Twist, you guys wasn’t gettin’ paid to
leave the dogs to babysit the sheep
while you stemmed the rose.
Now get the hell out of my trailer.
How are you girls doin’?
All right.
Jenny’s still got a runny nose
Ennis, could you wipe Alma junior’s nose?
If I had free hands I could!
Shh, come here.
- Girls all right?
- Yeah
Jenny’s still got a cough.
I think you should take the girls into town this
weekend and get ’em an ice-cream... or somethin’?
Can’t we move to town?
I’m tired of these lonesome old ranches.
No-one for Alma jr. to play with,...
...besides, I’m scared for Jenny,...
...scared she has another one of
them bad asthma spells.
No, rent in town’s too high.
There’s a cheap place in Riverton
over the laundromat.
I bet I could fix it up real nice.
I bet you could fix this place up
real nice if you wanted to.
I know you’d like it, too.
A real home,
lots of kids for the girls to play with.
Not so lonely like you were raised.
You don’t want it to be so lonely, do you?
I ain’t so lonely now.
You sure the girls are asleep?
Sure.
Come here.
Let her rip..., boys
He’s hangin’ on for dear life
Watch out there, he’s coming for ya!
Send in the clowns!
Shit.
Never mind folks,
there are the rodeo clowns!
I’d like to buy Jimbo here a beer.
Best damn rodeo hand I ever worked with.
Thanks cowboy. If I was to let every
rodeo hand I pulled a bull off of
buy me liquor I’d a been an alcohol long ago.
Well, bullseye for you buccaroo, it’s just my job.
Save your money for your
next entry fee, cowboy.
You ever try calf ropin’?
Do I look like I can afford a fuckin’ ropin’ horse?
- Do you wanna go in a little closer?
- No, this is fine, Jenny’ll get scared.
Woo-wee!  Look at this crowd!
Bound to be a lot of pussy on the hunt
in a crowd like this!
..scroll up.
.... like a frog.
Where’d you figure the most pussies at?
- Las Vegas?
- California.
...one town in Wyoming, I take Wyoming.
Hey, you might wanna keep it down.
There are two little girls here.
Fuck you.
I don’t want any trouble, but you need
to shut yourself up.
Listen to your old lady tonight.
What about it?  You wanna lose
about half your fuckin’ teeth?
It’s all right, buddy.
I’d sure rather not.
Here she comes, ladies and gentlemen!
Oh boy, look at her fly!
It’s Lureen Milton from right here in Childress, Texas.
Come on folks, she’s one of yours...
Let’s give her a big hand.
She’s cleared on two
She’s around three.
Come on folks, help her home!
Come on, come on!
And the time is...
...sixteen and a half.
Ma’am.
Next up is a newcomer, Jack Twist,
all the way up from Lightning Flat, Wyoming.
Let’s see what the judges say...
I tell you what.
That sure looked like a winnin’ ride to me.
You know that girl?
I sure do.  That’s Lureen Newsome.
Dad sells farm equipment.  Big farm equipment.
$100,000 tractors,
shit like that.
What you waitin’ for cowboy?  A mating call?
Wait, hold on.
You don’t think I’m too fast, do you?
Maybe we should put the brakes on?
Fast or slow, I just like
the direction you’re goin’.
You are in a hurry!
My daddy’s in a hurry.
Wants me home with the car by midnight.
- Hey, Monroe.
- Hey, En.
Is Alma here?
She’s in the condiments aisle.
The what?
- Ketchup.
- Thanks.
Hey honey!  What are y’all doin’ here?
I’m in a big hurry.
My boss called and, uh,
he wants me to go up the ranch.
Seems all the heifers decided to calf at the same time.
I figured I could drop the girls off with you.
I got a million things I gotta do
before I leave.
I don’t get off for another three hours.
Mama, I need to pee.
Not now, honey.
Ennis, please, you promised
you’d take them tonight.
I can’t afford not to be there
when they have these calfs.
I’ll lose my job if they lose any of ’em.
And what about my job?
OK, all right.
Call my sister see if she can take ’em.
All right, all right.
Be a good girl for mama, all right?
I’ll be half the night...
Oh boy!
Monroe, I am so sorry!
It’s ok, it’s ok.
I’ll clean this up, just as soon as
I call my sister to come get the girls.
Really, Alma, it’s ok.
- Forget it.
- Alma, come with me.
Watch your feet.
Alma.
I got two whole boxes of formula for you.
- 120 cans
- 120?
Dear, where’d you put ’em?
Oh hell.  Back seat of the car where I left ’em.
Rodeo can get ’em.
I can already see what little Bobby looks like.
Good job, little girl.
He’s the spittin’ image of his grandpa.
Isn’t he just the spitting image of his grandpa?
Hey.
Hey Ennis?  You somebody, name of Jack?
Maybe.  Why?
’Cause you got a postcard that
come general delivery.
Friend, this letter is long over due.  Coming through
on the 24th.  Drop me a line say if your there.  Jack.
Is it somebody you cowboyed with, or what?
No, Jack he rodeos, mostly.
We was fishin’ buddies.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org