- Doggerel?
- Yep. It means bad poetry.
I know what it means.
You just turned my dog into doggerel.
And it's what, 13 points?
Nope, 26.
Double word score.
I am forfeiting this game.
Oh, come on, Robert. You can't forfeit.
Sure I can. I've gotfive I's and an O.
Besides, you look too beautiful.
Focus. You have to focus.
I didn't come all the way up
here just to play board games.
You're not trying.
Now come on. You said you had an O.
Do you... do you havean... an r?
You could spell rumor.
Okay, let me see your letters.
- Oh, look at that. You have a T.
- So?
So you can spell tumor.
I don't want you staring at the word tumor.
Robert... do you think that I
have forgotten that I have cancer?
I had Kevin reschedule tomorrow's
press conference
in case the chemo takes
longer than they say.
Oh, no, no, no.You don't... you don't have
to do that, because, uh, I'm gonna be fine.
No, it's your first time. I should be there.
No, sorry. I've already decided that
you are not gonna be my chemo buddy.
W-w-well, who
is?
I don't know. I have a whole gaggle of
family members just waiting in line.
But you, my friend, you are gonna
be concentrating on the campaign.
What has happened to you?
I mean, you didn't even want me in this race,
- and now I want to be there for you...
- You're gonna be there for me.
You're running for Governor.
You're not going to the moon.
And besides, the last thing I
need is you quitting on my account.
Okay.
Can I at least quit this game?
Yes.
You can.
Excuse me, Dr. Condon?
Yes?
I'm, uh, Justin.
Justin Walker.
I'm sorry. Office hours don't start until 1:00.
You know what? This will only take a second.
I've been reading upon the
cancer research you've been doing,
and I know it's a bit late, but I was
wondering if I could possibly join your team?
My assistant positions
were filled a month ago.
I know. And I know this
would be making an exception.
Well, even if I could, my grant funding
only allows a certain number of students.
Okay, you know what ?I'd, uh, I'd volunteer.
I'd, uh, I'd work for free.
- Uh, what year are you?
- First.
You know, in my experience, it's
better not to rush into specializing.
You might want to take a year or two,
make sure oncology's what
you really want to do.
No, its.
Look, I'll, uh, I'll do anything.
I'll, uh, empty your trash.
I'll sweep the floors.
I can, uh, offer you a pen that works.
Here you go.
What was your name again?
Justin Walker.
I'll think about it, Justin.
Thank you. Thank you.
Um, I won't disappoint you.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Where are we?
- We?
- Yeah.
- You mean me.
- Okay. That's all right. We'll catch up.
I was trying to getan internship with Dr. Condon.
But you barely got this under control.
- Look, I can handle this.
- Look, I told you.
I'm not gonna get dragged down
but your unfocused, naive
approach to medical school.
Look, I told you I can handle this.
All right, Carter?
- Unbelievable.
- Carter.
I know this is probably not
what you're in the mood for,
but, uh, Rebecca and I are
gonna look at wedding venues today.
I would so love to, but I can't today.
It's, um, Kitty's first chemo
treatment, and I have to be there.
She hates hospitals, and she hates needles,
and it's... it's gonna be a very rough day.
- She needs me.
- Of course.
Besides that, I really don't want to
intrude on your mother-daughter time.
Please, we're going to be in-laws soon enough.
We would love to have you with us.
Thank you, Holly. I really appreciate that.
Okay, bye.
Holly, you wanted to see me.
Uh, yeah.
I want you to follow up a
line on a juice broker.
I think I have finally located
a supply of cheap wine
that we can use to make our blend.
I would do this myself, but
I have promised Rebecca
that we would look at wedding venues today.
Okay, but don't you think we should
wait until Sarah gets back to work?
I mean, she needs to weigh in on the possibility of
a low-budget or a second line plan.
And who knows? She might
have found something in France.
Well, we need the revenue now.
We need to put this deal into
motion with the broker today.
Okay, well, how do you know people
are gonna buy this $2.99 swill, Holly?
In this economy, people will
buy it if we market it correctly.
And if you give them a lottery
ticket to distract them from the taste.
You know what, Saul?
Forget that I even asked.
If that's the way you want
to leave it, that's fine with me.
No, what I want is to
generate new revenue now.
We have no idea how long it's gonna be
before people are willing to
buy high-end products again.
And quite frankly, we can't afford to wait.
- What, are we having company?
- No.
No. I just want to be prepared.
We don't know how you'll
feel after this first treatment.
So I made all your favorites.
I made tapioca pudding.
I made fresh banana bread, lots
of p... no, no, don't, don't.
Don't... don't drink that.
You don't want any of that. No, no, no,
look, I made you a protein drink,
because they say you shouldn't go
there on an empty stomach.
Yes, so I made you a great protein drink.
And it has almond milk and protein powder and...
It's thick.
- A little thick.
- Well, let me just thin it out for you.
And then I'll put it in a travel
mug, because we can take it with us.
And I am all ready to go.
Oh, mom. Oh, God, mom. I'm so sorry.
I totally forgot to tell you that...
that Sarah is actually going
to come here and pick me up,
and... and she's gonna be my
chemo buddy for today.
Oh, great. Good.
I mean, I, you know, I've hardly seen
her since she got back from France,
and I thought that it would be a
nice opportunity for us to catch up.
So, you know, it doesn't
all have to fall on you, okay?
I mean, look at... look at all you've done
so far, and it's only 10:00 in the morning.
I mean, I think you should take the day.
Take the day and just enjoy
yourself, because guess what.
- What?
- I am gonna be fine.
Yes, yes.
I know that. I know that.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
The truth is, Kitty and I spent a great
deal of time weighing this decision,
and the choice was clear... we could
suspend our campaign and let the cancer win,
or we could continue to live our own
lives and stand up for what we believe in.
And so that's why I'm staying in the race,
because Kitty and I believe
that's what's best for our family
as well as the state of California.
Okay, I'll take a few questions now.
Uh, one at a time. Steve.
- Senator, I think I speak for everyone in wishing Kitty well.
- Thank you.
But to focus on your decision
to keep campaigning...
do you risk losing donors who may
fear you might drop out down the road?
Well, uh, I think that my donors
appreciate that I'm stead fast in my decisions.
So, no, I... I don't think that's gonna be an issue.
Yes, Lynda.
If Mrs. McCallister does support
your decision to stay in the race,
why isn't she here today?
She's at home recuperating.
Of course, but, Senator, are you concerned
that continuing your gubernatorial run
in the face of your
wife'sconditions will appear callous?
Well, I think most Californians would
appreciate that this is a private, family matter,
and I think that they'll judge it as such.
Next question.
Now, Kitty, you may feel a little
cold as it reaches your vein.
Okay.
Here, let's warm you up. Come on.
Get you nice and warm.
Sarah... can you, uh, can you talk please?
What do you want me to talk about?
I don't know. I don't know. Anything.
You can talk about your trip.
Okay.
there it is.
it's okay.
You're okay.
So... we were running late,
sat on the tarmac for, like, two hours.
I don't know how the airlines get away with that.
We circled Paris for at least an hour...
Sarah, tell me a good story.
I don't want to have
to fire my chemo buddy.
I met a guy.
You did?
- Really?
- Really.
Well, you didn't... you didn't tell me that.
Well, I'm telling you now.
Oh, my God. Okay.
Okay, I want youto tell me every
detail, and don't skimp on anything.
Okay.
I was running late.
I'd been driving all morning.
I was lost looking for this little vineyard
outside a place called Bergerac...
Driving through these beautiful
fields peppered with sunflowers.
And there was this little farmlet, I
guess... beautiful, big, old barn.
Bonjour.
Je peux vous aider?
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-
Proudly Presents
Sync: Sunpy ÿÂ¨Â»Ã'
corrected by chamallow35
www.addic7ed.com
Ca dit ici, uh, il faut tourner
à droite sur, uh, rue de Chollet.
Oh, no. Uh, no.
Tourner à gauche. Il faut tourner à
gauche on rue de... de, uh, Chollet.
Avez-vous entendu parler
de Chateau de, uh, Chollet?
Vin?
You know... non.
You're enjoying this, aren't you?
Okay, look, I... I have an appointment.
Uh, j'ai rendez-vous... business.
It's a winery.
De Chollet.
Nothing?
Chateau Chollet.
Si. Oui, oui, oui. Chateau Chollet.
Of course. It's not so far.
You speak English?
Oui, bien sûr!
Of course.
Well, I'm very glad to have amused you.
It was cute.
Could you please give me some directions?
- I'm... I'm running late for this appointment.
- I take you.
I take you.
You'll take me?
Are... are
you sure?
Let's eat, and then we go.
Oh, uh, no.
I'm sorry I didn't explain myself.
I'm running late.
- I have to...
- You don't want me to take you?
Uh... no, no.
Uh... I just... I have to go now.
What do you think?
Kitty?
- How are you feeling? Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Any shortness of breath?
No, no. I... I feel great.
I... I feel like I could run a mile.
Good. How about chills, any of those?
- No, no, not at... not at all.
- Okay.
This is Sarah, my sister.
She just met a guy in France.
- Congratulations.
- Merci beaucoup.
She does seem to be shivering a little bit.
- Is that normal?
- Totally.
We'll just, uh, slow down the drip and
give you an extra dose of hydrocortisone,
- see if that calms things down.
- Okay.
I wanted to go over, with both
of you, the post-care information.
Okay, okay, can you just please,
um, maybe give us one second?
Sure.
Did you... did you stay?
- Kitty.
- No, no, no, just tell me.
Of course I stayed.
You know, Jean Harlow once lived here.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I'm so glad I found you. Did I miss anything?
- Hi, I'm Nora. I'm... I'm the groom's mother.
- Oh, welcome.
- What... what are you doing here?
- Hi, honey.
I asked her.
I thought Kitty was getting a treatment.
Well, yes, she did. We were halfway
out the door, and Sarah showed up.
They haven't had any time to
be together since Sarah got back.
And then I got to come help you here.
- Oh, that's so sweet.
- Oh, this is so exciting.
I can use all the help I can get.
Well, I'm... I'm... I'm thrilled, and look at this!
Look at... this is an impressive place.
Jean Harlow once lived here.
Did she live here?
- Oh, that must be Sarah.
- Oh, no, no, it's mine.
I'm sorry, Rebecca. This will just be one minute.
Yeah, what is it?
Yeah, I... I just need the price of the juice.
Fine, fine. Put me through to the broker.
Uh, now most of our couples do a
cocktail hour right out here.
- We fill the pool with floating candles.
- It's beautiful.
I mean, what do you think, Nora?
Well, I... I think... I think you
have to, you know, feel it.
Feel what?
Well, feel that it's right.
Feel that it's like you and Justin.
Well, I mean, Justin likes water.
Uh, I'm so sorry.
So where were we?
Uh, why don't we go upstairs?
We have a fantastic area for the bridal suite.
Are they shooting a movie?
Are you shooting a movie here?
Uh, yes. Well, you know, we rent the
space out for a variety of events.
I thought they'd be done by now.
Must be a period piece.
I... I think it is.
What period?
Olden times.
Yes. I can't keep up.
But why don't we go look at the bridal suite?
Shall we?
I'm sorry.
Are they shooting porn?
Really?
Here, now?
Well, now... now we don't rent out the
space for filming on the weekends.
And I would be happy to throw in free valet.
Free valet.
Oh, no. I don't think so, no.
Go, go.
We can get to the street this way, can't we?
Go right down these stairs.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
We need to discuss the Kitty issue.
Ternal polls are showing a drop.
First of all, can we please not refer
to my wife's illness as the Kitty issue?
Okay, sorry.
But if we don't get Kitty out there and
show the public she's behind you,
this is just gonna get worse.
No, it'll be worse if we do.
They'll think we're using her.
It's a risk, I agree, but we can't do nothing.
Look, Kevin... a... and jot
this down if you have to,
because I'm... I'm not gonna say it again...
Kitty's well-being has nothing
to do with the state of California
or my integrity or my job performance.
- Why can't we say that?
- We did say that.
We... we said that explicitly.
Yeah, and they didn't hear you.
You know why?
It came from the wrong mouth.
A statement at the least.
- No, I'm not gonna use her.
- I will help her draft it myself.
No, do not... Kevin, back o...
there is too much in play for
you to see this clearly.
Leave Kitty alone.
She and I have made a decision.
And that should be good
enough for everybody!
Including you.
Spend the most important day of your
life in the opulent astin ballroom.
Details include fine linens with
buttercup or eggshell,
silver, gold or black Chiavari chairs...
What's Chiavari?
Well, it's that. That's a Chiavari chair.
Okay, wait. W... what else is in this...
this love in the afternoon package?
A love in the after... it includes
a chocolate fountain.
Yeah, the idea of the Walkers in the
same room with five tiers of hot,
molten chocolate is pretty terrifying.
all of these packages... they're
like... the'yre like...
a slightly different version of
the same generic wedding.
Oh, well, maybe your mom has some
ideas how to personalize it.
Yeah, if she would ever get off the phone.
Sweetie, you know what? If you don't
like this venue, then we should just go.
There are plenty of others to look at.
Yeah, maybe we should.
So what do you think?
Does this place have potential?
- Uh, no. We're moving on.
- We just got here.
Well, maybe it seems that way because
you've been on the phone the entire time,
Rebecca, I was only on
the phone for five minutes.
Look, why don't we not make any
decision until we tour the grounds?
Why, so we can just sign a check
and get the search over with?
I mean, I know that this is an
inconvenience for you, clearly, but...
- You know, I... I don't think that...
- That's not what I'm saying.
I'm saying how can you
make an informed decision
without checking out the entire venue.
Because I've seen enough to
know that it's not right.
I mean, ask Nora. You either feel it or you don't.
Okay, I... I think there is something to that.
- But... but still, you... but...
- What, mom? You've never done this before.
Nora has, multiple times.
I mean, Kevin and Scotty'swedding was
perfect, and it was... it was so them.
I want that for Justin and me.
Oh, so what you're saying is that you
want to have your wedding at Nora's?
Well, she's sitting right here.
- So why don't you just ask her?
- You know, that...
If you would just listen
for once, you would know
that's not what I'm saying at all.
- I'll tell them I'll call them right back.
- Take it. Take it.
That's what you'd rather be doing anyways.
- Rebecca, please.
- Take the call.
- I don't have to take it.
- Nora, I'm sorry we wasted your time.
To think that we could actually do this together?
- It's unbelievable.
- Rebecca, don't be this...
Careful.
You'll sever the radial artery.
Hey, can you back up?
It's pretty hard to focus when
you're breathing down my neck.
Not bad.
- Uh, thanks.
- Thank you.
Justin, can you come by and see
me tomorrow during office hours?
Uh, yeah.
Everything... all right?
Just want to discuss a few things.
Yeah, yeah, I'll be there.
Great.
This is about last week's quiz.
Damn it.
I thought I nailed it. We studied
that for, like, six straight hours.
God, why does he want to talk to me?
I told him I wanted to switch lab partners.
- What?
- Sorry, nothing personal.
But I just need someone
who's 100% committed.
Wait a second. You told
Madsen I wasn't committed?
You show up late.
Yeah, and you freaked
out when you saw a cadaver.
I didn't go running to Madsen.
That was once, this is a pattern.
You know what? Screw you.
Back up, Carter.
Here we go.
P.B, mini marshmallows, oven-fried
chicken, mac and cheese and pudding.
God, how do I get your diet?
Oh, sorry. That was insensitive.
It's okay.
I... I guess mom is trying
to spark my appetite
by bringing out all my
old childhood favorites.
But... oh, no way.
I'm not hungry.
I don't care.
You are going to eat.
All right, I'll eat...
if you tell me more about Mr. Frenchy.
It's a deal.
You never made it to that winery
you were looking for, did you?
Not that week, no.
Week?
It was amazing.
Stop blocking your face.
You're making me self-conscious.
Your face, it is powerful and soft... like you.
What do you know about me, except
for my inability to read a map?
Your expressions... it tells me many things.
For example... your brow, your jaw...
Sarah, you're a woman who's in control.
You like control.
Your eyes and your smile...
they say something different.
You want to be wild, give in to your impulses.
Did they teach you that at art school?
No. It's something I simply see.
What else do you simply see?
That you're slow to trust.
Maybe a little.
But you want to let go.
Hello.
Hello. Should I come back?
- Yeah, yeah.
- No, no, yeah. No, no, no.
- Uh, you'll stay, I'll go.
- No, no, no.
- We'll, uh, continue this tomorrow.
- Oh, tomorrow?
- Keep her hydrated, will you?
- Yeah, yeah. Thanks.
No problem. I'll call you tomorrow.
When I'm better, we're going to France.
Wherever you want.
- How's Evan?
- Oh, his... his cold's getting better.
The doctor says he's almost well
enough to be around you.
Oh, good, good. 'Cause I... I really miss him.
Tommy. He sent a very nice note.
So how was it?
Uh, it wasn't, uh... it wasn't as
scary as I thought it would be.
And I... I'm definitely nauseated, though.
Here.
- At's that?
- Acupressure.
If I put pressure right on
your palm, it reduces nausea.
How come I never knew about this skill before?
'Cause I just looked it up online.
I'm just... happy to be
able to do something to help.
Are you gonna make me
ask about the press conference?
It went fine.
- Fine?
- Yeah.
That's it?
But you... but you always tell me everything,
right down to the distracting sheen
on the loaf of some Ted from the Times.
Usually, my wife isn't just
finishing her first round of chemo.
What were the numbers? I bet you're
down with women. What... what are they?
We took a hit.
- But I'm not worried.
- You always worry. That's why you win.
All right, well, this time, I'm gonna win
and I'm not gonna worry. How's that sound?
- Like a lie.
- Come here.
Just leave... California out there.
In here, it's just you and me.
Hey.
- Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh, what?
You're folding socks.
You only fold socks when you're upset.
Well, we don't have a wedding
venue and my mother and I fought today.
- Oh, well, that sucks.
- Yeah. How was your day?
Remember that oncology
internship I applied for?
Oh, no. You didn't get it?
Oh, that's up in the air, but check this out.
So Carter decides to tell Professor
Madsen that he wants a new lab partner.
- What?
- Yeah. He says I can't handle the workload that I already got.
Doogie thinks you can't hack it?
What a tool.
All right, so what's going
on with the venue things?
I mean, I had no idea that
wedding stuff is so cookie cutter.
- It's just not us.
- All right. So what would make it personal?
Becca, I sure when you were a little girl, you
know, you had plans about your wedding.
Kitty and Sarah used to play bride all the time.
So did Kevin.
Well, I didn't. I mean... I... I mean, it's not like
I had some wedding album of my
mother's to look through, you know?
I... I think you have a defective bride.
Rebecca, I don't have a defective bride... at all.
Well, I don't know. I don't know.
I... I think maybe you should plan the wedding.
Yeah. Well, unless you want
chili dogs and chicken wings
at a Dodger game, that's probably a bad idea.
How's Kitty?
She's asleep.
Great.
God, she's tough.
According to Sarah, they had fun today.
Good.
I'm glad Sarah's back.
Kitty needs you guys.
How are you holding up?
Good.
So I assume you don't want an update
on the polls, which are still down.
Correct assumption.
Uh, well, let's see, in other important
state matters... oh, yeah,
Madera county would like your support
in their campaign to change the state bird.
How about the ostrich? They're so cute.
You know, they do that whole
head-burying-in-the-sand thing.
I'm not burying my head in the sand.
Yes, you are. Come on, Robert.
You march into that office and
act like you're working.
- We all know what's going on...
- What do you want from me?
- You do realize, Kitty will not let you quit this campaign?
- I haven't quit.
No, you've stopped running, because
you know if you do nothing,
your whole campaign will
fall apart on its own,
and you can tell Kitty you tried your best.
Reality is, you're sabotaging
your chances, and you know it.
Kevin, stay out of it.
Hey, how are you feeling?
Oh, I feel like I want to vomit, and
the deep breaths are not cutting it,
so please, you need to tell me the end.
It was a vacation romance.
And... like vacations...it ended.
Oh, I know. But just tell me... tell me how.
- Sarah? Are you there?
- Yeah.
You know... he... he wasn't
who I thought he was.
The last day I was there, I went for a walk.
- Sarah...
- Who was that?
- I must explain.
- Don't bother.
I'm so sorry.
You wonder why I don't trust.
No, no, no. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
No, no, wait a... wait a second.
I know this.
You go back to your
car, and it doesn't start.
and then you go back to the farmhouse with
the both of them. It's the movie.
What movie?
This whole time, you've been telling me
the plot of that French movie
that mom used to love when we were kids.
Okay, you're right. You busted me.
I'm sorry.
You mad at me?
No, I'm not mad.
I'm... you took my mind off of everything.
I'm... I'm just very sad that you didn't get to
have a love affair with a hunky French man.
Yeah... me, too.
Hey, where'd you go? I thought
you were next to me the whole time?
Oh. You're not Robert.
He's at the drug store filling a prescription.
But I can sit with you if you
want. That's why I'm here.
Are you allowed to have that?
That blog waright.
Chemo definitely makes the beer taste better.
- Could I?
- Get your own. I have cancer.
So, um... Robert's been getting really beat up
for not suspending his campaign, right?
He told you?
Nope. He didn't have to.
- How bad is it?
- You know what? I wouldn't say that bad.
Well, that's because he won't let you.
But what's the plan?
What's the counter strategy?
Oh, great. You don't have one.
You know what? I'm kinda caught
here between a rock and his wife,
- so can we just...
- Oh, you know what? Come on, Kevin.
He's not doing anything.
It's... it's like the rope-a-dope with no plan of
coming off the ropes and
actually throwing any punches.
All right. So what are we gonna do?
Let him suspend... a clean, dignified break.
Why let him limp through a campaign he
doesn't even want to be a part?
All he wants is to be here with you.
Well, too bad. He can't.
Why not? You know, you keep asking
us to keep on living normally.
Well, you know what? People put
things on hold when people are sick.
- No, no, no, we're not gonna put anything on hold...
- Yes, they do. Take care of your wife.
- That's acting normally!
- Because if he quits, and I don't survive this, then what?
Don't... please do not go there, okay?
Well, I have to go there, Kevin.
I don't have a choice.
Now you are either in
denial of who Robert is or
you're in denial of how things
may turn out for me, okay?
If he quits, and I die, then what?
And we're not gonna let that happen.
And you are gonna help me, Kevin,
because Robert needs this,
- especially if...
- Please, one condition.
- What?
- No more if...
You're getting better. That's that.
Okay, fine. I'm getting better.
So how do we help him?
I think I have an idea.
Look, sir, I... I know that going for an internship
right now may not be the best idea, but...
Has someone in your family
been diagnosed with cancer?
Yeah. Um... my sister Kitty.
It's lymphoma, stage III.
- How did... how did you know that...
- Because I've seen this before...
a... a sudden academic fire, new
found interest in oncology.
I'm sorry.
I... you know, I... I... that's... I'm...
I just want to help somehow.
And there's nothing wrong with that,
and many of the greatest advances in medicine,
in every branch of science, has been made
by people who have very personal motives.
Then... then why is going for
an internship a bad idea?
Justin, because there is a right way
and a wrong way to go about things.
Taking on so much in your first year,
and then, God forbid, you fail?
How does that help anybody?
Yeah, you're... you're right. I... I... I get it.
And now... about Carter.
Carter, yeah. He, uh, he
wants a new lab partner.
Well, he is brilliant.
So he tells me.
But he's so afraid of failure that
he can't think straight.
Yeah, well, me, too.
But you have more practical life experience
than any student I've had in years.
And he's had less life than
anyone I've ever met.
So what, you... you want me to get him laid or...
No, Mr. Walker. I want you
to teach him by example
how to get along with people in the real world.
Yeah, I... yeah, I c... I can do that.
Good. And look, someday you may
become an extraordinary oncologist,
able to help people like your sister.
But every journey starts with the first step.
And in this case, the first step is the hand.
Start with the hand.
I left my cell phone in the car.
I'm surprised that you
wanted to meet me here.
- No, I... I asked you because I wanted your opinion.
- Yeah.
But, uh, I also really need to
apologize. I'm... I'm sorry.
I... I was frustrated, and
I took it out on you,
and I shouldn't have.
I promise I won't be all bridezilla
for the rest of the wedding planning.
You weren't that bad.
And I'm sure it was really annoying,
me picking up the phone all the time.
No, no. Is everything okay?
Yeah. Everything is great now.
I got enough juice that
we can start production on our new blend.
- That's great.
- It's great.
But today is about you and your wedding.
So what do you think about this place?
Mom.
Is it me, or do all of these places suck?
No, you're right.
None of these places have
been right for you and Justin.
So let's just take a step back, all right?
Okay, so now when you
think about your wedding,
what do you picture?
I don't have a picture.
I mean, where was I when
all of these little girls
were staging fake weddings in their bedrooms?
Outside in the backyard
splashing in the mud and
- begging meto let you stay outfor five more minutes, please, mommy.
- I remember.
You would stay out as long as I would let you.
You and that stuffed dolphin that I got
you at Sea World, running through the ferns.
- Awoka-woka.
- Awoka-what?
- Awoka-woka. That's it.
- What?
Mom, I... I think I know where
we should get married.
Great.
Thank you.
If you're not up for company,
I could come back.
No, no, I am. Come on in.
How are you feeling?
I'm tired, but, you know,
I'm actually not that bad.
Good. Or not good.
No, I... it's good.
Mom, are you... are you
angry about yesterday?
No. I am... over it.
Whatever it was, I'm over it.
You're the one that knows what's best for you,
and whatever you want or don't want...
just tell me what to do, and I'll do it.
Mom, you're already doing it.
I feel like I'm not doing enough.
Well, you can't cure me.
I wish I could pull every bit of that cancer
out of you and put it in me instead.
I wish it were me.
I know. That's why I couldn't have
you with me yesterday.
I didn't want to put you through that,
and... and besides, if you cry, I cry.
Did Sarah do okay?
Yeah, Sarah... Sarah did great.
- Just... aah.
- What?
No, it's just this... this, uh, injection
site is just pretty sore.
I don't know. Dr. Avadon said they're
gonna maybe put in a chest catheter.
It makes it easier.
I don't want to cry.
It's okay.
You can cry.
Are you at a good place to take a break?
Sure, if you can help me remember
the erector spinae muscles.
There's iliocostalis, uh, longissimus, spinalis.
I'm just trying to get a head
start on next week's work.
I.L.S. I love sex.
Erector. Sex.
Yeah. I'm into that.
I got it. I.L.S.
What... what's
going on?
Okay, um, so you know how you said that,
you know, little girls play bride?
Well, I... I didn't.
But I did play the isle of awoka-woka.
I would go outside with
my little stuffed animal...
bradmore... this little dolphin,
and we'd great strand... on a deserted island.
But instead of... instead of
being sad, we would be happy,
because, you know, there were palm trees
and tiki torches and... and coconut desserts,
and it was just... it was perfect.
And it was everything that I ever wanted
on this... this little island.
Please tell me this means a wedding in Hawaii.
- Oh, I love that.
- Yeah?
- I love that.
- Yeah? I mean, you can surf.
Uh-oh. Maybe a little bit of this?
- Yeah.
- A little of that.
- A little hula dancing.
- Yeah.
- A little bit of this.
- Look at your spinalis!
What do you say to people that think
that Robert should suspend his campaign?
Well, I would say that that would be
a real tragedy for the people of California.
California needs Robert McCallister.
And he will be there for us.
He'll be there for all of us.
You know, Robert needs
to continue to fight his battle
just like I need to continue to fight mine.
And I don't think you'll find either
one of us cowering in the corner.
- What is this?
- Your polls going up. Her idea.
I also truly believe that Robert has
this uncanny ability to stay focused...
even when he needs to
make hard judgments.
You seem well, Kitty, and I mean
you sound incredibly positive in
light of this difficult situation.
How do you achieve that?
With a lot of help.
I am surrounded by... by
so much love and support.
Ever since my diagnosis, my
husband, my mother, my siblings...
everybody has really...
really rallied around me.
Hey, mom. It's so funny you called.
I was just in this gorgeous patisserie.
They had those little pastries you love.
She's got what?
Oh, my...
I'll be home tomorrow. Okay.
Sarah. What's wrong?
It's my sister. I've gotta go home.
I've gotta go. I'm sorry.
Sarah.
Thank you for speaking
with us today, Kitty.
Well, thank you. It's my pleasure.
that was pundit and blogger Kitty McCallister,
the wife of Senator Robert McCallister, talking...
I thought we had an arrangement.
Which one was that?
That you we gonna concentrate on getting
well and leave the campaigning to me.
Right, right. But you weren't
holding up your end of the bargain.
It's not healthy for you.
You need to ignore it.
Well, then you need
to allow me to ignore it.
Stop throwing the game.
That's your... your plan, right?
I'd still be a senator.
I just wouldn't be in the
middle of this campaign.
No, I know what this is about.
This is about us. This is
about... this about us... before.
What if I'm not that guy anymore?
What if I don't want it at any cost?
Because I know that you are the
most important thing to me.
And I didn't know that before.
And I... I'm ashamed of that.
Honey... you don't owe me anything.
Yes, I do.
Well, then you can't stop being an example.
What do you mean?
You never give up.
I don't want you to give up now.
Please.
All right.
Just a second.
Pardon me. I lost.
I was wondering if you could help me.
Oh, my God.
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=-
Proudly Presents Sync: Sunpy ÿÂ¨Â»Ã'
corrected by chamallow35
www.Addic7ed.com