Cut it.
I got it back on.
It's really about the
innocence and loss of innocence.
And the exploitation of innocence,
always appeals to me because again
that happened in 'Tommy',
and I, and it certainly
began to happen with Tom and
Barry, the way they were bought.
Conjoined twins
desolate location, cut off
from everything, where they are,
where they grew up.
They're sold by their own father
and they move out into the world.
What happens to them then? I
mean, it's all incredibly Gothic.
Mum had been having these
terrible these terrible nightmares.
She thought she was expecting triplets.
Doctors got it wrong.
And mum passed away the next day.
Never even saw them.
And there they were my two brothers.
Joined together just here at the chest.
Peas in a pod.
The doctors wanted to
try separation surgery.
But father'd have none of it.
It was bad enough he'd lost his wife.
He wasn't having the doctors
messing about with his boys.
Father took us off to
live out on the Head.
Didn't let no-one near us.
No-one knew us.
We didn't go to school like other kids.
Dad taught us everything.
They were grand times.
Music hall. I trod the
boards before I could walk.
I did a double act with me mum.
Zelda and little Zak.
Ever heard of 'em?
Music business now is no
different to what it was then.
People want a show.
Punters wanna see
something a bit different.
Yeah, well, back in the late fifties and
sixties you know, if I'm being honest,
Zak Bedderwick was the king.
Whatever, whoever he wanted he had.
He reckoned The Noize was
gonna be the new Small Faces,
that Chris Dervish was gonna be
the new Steve Marriott.
The band collapsed when
Chris Dervish, the lead singer
took his 1968
Ford Shelby for a swim
in Staines reservoir.
The run of bad luck had left
Zak Bedderwick bruised and...
pretty battered.
He hadn't had a pop hit
of any kind for some years.
By 1974, he was ready
to, raise the stakes.
When my father signed that contract,
he believed he'd secured
Tom and Barry an income.
If you would just sign
there, please.
He wanted his boys to be
able to look after themselves.
Dad.
So many wanted to claim them.
In some ways, even more now
than when they were alive, but...
there's never been, like,
any real concern or love.
The contract stipulated that
Bedderwick Walker Entertainments
would own exclusive publishing
rights to the Howe twins' music.
In return, Albert Howe and his sons
were guaranteed a substantial salary.
Payable monthly for
a period of one year.
Hand on my heart, I never exploited
anyone who didn't want to be exploited.
Then Mr Couling took them away.
I never thought I'd be in a
rock band I thought, if we...
we might get away from,
from the head and that,
and I thought we might go
and get a job and that, but...
We listened to lots
of music, but it was...
Yeah, we like
and we always used to,
like, get the records on
and like at Christmas and
that, like, we'd always.
Put on some older.
Well, like, and, well, just generally,
we'd always, like, get on, like
but I, I think,
I dunno, we've got something special.
I mean
everyone who's ever been famous has always
had something that's special to them, and...
we've got something special.
But no-one, ever thought
we'd ever, ever, ever be...
Doing an interview.
Here, and, like, doing this with
a band and doing this, and...
Someone, someone
recordingan interview with us
actually, I mean no, no,
but I think it has always
been, like, sort of a, a dream.
A dream.
All right, hello, mate.
I just want a kind of a nice happy vibe,
but I'm gonna introduce you to the boys.
Sucking it out but holding it in.
This is, this is amazing stuff really.
Looking at it after all these years.
It was a weird place. Zak created
this, this magical wonderland.
He had every freak in the world there.
But, of course, the boys
were main attraction.
It was all about them.
I didn't have that much
going on myself at the time
so, they were gonna give me a
few bucks a week all my expenses
and I was gonna have the opportunity
to shoot whatever I wanted to about this
this weird idea.
Right?
Okay, now.
Hold them tight, press them down.
And just play those three.
Go on you'll get it.
Listen to him.
Just play the three that you want.
Most of the chords, you know, you can
put them anywhere.
You can write a fucking song with that.
Just keep doing that.
Make sure you've got it in your head.
I'm gonna put a song on.
No, it's do-do.
- Just don't tell me
- Don't argue
I'm not.
And listen.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
I want you to listen to this, right?
Paul, that's what I was playing.
And then all I have to teach you to
do is play another couple of chords
and you've got the song, mate.
Me and Zak go back to,
like, the mid-sixties.
He was always getting me
in to babysit the new kids.
Zak wanted singing Siamese twins
and he wanted them pop.
The name was his idea, The Bang Bang.
It was my job to sort
the boys out musically.
I can't reach. I hurt my fingers.
Well, it's gonna hurt, innit?
Tom, get off. You're getting in my way.
You're fucking it up!
I need to get that
plectrum now, don't I?
Where have you put it?
Well, Barry threw it.
No, I didn't.
Don't throw it.
Barry, look, at some point
you're gonna have to play it.
See what I'm doing?
You're gonna have to learn
this stuff at some point.
Won't.
Have a sing, then.
Sing it. Yeah, that's
a good idea. Sing it.
That's it.
Keep going.
A, E, A...
- Is that for me?
- Yeah.
Well, share it.
- There you go.
- Thanks, Paul.
You're welcome.
Keep going. E, A, E.
That's it, mate.
That's almost in tune. Drink a
bit more and then it'll be in tune.
It works.
Maybe that's what we'll do.
We'll string a load of
those together and...
Bottle solo from Baz.
That's it.
An apprenticeship, he called it.
My future in the entertainment industry.
Fucking hell, he's there!
Oh, he's got it Georgie Best!
Georgie Best!
They were a shock.
That's what they were
like. A real shock.
Fuck it!
Bedderwick had called me.
He told me, but he didn't tell me.
If you know what I mean.
Two-one!
Two-one...
I was just a henchman.
Just his henchman, you know?
Unpaid arsewipe.
Handling all those freaks was
just another shitty gig to me.
Here.
Paul. Paul.
Look, give the other one a guitar, yeah?
Give 'em both a guitar. It'll look good.
No, trust me, give 'em one each. Yeah?
Give 'em this one.
There you go.
Here you are, Barry. Barry.
No, it'll look good.
It's not gonna work, Paul.
It's a stupid idea.
Let's just start,
let's just Fucking hell!
Have you got something
to say to me, Barry?
You should turn it off.
It's a fucking joke.
There was a bit of a discipline problem
with Barry right from the start, you know.
So I used to hose him down
if he got out of control.
No, I'm serious.
You know, with kids and that
well, you've gotta have
a firm hand, ain't ya?
Barry, you know, he was
always holding something back.
There was always something
else going on with him.
I mean, a lot of people's take was
he's mischievous, he's a country kid
but, no, I think, very deep.
I think it was something
that ran real deep with him.
I'd like to be going home.
Why does he have to come in?
He's gotta come in, Baz.
- Why?
- Well, he's gotta see it, mate.
He'll see, you know,
how much you've improved.
Look, boys, I mean do
it for me, you know, cos
cos I'll get shit on if, if I'm
not seen to be doing my job, so...
Let's just do it.
I'm not playing if Nick comes in.
You have to, mate.
You have to. I can't get around
it. You gotta do it, you know.
And at some point you've gotta do
it in front of an audience, so...
I mean
you know, Nick's the
least of your worries.
So, Paul, we haven't really
spoken about Nick Sidney
and how he interacted
with Tom and Barry.
Why did you stand by when these
kids were getting beaten up?
Fuck off! Fuck off, Eddie!
What you fucking still doing here?
What's going on?
What you doing up there?
Both of you, down now!
Fuck off!
Do you...
Jesus!
Tom, what do you think
you're playing at?
This is silly.
Eddie, fuck off!
What was that?
Do you wanna be in the band?
Jesus Chr... little bastard!
I swear to God, if
you don't come down...
All we want, though.
You will not be in a
band. I will take you home!
Do you want it?
You fucking cunt, you'll be out of
a job if you fucking take us home!
You need us more than we need you!
What's Zak gonna say then, eh?
Yeah, sure, there was
a bad vibe, you know.
Barry was out of control, so what?
Barry delivered when he
was under the cosh, yeah?
The treatment I give him worked.
You see all them girls?
Yeah?
That's you.
He called me, he: said "The boys need
a band, and they need an original song".
Their signature, if you like.
And the only brief he gave me,
he wanted something a bit sexy.
So I thought, "Okay, well, we've
got two Siamese twins, well, you know
a pair of Siamese twins".
So I called up Tubs Puller,
the ex-Noize drummer.
And I knew this art school
kid, Spitz, on guitars.
And I was on bass.
Here we go.
Well, 'Two-Way Romeo', if
you Twolisten to the lyrics,
it'll tell you what it's about.
And then the chorus again.
We're gonna play down at this,
grotty little pub in Stokey.
But they had a great
reputation for good new bands.
I mean, back then, we had,
music three nights a week.
DJs Wednesdays bands
Fridays and Saturdays.
Now they'd rather have a meal.
Yeah, the bands used to
just walk through here.
There was a bar along here.
And over there in the
corner was the little stage.
It was a rough crowd that night.
Really nasty.
At Humbleden, these guys were protected.
But suddenly they were
thrusted to this audience.
They were dead nervous.
The crowd are just, I mean, they're
shouting things out at them, things like
you know, "Who are these two poofs
coming on cuddling each other?"
Chanting.
"Get off. Get off you queer wankers!"
Everybody just froze.
Everyone just froze.
Out of the blue
I'll never forget this,
Barry just grabs the mic stand
and starts screaming the lyrics.
I mean, really snarling it out.
I'd never seen anything
like that before.
Audience are going fucking
mad, throwing things at them.
And then one of the lads just
he just started kind of
taunting the audience back.
Barry's lifting his shirt up.
Tempting them, you know?
Showing them kind of where the join was.
Everyone in that audience
thought it was a gag.
"Show it, show it, show it!"
And then he just rips open his
shirt, and you just see this
incredible, you know, band
of skin joining them together.
It was like a freak show.
It was like
"Here I am.
Fuck you".
Bedderwick didn't want
no filming that night.
Just in case they flopped.
Well, they didn't flop.
That was The Bang Bang.
I called Zak straight away.
"Zak, you got a band. It's working. "
Happy Christmas.
What is it?
That's a special from
Mr Bedderwick, mate.
There's a letter in there as well.
Let's have a look.
It's an antique. Don't just
gently, lads, gently, gently.
I hope you can do something with this.
With great expectations.
Zak...
Zak Bedderwick.
Let's have a look.
Look, it means a lot to
him that sheet music. Yeah?
What is it, Tom? Show me.
- 'Every Little Moment. '
- The Hilton Sisters.
Words and music by Bobby Jones.
Featuring the phenomenal
success. The Hilton Sisters.
The Hilton Sisters.
Yeah, they were another Siamese act.
Siamese sisters?
Gently, gently, it's an antique.
Well, what does he
want us to do with it?
I don't know.
You figure it out, boys.
God, right.
Go on then, sing it.
It's not a fucking joke. Come on.
It sounds like one of
our dad's old songs.
I don't care what it
sounds like, you know.
Change it, do something with it, yeah?
Just...
- We'll change it, we'll change it.
- Change it. Take it back.
Whole idea of it was
it was Zak's blessing.
It was, it was his blessing.
It was, it was his way of
saying "Go ahead, make an album.
Go for it, I'll pay for it. "
I mean, Zak...
Zak thought it: was just a matter of,
you know, padding out a couple of
catchy hits with a few extra tunes.
Nobody else, just me.
I wanted it to be me in the room, and
it felt like it was me in the room.
Yeah, the boom boom, bang bang thing.
Really really buzzing
from it. It was brilliant.
My ears are ringing and,
and I've just been so upset.
She's been so upset.
But I, I didn't care any more because.
Doesn't matter what you look like,
doesn't matter what you dress like.
Here to dance.
Oh, my mum's gonna kill
me when she finds out I...
When he undid his shirt,
we kind of fancied them.
If they can do that,
then we can do anything.
- That's fucking rocking.
- Yeah, yeah.
Zak Bedderwick wanted me to get
the photo for the album sleeve,
the record sleeve, you know, and...
well, I was going to do
this kind of Fontainebleau.
You know, the two women that
are holding each other's nipples.
Well, one's holding the other one.
So I thought that, you know,
with the play, with the twins,
with the join, with the
girls with the masks.
And then Barry
he took the whole thing
completely out of my hands.
The girls didn't know...
I didn't, I just thought
I've got to go with this.
Tom was, he was a little studious boy
that wanted to be a good musician,
that wanted to get it right
that wanted to please me.
And Barry wanted to fuck with me.
Testosterone.
That's what happened.
Well that's what I'm
talking about, they're,
they're threatening to
do an expose. Muck raking.
They're talking freaks, Henry.
- They're talking cruel training methods.
- Right.
...Mr Bedderwick, would you say that
the information in this proposed article
comes within any appreciable
distance of being accurate?
Well, that's what I'm worried about.
I know the journalist. So do you.
Laura Ashworth.
Laura Ashworth?
Laura Ashworth was a slapper, mate.
If you're in trouble
and you need a friend.
Laura Ashworth is the last person
you want coming round the corner.
Maybe a cowbell.
Hello, Laura.
How are you, sweetheart?
Good to see you.
It's been a while, ain't it?
Look at you.
Paul, what's this, who's this?
This is Laura.
- Laura Ashworth.
- Is it?
Yeah.
Bit old for a, a groupie,
aren't you, darling?
Actually, no, I don't think I am.
I think you are.
Do you?
- Yeah.
- Oi... gently.
It's Tom, isn't it?
That's right. You are correct.
I am Tom.
Good to meet you, Tom.
This is George.
- I thought it was Barry.
- Hi... I'm George.
George. Do you mind
if I call you, Barry?
Look, he's, he's joking.
I'm actually Barry.
- Call me Georgina if you want.
- I'm Barry.
Shake my hand. Touch my hand.
Hello.
I'm Barry.
Bloody hell.
What's the, what's the fucking gag then?
What is she doing here?
Haven't you been told?
She's gonna write your autobiography.
Is she fuck.
What?
No, I'm not writing your autobiography.
No, I know you're not. See you later.
Nick.
What?
What exactly have...?
So that's all right.
So what, are you a music
journalist then or...?
Well, not quite, but the...
I'm writing for an academic publication.
Yeah, you're gonna be in
an academic publication.
Academic publication no less.
- Academic publication.
- Yeah.
You're on the way up.
Well, you guys specifically.
What about us?
Well, you know
you're kind of you know,
you're, you're, you're different.
- You're...
- What?
- young and exciting and, you know.
- Young, exciting, give me, give me a third.
Listen, I'm, I'm actually writing
an article about exploitation
of the physically impaired.
Speak to Tubs, he's got a dodgy ankle.
Of course, I had this image of
these two young victims, these
poor defenceless boys that
were being totally exploited.
And then
when I see these, these, these, these
young, vibrant men with this
energy and this presence, and
it just threw me totally.
When Mr Bedderwick
approached me with the Laura
Ashworth problem
I suggested he took her on the payroll.
I knew she wouldn't be able
to resist recapturing her past.
And I knew she wouldn't be
able to resist the twins.
It was child psychology.
So have you interviewed loads
of other bands and stuff, Laura?
Unofficially, yes.
Off, off the record.
- Co, covert, covert operations.
- Off the record. On the QT.
- Yeah.
- Microphone down your panties?
Barry.
I have to keep him on a lead.
- Do you?
- Yeah.
Is that your job,
between the two of you?
Yeah. Yes.
- Really?
- Yeah.
How do you, how do you feel
about the people at Humbleden?
- Tubs and Spitz?
- Tubs and Spitz. It's...
And...
It's a great crowd.
You like them?
Yeah, well, the...
you know, there's lots of...
And Mick and Aaron and...
Felix and Ben.
Are there any people,
in particular that you
you get on with more than.
Ask him about Adelle.
Who's Adelle?
Adelle.
- Adelle?
- Just a girl I like.
Just a girl.
Oh, really? Is there interest already?
Well, you wanna ask Tom about that.
Tell me about Adelle.
No, it's not important.
No, go on, te...
Am I embarrassing you?
No, don't
What, what's that?
- What was he gonna hand me?
- It's just my songbook.
It's what I write my chords
in and that, and like...
Have you written a song about a girl?
No.
It's talking, talking dirty.
And,
says you, says you wanna, says you
wanna, says you wanna have sex with her.
What?
What? Oh, what?
Tommy does.
Tommy, Tommy wakes up in the
night, what, talking about
Adelle and that and that he wants to
he wants to touch her bum.
Shut up.
And, and he fiddles.
- He rubs himself up and down at night.
- Shut up.
- He does.
- He does. He does.
- Shut up. Shut up.
- He wakes up in the night and he's always
- Just shut up. Just...
and I can feel the bed rolling
around and I know it's...
Look, just shut up, Barry.
What's that?
What's that, he likes to touch himself?
Barry, just shut up.
Right, guys, why don't we just Shut up.
- Cos Tommy likes...
- Shut up.
Does Tommy like to touch?
Just shut up!
- Just fucking shut up!
- Does Tommy like to touch himself?
Shut up!
Tommy fiddles with himself at night!
Just shut up!
Tom, you're a bit sensitive today.
Shut up.
He hasn't had his normal morning wank.
Probably heard it all before.
What?
Probably wanked boys off yourself.
Barry.
You two should go upstairs
and take your boots off.
And go in there and spread your legs.
Okay,so, can I ask you what
what happened there?
He speaks the truth.
Who, who does?
Hasn't got a name.
He's just there.
What?
It's nothing. sits there.
It's nothing, nothing's there.
Just...
just sometimes
I'm just interested to know.
heil, Sieg heil, Sieg heil
In the first series forty-seven
left wing protesters were arrested.
Tension rose still higher
as the National Front march,
well over a thousand strong, reached
the entrance to Red Lion Square.
Their way was left-wingers
and both sides were
kept apart by the police.
I noticed that Tom was writing
stuff down, he had a lot of ideas.
So I let him let him, you
know, just, just go with it.
I mean, it was like
an explosion of stuff.
If you listen to the lyrics of the songs
it was very small, it was all about
really the places they came from.
They always had an edge. They
always had a sense of danger.
Play it again, yeah?
Two to one and one is three.
Are you you or are you me?
Now you tell me what that's about?
Like all little kids, Tom and Barry had
a secret friend they used to talk to.
I had two myself.
Doola and Dawla.
They lived in my shoes.
I don't know what the
boys called theirs.
...bury me.
Bury me.
Kill me.
It was their secret friend brought
all those terrible nightmares.
His oldest trick, right, what it is,
is we got lots of rubber bands, right
from Robbie's box, like,
sewing box and that...
Robbie's box then we put them all
together, and that just stuck us together.
Tom grows on Barry
and Barry grows on Tom.
And that is...
And that is what it is.
Life is that...
Come on then.
Will you give us one...
You got the lyrics there?
As long as we're in
together, be all right?
Bang bang Ready?
Come on.
Too fucking right.
One more time!
You did and you didn't forget that they
were actually physically joined together
because they were two
very different people.
I found the way Tom held his
silence was attractive.
And Barry was
vulnerable and I tapped
into that very quickly
and although he made
me feel uncomfortable
because he was so in your
face a lot of the time
I just wanted to
protect him, really.
They're, they're, they're,
they're right through,
they're right through these posh girls,
hang out, whatever they've got,
the education got, you know, I'd...
you know, they lead
lead people astray, mate,
lead people astray, they
It's generally held that conjoined
held that conjoined separated
whenever medically possible
as early as possible.
The Howes were omphalopagus.
Joined at the lower chest.
As were the original Siamese
twins Chang and Eng Bunker.
Tom and Barry Howes'
circulatory system was inter
- interconnected.
And in addition they shared a liver.
An operation to separate the
twins would have been accompanied
by extraordinary dangers given
the medical knowledge of that time.
Especially as Barry had been born
with a congenital heart defect
which made him the weaker sibling.
However, I have no doubt that that
would have been the correct decision.
- Chang and Eng.
They were born in Siam.
- And they were like...
- They could have cut themselves apart.
We got a bread knife, cos
that's probably better,
but this is like, it's like, it's like,
like a hot knife through butter, that is.
Bye-bye, Ba... bye-
bye, Barry.
Bye-bye,
bye-bye, Barry.
Do you wanna be separate?
Might do, might not.
Could do.
Could not.
Are you guys gonna have kids?
Dunno.
Are you gonna have a kid?
Imagine if I had twins.
Imagine if I had triplets.
Imagine if I had quads.
Imagine if I had.
Sextuplets.
Five-tuplets.
If I had conjoined twins
I would cut 'em down the
middle like a slice of bread.
I think Ken Russell should
stick to 'Women In Love'
which I think is brilliant.
But like a lot of biopics, you know,
they miss the essence,
the essential beauty.
- Are you done with those?
- Oh, my darling.
Thank you very much.
You're a star.
You're my wonderful woman.
- Excuse me.
- Adelle?
Adelle?
That's just how I like them.
Something I can dunk my soldiers
in if you know what I mean, Laura.
Do you like dunking
your soldiers, Barry?
I love to dunk my soldier.
You love it when I dunk my
soldier, don't you, Laura?
Shut up, Barry.
Oh, hard.
Never mind, never mind.
I reckon what we should do,
just to make this beautiful
sunny morning even better
put
Does it look nice?
- I love it. It's lovely.
- Thank you, Barry.
You look very pretty, Laura.
You do, you look very pretty
this morning, actually.
What?
What, Tommy?
Want a soldier?
Play something else, Tom.
Tom.
Tom, play another fucking song.
Tom, you've been playing that song
for the last fucking half an hour.
Look, it wasn't an ideal situation,
and I know that, you know.
And I had my own anger
and frustration about it.
I fell in love with Tom.
You can't choose who
you fall in love with.
When Barry performed, it was
like he was fighting for his life.
It was like
he just wanted that
to keep going.
And I think he was afraid it would stop.
I think the thought of not
having that kind of sense of
of power, maybe.
Sense of being wanted.
Of being adored.
I think that frightened Barry a lot.
Fuck off!
Stop it!
All right, Tom, all right.
Get off!
There were always fights, but...
one time in particular
Barry actually threatened
Tom with a knife.
And it got very real.
I actually examined the Howe brothers
on a, on a single occasion, just once
after one of those,
violent episodes that
they were prone to.
And it was here that I discovered
something very interesting.
This dark patch.
And growth of some kind.
Now, Barry's mood swings and
restlessness and general paranoia
are indicative of
amphetamine abuse, but...
those symptoms can also
be attributed to a tumour.
There have been cases where one
twin is encapsulated in a cyst
or tumour inside the other.
It's known as foetus in fetu.
There was the case of a
farmer, aged twenty-eight,
who went to the doctor
complaining of a stomach ache.
He was found to have a thirteen
pound foetal twin inside his abdomen.
On opening the head of the foetus,
two additional foetuses were
found in the cranial cavity.
It's conceivable
that Barry Howe
harboured the rudiments of a
third foetus in his cranium.
A lot of people have asked
me about this, this third head
on, on the shoulders
of the, of the brothers.
In the novel I just, I just simply
didn't believe it, because things
don't grow like that, whereas
a sort of growth on the... on
the back of the neck.
These, these things, you know, are
medically documented in such cases.
But I did think it was a
wonderful metaphor for their
for their genius, if you, if you like.
It was as though it, it, it
contained the essence of their being.
If you stopped and tried to
change the world every time
you've got the camera turning,
I guess you'd never make a
film, and maybe you shouldn't.
Maybe you should never be there for...
I know one thing.
We should have had a
psychiatrist at Humbleden.
You know, if you're gonna push all
those buttons with people's psyches
somebody should be there qualified to
handle it when it gets out of control.
Is there anyone here
tonight called William?
William? Is there anyone
called William here?
Yeah.
You're a fucking cunt!
Fuck off!
Get off the stage. Off.
Put your arm round me,
Barry. Put your arm round me.
Get the door, Tom.
Get round the fucking front.
Get in the back.
Where are you, Tom?
What can you see?
Where's Barry gone?
He's whispering in his
ear. He's whispering.
Who's whispering Tom?
Is Barry whispering?
Growing out the sand.
What's it saying, Tom?
He's getting out.
Tom, it's just a bad dream.
Just a bad dream.
There's nothing going on with the
band. Everything is good, Mr Bedderwick.
Well, you'll see for
yourself, won't you.
You'll see for yourself.
And when you see for yourself
you'll be very, very happy.
Tom, how's it going?
It's great, Eddie, it's
great. It's really great.
Yeah? What's happening?
Oh, Barry did a monster one, didn't he?
You don't have to answer
his questions, Tom.
Tom does one, Barry does one.
Goes in a circle, doesn't it, Barry?
- Barry.
- Eats itself.
Eats itself, don't it, Barry?
What's happening, Baz?
What's happening with you?
Tom does one.
One.
- Barry does one.
- No!
Barry does one.
Bang bang.
I know as time went on
that Tom became less and less happy
with his situation, and...
I know that may have been
something to do with me,
but if it wasn't me, it would have
been somebody else, you know, and...
I think he wanted his freedom.
The emotional and intellectual
lives of conjoined twins
are entwined in a, in
a highly complex way.
There may be a physical separation
that is successful, but...
in my opinionl think
it's very, very difficult
to have a successful
emotional severance.
Fuck all to do with me.
- Stop playing for two minutes.
- What?
Read it.
It's to Laura.
What?
Right.
Where's Laura?
Where is Laura?
I dunno.
Paul, what does it say?
It's from some doctor.
"Come in for a consultation"
with reference to
fucking separating 'em.
To Laura.
I received this letter
from Laura Ashworth
acting on behalf of the twins.
The gist is they wished to explore
the possibility of separation.
I didn't send that letter
to Allardyce Stevens.
Who else would have
wrote a letter like that?
Who would else
you know, who would
have had the connections,
who would have known them
sort of people, you know?
Course it came from Laura.
Got to, ain't it? Sort of
thing she would have done.
I have serious doubts that both twins
would have survived the operation.
As it was, my response went unanswered.
I never heard from them
or Laura Ashworth again.
Bedderwick, you know,
he went fucking apeshit!
He said that bitch had to go.
Someone had to shut her up.
I left because Tom didn't
ask me to stay, really.
You know, he didn't
say anything, he
didn't back me up. He...
I wasn't really in a
position to defend myself.
Or I didn't feel I was then, anyway.
Really I was set up.
Well... if you ask me, I think
Tom guessed who sent the letter.
So, are you guys gonna get separated?
Maybe when one of us...
What?
He says when one of us dies
then we both die.
Together. We go together.
Go together.
Yeah.
Sounds fucking good.
It sounds fucking brilliant.
So let's get the bass right.
Bury me...
Tom was a very cool customer.
But...
I don't think he knew
how angry he was. I...
I think
I think that he was a walking time bomb.
This is a special
night for The Bang Bang.
First we'd like to welcome
the record company people.
And, of course, Mr Zak Bedderwick.
Bedderwick? She okay?
She didn't wanna come tonight, no?
No, no, no, no. Not tonight.
Tammy, have a nice evening,
pleased to meet you.
Hi, how you doing?
A lot of you have been here before.
You have seen 'em many,
many a fucking time.
So you know what's coming don't you?
Who do you want?
Bang Bang!
Who do we fucking want?
So here they are.
The Bang Bang.
Is there anyone out there called Zak?
This one's for you, Zak.
What you give you get back.
This was the future.
That's what we were trying to do.
It was something to do with the future.
And Barry and Tom just took
it into a different place.
Just build and build and build
and it was fucking wonderful.
Here.
Impossible to see exactly what happened.
I didn't see. I was...
I couldn't get to them. I just...
There's the guitar being
lifted, right there.
Now where's Barry?
There was a few rumours
going around, weren't there?
Some people said they saw this,
some people said they saw that.
But you can't...
I would have to say that
Barry had been struck.
Look how anguished Tom is here.
I just think that he snapped.
I mean, Barry was out of
it by then, and Tom was,
he was shaking when he come out.
He didn't speak or nothing.
White.
I didn't see the twins.
Nick bundled them off,
got them back to Humbleden.
All I know is that
they were in bad shape.
It's a long time ago,
mate, long time ago.
When I went to the big
house to collect my brothers
they were in terrible state.
And no-one could tell
me what had happened.
Tom was crying.
In anger.
And fear, too.
And Barry
just stared.
It's like he wasn't there at all.
Unbury me.
"You better take us
home, Robbie," Tom says.
So I did.
Who's burying me?
I can't, I can't breathe.
Can't breathe, I can't
breathe, can't breathe.
Shall we do it, Tommy?
- Shall we do it?
- Go on then. One, two, three.
Go on, I'll close my eyes.
- Go on, do it, just do it.
- Hold the other side.
All right.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Look away a minute, look away a minute.
Yeah, I've done it.
Done it.
I just can't be bothered to move.
No. Can't.
That was where I found 'em.
They were... they were huddled together.
It was like they were sleeping.
Like when they were little kids
I'm not sure if Barry
had died first, but Tom
you could see where he'd
tried to sever himself
from his brother.
Where are you, Tom?
What can you see?
Sand.
Where's Barry gone?
He's whispering... he's whispering.
Who, who's whispering, Tom?
He doesn't have a name. He doesn't...
Tom, it's just a bad dream.
It doesn't have a name.
Just a bad dream.