And good, very good.
And...
Just bring the shine down on the lips.
Yeah, I got it.
Put the J somewhere,
maybe there?
What do you think?
- Try the right.
- Okay. How about there?
Yeah, I like that.
Let's get crazy.
- Take a break?
- Five minutes.
- How's it look?
- Looks great.
Excellent.
Hey.
So what did they say?
Really?
I can't just get one day?
No, it's just, you know,
I thought maybe I'd get
one day of rest, but obviously not.
Okay.
No, whatever.
Thanks for trying.
All right.
You're the only one
that loves me, Suzie.
Hi. You doing okay?
Um, I'll have an apple martini.
And if I could get a water and a dish?
You got it.
Hey, Suzie, is that good?
Yeah.
Where am I?
Fuck you!
How did you get in my apartment?
Let me out of here, you fuck!
You bastard!
Dirty voyeur.
You won't get away with this.
There will be police all over this!
Please let me go!
I'm sorry!
I'll do anything you want.
Anything.
I promise I won't disobey you.
Please!
Please. Please.
No, please! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry!
No!
Please...
Please.
No! Please, no!
Please!
No! Please!
No!
Stop!
Our Father,
which are in Heaven...
- I'm sorry. Please!
...hallowed be Thy name.
Get me out of here!
No, please. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No. No.
I'll do whatever you want.
Anything!
No!
No. No!
Help!
No, you know what? They're...
No. Never.
There's definitely no Mr. Right.
I guess my parents weren't in line
when the loving gene
was being passed out.
No!
What are you doing?
Please.
I have money.
Please, I'll give you whatever you want.
Just... tell me
what you need and I can...
I can get it for you.
Please.
Why?
Please let me go.
No! No!
What is that?
No!
Please.
No! No!
No.
No!
No! Please!
Yeah, I think, um... How should I put this?
Beauty opens doors, doesn't it?
Look, it's not just me who thinks this way.
This is a scientific fact.
Beauty rules, and it always has,
and it always will.
Captured.
Please!
Please.
Please help me.
Help.
Hey.
Hey. Matches.
I'm Gary.
Jennifer.
We can't waste those.
What do we do
when they're all gone?
We're just going to keep talking, okay?
We're going to talk our way through.
- We gotta get out of here.
- But this whole place is sealed.
I think it's like
some kind of wine cellar.
I tried going through the vents.
I got part of the way.
He caught me.
Have you seen him?
No. He's been drugging me.
I have absolutely no fucking sense of time.
God, I know this might
sound incredibly selfish,
but right now I'm thanking God I'm not alone.
Me, too.
You okay?
Did you just hear that?
Come on down here right now!
You think he's been listening to us?
Gotta figure yeah.
Assuming he is even a he.
Oh, trust me, he's a he.
You know that for a fact?
Yeah. I've been stalked,
and I know creeps.
It comes with the job.
Are you telling me it's, like,
a big deal that you're gone?
Maybe, maybe not.
I flaked out a couple times.
He knows all about me.
He's been to my apartment.
Yeah, he got books and stuff from mine.
Yeah, he's got my clothes.
Everything else was easy.
Easy?
Every interviewer's asked me
anything you can imagine.
"What are you afraid of?
What's your idea of hell?"
You always give them the answers?
Sometimes you tell them the truth,
sometimes you don't.
But even your idea of hell...
I didn't tell them that.
Because. Isolation.
Fuck.
Damn it.
It's okay. Look at me.
How did he get you?
I got suckered into going
to this... charity event at a club in Soho.
Someone must have put something
in my drink.
The last thing that I remember
was ... at the bathroom.
At the end of day two of search
for actress and model Jennifer Tree
Police still have no leads.
A spokesman of the celebrity told the station
that they have a heard from her.
She was last seen two nights ago
when the star starting benefit of Soho slub.
If you're in here...
what do you want?
I knew you were going to do this to me, too.
You know? I've never been
comfortable with the dark...
...being alone.
It's always been a phobia.
Just, nature is so awesome, don't you think?
It was sort of scary,
too, at the same time, even though I loved it.
All that space is what freaks me out.
Help!
Here in the public eye,
how could they refuse
the business, you know?
It's just sort of...
I helped them in a way.
Help!
Help! Help me!
Jennifer!
Help!
Let me out of here!
Please!
Oh, my God.
Help! Help!
Hey! Don't you touch her!
Help me!
Fuck!
I'll find you!
Help!
Stop!
Please!
No!
Help!
Wait!
No!
Help!
Come on.
It's okay.
I gotcha.
Come on!
- Keep moving.
- What?
Keep moving.
Come on, come on.
Where are we?
Crawl space.
The ground floor to this house...
it's just above our heads, I think.
Come on.
Fuck!
"Why do bad things happen
to good people," you ask?
That's the mystery.
No!
- Battery's dead.
- Pop the hood!
Fire it up!
Gary! Gary!
Gary! No!
No! Damn it!
No! No!
Shit.
Suzie?
Suzie!
Oh, God.
No.
Oh, shit.
Please.
Oh, God!
No, please. Shit.
No.
No!
Damn it.
I'm sorry.
...looking for any kind of lead.
So far, they've interviewed everyone
from the doorman to the caterer...
Suzie.
Suzie. Suzie.
Suzie! Hi! Hi!
- I was a rebel.
- Really?
In high school.
Always had, like,
a little bra strap showing,
black lipstick, you know.
God. But you know,
I liked the attention...
walking down the sidewalk,
and all those eyes on me.
Right.
But you know, if a guy tried to talk to me,
I was like, whoa, so out of there.
We're not getting out of here, are we?
He's playing with us,
showing his power.
Fuck.
When the doors opened, we didn't move.
I wanted to.
Yes.
I was afraid that you weren't real.
What's real?
What you can touch.
Key number 4.
No, don't.
Come here!
What's real? Tell me again.
What you can touch.
Wha...
What is that?
Gary. It's my son(?).
- Oh, no.
- Don't look at that.
No, don't look at that.
No.
You sick, twisted freak!
Don't think I know?
Gary!
Come on!
No!
Don't kill her.
I'm sorry.
No.
I'm sorry, Jennifer.
No, don't kill him!
What do you want to hear?
Tell me what you want to hear!
Don't kill him!
Are you going to kill me?
Fucker.
Jen.
Jennifer.
No. No.
Gary.
Please get us out of here!
No! No!
Gary!
Stay calm.
Oh, God.
I'm so sorry, baby.
You know when Mommy touches you,
I really love you.
Do you... Do you like it
when Mommy touches you, baby?
I just love to touch you.
Mommy doesn't feel very good, but, um...
it makes me feel really, really good.
I'm so sorry that...
Ga... Gary!
Hey! Hey!
Oh, Gary!
Don't touch her! Hey!
- Get off of me!
- You sick bastard!
Hey! Hey!
You twisted asshole! Hey!
- Oh! What...
- Don't you even touch her!
You sick piece of crap!
- What...
- Hey!
Look at me! Look at me!
Hey! Yes, you!
- No!
- Me! Me, not her!
Me! Yeah!
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Yeah, bring it...
Please! No! Stop! No!
No! No! Stop it!
No!
Stop! No!
Fuck you!
No! Oh, my God!
Oh, God! Gary!
God, I'm not your mother!
You know what? Kill me!
Go! I'm ready! Do it!
Fuck you!
Gary.
Jennifer.
- Jennifer?
- Oh, thank God.
Still no new news in
Jennifer Tree disappearance.
And is last night the modelist
have been missing for four days.
Police ... for any kind of lead.
So far the interviews...
Can't stop staring at you.
Guess you get that
a lot, though, huh?
Can't stop touching you.
Me, neither.
Jennifer.
Jen.
I'm tired.
Come on.
Get on your feet.
Hey, hey.
Jennifer, talk to me.
I can't.
Just let me sleep.
Jen, can you hear me?
Fuck.
...feel really, really good.
I'm so sorry that I make you mad.
....
Gary...
Gary, is that you?
Gary?
That's for fucking up the cameras.
Those cost money.
Are you nuts?
You should show me
just a little bit of respect, man.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Shoes off up here.
How often do I have to tell you that?
- Why'd you put her out now?
- Don't.
Thought you were going to wait till morning,
have another night of hero sex.
It was my call.
Okay.
Was it good?
One of the best.
Don't you ever want to be the one?
The one?
Experiencing it.
Hah, I do.
Always.
You're inside her, I'm inside her.
Doesn't it ever get predictable for you?
That's the point.
Predicting it.
I said it would be the fourth day.
It's the fourth day.
She worships you.
What if I don't want to end this one?
Oh.
Well, you know the drill.
The last one didn't even last three days.
It's not like we got
anything written in stone.
Hey, look at me.
No, no, no, look at me.
We do this now
while she's still a smile on your little face.
Ben... I don't know about this girl.
I feel like this could be the one.
You stop playing the game
before it starts playing you.
What do I always tell you?
Play them...
Not with them.
It wouldn't last.
It's the tapes and the
books that make it better,
make it last forever, right?
I'm so sorry.
Hello.
Yes?
NYPD.
Mr. Dexter?
Which Mr. Dexter do you want?
Benjamin Dexter.
Is he home?
Uh, no.
I can tell him you stopped by.
You are?
I'm his brother.
Yeah, like the truck says, huh?
- Dexter Brothers? Right?
- Yeah.
So are you gonna open
the door, Mr. Dexter...
...or are we gonna knock it off the hinges?
You two always
live together?
No. This was our parents' house.
My brother lives here.
That's a pretty bad cut you got there, man.
You all right?
Oh, God, yeah.
No, it's, uh... Football.
Go ahead.
You were saying?
Uh, I was just saying
that I'm staying here for a few days
while my apartment's being refurnished.
Where would that be?
Queens.
Hey, your sink doesn't work in there.
Yeah, I know.
My brother doesn't use this floor too much.
So, you guys,
you wanna tell me why you're here?
Well, we're investigating a missing person.
Uh, it's a woman.
- Here's a picture.
Pretty girl.
How can I help?
We just need to check on everyone
that works for Dexter's Catering.
Two minutes, man.
Couple questions,
we're outta here in no time.
Yeah, sure. Do you guys
want a drink or something?
Sure.
You got any iced tea?
Yeah, I think I do.
- You want one?
- Anything.
Okay. Excuse me.
- Oh, sure.
- Yeah, go ahead.
Take your time, man.
Hey. Thought we'd save you the trip.
Sure.
So then, you're not in the catering business
with your brother, then?
Well, I help him out once
in a while when he's in a pinch.
Like Tuesday night.
Club Shine?
No, I wasn't there.
You weren't there at all?
No.
Okay.
- Here's my card.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Oh, you know what?
The playoff game is on Channel 9.
- It's the last quarter.
- That's right.
Do you mind if we check
the score real quick?
- Channel 9?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, that's great.
Maybe your brother will be back
by the time the game is over.
Hey, look at this.
We're winning.
All right.
Oh, man.
What the fuck is this roaches shit?
Get the fuck outta here.
Look at this fuck...
Gotta wake up, Jennifer.
- You gotta wake up. It's over.
- No.
- Over?
- It's over.
- What's over?
- This.
There's no one to keep us here anymore.
How?
I killed them.
- Them?
- Yeah, there was two of them.
- I killed them.
- Oh, my God.
They underestimated me.
One of them came in, and I was ready for him.
And I got his gun...
Where are they?
They're upstairs.
We... We gotta make a move. Come on.
Where are we?
In some old house.
I haven't been outside.
I don't know where we are.
Did you call the police?
Not yet.
Where's the phone?
I don't know.
Come on.
Here's the phone.
No, not yet.
Wait. Sit down.
I think these sick fuckers
were taping us.
You know, I wanna find those tapes.
If they get in the wrong hands, you know...
You okay?
Gary! Gary!
Gary!
He was alive.
You did what you had to do.
He had a gun.
He would have...
Jen, listen to me.
You did nothing wrong.
He had a gun.
I should never have left you alone.
Maybe you should come with me.
Don't touch anything, okay?
No, the phones are dead.
We need to call for help.
Sit down.
Now wait right here, okay?
Don't even think
about what you just did.
Now, a few minutes more,
we're gonna be outta here.
Beg.
Oh, my God.
I need you to help me clean up.
You belong to me.
Yeah.
Show me.
You little...
It's not dark.
You naughty girl.
- Don't be stupid.
- Shit.
Where are you gonna go?
Come on, you couldn't
even find yourself in broad daylight.
Come on!
There's no one
coming for you!
I'm all you got!
Jennifer?
There's nowhere to go, Jennifer.
Thank you.
Thank you, Jen.
What's real, Gary?
Huh?
Put the gun down, Jen.
Put it down.
Down.
You should have...
cocked it, sweetheart.
You look so beautiful.
You're so fucking beautiful.
- Are you ready?
- No.
Are you ready?
Thanks for the lesson...
Gary.
I'm with model Jennifer Tree
on the one-year anniversary
of her abduction.
Jennifer, thank you for speaking with us.
- How are you?
- It's been a tough year.
- How so?
- It's taken me time to accept what happened.
- It hasn't been easy.
- I'm sure it hasn't.
But you look great.
Are you starting to mend?
I don't think anyone
could ever get over something like that.
I've read many
of your accounts.
These people are...
They're sick.
Would you mind telling us
about your ordeal?
There's no emotion to it.
No feelings of remorse.
No feelings of regret.
No pity.
Just relief.
Closure.
And when it's over,
they make a record of what they've done.
And then they move
on to the next victim.
Wow. Chilling.
Well, with the controversy
over this vigilante
who's hunted down and killed
two serial killers in the last year,
what do you think of the vigilante?
Is it right to kill people?
Even if they are bad?
They got what they deserved.
Taxi!