Mr. Woodson! Take a shot.
Oh, nice shot.
- Get up.
- Hey, over here!
- Mr. Woodson!
- Nice pass.
Hey, John.
Listen, the board met
this afternoon...
...and it's as bad as we thought.
They're cutting back
the whole department.
What, are you laying me off?
We knew this was coming. At this
point, it's just a leave of absence.
With any luck, you'll be back
with us next fall.
You're laying me off.
- I'm sorry, John.
- That's okay.
Hey, hey. Michael Jordan was only
5'2" when he started.
Of course, he was in kindergarten
and he could dunk the ball.
Just keep practicing. All right?
- Hello?
- John? It's Charlene.
Charlene? Wow, I was just
thinking about you the other day.
Listen, I'm so glad I was able
to reach you. I'm in town.
I was hoping you might have
some time to get together.
Oh, yeah, I got a lot of time.
Well, I'm staying at the Hilton,
near the airport.
So, what did you wanna
talk to me about?
Last month I was in Peru
doing a piece on a relief project.
We went to this place called Viciente
and I met a priest there.
His name is Father Jose,
he's also an archaeologist.
He told me about some scrolls that
he had discovered a few years ago.
What kind of scrolls?
Ancient writings.
No one knows who wrote them.
It's a prophecy.
Really? What does it predict?
According to Father Jose,
it says that...
...all the conflict, the chaos
in this world, it's changing us.
And what does that mean?
It means that the violence
is waking us up, in a way.
The prophecy says that
we're going to discover something.
Which is?
He was vague about it...
...but he said that it'll make us
look at everything differently.
I know this all sounds weird...
...but if you'll just listen...
Okay. Okay. I'll listen.
So when is this revelation
supposed to happen?
The prophecy says it'll begin during
the first years of this century.
Well, that's now.
Yeah, I know.
Excuse me, sir. Can I
please get my luggage?
Certainly. Will you be needing
a taxi today?
- Yes, please.
- The baggage will be out by the cab.
Great. It's just one bag.
Have you ever wondered why
we don't spend more time together?
How long have I known you,
five or six years?
About that long, yeah.
How many relationships
have you had?
You get involved with somebody
because it makes you feel good...
...but it never works out
because you're not really there.
Whatever happened to that
big theory you were trying to find?
Inspire all those kids.
What happened to that?
I found out it isn't that easy.
You should go to Viciente, John.
They're studying this prophecy
down there. I can't explain it...
...but the people there are different.
This place is different.
Why are you calling me
about all this now?
Because every time I would think of
this prophecy, I would think of you.
Then I found out that
I had a stopover here.
Maybe you're hearing this
at the right time.
Hey, Meredith.
Whatcha say, darling?
How are you?
Have a good day, girl?
Better than mine, I hope.
You should go to Viciente, John.
The people there are different.
This place is different.
Travel agency...
Cancellation? When's it leaving?
Tomorrow?
Yeah, I'll take it. All right, thanks.
Wanna go to Peru?
I haven't been in Lima in quite a while.
How long have you lived there?
Oh, I'm new to Peru.
I've lived in Bolivia...
...for the last 10 years, so I haven't
met your Father Jose.
In any case, the local priests are
so numerous, aren't they?
I suppose they are.
Excuse me. I just heard you
mention a Father Jose?
A friend of mine
just told me about him.
Dobson. Dr. Sidney Dobson.
Would you like a drink?
Two more Scotches, please.
Sure, right away.
- So are you a scientist?
- Oh, no. John Woodson, tourist.
But I'm going to Peru because I'm
interested in this place called Viciente.
Yes.
I met Jose in Boston
at an anthropological meeting.
I kept in touch over the years.
I had no idea what he had found until
several weeks ago. He called me...
...and asked me to help affirm
the prophecy's authenticity.
He sent me copies of the first two
scrolls along with translations.
Real thing.
There's no doubt about it.
Written no later than 5 or 6 B.C.
But you know the curious thing?
They were found in a wooden box...
... which dates to
only about 1600 A.D.
Someone in the early Church
had buried them.
Early Church? Franciscan or Jesuit?
Oh, I'm a history teacher.
Well, apparently Franciscan. Although
they seem to be inspired by a pope.
Celestine V, I think.
You mentioned that you had copies of
them. Can you tell me what they say?
No, not really.
They talk about a shift in human
understanding, I don't know.
But, you know, the curious thing,
the most astonishing thing...
...is the description
of the modern era.
Our problems, our technologies.
I mean, it is utterly amazing.
Think about it.
A document this old, speaking
in such detail about our time?
Think about it.
It was a pleasure
traveling with you.
- You staying in town?
- Delgado.
I'm just down the street
at the Hacienda.
Father Jose's church is just down
the street from there.
Why don't you come see him
with me in the morning?
He has the original scrolls.
He wants to make them public
as soon as possible.
- Why's that?
- I don't know.
You can ask him yourself
in the morning.
You see someone
down there you know?
Oh, no. No, not really.
Pretty girl.
Saint Francis was a great man.
He could see beauty
where others couldn't.
- I'm sorry, I was just taking a walk.
- It's all right.
American? Now, what has
brought you to Peru?
You're Father Jose, aren't you?
I'm John Woodson.
A friend of mine, Charlene Benet,
met you a few weeks ago.
And she told you
about our prophecy.
John, listen to me. I know you.
You're here to do
something important.
But you need to leave quickly.
- What are you talking about?
- Go!
I will try to help you.
You have caused us
a lot of trouble, old man.
It was in a hidden compartment
in the wall of the sacristy.
You should have
hidden them better, Padre.
Eight scrolls.
Where's the ninth?
Okay.
One way or another,
I'm going to put an end to all of this.
You're going to try.
You will do everything you can.
But it's already too late.
You are very calm
for a man about to die.
Everybody dies. Even you, senor.
John! Wait. Slow down a minute.
Why didn't you just call the police?
I'm not sure what's going on.
It could be nothing.
Nothing? You got me out of bed in the
middle of the night for nothing?
Don't do that.
You'll never get rid of her.
What the...? John!
Need some help?
They seem to have left.
We were going to that church a block
away, looking for the priest.
Father Jose?
- Yeah.
- And who is "we"?
This professor, I met him on a plane.
He's looking for some artifact.
The prophecy.
Go on.
Wait a minute.
You know about all this?
Who are you?
Part of your story, apparently.
My name is Wil.
- John.
- I'm a guide.
I was working with Jose
when he found the scrolls.
That's him, yeah.
- Who's this woman?
- Julia Sims. She's a friend, a linguist.
- Translated most of the prophecy.
- And him?
His name is Father Sanchez.
He lives in the mountains
with the local Indians.
Philosopher, you could say.
I have a feeling you'll meet him.
Now, what about your friend, the
professor? Tell me what happened.
They took him, right in front of me.
That's why I was running.
I think they got Father Jose too.
Put this on.
We have to leave.
You think it'd be safe
to go back to the hotel?
- I don't think so.
- Maybe you could take me...
...to the American Embassy.
Too risky.
General.
His Excellency Cardinal Sebastian.
Such a surprise
to have you visit me.
You've arrested an American.
A professor.
On his way to meet with
your Father Jose.
Cigar?
Don't you realize this will only bring
more publicity?
You should have consulted me.
Permit me to remind you,
Your Excellency.
It was you who informed me
of the dangers of the prophecy.
And it was you who sought my help.
I said the document was heretical.
That it needed to be contained.
I didn't say create an incident
with the Americans.
There will be an investigation.
This country is a democracy now.
This prophecy
is creating instability...
...at a time
when we're already threatened...
...by insurrection. Besides, you must
understand that there are other...
...interests involved in this matter now.
This prophecy must be dealt with.
Other interests.
Father Jose, he was not present
at Mass this morning.
No one can find him.
People go missing every day
in Peru.
If you want,
I'll have someone look into it.
The scrolls are Church property.
They must be returned to me.
It's all I can bear,
to tolerate his arrogance.
In a moment, he can remove
anyone from the Church.
Damn them forever.
We might control
the people's minds...
...but he controls their souls.
He can be used.
That's all that interests me.
This is all a waste of my time.
This prophecy, it's nothing.
Why do you fear it so?
Because, general,
in the world it predicts...
...there's no need for people
like you and me.
Do your part and
you'll get what you want.
Do you have the pictures
of the other American?
General, what about
Professor Dobson?
Call the American Embassy.
Tell them his detention was a mistake.
Then take him to the airport.
I think he'll be ready to go home.
Now, who are you?
And what are you doing
in my country?
I called the embassy.
Dobson's okay.
They're saying it was a case of
mistaken identity.
He's already headed back to
the States.
What about Father Jose?
No one has seen him.
I think someone is trying to
suppress the prophecy.
Who'd do that, Wil? Why?
Certain people in the government,
probably.
They view it as a threat.
It's not, of course,
but they don't see that.
Maybe I should try to get home too.
If they let Dobson go,
maybe it's safe for me to leave.
Or maybe you should come with me.
Do you suppose it was an accident
that you came to Peru...
...that you met Dobson?
How did you end up taking
that particular flight?
Think about it.
Why did I see you from my window
when I did?
You're gonna love this.
I was all set to get out of there,
I was packed, I was ready...
...and then I had this strange feeling
I'd forgotten something.
That's when you showed up.
Are you telling me
this is some kind of a fate thing?
That I'm supposed to go with you?
For what?
There's part of the prophecy
that still has to be found.
One more scroll. The ninth.
No, no, no. Forget about it.
I don't even know if
I believe this stuff.
All I had in mind was to come to Peru
and find Viciente. That's it.
Where you headed to, anyway?
Viciente.
Viciente, what's it like?
It's an old ranch, about 1000 acres.
Been in the owner's family
for hundreds of years.
It goes all the way back to
the Spanish land grants.
The Moors.
These days, it's a kind of retreat.
And the people there,
they're studying the prophecy?
Some of them.
Tell me about it.
So far,
we've discovered eight scrolls.
Each one contains a certain truth
about our existence.
We call them insights.
Insights, the prophecy says,
we've all gotta understand.
Look, I could describe these insights
to you right now...
...and you would hear my words...
...but you have to do more than that.
You have to experience it
for yourself.
The prophecy has to happen to you.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
I'm talking about
seeing the world, John.
The way it really is.
You get the first insight
when you realize...
...there's a mystery
operating out there...
...moving us somewhere,
for a reason.
It's there for everyone,
but only a few notice.
You're talking about
these weird coincidences?
Once you begin to really look,
you start seeing them more and more.
Well, if it's true they have meaning,
that would be incredible.
I mean, I know history.
That would change everything.
That's the second insight,
that the world is about to change.
What about the others?
In time,
you'll open up your perception...
...find your guidance.
You'll discover
why you're really here.
What about
the missing ninth scroll?
I believe it puts the others
into perspective.
Shows us where it's all leading.
And what makes you think
you can ever find it?
Because that's why I'm here.
Dream anything last night?
Yeah. Little girl
I dreamed about before.
It makes no sense.
It's probably important.
Why would you say that?
Because regardless of
how confusing they are...
...dreams are always trying to
tell us something.
Maybe you just need
a larger perspective.
My God.
What is this place?
Celestine ruins.
They found the
first eight scrolls there.
- Maybe the ninth is there too.
- Maybe.
What's that over there?
The mission. Cardinal Sebastian
had it rebuilt 10 years ago.
He's the head of the Church here.
Viciente, where's that?
In a hurry?
Rebels.
It's been going on for a while here.
They're trying to
overthrow the government?
These things are always about
power struggle.
- They're really well supplied.
- Yeah.
Let's move.
Miguel.
Wil. I had a feeling you'd show up.
Good to see you.
It's good to see you, my friend.
Julia's already arrived
and Father Sanchez is on his way.
I knew it.
You think it's time, don't you?
Yeah. I do.
John.
Meet my friend, Miguel.
We are his guests here.
Hi. It's a beautiful place.
Heck of a time getting here.
Yeah. We like to consider it
our little oasis.
Well, look what the wind blew in.
Julia. Julia.
I saw your truck come in.
I'm so glad you're here.
Did you drive straight through?
- Meet John.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
We've been working on the
translations and we found something.
It seems to be saying that
the ninth isn't on a scroll at all.
It's going to just appear.
Appear?
Could be there's something
we have to do.
Something to make it happen.
That was some ride.
He's involved somehow.
Maybe you should talk to him.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Come walk with me.
What's going on here?
What are they doing?
Let's just say they're
giving the garden their attention.
How much do you know about
the prophecy?
Not that much, not yet.
Have you been having dreams?
Something brought you here, right?
Synchronicity?
Yeah, how'd you know that?
Because that's how it begins
for everyone.
Wil told me I had to open up,
whatever that means.
And you think that's strange?
Well, I have no idea what
he's talking about with that. Seriously.
There's much more to the world
than you think, John.
A beauty...
...and energy.
You talk about strange,
I know that woman.
I saw her at the airport.
Go talk to her, if you'd like. I'll wait.
Hi. I hope I'm not disturbing you.
I'm John Woodson.
Julia's showing me around.
Marjorie Carter.
Some place here, huh? I hear it goes
all the way back to colonial times.
Yeah. Yeah, no, it's one of the most
incredible spots I have ever seen.
I suppose you're staying here
at the house?
We should get together later.
Talk some more about all this stuff.
Not this time.
Come on, you should do this.
It'll be fun.
You can tell me all about
what's happening here.
I'm interested in everything.
I've got a lot of work to get through.
I'm gonna get to it.
Nice to meet you.
What was that?
Didn't work out too well, huh?
That's the understatement
of the year.
What did I say?
It's not what you said,
it's what you did.
Your energy made her feel as though
you wanted to control her.
She felt dominated.
Oh, come on. I wasn't doing that.
Really? You weren't trying to
coax her into something?
- No.
- Manipulate her?
She isn't used to that around here.
That's completely nuts.
Where are you getting this stuff?
I could see it.
Remember the halos
the old masters used to paint...
...around their religious figures?
You think they made those up,
or were they seeing something real?
It's the energy, John.
It reveals what we do to each other.
You may not be conscious of it,
but you were taking her energy.
I could see it.
So could she.
How did the afternoon go?
I spoke to Julia.
So I heard.
I got lots of questions.
This stuff never ends, does it?
It's all gonna make sense,
eventually.
Everyone you meet here is
gonna show you something.
John and Wil. Please, join us.
We've got great people, great food.
Everything is fresh from the garden.
Miguel?
Who's that man over there,
on the other side of the table?
Jensen. He's an archaeologist.
He's here on sabbatical.
A friend of a friend.
- Would you like me to introduce you?
- No, no, no. Never mind.
- I knew I'd find you here.
- Waiting for you.
You seem happy.
I am. Really good.
I'm celebrating my fourth with Tom.
Oh, come on, Wil.
You never had time for us anyway.
True. But I'm glad for you and Tom.
And you and I will always
be connected.
University of Miami.
Your Hurricanes crushed
my Bulldogs last year.
I'm still not over it.
Yeah. You got me.
I teach there with Julia.
I've been helping her with the
translations for about a year now.
In fact, I was on my way back
when you saw me.
That mean something,
that I saw you?
Maybe. Maybe that we have
something to talk about, actually.
If you believe the prophecy.
You were thinking
about a child last time.
You were going to adopt.
It's not that easy.
We've met a few children...
...but I guess it has to be
the right one.
It'll happen for you.
Listen, I've been thinking about
Father Jose.
He was too public about it.
I tried to tell him.
Others have to know, Wil.
They have to know about
the prophecy.
Your friend John, for one.
Yeah.
What do you think of him?
I think he'll get there.
Unless, of course,
he gets too distracted.
Julia told me that
you could see things happening...
...when we talked in the garden.
I glimpsed it, I guess.
But to be honest,
I felt it more than anything.
There's just something
so familiar about you, I can't...
John, this player thing you do
really gets in your way.
I'm not playing. Didn't you say
we were supposed to talk?
God, it's amazing how easy it is to
lose yourself around some people.
Why, are you losing yourself?
I'm talking about you.
Good night.
We're going to do something
about Viciente.
We intend to rid this country of
everyone involved with the prophecy.
The opportunity is at hand...
...to destroy all
the remaining translations.
Who are you working for?
You don't want to know.
Just think of them as
powerful people...
...who, like you,
have their own agenda.
They are making many
investments here in Peru...
...and they demand stability.
We must cooperate.
They wouldn't be helping you with...
...your own political ambitions
as well?
They see the prophecy
as disruptive.
And it would seem that in this matter,
at least, your interests...
...and theirs are the same.
Viciente will cease to be a problem.
It will all be over soon.
I'm asking you not to interfere.
Your Excellency.
You and Marjorie have
come together for a reason, John.
She's showing you the
third and fourth insights.
The prophecy says
we'll stop building ourselves up...
...by taking energy from others.
There's another source, inside.
But we have to really connect with it.
That's what Wil meant
when he said "open up."
And if you open up enough, it literally
changes the way you see the world.
But you have to really believe
the experience exists.
Open yourself to the possibility that
there's something more...
...right here in front of your eyes.
Did you see that?
Come on. I wanna show you
something over here.
Wow, Julia, this place is so alive.
It's amazing.
Have a seat. Let's try something.
Put your fingers together like this.
- Okay.
- Go ahead.
You're gonna look at the space
between your fingers.
Relax your focus just a bit.
What do you see?
Look closely.
Let your eyes
go out of focus just a bit.
What do you see?
It's like a wisp of smoke
or something.
That's the energy. Now look around.
See that philodendron?
It's the opposite of trying to make
something happen. Just let go.
Take in the plant.
The beauty, the color,
the way it stands out with presence.
That's it.
Breathe it in.
Now take in more beauty.
That's amazing.
That's... Oh, hold on. I lost it.
Here.
Try again.
Wow, that's incredible!
Senor!
Keep your focus, John.
You have to get this.
Senor John! Senor John!
Senor, the gentleman
in the second cottage...
...he need to speak to you
immediately.
He says very important.
- John.
- Hi.
Miguel told me all about you.
Listen, there's something
I have to talk to you about.
How much do you know about Wil?
Wil. I only just recently met him.
I'm sorry, but I have to tell you
Wil is wanted by the military police.
What are you talking about?
They are on the way
to arrest him now.
But if you allow me, I can help you.
How can you help me?
Peru is a very dangerous place
for someone all alone.
In over his head.
I have official clearance
to study the prophecy.
I can move around freely.
But I need you to tell me what
you know. Where's the missing scroll?
I don't know anything.
But you're one of them, John.
They all accept you.
You must know something.
I can even get you back
to the United States...
...if that's what you want.
But you have to leave with me
right now, before the soldiers come.
John. John.
John.
John. We have to go.
Don't listen to him.
Your survival depends
on your staying with me.
Are you coming?
Yeah.
You're making a bad mistake,
both of you.
He was undermining your confidence.
Taking your energy.
Now you know what it feels like
when someone does it to you.
I felt weak. I couldn't think.
He's just a remote controller.
But you're probably
gonna have to deal with him...
...so you'd better figure it out.
Wait. Is that in the prophecy too?
There's a world of energy
that we are all going to understand.
It's the real human condition.
Energy is what we all want.
But we're stuck
battling for it with each other...
...instead of finding it in ourselves.
That's what you
still have to do, John.
You haven't really
opened up, you know.
Wil. Wil.
John. The military is on its way.
You need to leave.
Go while the north road is still open.
- What about Julia and Marjorie?
- They've already left.
You'll be behind them. I'm gonna
go to Lima, see the president.
Maybe something can still be done.
- Listen, you remember my cabin?
- In the rain forest, yes.
It's probably the safest place
for you now.
Wil.
- Finish this thing.
- Yes.
Good luck, Miguel.
Forgive me for what
I've allowed to happen.
Remember I told you
the way to Miguel's place?
Yeah?
If anything happens, you go there.
They'll need your help.
- What about you?
- I have to keep going.
I thought you were here
to find the ninth insight.
Nothing's changed.
Just keep learning, John.
You'll find help.
There's always help.
The right person
will come along if you stay alert.
Something will happen for you.
What was that?
Rebels. Sit tight.
It's Julia's car.
My leg.
Wait, wait!
- Julia!
- I'm okay. Find the cabin.
I've got the translations.
How you feeling?
- I'm terrified.
- You need to rest?
No, no, let's keep going.
- Is that Wil?
- What?
- Stay here.
- No, no, John...
I said, stay here!
John!
- John! Run!
- Marjorie!
Saint Francis could see beauty
where others couldn't.
I'm Father Sanchez. I can help you.
I remember you
from a photograph I saw.
You and Father Jose.
Don't forget Wil. He was also there.
Wil told me if I needed help,
someone would show up.
I guess he meant you.
Tell me what happened
on the cliffs, John.
I knew I was gonna die...
...so I just let go.
Waited for the bullets.
Then everything
began to change and I felt this...
You had an amazing experience,
my friend.
You opened up. You are changed.
Did Wil explain this to you?
He tried. I couldn't get it.
Oh, you got more than you think.
Tell me what you know.
You mean the insights?
Well, the first and the second
are about noticing the coincidences.
Things happen for a reason.
They're waking us up,
showing us the energy.
And that's the third
and the fourth, right?
I mean, that it's real
and people battle for it.
Causes all the conflict in the world.
Between nations,
in the workplace, families.
There's only one solution.
Opening up.
Finding our own energy.
Fifth insight.
Connects you
with the one true source:
The real world.
But I lost it. Why?
Well, the prophecy says...
...when you find this true connection
with the energy of God...
...it's like a glimpse into the future.
One day, we'll all see that way,
live in that world.
But now it's a difficult thing
for anyone to maintain.
We are evolving in that direction.
I saw the world's evolution.
How it all came to be.
My life seemed to be a part
of everything, right up to now.
Everything made sense.
Growing up at the lake...
...working with kids,
trying to understand history.
I spent my life
thinking there was something more.
That's the sixth insight. It says we are
part of a larger flow of evolution.
We are here to do something.
And if we are true to that purpose...
...we'll help move humanity
towards the world you saw.
But I don't know
what I'm supposed to do.
That's because
you're not through yet.
How to know what to do next
is the seventh.
You have to discover your guidance.
You're talking about hunches?
Intuitions? I've seen Wil have those.
If you stay alert,
you'll notice certain ideas...
...images coming into your mind.
They're there to guide you.
Follow them and the coincidences
begin to increase.
Just step into the flow.
I don't think I've ever
experienced that before.
You just need to open the door again.
Get some more energy.
You remember
how you felt on the cliff?
How the world looked?
Just breathe in the memory.
You were daydreaming.
Yeah, I guess I was.
What was coming to you?
I was thinking about Marjorie.
How it's my fault
that she got captured.
What all were you seeing?
- I don't know.
- No, come on, think.
Most people
overlook these experiences.
Well, it's the same thing
I saw yesterday on the mountain.
And it felt like the future.
She was in this place,
surrounded by dense jungle.
Go on.
Well, she was looking at something.
A small flower.
A small yellow flower.
Well, that's clear enough.
Yeah, clear as mud.
You know you have to do something.
Except you don't know what.
Then you have
this image of Marjorie.
Well, that little daydream of yours
was a guidance.
Okay. I'll buy that.
What's it saying?
You saw her in the rain forest?
Well, the rain forest is that way.
I don't know if I should do this.
Maybe I should go with you.
There's no need. I can find Julia.
You have to go your own way.
Follow your own intuition alone.
We can't do anything without Marjorie,
so get moving. Find her.
I'll see you at Miguel's cabin.
Find her?
I don't know where I'm going!
None of us know where we're going.
Not really. Just listen inside.
Pay attention to the way things look.
Something will happen.
Father Jose?
We thought you were dead.
Well, things are not always
as they seem, John.
I thought I was on the right path.
I guess I made a mistake.
It's a mistake
to think the worst too quickly.
Always find the deeper meaning,
the silver lining.
That's what keeps you in the flow.
- Marjorie.
- John.
I don't know how this is happening.
It's just...
Don't worry.
- We're gonna get out of here.
- Okay.
Okay. What now?
This is it.
Thank you.
Okay.
All right, I've been to Miguel's cabin
once before and I...
Wanna know what I think?
I think we should make for the border
and get out of Peru while we can.
Have you forgotten why we're here?
We could try to contact the others
when we get there. No more shooting.
John, you're past this.
Listen to yourself.
Now, I promise you,
I can find this place.
You just give me a minute, all right?
- No.
- Hold on.
- It's too dangerous. Marjorie.
- Will you talk to me, please?
- You don't wanna talk.
To talk, you'd have to actually listen
to what another person is feeling.
- You're dense as a post.
- I'm trying to...
You're controlling, John,
because you're scared...
...and it's wearing me down.
It can't happen anymore.
Not if I can help it. L...
John. Leave me alone.
Hey, what took you so long?
Julia! They're here.
You did it.
- What's going on?
- Oh, it's okay. Don't ask.
Come on, John, you did great.
Come on in.
Come on, give me another chance.
You're the one that's supposed to be
good at all this stuff.
You are not making this easy on me.
I am doing the best I can...
...but I don't have it figured out yet.
You can start by calming down.
I can be a little
hard-edged sometimes.
I've always gotten lost
in other people.
Guys. Mostly the charming ones.
Not stood my ground
when it was really important...
...and I vowed to myself,
not anymore...
...and then you come along,
like it's some kind of test for me, and...
...I just get angry because I don't
wanna slide backwards, John.
Neither do I.
That's why I wanna find out exactly
what happened and get through this.
The couple thing is the hardest thing
to work out.
Especially if the relationship
is familiar...
...if it feels
like I've known you before.
Did you think I didn't feel it?
When couples first meet, usually
there is this wonderful feeling...
...but it almost never lasts.
One person gets insecure
and starts controlling...
...wanting more
from the other person, and...
...the other one gets threatened
and backs away...
...and it leads to a power struggle.
- It doesn't have to be that way.
No, it doesn't.
I mean...
...if both people stay connected...
...then whoever has
the strongest intuition leads...
...and there's no competition.
Control is shared,
and that's the relationship I want.
That's just it,
I can't stay connected.
I want to, but I'm not there yet.
But there is a way, John.
And we all have to work on
doing this one critical thing.
It's what I need to remember
instead of getting angry all the time.
I mean, that's the eighth insight.
Come here.
It says that instead of taking energy
from each other, you give it.
All the time, no matter what.
Like Father Sanchez is doing.
Look at him, John.
Really look.
Giving energy is a process.
When someone's energy increases,
you can see it in their expression.
So you look
for that higher expression.
And in every situation...
...you know your energy is moving
into them when you get a feeling.
A feeling?
On the cliff, when you opened up,
remember? What did you feel?
I felt a kind of completeness.
A wholeness. This...
This unmatched euphoria.
- You're talking about love, aren't you?
- Yes.
Giving is the secret
to keeping yourself connected...
...because your energy, your love...
...builds up in you first
as it flows out to others.
It's what the saints
have always known how to do.
It's what you and I have to do now
to help them.
Wait a minute.
Maybe we're misreading this.
Father Sanchez, John, come here.
I found something
in the translations.
Look at this. This phrase:
- What does it mean?
- It means, roughly, to amplify.
I thought it just referred to one person
giving energy to another.
But now I think it's something more.
It's one thing to just give energy...
... but if we give it to someone
who is also giving it back...
... then we build energy
among ourselves.
It amplifies, back and forth.
It says if we were all doing this...
... humanity would take another step
in evolution.
Does it say where we'll go?
Maybe that's what the ninth
is going to tell us.
That's it. Isn't it?
That's where it's gonna happen.
Hey, John, we have to get going.
It'll take about two hours
to get to the ruins from here.
Does anyone know
exactly where to start looking?
There's someone who knows
exactly where to look.
You got it all, John.
All the prophecy that we know.
You've caught up.
Now you live in our world.
You could just let it go.
You don't owe anything to anyone.
No, you go ahead.
I'll catch up with you.
I think I have to go with him.
- So why have you come here?
- To seek reconciliation.
I want you to understand
the course I chose.
There's nothing to understand.
All this talk about prophecy must end.
The people have the right
to know what it says.
It makes our religion,
it makes every religion, come alive.
- Really?
- Of course.
- Look what it's done to us.
- Hear me, please.
From the time of Peter, the Church
has been about faith, about belief.
We have kept that belief alive.
But we can go past that now.
We can begin to live the promises.
The kingdom can come now.
It can all lead to chaos.
No. The guidance inside
will prevent that.
The perception can expand
and evolve.
Evolve?
Listen carefully
to what you are saying.
We have always fought
against the idea of evolution.
Against the idea
of evolution without God.
But evolution is a creation
that's still happening.
We can all participate.
Don't lecture me about theology!
Only God creates, not us.
But it happens through us,
don't you see?
You protected
the Franciscan documents.
You showed us
where the scrolls were.
They were placed in the ruins
for some reason.
It's time to find out why.
Please, join us.
No. It must end.
It doesn't matter now.
There will be no ruins,
be no ninth insight. Nothing.
What have you done?
It's over.
It's out of our hands now.
Come on.
We need to find the others.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
It's Jensen.
We gotta get moving.
Remember you told me
I need to follow my own intuition?
This is mine to do.
So where's the ninth scroll?
You should have come with me before,
when I gave you the chance.
You're gonna destroy the ruins.
Aren't you?
Let's just say
there are people out there...
...who want certain things
to happen.
Your prophecy isn't one of them.
How did you think
this would end, huh?
If you only knew
what the prophecy says...
...how the world really is...
The world is the way it is
because we make it that way.
When there's prosperity, we create it.
When there's war...
...well, sometimes war
can be useful too.
- You wanna destroy this democracy?
- Not destroy.
Limit.
Progress depends
on people's willingness to be led.
The world has changed.
Religious fanatics
are threatening everything.
Now this prophecy pops up again
after hundreds of years.
Oh, yes. I know all about it.
We have our writings too.
We've always known the dangers
of what it promises.
This dreamy liberation.
The illusion of security.
It undermines everything.
It's not an illusion. It's real.
It's the only thing that's real.
Trying to control isn't the answer.
When we find
the true God experience...
...the fight over whose religion
is best, it fades.
- There's just one truth.
- You people, so naive.
Thinking there's something spiritual
guiding this world.
Well, there's nothing out there.
Just us humans.
And those of us who know that
will always be in control.
The way of this world...
...is power.
- Can't let you do this.
- You could never stop me.
You idiot! You have killed us all!
John, I found the others.
Let's get to the circle.
I'll be right back.
You feel that?
It's happening.
Someone's helping us.
Send the energy back. It will build.
Remember?
Oh, my...
How incredible is this?
I can read it.
I can read this. It says:
"The guidance within
evolves the world towards a...
Towards a heaven
that is already here.
To know this
is to know our destiny."
- Wil?
- You made it here first.
Wherever this is.
You were helping us, weren't you?
- Father Jose.
- He's been helping us too.
They're all helping us.
We are being shown heaven.
It's where evolution is taking us.
Where it's always been taking us.
That's the ninth insight.
No! Don't hurt her,
she's just a child.
No, keep your energy.
Hold on, they'll see you.
Julia.
Stay focused. Keep your energy.
John.
Take them to the ridge!
Marjorie? I wanna
tell you something.
I don't think we have much time left.
But I wanna thank you for all of it,
for everything you've shown me.
I was a reluctant student at first,
I know, but I'm glad you...
...didn't give up on me.
I think I was the stubborn one.
And, John, we weren't
supposed to be together.
Not this time. We were just
supposed to find a balance.
I think we did.
Yeah.
In the name of God. Wait!
Lower your weapons!
These people
can do you no harm now.
They'll have no credibility.
I'm making sure of it.
This is not your affair,
Your Excellency.
No.
Let them live. We're not murderers.
The prophecy has been destroyed.
The jungle will take the ruins.
Nothing is left of this prophecy.
The prophecy is finished.
Take them to Lima.
I knew it was you.
It's pretty intense in there.
I have 45 minutes to leave the country.
They got me on the next plane out.
What about the others?
Marjorie?
She's already back home.
She was there to set you free.
Julia and the girl,
they're all right too.
Wil?
The scrolls? The translations?
Anything left?
They don't matter, John.
We were able
to understand the ninth.
Now we know
what life is really about.
That changes everything.
Here.
I thought you'd find this interesting.
How about that?
We made the news.
She sent me here.
Maybe now you can
have something real.
Yeah.
Maybe I can.
So, what are you going to do now?
I don't know. I don't know.
You have to take all this
with you, John.
You'll meet others
who have to know.
Just keep your eyes open.
Something will always happen.
One last thing.
Something tells me
you'll be getting a message.
From Wil.
Magazine?
Thank you.
There's a tenth insight.
-= resynch by aziraphale =-
visit opensubtitles.org