Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
CHANGING TIMES
Where's everybody?
-You know, it's Sunday.
-What do you mean, it's Sunday?
You know we need
to get things moving.
Why aren't they working?
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Thank you.
Welcome to Tangiers.
I am Nabila Balouch.
Hello, Nabila.
-Did you have a good trip?
-Yes.
Things didn't go well in Marbella.
They disagree with the estimate.
Is that your only luggage?
Yes, I am not a tourist.
I am a traveler.
One of the issues we had
with this project
was to design
a perfectly insulated building.
It's only 550 yards from an airport
supporting big commercial airplanes.
So, the facade is insulated
with double-glazing windows,
the interior has false ceilings
made of mineral flagstones,
and, for the most part, the stones
on the floor are carpeted.
Christian is better suited to tell you
how things are going inside
the building, on the technical side.
How does last minute information
get broadcasted live?
Where are the teleprompters
and the telexes?
Are they at the same level?
By the way,
you haven't forgotten the flowers?
A daily bouquet since last week.
-No signature.
-That's perfect.
Roses every time, right?
Yes, but you haven't
told me which color.
-I thought red was too daring.
-Be daring then, Nabila.
So light will go
through the window anyway?
Yes. There will be light,
but it will be dimmed.
Behind the window, we'll have blinds,
something like that.
This building
must be able to function 2 4/7.
Is it facing north?
Yes, it is facing north,
but its two main facades. . . .
The land we have chosen
for MEDI 1 S A T
is located in the northwest area
of the Tangiers' Free Zone,
bordering the airport.
It has a surface
of 1 92,800 square feet,
which gives us enough space
for our main building.
Construction and equipment
techniques chosen
to build MEDI 1 S A T were designed
to insure the durability
of the investment.
Walls and curtains built with
lacquered aluminum structures,
mounted with double-glazing
dimmed windows,
full walls or covered with plastic
coated sheet metal cladding.
In the western wing of the building,
an 820-square-feet set
is dedicated to live news broadcast.
It communicates with a control room,
processing sound, image, light,
and external broadcasting.
Cecile, I don't want to show my face.
Or at least not yet.
I am afraid you won't recognize me.
It would be nice
if you closed your eyes.
That way you would only
hear my voice.
Every night, I hear yours
on the radio, I look at the city,
and to me,
you and the city become one.
Now, the moment has come to...
Shit. That's bad.
You cut your hair?
Good idea. You look better that way.
With or without curls
My style is right
You know, I didn't come alone.
I came with Nadia.
You could have told me.
I thought you would be happy
to know her. It's been so long.
Well, sure, but not like this.
You're impossible.
You put people
in front of the situation,
and you let them deal with it.
Anyway. It's all right.
Where is she?
She's afraid to come out.
Come on.
Hello, Nadia. It's very nice meeting
you. Better late than never.
Hello, Rachid. How old are you?
Nine and a half years old.
My name isn't Rachid, right, mom?
His name is Said.
I didn't know you were coming,
but let's celebrate.
Nadia came to see her sister.
Are you sure she's coming?
Of course she is. I'll wait for her.
Don't worry about me. I'm fine.
I feel bad leaving you here.
I'm fine. Go ahead. Seriously.
We'll go have an orange juice.
I'm sure her sister won't come.
Do you mind if she stays with us?
Honestly, Sami, I would have preferred
if it didn't happen this way.
It's very simple. Just say yes or no.
I am the one who has to make
the decision?
Well, ask your father.
It won't be a problem, then.
He has always respected my freedom.
Right, and to you, freedom means
imposing your whims on others.
Don't start, please.
We'll end up doing what you want
anyway, as always.
I'll go get her, then.
Don't stay here. It's ridiculous.
Something must have come up.
It happens.
I have her cell phone number.
She'll answer the phone at some point.
Stop it, Nadia. You've been
leaving messages for a week.
If she wanted to talk to you,
she would have done it already.
Don't say that.
I know her better than you do.
Fine.
Meanwhile, come
to my parents' house. It'll be easier.
No way!
I've already told you that.
At least for tonight.
We'll figure it out tomorrow.
Where's the lady?
She's waiting for us in the car.
Is she your mommy?
Yes, she is.
Why did she call me Rachid?
She made a mistake.
What's her name?
Cecile.
It was a floating island, surrounded
by an indestructible bronze wall,
with a smooth rock pointed at the top.
Twelve children were in the palace.
They were born in Eole. Six boys
and six girls in their blooming youth.
What does "blooming" mean?
It means they were
opening like flowers.
Like you.
I am not an opening flower.
I'll continue reading.
On the island, Eole's daughters
had married his sons.
The most diverse meals...
Why aren't you coming?
Are you hiding?
I am not hiding.
I didn't want to interrupt.
It's 8:00 pm, anyway.
I have to run to the station.
I left the window open.
The eastern wind has calmed down.
But if you would rather close it. . . .
No, it's okay.
Above all, make yourself at home.
You promise?
Yes, madam.
Madam? Don't call me madam!
Come on, Nadia.
Don't be anxious like this.
I am very happy to have you here.
Good night, Said.
Well, I am going out for a bit.
Can you give me a ride to town?
If you want to.
See? I told you things
would go well with my mother.
She's overdoing it.
It makes me uncomfortable.
She's always distant, so she's making
an effort to be affectionate.
It comes off as clumsy.
Did you see? Your parents
put us in the same room.
So? We've slept together before,
right?
Okay, I'm taking off.
Already?
You didn't even unpack.
You want me to stay with you?
No, it's okay.
I feel a little uncomfortable to be
alone in this house with your father.
Don't worry. He doesn't talk much.
You don't even have to greet him.
-What is this?
-My toys.
We could give them to Said.
What do you think?
You don't want to dive in?
No, thank you.
Actually, I'll just walk.
Come on. Stay a little longer!
You're always running away.
Shouldn't we try to talk a little?
Talk about what?
I don't know.
Talk about you, your life.
It's only normal.
You call once in a blue moon.
You're exaggerating.
I always tell you what's going on.
I'm not mad at you, Sami.
I just want to understand.
There's nothing to understand.
What about Nadia? Said?
This is news to me.
I told you we lived together in Paris.
It's not a surprise, is it?
What time is your show?
In 1 0 minutes.
I'll never get there on time.
Just walk. I'll take the car.
I'll leave it on the parking lot.
No, keep it.
I'll take a taxi to go home.
You didn't tell me how long you were
staying, you and your friends.
Is ten days all right?
Last time, you didn't last a week.
May I remind you
that you were never around?
You want people to be here,
and you're always somewhere else.
I hate you!
Wait a second!
Nadia?
Aicha?
Hold on.
I left a ton of messages.
You could have called me back.
Calling cell phones is expensive.
I can't afford it,
especially foreign cell phones.
So, are you here?
Yes, Sami took me
to his parents' house.
But I would much rather
stay at your place, because...
You can't stay at my place.
It's too small.
Hold on.
Nadia? Nadia?
What's going on? Are you ill?
No, I'm fine.
So what's new with you?
Not much.
I need to pay for mom's
hospital treatment,
so I work overtime at McDonald's.
I sleep. I work a lot.
What about you?
Did you bring your son?
Of course.
I can't wait for you to see him.
Please be discreet.
Don't come by my work.
They don't know I have a twin sister.
Besides, I don't want them to ask
questions about you or your life.
You know how people are over here.
This is not Paris.
Don't worry. What time do you get off?
It depends. Never before midnight.
That's late for a child.
Listen, I think we should do this
some other time.
What do you mean,
"some other time"?
I haven't seen you for six years,
and that's all you can say?
Listen, I just got off work.
I only get five hours of sleep.
I'm completely exhausted.
I understand that you're tired,
but still. . . .
Listen, Aicha.
If you don't want to see me ever
again, please be honest about it.
Well, okay, then. I'll be honest.
I don't feel so well, and I don't
have the strength to see you.
I am afraid it will hurt me.
I need to learn
how to live without you.
When I succeed,
I promise we'll see each other.
I'm sorry, Nadia. I love you
very much. I'll call you back.
You have oversized the structures.
We had to,
because of earthquake hazard.
-What level?
-Level three.
What's that?
Is this how far you got
with the drilling?
-Yes.
-Get going then.
We've already lost two weeks.
All right.
Look, here.
I trust you to get things moving.
Give me the number.
Okay. Let's check the measurement.
That's no good.
Follow me, my friend.
To my wife and all my friends
in Algiers.
To my fiancé, Youssef,
who went to work for an insurance
company in Casablanca.
Dedicating this song to my love.
I want to dedicate this song to all
my friends who will recognize me.
Walid, Karim, Omar,
as well as my whole family.
Even if I don't see them often
because we're far away,
I hold them close to my heart.
Walid, Karim, Omar,
as well as my whole family.
To all Reggae fans and
to the Tangiers soccer team.
After listening to this song,
we will listen to the news
with Patrice Martin.
After this song,
we'll give you the news.
It's better to think of nothing
Than not to think at all
Nothing is already something
It's already a lot
We don't remember a thing
And since we forget it all
Nothing is better
Nothing is better than anything else
I say "he," but maybe it's a woman?
I don't know.
Give them to someone, sell them.
But, please, dear,
stop talking about it.
If I were you,
I would die to know who it is.
Are you sure you don't want me
to ask the flower shop?
Are you crazy?
Anonymous gifts are like
anonymous letters. It's blackmail.
Give them to me.
It's too bad.
How is Sami?
It's hard to know with him.
Resolution 1 546 was voted earlier
at the UN headquarters in New York.
Iraq is scheduled to recover
its sovereignty on June 30th.
Where are the dogs?
It's lunchtime for them.
So you finally made up your mind?
Hi, Bilal.
-Don't just stand there. Come in.
-Am I interrupting?
What are you talking about?
You woke me up
in the middle of the night.
I was afraid. I didn't know if you
were allowed to have friends over.
My bosses don't live here.
I see them once a year in July.
I didn't know if you wanted to see me.
I told you to come in. Are you deaf?
The garden looks beautiful.
Can you take me on a tour?
Is that why you're here?
No. I came for you.
Why aren't you looking at me?
Well, there. I am looking at you.
You want one?
No, I quit smoking, drinking,
and going out.
I quit everything.
Even sex?
That's the only thing
you have in mind.
I don't care. I could do without.
I don't believe that.
See? I don't need anything.
I live like a king here.
I make 2,000 dinars a month.
A garden, a swimming pool,
a view of the sea.
That's true. I couldn't give you
all that in Paris.
Don't start again with Paris.
It's nice to visit,
but I wouldn't stay there.
I've always told you.
I don't want to depend on you.
Sorry for talking about Paris.
Always apologizing.
Like all Europeans.
The "love of my life" trick,
is that European, too?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You know how it goes.
They pick a guy, they take
him home in their luggage,
and if there's a problem,
they send him back to his village.
I would never do anything
like that to you, Bilal.
You're too suspicious.
You need to learn how to trust people.
Trust? That's right.
You're not honest, Sami.
What about that poor Nadia?
I don't understand
what you're doing together.
I need her.
Of course, you don't know anything
about connections between people.
You despise everyone.
You're wrong, Sami.
I am not looking for love.
I just want respect.
You don't know what you want.
You don't make decisions.
It's understandable, though.
Half Moroccan, half French.
Half man, half woman.
It must be hard for you
to figure it out.
Where are you going?
It's time for me to go
take care of the garden.
How's everyone?
Well, I'll let you work, then.
No, wait.
I want to show you something.
Look at this.
40,000 dinars.
I got a two-year financing plan.
-Isn't it beautiful?
-Yeah.
What are you waiting for?
That's why you came, isn't it?
I thought you didn't want
to have sex anymore.
I don't miss it,
but if I have the opportunity. . . .
Come on, take your clothes off.
Is this all you have?
Is it for a ring or a necklace?
I don't know yet.
I am here to help you. But it is
difficult without knowing the person.
Wait. I have a photo.
It's an old one,
but she's about my age now.
Too bad it's a black and white photo.
The color of her eyes
is very important.
She has green eyes.
I need to think about it
a little bit more.
Thank you very much, sir.
Why didn't Said come with us?
He prefers watching television.
Watch out with the bottles.
Double the bags.
Do you need help?
You know children don't like shopping.
Don't move. Don't strain yourself.
I am a doctor. Let me see this.
It doesn't seem broken.
It's only the cartilage.
You need to get some X-rays.
Breathe slowly. With your mouth.
How do you feel?
My stomach hurts.
Does your head hurt?
I'm telling you, my stomach hurts.
I am. . . .
You're what?
I'm emptying my bowels.
I have the runs.
Stay back!
Don't lower your head.
Keep your head back.
Where's my savior?
Your savior's name is Nathan.
He's my husband.
He had to go.
You're not his only patient.
He really wants you to get an X-ray.
It's nothing. I'll have a bump
on my nose tomorrow.
Still pretending to be a brute?
Yes. I am a constant guy.
That's my nature.
What are you doing in Tangiers?
I am overseeing the construction of a
broadcasting center in the Free Zone.
Yes, I've heard of it.
It's an ambitious project.
It's very involved, politically.
You know, I only handle
the construction part.
I need to give them the building
in six months.
I don't care about the rest.
It's a TV channel
that will serve all of North Africa,
as a rival to Aljazeera.
It will promote moderate Islam.
Sir, may I remind you that you have an
appointment at the consulting office?
And I'll remind you that
the appointment is in an hour.
Yes, but you wanted to talk
about the contractors' estimates
before the meeting.
Very well. I'll be right there.
Why are you laughing?
When I first met you, you were skinny
and you were always talking
about how you were broke
and proud of it.
So?
So, it looks like you've made it,
as they say.
Your family didn't come with you?
No, I'm single.
I'm the same as when we met.
You never got married?
No. Why?
Oh, nothing.
Well, Antoine, I have to go,
because I do have a family,
and I need to take care of them.
I can give you a ride.
That's very sweet, but
I don't need it. I have Nathan's car.
But we're going to see each other
again, right?
Of course, if you're here for six
months, there will be other occasions.
Tell me when. It will be easier.
I would love to have you over
for dinner,
but I work every night after 8:00 pm,
so it's not very practical.
I know. I listen to you every night.
I used to be the news host.
That was more appropriate for me,
but I need to make a living, so...
So, when do we see each other?
Listen, Antoine, I'll let you know.
I know which hotel you're staying at.
I promise I'll call you.
What should I plan for Sunday?
The company has agreements
with the Yachting club.
Would you like to go on a boat ride?
No. I'd rather stay in the hotel.
If you refuse all entertainment,
you'll end up being depressed.
There are many things to see.
The Phoenician tombs,
the Caves of Hercules, Cape Spartel.
Don't bother, Nabila.
I am not interested.
What are you interested in, then?
I am paid to organize your leisure
time. I don't know what to do anymore.
You really want
to do something for me?
Tell me about witchcraft.
Witchcraft?
Well, yes. It is still practiced
in your country, isn't it?
Parallel activities are not included
in my job description.
I would be too scared to get fired.
Nobody will know about it.
It will be our secret.
Of course, your price will be mine.
It's not only a question of money.
It's a question of belief, knowledge.
Well, precisely. Teach me, Nabila.
I only know the most common rituals.
Put a spell on someone
or break that spell.
That's exactly what I need.
I would like someone
to fall in love with me.
In the name of God. . . .
God is great!
What are you doing here, Nabila?
This is a documentary
about the Gnawa Brotherhood.
There are other brotherhoods.
The Issawa, the Hmadcha.
In this one, you'll see a Lila.
It's a therapy that exorcises
the demons within us.
I don't need therapy. I am not sick.
It could set you free
from that person.
I don't need to be set free.
I want to cast a spell on her.
Most spells are evil acts.
Let's be clear. I mean no harm.
You can't possess someone
without hurting him or her.
Fine. Well, I thank you, then.
Listen, Nathan.
You should really talk to Sami.
Did you see that poor Nadia?
She's completely lost.
I don't know how you can be
so unperturbed.
You didn't have to invite them.
You're impossible!
What did you want me to do?
What would you have done?
I would have welcomed them.
I would have accepted them
the way they are.
That's called controlling yourself.
Nonsense. I call that cowardice.
You're always over-dramatizing.
It's just a matter of behavior.
You should reflect on that.
It would give everyone a vacation.
The law of silence. As always.
You're not working today?
I am. At 1 1:00 am.
You start working later every day.
It's not my fault. Clients
don't come rushing at the door.
You have no excuse today.
Did you see the weather?
You have to make an effort to go out.
It will do you good.
I don't feel like going out.
What's wrong, Nadia?
You don't want to tell me?
It's nothing, madam.
It's just a little down phase,
as Sami would say.
He's something else. Never around.
Always out and about.
It's only normal.
He hasn't been here for a long time,
so he's enjoying himself.
I hope he takes care of you
a bit more than this in Paris.
I don't need anyone
to take care of me.
Do you like it there?
Do you have friends?
Look, don't worry about me.
It's not a problem.
I am used to being alone.
Besides, I have Said.
You know how children are.
You don't have time
to get bored with them.
Stretch your arms
and push with your legs.
There. Push with your legs.
Come on! Come on!
Like that? Is that okay?
Are you cold?
No, I'm fine.
So, how was it?
It was awesome.
-Yeah?
-Yeah. Can I watch television?
Yes, but take a shower first.
Quiet!
Sam has agreed to do something
for Norreddine,
in order to help him with the issues
tearing his soul apart.
Everything is blessed with incense.
Norreddine is wrapped
in various cloths
bearing the colors of the Gnawa.
Each color stands for one
of the spirits living in our world.
Sam tries every color, because
he doesn't know yet which spirit
has entered Norreddine's soul,
disrupting his existence.
He has also chosen a multicolored
rooster for the same reason.
Sam calls the various spirits,
inviting them to move away
from Norreddine.
At one point, he threatens them
with his knife.
Two terrorist attacks and four
hostages were liberated in Iraq today.
We'll start with information
given by a Polish general
to the judicial authorities
in his country.
Four hostages were liberated by
elite units of the Coalition forces.
Soldiers were buried last Saturday
with one of their compatriots,
Pietro Petrucci.
I don't mean to be a party pooper,
but we do need to work.
Jerk!
"To people who listen to Baid escata."
"To students at the National
Business School in Agadir."
"To Rose, my dear wife,
mother of the beautiful Ines."
Hey, you're lucky to have
your little tribe around.
That's true. I'm lucky.
I didn't hear from you,
and it's Sunday, so I thought. . . .
I'm sorry, Antoine.
I completely forgot about you.
I'm sort of busy these days.
How is your nose?
Look, it changes colors.
You're exaggerating. It's almost gone.
Would you have a glass of water?
It's so hot. I'm really thirsty.
Sure, come in.
I'm warning you, the house is really
messy. We sort of live like nomads.
This is Rachel Meyer,
my work partner.
Antoine Lavau, an old friend.
An old friend?
I don't really like that.
Antoine was my first love.
Is that better?
It seems more accurate.
It's nice to meet you.
You said you wanted a glass of water?
Yes, a glass of water with
a little scotch, if you have some.
I told Cecile how much
I liked your show.
All those people sending signals
to each other in the night.
It makes my imagination wander.
It's always the same messages.
It's a little monotonous.
Not for me. People's love life
is the only thing I am interested in.
It's so refreshing to meet a man
who isn't afraid of feelings.
Right, Cecile?
Tell me, do you think the first love
can become the last love?
Don't pay attention to him.
He's crazy.
Here, take this. You need it.
So, how's the cripple doing?
I apologize for showing up at your
house like this, unannounced.
You're welcome here.
My wife's friends are friends of mine.
-Thank you.
-Don't stand like this. Come here.
Can you serve me a drink, too?
Do it yourself, honey. I need
to work on the show with Rachel.
I married a feminist.
She doesn't let anything slide.
So how is my head?
Everything's normal.
Let me see.
Tell me, Nathan, do you receive
patients in your bathing suit, now?
Please go ahead, doctor.
It doesn't bother me.
I have to say, I like to spend
my Sundays naked.
Your friend is less of a conformist
than you are.
What kind of lotion are you using?
"Morning Care" by Clarins.
The pharmacist recommended it.
That's just cosmetics.
It doesn't heal the bruise.
So? Not too disoriented in Tangiers?
Oh, you know, I travel a lot.
I've worked on construction sites
in Mali, Turkey, in the Philippines.
I even lived in Chile for two years.
Well, if you're staying for a while,
it's silly to stay in a hotel.
There are plenty of houses
to rent around here.
Cecile didn't tell you about it?
It would be nice, but I don't
want to abuse your generosity.
I'm sure she could help you.
Right, Cecile?
Thank you. You're embarrassing me.
What do you do in the evening?
Absolutely nothing.
May I use the restroom?
They're at the end of the hall.
Pardon me.
Your friend looks a little lost.
Should we have him stay for dinner?
Don't you think
there are enough of us already?
Listen, Cecile.
Is he your friend or not?
Of course he is.
But we don't have that much food,
and we're not done yet.
We have to be
at the station in an hour.
As you wish.
Would you mind
putting some clothes on, Nathan?
I'll jump in one last time.
"To students at the National
Business School in Agadir."
I like the one from Montreal.
I want to dedicate this song
to Moroccans living in Montreal.
"My brother, my sister. . . ."
I don't understand this one,
but if you do. . .
"I miss the family a whole lot."
"To my neighbors and friends
in the community."
Come swim with me, Said.
No, I don't want to go.
You're scared! I know it.
You're scared!
Come on.
That's it. Let go.
There you go.
You like it?
How far are we?
Two or three miles.
It's beautiful. You'll see.
It's worth the effort.
If you like it so much,
why don't you rent it yourself?
I can't afford it.
The windshield is filthy.
It really doesn't matter.
By the way, how old is your husband?
He's younger than me.
-Why are you asking?
-No particular reason.
How is the retirement situation here?
What kind of question is that?
You want to know if we make
a good living? Not really, Antoine.
Well, with your job at the radio...
You know, my job at the radio. . . .
They give priority to Moroccans,
which is understandable.
Besides, I don't speak Arabic.
Well, what. . .?
That's all we needed.
Are you trying that old trick on me?
Please, Antoine. It's not funny.
Doesn't look like
there's much traffic on this road.
Nathan probably
tried to work on the car again.
Look at this. He replaced the fuse
with a piece of wire.
-Is it serious?
-What an idiot.
I shouldn't have washed
the windshield.
The water created a short circuit.
I could have ruined
the wiring harness.
Well, I didn't know you
were such an expert mechanic!
I had to learn, Antoine.
I don't have a driver.
I feel like you're giving me grief
for having money. It's tiresome.
Are you going to be able to fix it?
No. We need a mechanic.
Can I use your cell phone?
For once that we were alone,
I didn't want to be interrupted.
I don't have my phone, either.
I always forget it.
So what do we do?
Well. . . .
I'll show you the house, anyway.
Come with me.
We'll take the shortcut.
What are you thinking of?
Nothing in particular.
I'm thinking I would like us to get
lost, where nobody could find us.
No risk of that over here.
You can always find your way
by looking at the sea.
Look, right over there.
It's strange, but I have the feeling
you completely forgot about me
all these years.
It's only normal.
I don't live in the past.
I have a life, Antoine. You saw that.
Alas, I did.
For me, it's the opposite.
Absence brought me closer to you.
As time passed,
I missed you even more.
You want me to believe that you
have missed me for 30 years?
3 1 years, eight months, and 20 days,
to be precise.
But I always knew
I would see you again.
It's a coincidence, Antoine.
Oh, no, it is not. I looked for you.
What do you think?
One day I found out
that you lived here.
The hardest part
was to be sent to Tangiers.
It took some time.
I did everything I could.
Anyway, I couldn't come any sooner.
I don't really understand
what you're getting at.
We said we would love each other
all our lives.
You don't remember?
What are you talking about?
I am sure you loved other women.
I am not talking about sex.
It has nothing to do with it.
Love doesn't change
like one changes partners.
What do you want from me, exactly?
I want to grow old with you.
You're completely nuts,
my poor Antoine!
I knew you would say that.
It doesn't matter.
I don't want to force it on you.
I will wait.
Did you send those flowers?
Yes, I knew you liked roses.
I am happy you understood.
Listen, Antoine. If you want to see me
again, don't talk about any of this.
We're not 20 anymore.
Passion is behind us.
All right?
Fine, as you wish.
What's ahead of us, then?
Nothing.
It's like this forest. It stops here.
Beyond, there's a cliff.
There's nothingness.
That's not true. It isn't nothingness.
There's the sea.
And look, there's a ferry crossing.
Over there, there's some fog.
Behind the fog is Spain,
and Spain is the beginning of Europe.
Stop it, Antoine. You're tiring me.
I even forgot why we came here.
You wanted to show me the house.
That's right. The house.
It's that one.
Don't look at them like that.
They'll feel obliged to do something.
You knew they were there?
Of course. I saw them.
They know they have nothing to fear
from us. We're just two lovers.
Between police raids and robbers,
I don't know how they survive.
Maybe they survive because
they have a goal. To reach Europe.
This is the last stop before paradise.
Is Cecile home?
She went shopping with Said.
Is Sami still asleep?
You want me to wake him up?
No, I came to see you.
Did you write this?
Are you out of your mind?
The pharmacist knows my handwriting.
There aren't that many doctors here.
She refused to serve me.
I'm not surprised she called you.
Do you often take that kind of crap?
I am an adult.
I can do whatever I want.
Let's talk about this with Sami.
Let me go! You're hurting me!
Listen, Sami. Either you keep an eye
on your friend or you leave.
What the hell is going on?
Don't yell at me. I don't know
what you're talking about.
Come with me. Go ahead.
That girl is a wreck.
And she has a kid, on top of it.
You're completely irresponsible.
Calm down. Tell me what's going on.
What's going on
is that she's loaded on pills.
It's dangerous.
She steals my prescriptions, too.
I'm tolerant, but this goes
beyond the acceptable.
Are you all right?
Don't ask me if I'm all right every
five minutes. Yes, I am all right.
Mommy's hands are cold.
Then let me carry you.
So how does it feel to be tall?
The lady read me a story about giants
last night. I'd like to meet one.
Giants don't exist anymore.
Only midgets still exist.
Otherwise,
humans are the same height.
How tall do you think I will be?
As tall as you?
I don't know. It's too soon to know.
When can you know?
You know it when it happens.
Come on. Let's fly!
You don't want to play soccer?
No, I don't know these guys.
That way, you'll get to know them.
You want to play on the slide?
No, that's for little kids.
Why don't we go to the beach?
Your mommy can't handle the sun.
Why did we come here?
So you could have fun.
I prefer watching television.
Vacation is not
for watching television.
I can't believe you still
haven't been to the sea.
I don't want to go with the lady.
Why don't we go? Just you and me?
Don't bother him with that. He doesn't
have time. He has things to do.
It's the same in Paris.
You never do anything with me.
Can I go over there?
Yes. Be careful not to fall.
Do you want to go back to Paris?
I don't want to stop you
from seeing Bilal.
Bilal is just a fling, you know.
He's not essential. You're
the most important thing. Seriously.
Would you rather stay
or go back to Paris?
I am unable to make any decisions.
Okay, let's go back.
I'm making the decision.
Sometimes,
I feel like I'm ruining your life.
Are you kidding? If I didn't have you,
I don't know what I would do.
You would live with a boy.
Don't say that. I'm happy with you.
Seriously.
Why are you wearing
this much makeup?
I looked dead this morning,
so I added a little color.
What are you doing?
Cleaning the swimming pool,
as I do each year.
So you'll put a tarp on it, and we
won't be able to swim anymore?
There are still some nice days
in September.
Once again, I do something,
and it's wrong.
I was surprised, that's all.
I'm sorry.
I need to give an answer
about Casablanca.
Go ahead, if you want. I've already
told you I didn't want to live there.
It could be a good thing, you working
in Casablanca and me working here.
At least, we would see each other
only when we wanted to.
Routine destroys relationships.
Don't use that old tired argument.
All I see is a better
financial situation.
This month, I am completely broke.
What do you mean?
I gave Sami some money for Nadia.
She needs to go to rehab
in a proper institute,
where they can do a good follow up.
What about the kid?
Will Sami take care of him?
Yes, the time for her to recover.
Do you see Sami raising a child?
He will learn. He'll figure it out,
like everybody else.
Sure, let him deal with it.
I think you don't really care.
I do care.
I talked about it with him.
We get along well.
I noticed.
You keep smiling at each other.
We understand each other.
It looks like it bothers you.
It bothers me because it's fake.
You don't know anything about Sami.
You don't even know he likes boys and
you're talking about understanding.
What? He likes boys?
Did he tell you that?
No, but I've known for a long time.
And how do you know that?
You've seen him have sex with a man?
Don't over-dramatize.
I know because I watch him.
I pay attention to him.
It's important to know these things.
Maybe we should talk
about it with him.
I don't want to talk about that crap.
It's pointless.
You're not going to cop out?
It's your son, after all!
My son, my son. What does it mean?
Don't get on my nerves with this!
Stop yelling!
We can't even have a simple and
direct conversation in this house.
Listen, Cecile.
This is simple and direct.
If you want to get involved in your
son's sex life, it's your problem.
I consider that it's
none of my business.
I'm going out. I am not sleepy.
I am dedicating this song to all
my friends in the neighborhood.
Youssef Borki, Issam,
Adissad Gaza, Younes, Aissa,
all my family, and my friend Salma.
To my love, Ghizlane,
I love her very much.
-Absolutely.
-It's not the first time.
Hello. I hope I'm not bothering you.
Not at all.
I just wanted to see how it's done.
-You want some coffee?
-No, thank you.
Come here.
I dedicate this beautiful song
to my mother, my father,
my sister, Anna,
and my little brother, Zacariah.
You're lucky.
We have great songs tonight.
. . .if you don't know my name.
Thank you.
And here is a song
requested from Germany.
-Get out of here, Antoine. Out!
-But...
There are no "buts."
I am tired of you imposing yourself.
You come to my house
without warning!
Now you show up when I'm at work!
That's harassment!
You seem on edge.
Shut up, Antoine. Leave!
I don't want to see you anymore!
Never!
This song was requested by Aydan,
to all her family and friends.
Now we're going to listen to
"Okam Bale" by Angelique Kidjo.
And here is the song
by Angelique Kidjo.
It's the fourth version of
the British-American resolution
presented to the UN.
The Americans hope for a vote.
They're hoping, but nothing is done.
It's the fourth reunion...
On site, two individuals
were found dead.
Cecile! You see, he's not here.
Look, Rachel. I know him by heart.
He won't give up so easily.
The only thing he's interested in
is making a mess of my life.
I'm sure he's hiding somewhere.
As you can see, there is nobody out.
Where's your car?
I took it to the mechanic.
It broke down.
Can you give me a ride?
No problem.
I can't believe you're so nervous.
All this for a ghost.
A ghost.
Do you think you can safely see
a ghost you were madly in love with?
I don't know what happened
between you two.
You never wanted to talk about it.
So you were madly in love with him?
Yes. It was both lust and love.
I never found that with any other man.
I have desired Nathan.
He gave me a lot of pleasure,
but I could never really love him.
I see him as an enemy.
-Let's close it. It's cold.
-Thanks.
One, two, three. Come on.
You should sleep with Antoine.
That's the only way to end it.
It happened to me in New York.
Some guy I hadn't seen for 1 0 years.
We met randomly, we spent a night
together and after that,
we realized that it was over.
There was nothing left between us.
We said goodbye without pain,
feeling a great relief.
It has nothing to do with Antoine.
It's not about sleeping with him.
It's something else.
I have the feeling
that after all these years,
he came to find me in Tangiers
to claim what he is owed.
Place your bets, please.
Four. Six.
The bets are placed. Thank you.
2 1, red.
I'd like to cash out, please.
Thank you.
Good evening, sir.
20,000.
Here you go. 20,000 dinars.
Thank you.
Good evening, doctor.
I didn't know you were a gambler.
I never gamble.
I am absolutely not suicidal.
Then what are you doing here?
As you can see, nothing special.
I am drinking.
It's the only place
open day and night.
It's strange how things
close early in this city.
It's the same everywhere
when it's off-season, isn't it?
September is still summer.
That's what my wife says.
May I?
Did she tell you how we met?
No, she just said you were in love
with her when you were kids.
Kids? Really?
She also said you were
possessive and jealous.
It's only normal.
She was important to me.
She left me to marry a psychiatrist.
That guy was definitely not a kid.
He was 1 0 years older than her.
Dr. Bertrand Ferry. Do you know him?
Yes, she lived with him
when I met her.
She followed you to Tangiers.
That's not surprising.
No, first we lived in Casablanca.
That's where I am from.
I have a lot of admiration
for you, doctor.
You managed to settle with her.
That was my dream. It still is.
If I may be frank, I came to Tangiers
hoping to take her from you.
I am not sure she agrees.
Did you talk to her about it?
Of course. That's why I came.
And?
She said no.
At least for now.
She even told me
I wasn't allowed to see her.
I don't know what to do.
I am not sure I can help you.
In fact, I think
I'm the wrong person for that.
Obviously.
Do you love her?
After 20 years, couples are not
madly in love anymore.
It's something else.
Do you ever cheat on her?
Of course. She knows,
and she has no problem with it.
That's right.
Polygamy is part of the culture.
That's not it at all.
I have one wife
and several mistresses.
I also have more than one culture.
She was always in my mind,
even when I was with other women.
For me, it's the opposite.
Since I live with her,
I sometimes need novelty.
I don't understand why you've waited
so long without writing or calling,
without contacting her.
I was afraid. You can't imagine
how much I was afraid.
-Afraid of what?
-Afraid she would reject me.
Then I tried very hard to forget her,
but it didn't work.
I did a lot of thinking and I thought:
"When I see her again, she'll be
older, her children will be married.
My coming back may be good news,
you know what I mean,
some kind of resurrection."
I was wrong.
She prefers staying with you.
No.
Here you go, sir.
Let me pay for it.
I'm sorry.
Cecile, what I feared has happened.
I didn't find the words
to convince you.
I thought a miracle was possible,
but the miracle didn't happen.
I don't have a reason
to stay in this country anymore.
I will ask to be replaced
on the construction site.
I'll never be able to replace you,
because the more I tried,
the less I succeeded.
Today, I feel happy
after seeing you again.
I managed to steal a few moments.
The time marked by the clock doesn't
count, because in one look from you,
one move, in the timber of your voice,
I found eternity once again.
...recognize me.
It would be nice
if you closed your eyes.
That way you would
only hear my voice.
Every night, I hear yours
on the radio, I look at the city,
and to me, you and the city become
one. Now, the moment has come...
Let's not stay here. I don't want
people to see me with a stranger.
Especially not a man.
Nadia told me to give you this.
They're CDs.
Why do you refuse to see her?
Because it's not good for me, Sami.
You know, I saw the Taleb last year,
when I was sick.
He told me that twin sisters
have to separate once and for all,
if they want to have a life.
Said and I could come eat
at McDonald's. Children love that.
That way, you'll meet him.
I am not allowed to talk to clients
when I work.
You won't talk to him,
but you'll see him.
Does he speak Arabic?
No, Nadia, and I speak French.
We live in Paris. It's expected.
Is he circumcised?
You know, Nadia.
She doesn't care about religion.
What does that mean?
He's not Muslim?
He has a Moroccan passport.
I handled it myself.
Everything's fine.
Does he have your name?
No, his mother's name.
Why don't you get married?
Wouldn't it make things easier?
I don't know.
We never talked about it.
Nadia needs a real husband.
She waited too long,
and she was very unlucky with men.
I disagree. She just experienced life.
Besides, it gave her Said.
That's good, right?
I know that she's unhappy.
I know her better than you do.
I have my mother's car.
Do you need a ride?
No, I'm fine. I am used to
walking home. It's healthy.
It was good to see you.
Take good care of her.
Now that she doesn't have a sister,
I'm glad she still has a brother.
Aicha! Nadia wanted to know
how your parents were doing.
Tell her that our father went to
Agadir to work during the season,
and our mother stayed in the village
to rest after her operation.
Here. It's not much, but it would
make me happy if you took this.
It was her idea or your idea?
Both of us.
You know what the Taleb says?
A piece of meat earned by working
is worth more than a lamb
offered out of sympathy.
Does that mean you don't want it?
Yes, I'll take the money. I need it.
Thank you.
1 2 dinars, please.
One Coke, small fries. Okay.
And a cheeseburger.
For here or to go?
Bilal!
Go away!
It hurts.
You're not going to burn my leg?
It's the only way.
To do what? You don't heal a dog bite
by burning the wound. That's torture.
I'm telling you, I've already done it.
You always think you know everything,
and you know nothing.
My father taught me how to do it.
It stops the bleeding,
it kills the germs, it dries the...
I don't know how to say it.
Cauterize.
You have to do it with the house key.
The house key?
What the hell are you talking about?
It keeps the bad spirits away.
Who cares about spirits?
I hope your dogs don't have rabies.
No danger. The vet comes
to check them every month.
My boss likes to do things well.
Let me see.
Stop it! Don't do that!
It's bad enough as it is.
I don't believe in your stupid
remedies, anyway.
See, you say I'm suspicious, but
you're the one who doesn't trust me.
It's not the same.
I hope they won't need to amputate.
Would you sleep with me
if I only had one leg?
Stop it, Sami.
If you could change one thing
when we have sex, what would it be?
Sex is something we do
but don't talk about.
Your motorcycle is a beast.
How fast can it go?
1 25 mph on the freeway.
But you would have to go to Larache.
Around here you can't go that fast.
How did you pay for it?
Your loan story is phony.
It's a gift.
You won't tell me?
Stop it, Sami.
I don't owe you anything.
What time do we meet?
We won't meet today. I'm going back
to Paris. Nadia's not feeling well.
She's never well.
Why do you live with her?
I told you. Because we get along.
You always like to invent
chores for yourself.
She's a burden. She's nice, but she's
a burden. Give her a kiss for me.
Here. It's an open plane ticket
to Paris. It's round trip.
Come see me whenever you want.
I can't leave my job that easily.
Besides, remember last time?
It was a hassle to get a visa.
It took a while, but it worked. You
just need to do it ahead of time.
If you have proof that you're going
to stay with someone, it's easy.
I don't know. I'll think about it.
I can't promise you anything.
You know how I feel about Paris.
I would much rather be a prince here
than a bum over there.
You won't be a bum.
I should go.
I wish you many good things.
See you next time.
How come you're already up?
I can't sleep.
Well, it's a good thing.
Look. A dog bit me.
I took a taxi home.
I wanted to walk home, and bam!
Is it serious?
No.
Let's go to the pharmacy.
I'll give you a shot.
-You want some coffee?
-Yes.
What time is it?
Almost 7:00.
You still don't have a watch?
Said should wake up soon.
That kid always wakes up early.
I noticed. He is very quiet, though.
He seems to be a very nice kid.
Not really. He won't let anyone
touch him, even his mother.
He's timid. It will go away.
There are weather issues.
Don't wait here for two hours.
You should just go home.
I would like to talk to you for
a while. We barely saw each other.
It's always like that.
I hope you don't mind, Nadia.
We're going to the cafe.
Not at all.
How's your job? You didn't tell me.
It's all right.
With overtime, I make a living.
You don't look too motivated.
No regrets?
No.
Two coffees.
I do regret having studied in France.
It would be hard
for me to find a job here.
Every time I come back here,
it's strange.
I don't know who I am anymore.
Why do you say that?
Look at your father. He studied
medicine in Paris and he works here.
It's very different. He speaks Arabic,
and he's at home here.
Besides, medicine is the same
everywhere. Whereas law. . . .
I heard he was offered
twice his salary
to work in a hospital in Casablanca.
Why don't you want to go?
When did he tell you that?
This morning. When he gave me
the anti-tetanus shot.
He's impossible.
I didn't know it was a secret.
It's always the same with you.
You want to talk, and when we talk
you dramatize everything.
I am not dramatizing.
My job is here at the radio. If I go
to Casablanca, I lose it. That's all.
I don't understand
why you're clinging to this job.
Considering how little you get paid.
I'm sure it would be good
for you both to have a new life.
You don't love him enough to say yes.
You think women always
have to be the ones to yield?
Not particularly.
For instance, I am going
back to Paris for Nadia.
She looks better just knowing
she is leaving this country.
Did you notice?
It's not the same.
You're not attached to anyone here.
I do have someone.
Someone you don't know.
I don't know
if you're attached to anyone.
How can you say that?
You don't think I am able to love?
I don't know.
Hello.
Antoine?
You look exhausted, Antoine.
Luckily, tomorrow is Sunday.
Unfortunately, we also work
on Sundays. We're late.
Do you have time to go have a drink?
Look at me. I need to change.
We'll be more comfortable
in your room.
If you say so. Come with me.
You have a nice view.
I wanted to call you,
but I didn't have your cell number.
Here. Help yourself.
I really need to take a shower.
What are you doing?
I don't want you to disappear.
I won't disappear, Antoine.
I'm the one who came to see you.
I'm happy to be here.
But if you lock me in,
that's not a good start.
I know you saw Nathan the other night.
Yes. We just said hi, from far away.
Here is what I came to tell you,
Antoine.
Your love story with me doesn't exist.
It's easier to love someone in
your head and dream about them
than deal with them on a daily basis.
You're like my friend Rachel.
Her lover lives in Rabat.
She talks to him on the phone every
day, but they never see each other.
There's a song about this.
I love you even more
When you're not here
Because I can dream of you
But see, I am here. I don't like
my body anymore. My life is a mess.
But I'm still fighting, even though
I lost control a little bit.
So what I'm suggesting is the opposite
of what you're offering me.
I can't commit
to spending my life with you,
but I'd like to rest
with you for a while.
Just a stop over.
And then, I'll go back to my life.
A stop over? What does that mean?
That's what I like best in life.
You forget the purpose of your trip.
You don't think about the itinerary
anymore. You stop to rest for a while.
All right. Let's stop over.
I would really like to change now.
Did you see my clothes?
I talk too much. Sorry.
Turn the light off.
I couldn't miss you.
I mean, you really look like her.
Sami insisted that I see you,
but he didn't tell me clearly
what the disease was.
Come with me, I'll give you a ride.
That way, we'll talk
about your mother in the car.
I don't want people in the
neighborhood to see me with a man.
If they do,
they won't respect me anymore.
Would you prefer going to a cafe?
I am not like Nadia.
I don't go to cafes.
Let's walk a little bit, then.
In the street? Today is Sunday.
Everyone will look at us.
Can't we go somewhere quieter?
We'll try to find something.
Come with me.
Well, get in.
Help me.
With synthetic hormones,
it's all about the right dosage.
Does she get her blood
analyzed regularly?
Yes, every month, she goes
to the hospital, in Tafraoute.
It's a little far, though.
Where does she live, exactly?
In Taouz. That's where
Nadia and I were born.
I hear it was quite an event.
They had never seen twins before.
Taouz? I don't know where it is.
It's in the middle of nowhere,
in the Ziz Valley.
Some people know it because
of the stones falling from the sky.
-Meteorites, right?
-Meteorites.
There are tons of them in the area.
They've been there for millions
of years. Nothing has moved.
There's no life. It's the desert.
This road isn't very good.
You wanted a quiet place.
-Do you have family in Tangiers?
-No.
I hope you go out, a little bit.
No, I don't like places
where there are lots of people.
Nadia and I used to go to clubs.
She would dance. I never had fun.
Now that she's gone,
I prefer being by myself.
That way, boys don't bother me.
If you lock yourself up like this,
you'll never meet anyone.
I don't want to meet anybody.
Men all want the same thing.
If you knew how much I hate them.
I see.
In fact, I see that
you don't know them.
I don't want to know them.
Will you be shocked
if I strip to a bathing suit?
No.
I like the way you laugh.
You don't want to go in the water?
No, there's too much wind.
Besides, I would
have to take my clothes off.
Look around, there's nobody here.
Are you afraid of me?
No.
Look, the coast is clear today.
You can see Spain.
I'm starting to get hungry.
I thought you wanted to go for a swim.
I'll go, then.
Where's everybody?
You know, it's Sunday.
What do you mean, it's Sunday?
You know we need
to get things moving.
Why aren't they working?
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Hello. I have a meeting
with Antoine Lavau.
I've been waiting for an hour.
Did he leave a message for me?
One moment, please.
-There's a woman...
-Hold on a second.
-Hello.
Mr. Lavau had an accident.
An accident?
After the rain, part of the
construction site collapsed.
He's in the hospital.
I'll give you the address.
My son called me last night.
He's going to spend Christmas in
a mountain cabin with some friends.
Otherwise, I still work with Rachel.
We've put together a new proposal.
I hope they say yes to this one.
I wonder if you can hear the rain.
It's my favorite noise.
I think he met someone,
but I didn't ask.
He moved all his belongings
to Casablanca.
I kept a bed, a coffee table
and the sofa chairs.
That's why I can't stay
for too long today.
I need to be back by 5:00 pm
to wait for the workers.
They're going to put all that stuff
in a storage space at Rachel's.
It will save me some money.
I'll have the same thing.
What's up?
They're taking him back to France.
Really?
I didn't know you could transport
someone who is in a coma.
They won't keep him in Tangiers.
They're transferring him to a special
clinic in Berck-sur-Mer,
in the Pas-de-Calais area.
When do they want to transfer him?
As soon as possible.
They're saying it doesn't make sense
to keep him here any longer.
Is someone going with him?
Yes. I'm going.
He didn't have any friends of family?
I don't like it when you talk
about him in the past.
I've never seen a man like him.
What do you mean?
Usually, women are the ones
to fall madly in love like that.
Rachel decided to make
a Christmas tree this year.
She wanted to get an early start.
This morning, we got up early.
The weather was nice.
We went to Missnana. You remember?
That's the forest
where I showed you the house.
The illegal immigrants
were still there.
Maybe they were different ones.
They try their best to be anonymous,
so it's hard to know.
You should have seen Rachel and me
dragging the Christmas tree
for 200 yards.
By the way, we had a hard time
fitting the furniture
in the storage space yesterday.
Especially the bed. It was too big.
I found this
underneath the box springs.
That was a crazy thing to do.
I wanted to tear it apart.
I didn't sleep all night.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org