Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Father.
What is it?
What more must I do?
What more must I do for your approval?
I've done the best I can.
What more must I do
to make you believe in me?
Tell me, Father.
Tell me.
This can't be happening. It just can't!
How can he do this to us?
Is he torturing us?
Your Highness, calm down.
How can I at a time like this?
What were you thinking?
Did you give up after one try?
You should've tried again and again!
This is all my fault.
My prayers weren't enough
to move the gods.
You're right about that.
Who made you Sorceress?
What happened once can happen again.
Mother, please calm down.
I should've tried harder.
What do you mean? How much harder?
You did something the King couldn't.
Your achievements are already
much greater than his.
- Your Highness. Don't say that.
- Why, am I wrong?
I can't take it anymore.
If he won't give it to me,
I'll take it from him.
I thought he'd accept the petition.
It's not that simple.
I quit the competition
and Daeso made a steel sword.
There's no reason to postpone it.
Why won't he make his mind up?
The King is trying to
maintain his authority.
What do you mean?
Figure out the power struggle
and you'll get what I mean.
I want you to remember that
the Queen and Daeso are upset.
It will work against you.
They've done a lot in the past.
Goodness knows what they'll do next.
What more must I do?
What more must I do for your approval?
I've done the best I can.
What more must I do
to make you believe in me?
Father.
I feel as if I'm King Gou Jian,
sleeping on sticks and chewing gall...
while plotting his adversary's downfall.
I will use my anger...
to sharpen my sword of revenge.
Until the day I wield that sword...
I'll willingly withstand
all trials that come my way.
He was Daeso's weakness after all.
I'm sure that's why
the King postponed the investment.
Now that you have the chance,
it's your turn to attack.
Attack?
Yes.
Now it's your turn to impress the King.
Searching Yuntabal's troop
did nothing for me.
I didn't know Father and Daeso
trusted him so much.
Your Highness.
Go on.
How about using them both?
Use them both?
For as long as you compete with them...
both princes are your opponents.
Now that Prince Jumong
is Head of Palace Bodyguards...
he'll have just as much power
as Prince Daeso.
Use Jumong against Daeso...?
That's it.
Make them fight each other
and you'll emerge the winner.
I'll be the winner...
Dochi.
Yes, Your Highness.
You should be more than a merchant.
I'll make you my tactician.
Your Highness. I like being a merchant.
I'll just do all you say
while buying and selling goods.
Then do as you want.
I should get going.
Then...
- Take care.
- Bye.
My goodness...
I've never used my brain so much before.
Sir, you were amazing.
I'm so proud to be able to serve you.
You jerk!
You know how much I hate sweet talk.
How dare you talk to me like that?
Why you...
OK.
- It's me, Jumong.
- Oh! Come in!
Welcome. Have a seat.
Go on.
What's the occasion?
Remember I wanted to congratulate you?
Here, have a drink.
But I'm still on duty.
Who cares? Here you go. Go on.
Let's drink.
Jumong.
I've wanted to say
we should bury the hatchet.
I know I've wronged you...
but we're in the same boat now.
I too went through a lot
because of Daeso's selfishness.
Remember how hard he was on us?
I worked you up...
because I had no choice
but to give in to Daeso.
Take Buyoung for example.
That was all because
Daeso wanted to beat you so much.
Oh.
And it was Daeso who made me
kill the man you met in the cave.
I didn't even know who he was.
As I said, we're on the same boat.
Daeso forced us apart.
There's no reason for us
to be hostile towards each other.
Don't you agree?
Youngpo.
What is it?
We're both old enough
to take responsibility for our actions.
Whether Daeso forced you or used you,
you should take responsibility now.
You're right.
I want to bury the hatchet too.
Yes, let's. We should move on.
Such bad memories will just
get in the way of our bright future.
But...
There's one thing I can't forget.
What's that?
You'll find out...
my secret in due time.
I'm still on duty. I should get going.
OK...
We should do this again sometime. Bye...
Make my enemies fight each other...
It's so hard...
Your Majesty.
Please don't put it off any longer.
It's the best and only way
to calm the panic-stricken people.
Even the ministers are confused
because you keep putting it off.
It's dividing us up into factions.
Your Majesty, invest Prince Daeso.
Are you my subject...
or Daeso's?
Your Majesty.
I only want what's best for you
and Puyo's royal family.
Please don't question my loyalty.
Why do you think I'm putting it off?
If I invest Daeso,
the power balance will shift...
in favor of the Queen
and her relatives in Maga.
You know that too, don't you?
And if that becomes reality...
that'll be the end of the power
you've enjoyed for many years.
Think about it.
Your Majesty.
Like you said, I've enjoyed something
far beyond what I deserve.
I'm not afraid of losing all I have.
I just want to stop the royal family
from drifting apart from the public.
Think of the confused people
and take my loyal advice.
How are things?
Do you like being bodyguards?
Like Oi said,
I prefer living in the streets.
Yes, Commander.
We have to be on guard at all times.
It's really hard work.
It's not as bad as I thought.
I thought so too.
I'm sure all the rules and regulations
are making your lives hard.
I know but bear with me.
Yes, Commander.
There's something I need you to do.
We're at your service.
The Hyunto blacksmiths add
a secret ingredient to the liquid iron.
Find out what that is.
Daeso's men guard the iron chamber
ever since they came here.
- You must be careful.
- We will be.
- Commander, this is Songju.
- Come in.
His Majesty wishes to see you.
- You asked for me?
- We're leaving the Palace.
In the royal carriage?
No. It'll be a short visit
to see how the people are.
I'll go in secret. Get ready.
I will, Your Majesty.
His Majesty and Prince Jumong
left the Palace.
I'll follow them.
- Forget it.
- Pardon?
He probably went to see how the people
are reacting to the rejected petitions.
Shouldn't we let him know
the people are on your side?
I'll get ready.
Don't.
I don't want to stoop that low.
Mari.
What is it?
Pig or ox bone...
Found something?
Why is it so quiet?
People don't come outside
since the omens appeared.
See what they're up to.
OK.
That'll do.
Whatever evil strikes Puyo,
it will leave you unharmed.
You can go.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
He's a shaman warding off evil.
Let's go.
Warding off evil?
It's a new trend,
taking advantage of the confusion.
Let's take a look.
Your Majesty.
He's a mere shaman.
Who represents the people.
Anyone else?!
Water has turned to blood
and the rock is weeping.
There will be bloodshed.
No one is safe without my powers.
Come to me and save your life!
How about me?
Will disaster strike me too?
The King abused the Shrine
and Yeomieul left Puyo.
Who can avoid disaster
when the gods are angry?
The Palace will pay
for bringing the gods' wrath upon us.
What should I do?
Buy an amulet.
Then you can escape
when disaster strikes.
I'll take one.
You want to escape danger for free?
- Is that him?
- Yes.
- Are you sure he's good?
- I'm sure of it.
- I can never trust shamans.
- You have nothing to lose anyway.
Sir! What's wrong?
Sir!
He's only making money
by bewildering the people.
Don't mind him.
I'm the cause of their suffering.
I can't help but be heavy-hearted.
Your Majesty.
What is it?
The people will get over it.
But you've forgotten something else.
AncientJosun's migrants.
I visited Hyunto, Imdoon and Jinbun.
I saw tens of thousands
suffer under the Han's oppression.
Those who'd escaped from Hyunto
didn't even want to come to Puyo.
You once led the Damul Army,
so they waited for you to rescue them.
But now they've given up all hope.
Your Majesty.
Puyo's people will recover.
But who will look after
the poor suffering migrants...
who look forward to dying?
Have you really forgotten them?
- This is confidential.
- Don't worry, Your Highness.
- Who was that for?
- Uncle Maga.
About the Crown Prince investment?
Yes.
The King rejected their last petition.
There's no point in trying again.
Who said it's a petition?
I'm going to force him instead.
I told them to ignore the King's orders
unless he invests you as Crown Prince.
- Mother.
- The Jega rule Sachooldo.
They have more soldiers than we do.
The King is powerless
without their cooperation.
What if it backfires and leads to war?
This is too dangerous.
The King wouldn't dare
go to war against them.
Wait and see.
I will make him give in this time.
Your Majesty.
Puyo's people will recover.
But who will look after
the poor suffering migrants...
who look forward to dying?
Have you really forgotten them?
Commander, this is Mari.
Come in.
Commander.
This is what we found.
Where will you go?
It's time to go to Jolbon.
Inrang.
Yes, Yeomieul?
Go to Puyo and
bring Soryung and Byuriha.
OK.
(Keru)
Hard, soft.
Hard, hard, soft, soft, hard.
- Soft, soft, hard, hard, hard...
- Lady Sosuhno's here.
Welcome.
This is the Han blacksmith.
This is our director.
Teach him how to make steel swords.
You can't make a steel sword like this.
That's why I want you to tell us how.
Wait.
I can't tell you that.
I'll tell you one thing.
You need to add something...
to galvanized iron to make pig iron.
I don't think you know what that is.
What's he saying?
You need to add something
to turn galvanized iron into pig iron.
We don't have it here.
Ask him what it is.
He can't tell us.
Dang...
What does he mean?
We melt iron ore
to make galvanized iron.
But it's so strong
it breaks whenever we temper it.
That's why we can't make a decent sword.
The secret to parching
lies in making pig iron.
We need to add something
while melting the iron ore...
we just don't know what that is.
Miss.
Our team in Hyunto got back to us.
Do you know what Daeso's deal was?
He agreed to marry Yangjung's daughter
in return for the blacksmiths.
He'll become Puyo's Crown Prince.
Who cares how many wives he has?
You want me to be his concubine?
He doesn't know what you're like yet.
I wonder what he'll say
when he finds out I know about this.
We should get back to Puyo.
Tell Wootae to get ready.
OK.
We sent steel weaponry to Jolbon
in return for gold and horses.
Send the gold to the Capital
and the horses to the Iron Army.
I will, Governor.
- Dongsun.
- Yes?
Select some skilled soldiers
who speak Puyo's language...
and teach them Puyo's customs.
What for?
I'll send them to Puyo.
You mean...
I'm going to send some spies.
I see.
Guess what this is.
It's from Prince Daeso.
That's nice.
Do you like him?
Yes.
Ambitious men tend to disregard women.
But I'm glad he shows his interest.
Yangsullan.
Yes?
Thank you for agreeing to marry him
without giving me a hard time.
(Yangsullan, Yangjung's daughter)
I complied with it for my sake.
Despite your talents,
all you can be is a mere governor.
When I become Puyo's Queen
I'll invite you to Puyo.
I'll make it up to you.
Very well.
Then I'll make Daeso the King of Puyo.
You'll have him wrapped round
your finger so you'll be the real king.
What do you know?
Like you said, they're making
steel weapons with Puyo's director.
(Songyang, Piryu chief)
What is Sosuhno up to?
She's preparing to return to Puyo.
Kill her the minute she leaves.
OK, chief.
Attack!
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
I bet it was one of the chiefs.
We should get out of here fast.
Miss!
Wootae!
Wootae...
Wootae.
How is he?
I did the best I could
but the poison has spread.
We have to wait and see.
Wait and see?
You should do all you can to save him!
What do you mean wait and see?
- Dang!
- Kepil. Calm down.
Thank you.
Wootae...
Wake up, will you? My goodness...
Oh, Wootae...
Wootae...
Miss, how is he?
In critical condition.
Who would do such a terrible thing?
I think I know. Want to make a guess?
Who is it?
I sent Sayong to check.
We'll find out soon.
Found anything?
Yes. It's the Piryu chief,
just as you predicted.
(Yangtak, Keru's temporary leader)
Summon the soldiers.
Miss. You should tell your father first.
This may spark a tribal war.
There's nothing to fear.
I'll show them what happens to...
a tribe that stands against Keru.
You wretch.
How dare you insult me?
Where are your manners?
Chief.
I haven't even started yet.
Please don't say that.
What will you do to me?
What happens to you
depends on what happens to Wootae.
If Wootae dies so will you.
If he recovers...
you get a second chance.
I think you should pray to the gods.
Escort him away.
Yes, Miss!
Wootae...
Please wake up.
Miss.
Oi, Mari and Hyupbo are here.
Prince Jumong sent this to Mopalmo.
- Oi.
- OK.
(Keru iron chamber)
What's wrong?
Powdered bones...
ground up seashells...
I've tried everything.
How about this?
That too.
Thanks anyway.
How's Prince Jumong?
Good.
I'll do everything I can.
Tell him to hang in there.
Carry on then.
- Musong.
- Huh?
- Take care.
- Bye.
I'll throw this away then.
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Hang on.
Isn't this ocher?
I haven't tried this yet.
Miss! Miss!
Yeomieul is here.
He's near death.
Bring me the secret medicine.
I will.
How is he?
He's gained consciousness.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you...
We've prepared a Shrine.
Please go and rest.
- Kepil.
- Huh?
- Escort her, please.
- OK, OK.
This way...
Bring the Piryu chief.
OK.
Untie him.
The gods didn't forsake you after all.
Wootae made it.
I will never forget what you did to me.
Please don't.
I'll have to remind you if you do.
Let him go.
OK, Miss.
Let's go.
From now on, I will accept
all Ancient Josun migrants...
who wish to settle in Puyo.
Your Majesty.
This will affect our ties with the Han.
We almost attacked Okjuh for their salt.
This might lead to
an all-out war against the Han.
Prince Daeso is right.
No other country will take them in.
We shouldn't take the lead.
I will take them in
because no other nation will.
The Han have used
and abused the migrants.
They have nowhere to go
even if they do escape.
We'll give them hope, a reason to live.
Anyone who dares to object
will be considered...
a subject of Han, so be careful!
Chief General.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Order all the sentries...
to protect those who enter our borders
from pursuing Han soldiers.
I will, Your Majesty.
The migrants?
Yes, Your Highness.
The Chief General was ordered to
protect those who enter Puyo.
Everything is going
as Yeomieul predicted.
His Majesty is ruining Puyo.
I'm actually rather glad.
This might just work out...
The Queen is here.
Sit down.
- Have you heard the news?
- Yes, Your Highness.
What do you think about this?
Accepting the migrants
means going to war against the Han.
All the evil omens
are finally coming true.
We're not ready to accept the migrants.
But His Majesty is willing to go to war.
No one can make him change his mind.
But if he doesn't
we will lose to the Han.
We must stop him.
I want you to take charge.
What authority do we have...?
What do you mean?
You must tell him what you all think
even if he ignores you.
Only then will the people know
what the gods want.
What did you say?
The gods want me to reject
the migrants entering Puyo?
- Your Majesty, if you accept them...
- Mauryung!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Do you know why Yeomieul left?
Because she acted against my will,
just like you are now.
Do you want to end up like her?
Leave me at once!
Your Majesty.
We have a messenger from Sachooldo.
Let him in.
This is a petition signed by
all the Sachooldo Jega.
The ministers, the Shrine and the Jega.
Opposition is stronger than I thought.
I put you on the spot.
Not at all. The migrants
aren't the only reason.
Everyone's attacking at once,
as if they've been lying in wait.
Backing out now might mean
giving up my throne.
I won't tolerate that.
Commander, we're back.
Come in.
We gave the powders to Mopalmo
but I don't think it'll do any good.
He's tried them all before.
But he did tell you not to worry.
He's trying his best.
Well done.
Is Sosuhno well?
We escorted her back to Puyo.
We're back.
Good job.
How's Wootae?
Much better,
thanks to Yeomieul's treatment.
I heard you imprisoned the Piryu chief.
Why did you do that?
If that leads to war then...
Well done.
Yuntabal, if this leads to war...
Then we go to war,
if that's what it takes.
Miss.
- I have a favor to ask.
- Anything you want.
I'd like all the information you have
on Jinbun and Imdoon.
Tell me what it's for.
I'll select the documents you need.
Give me all you have.
I'll select what I need myself.
I'll get them ready.
Why do you need all this?
As you know, Jinbun and Imdoon
are much weaker than they used to be...
when they became commanderies.
They don't even have
a permanent governor.
Even the people
are moving to other regions.
This is the perfect time
to attack Imdoon and Jinbun.
You want to go to war?
Yes.
I'm going to look into it
and persuade the King.
It could lead to a war against the Han.
They're still fighting the Southwest Yi.
They can't send reinforcements
even if we do attack.
What was that?
What's that clanging noise?
Watch closely.
Mopalmo!
I did it.
I did it...
Don't just stand there.
I must take this to Prince Jumong.
Now!
Commander. Mopalmo is here.
Your Highness.
Mopalmo. What's going on?
I did it.
I made a steel sword that doesn't break.
Are you serious?
Yes, Your Highness. This is it.
- Oi.
- Yes, Commander.
Is your sword the one Daeso made?
Yes.
Step forward.
Commander...
It broke...
Commander!
Mopalmo!
Your Highness!
I have something to tell you.
Take a seat.
What is it?
I've been looking into
Jinbun and Imdoon.
What is this report for?
Give me some troops.
I'll attack Jinbun and Imdoon
and save the migrants.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org