Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
Cherry Blossoms
I always wanted to
go to Japan with him.
Just to see Mt. Fuji once.
The cherry blossoms. With him.
Because seeing anything without
my husband, I can't even imagine that.
That would be like not really seeing it.
How can I go on living without him?
We wanted to talk it over
with you first.
If you think your husband
can cope with the diagnosis...
people react differently...
How the disease progresses
is hard to tell.
It could be that your husband won't
even have any symptoms for a long time K
You might want to think about
doing something together...
a trip...
something a little adventurous...
My husband hates adventures.
He'd prefer it if
nothing changed. Ever.
Nothing. At all.
Every day he takes
the 7:28 train to Weilheim.
He used to work at the passport office.
Now he's the head of the
waste management department.
Recycling is good.
Reusables are better.
He's only been sick for one week
in twenty years. 1991.
The flu and an eardrum infection.
He eats the sandwich that I make for
him at 1 pm every day and his apple.
"An apple a day keeps the doctor away."
He says that every morning.
§An apple a day keeps the doctor away.
Hello, Rudi.
How was your day?
So so...
Yours?
Okay.
Aren't you hungry?
- No.
Down more, Elke!
And with a smile, please!
Everything goes easier with a smile.
And peppy! And down!
Back already?
Karl Angermeier, leave messages
after the beep. Thanks.
Yes, Karl. This is Mama.
I... I wanted to... it's...
everything's okay. Talk to you soon.
Want to visit the children in Berlin?
Berlin? I don't know.
What if we finally went to Japan?
You know...
Fuji's just another mountain.
Yes, but we could visit Karl.
It'd be cheaper if he visited us.
Oh, Rudi!
Shall we go on?
I'm hungry.
Nothing to eat?
Rudi, we haven't been underway
for 5 minutes.
"An apple a day keeps the doctor away."
You want it?
No, not me.
I'll eat it later.
Imagine... the train stops in Hanau
for 2 minutes...
so if you don't get off fast...
He wanted to meet us on the platform!
What time is it? Look at your watch.
I'll give him 5 minutes and then
we'll take a taxi or something.
Hey!
Well...
Where were we?
- Where were you, Klaus?
Track 11...
That's where the train arrived.
- Track 11. We were there.
Klausi, hi. Klausi...
- Hi, Mama.
We waited for 20 minutes.
I waited for 20 minutes!
What?
- I'm fine.
Let me take it.
- No.
Straight ahead.
Mama, the flower bed!
Mami, can't you watch out!
Hello, we're... oh!
Hi.
Hello, Emma.
Hallo.
Robert, Celine!
How about a kiss?
Robert!
Have a seat. We baked a cake.
Bought one.
Ah!
- Let them.
Thanks.
Gameboy or cake?
- Let them play.
Who'd like coffee?
- No coffee for me. A beer maybe.
Uh...
Then forget it.
Okay.
Forgive the intrusion. Mama had the
sudden urge to visit all of you.
One after the other.
Karl too? That's great!
No, not Karl. Unfortunately.
Why not? That would be so nice.
Maybe next year. After I retire...
You'll have plenty of time.
You okay?
It just went down the wrong way.
Need some water?
- No, I'm fine.
Hey, where have you been?
- Sorry! Hi.
Why did they decide to come,
out of the blue like this?
No idea.
How long are they staying?
- They didn't say.
I have no time.
You think we do?
Hello!
Rudi, not now.
They have to go in the fridge.
Thanks, Pop. I've only been
a vegetarian for six years.
We'll take them. We love them.
But aren't they traditionally
supposed to be eaten before noon?
No, no, they have to
be eaten this evening.
Alright then, we'll have them tonight.
You poor thing, we're taking
your room away from you.
It's okay.
You don't like them, do you?
Not really.
Thanks.
So, more sausage.
- Thanks.
Want to go sightseeing tomorrow?
I'll drive you around a little, okay?
Show you the city.
Oh yes.
And then we'll visit you for coffee.
- Yeah. Great.
Mama wanted to see
some dance performance...
Oh, God, do we all have to go?
A famous Butoh dancer
from Japan is in town.
Butoh, what's that?
- A modern Japanese dance form...
Have another beer?
Bring me one too?
But I don't have to go.
- Sure you do.
Let's do something
we'd all like to do.
We'd love to go with you.
Okay, Mama! Come on.
Please. "The Mayfly".
Go on, Mama.
Mama, Please recite it for us.
Come on, Mama, please!
"Stop! What you're doing is murder
"Such cruelty is not a must
"The mayfly has but one short day
"One single day of pain
One single day of lust."
- "One single day of lust"
"Oh, let it hover there.
Until it meets its end.
Its heaven lasts forever.
Its life one day to make amends."
Right, Mama?
Stop it!
Okay, it's set!
- Look at the birdy.
Come on.
- It's blinking.
Hurry!
Everybody smile.
Say 'ant shit'!
Papa, smile, too!
- I'm smiling already.
That doesn't matter.
Celine, don't you want to...
- She's not part of the family.
Exactly.
- Take the sunglasses off!
Come on! Okay, everybody.
Everybody look in the camera...
And now!
Yeahhh!
You're doing a great job.
A little more.
You're good.
Where'd you learn that?
I don't know. From me.
From you!
But I can't anymore.
Thank you.
It was great.
What a massage.
See, now he feels great.
I forgot to offer your parents some.
Karl always sends them.
I don't touch mine.
I'd rather eat yours.
- How sweet!
They are good! Hmmn?
Oh, it just occurred to me.
I have a meeting all day tomorrow.
You're a pain!
- I don't believe it.
What'll we do with them?
All you politicians do
is sit on your butts!
You told them
you'd show them around!
Sorry, but I just forgot!
I don't have time.
No way. I'm having them
for coffee and cake. That's plenty.
They're staying with us.
They're driving me nuts already.
Hey, they just arrived.
I hate myself for it
but they drive me crazy.
I go whacko in seconds.
Oh, God and I killed a fly.
That was bad.
Yes, I know. Thanks for your support,
dear. It was bad.
Yeah, "The Mayfly".
Right. And the only one of us
they're interested in is Karl.
Hmm?
I just said they're only
interested in Karl anyway.
That's always how it was.
- What I do doesn't interest them at all.
You think they care about what I do?
"Look at Karl! Isn't he cute!
Look at what he made and isn't it
nice the way he play...
Klaus, Leave Karl Alone! Go away!"
No. Remember?
"Karo! Klausi! Let Karli play...
Hi, sweetie!
- Hey.
What's the matter?
- I can't sleep!
I want to be in my room.
Yes, darling, I know.
They're not staying long.
How long?
Forever!
Are you tired?
No, not really.
- Neither am I.
Well...
I'm glad they're all doing well.
- Yes.
Funny.
I can remember them
so well as children
but now I simply
don't know who they are.
Disappointed in them?
I just don't know them anymore.
Well, they're all healthy.
You can't expect too much.
HAPPY AT THE PARK
How long are they staying?
- No idea.
You have to look after them!
How? I don't have the time.
I like your parents.
I wish mine were like yours.
Sure, you don't know them well.
We could get them tickets for
the show in the Friedrichstadtpalast.
My mother hates revues.
She's really gotten old.
Wow.
Yeah, strange how people change.
I wonder what we'll be like.
No idea.
We just won't get old.
What are they doing today?
I can't.
What the hell are we
going to do with them?
No, no, no
Please.
So now you're going to meow or what?
Please...
No. I have to go to the upholsterer.
I don't have time.
I don't either.
No, really, I have too much to do.
No! No.
- Please. Please.
No. No.
- Please.
Please.
So...
Come on. She's here.
So now I'll show you our old apartment.
Karo and I lived up there.
Right over the bar.
Very practical. And a disaster.
But it wasn't renovated then.
We heated with coal.
Oh, man, okay! Alright already!
Sorry! Yeah,
and fuck you, too, asshole!
To your left
the golden dome of the synagogue.
And straight ahead
our beautiful TV tower. Look!
Wow, that must have cost.
What a cake!
We never bought cake at home,
did we, Mama?
Thanks for today, Franzi.
We saw a lot of the city. Thanks.
Thanks!
Did you have a nice time?
- Very nice, yes.
This is good beer.
I hardly ever drink beer anymore.
Thank goodness.
And Karl? Does he still drink?
How should I know?
Karl never drank very much.
Oh, yes he did.
Like a fish for a while.
That's absolutely not true.
- Nonsense!
Does Karli have a girlfriend in Tokyo?
Mama, you call him all the time.
Ask him next time:
"So Karli, how's it going?
Still boozing and what about chicks?"
So, what'll we do now?
What would you like to?
You're both probably tired
and want to go straight to bed.
It's not even six?
We could cook something.
No, Franzi, you've done enough.
Let's go, Rudi.
Want us to drive you home?
No.
Franzi!
Let us take the S-Bahn...
a little big city flair
for us country bumpkins...
Take care.
Come here.
See you tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
We have a date.
- Aha.
Papa!
So long!
- Bye!
Bye, Mama.
Are you coming?
Let's have some wine.
Let's drink something. Come on.
I'm awful...
- No!
Where do we have to go? Herrmannsdorf?
What?
Berlin Center. Where is it?
Has to be in the center somewhere.
Give me some change.
How much?
The train's leaving! You'd know it!
It won't go in.
- Try it again...
It won't take it. How am I
supposed to buy a ticket?
Try this...
It won't go in. It doesn't work.
That's Berlin for you.
- Rudi, I think you need paper money.
They're out of their minds.
A machine and no tickets come out.
Wait... Berlin AB, just what I said.
What now?
We need one more.
So now we have one ticket
for either you or me or what?
Read what it says "Two people
can't use one ticket." Look here!
You can't even pay here.
Am I supposed to walk? Or you?
Or one of us doesn't pay or what?
Rudi, don't get so excited.
I'm not excited. I'm furious.
I think I want to go home.
Oh, Rudi...
The kids don't have any time for us.
The Baltic isn't far.
- Hmm?
When was the last time
we were at the beach?
At the beach?
I can't remember either.
1987? With the kids?
Or was that Lake Garda?
You want to go to the beach?
Yes, would you?
If you want to.
- But what do you want?
I always do whatever you say...
The beach isn't what
it used to be, either.
You old grouch. Aren't you cold?
You know what?
Slip in there.
What?
- It's warm. Go on.
Tomorrow we'll get up early
and take a long walk on the beach.
What? You want to take a walk?
Wonderful!
I'd like my ashes to
be scattered at sea.
What makes you say that?
Nothing. Don't you ever
think about that?
Really? Well, I do every now and then.
How much time we have left...
Rudi...
You're right.
One ought not think about it...
We've been lucky so far.
Assuming we didn't have much time
left, what would you like to do?
Ah, that line: live every day
as if it were your last.
What nonsense.
What else should you do?
Let me tell you: I wouldn't
do anything differently. Nothing.
I'd go to work in the morning
and come home to you in the evening.
That's what I'd do.
Yes.
Can't you sleep?
The surf is so loud.
And now that.
- Come on, Rudi!
It's nice.
You are and always will be loony.
Oh, come on!
What on earth are you doing?
Come on. You can't sleep anyway.
Cut it out!
Dancing in the middle of the night?
Other people are asleep.
What's with you?
- Nothing. Nothing at all.
What's wrong? Have you had enough?
Didn't you sleep well?
I didn't but you did.
- Me? Not one second.
You slept like a log.
Let's go home.
We've seen Berlin,
we've seen the Baltic,
and we've seen the children.
Let's go home.
I thought you'd be glad to
see your children.
I don't know them. They don't know me.
Our children are better than most.
Yes, we're fortunate.
We have each other.
That's real happiness.
What is it?
Nothing.
I just didn't get
a good night's sleep.
Whenever I woke up
you were sound asleep.
How calm the sea is.
As if was always that way.
It's time to rise and shine!
Come on! Get up you lazybones!
Trudi...
Papa, Karl's here.
The sea is so calm.
Come on.
I can't stand her lying
in that box in there.
I haven't seen her for so long
and now I'll never see her again.
I should've visited her.
Or at least flown her to Tokyo.
I never did anything for her.
And now there's nothing I can do.
We have to look after Papa now.
And how am I supposed to do that?
- I understand.
We never went to the beach
when we were kids.
No, always to the mountains, right?
We were in Italy once.
But not at the beach.
- Lake Garda.
Grosglockner. We took the Grosglockner
pass over the Alps, right, Papa?
Yeah. We all got carsick
but Mama had a plastic bag
for each of us.
She was so full of life back then.
How old was she?
A little older than we are now.
She devoted almost her
entire life to you kids and me.
She wouldn't have put it that way.
Want me to go with you?
It's just not right. It's not fair.
She can't just leave him alone with us.
I don't think she planned it like that.
- Yes, I know.
Mama would've been able to
get along... No problem there.
But him? What are we
supposed to do with him?
When are you flying back?
I can't stay long. My flight leaves
tomorrow afternoon from Berlin.
We have to get back, too.
So do we.
The kids are at the neighbors.
Who has the bag?
What bag?
The bag with her things. I'd like to
have the kimono if you all don't mind.
She always used to
have it on in the kitchen. No.
Yes.
It's all over. And it's impossible
to even imagine beforehand.
If I had known
it would end so suddenly,
I would have been nicer to her.
Papa, nobody can know that.
Thanks for us to be able to
sit here like this.
She would have been
very happy you came, Karl.
What are you going to do now?
I'll have to get used to it.
Don't worry about me.
Thanks.
Emma, give me a little more wine.
Excuse me.
My condolences.
- Thank you.
And this must be Karolin.
No, no, Karolin is in Berlin.
And our youngest is in Japan.
Ah, yes. And Klaus? Where is Klaus?
He has a very important meeting.
- I see.
My condolences.
My condolences. My condolences.
The dance performance was
what she enjoyed most in Berlin.
She said she'd never met
a nicer girl than you.
I'm not that nice. I don't know
why she thought that of me.
She told me about how
she always wanted to dance,
to become a really good Butoh dancer,
more than anything else in her life...
and how she would've liked to
go to Japan so much to study it there
and how everything
turned out differently
and that it was a good life but...
Not that you think that she wasn't happy.
No... I thought...
maybe there's another woman in her...
that nobody saw...
and I saw that other person...
that's all...
That's her?
I didn't like it.
It was so... so extreme.
It embarrassed me...
I didn't want her to keep it up...
We locked her up in here.
But she was happy here.
For sure.
I don't know.
Goodbye.
All the best.
- Thanks.
Have a good trip!
- Okay!
One hundred Views of Mt. Fuji.
Trudi, where are you?
Where?
Papa.
- Ah!
I thought you'd forgotten me. Hi.
I couldn't get away earlier.
How are you? Was the flight okay?
- Fine.
Papa, come on.
You have to take your shoes off.
Oh, yes.
Wait...
There.
I brought my own.
- Okay.
It's not exactly big.
No.
Want something to drink?
Mama always sent you this.
You can't get bread like this
in Japan and the sausages.
And these, two flavors.
Papa, I have to get back to the office.
What exactly do you do?
I've never quite understood...
Nice of you to ask after five years.
I crunch numbers.
What you do with garbage fees.
I do pretty much the same thing as you.
Look... Radio, air conditioner,
satellite receiver, TV.
See you this evening, okay?
I'll be back around six.
My dear Karl,
here's the second stanza:
Oh, let it hover there
until it meets its end
Its heaven lasts forever
It's life one day to make amends
Want something else?
- No, it's fine.
We'll think something out for you
tomorrow. I have to go out later tonight.
Okay.
I'm sorry that I have such little time
but I didn't have much warning.
I don't want to get on your nerves.
- Come on, don't even say that.
Why didn't the two of you
ever visit me?
We thought we had time.
I think I kept your mother from
what was most important to her.
You can't do things for the dead.
Papa...
Look, here's some yen.
I'll pick you up later.
Don't move from here.
I don't want you to get lost. Look,
I work over there.
- Which building?
Next to the black one.
So, I'll pick you up later. Bye.
Uh... beer.
Thank you.
Ahungu what?
Nein, I'm, I'm not understand.
Oh, no, es ist, it's good, it's good.
Hey! Where were you? Are you crazy?
I was so worried.
I thought I'd lost you for good.
Unbelievable!
The doorbells, I couldn't read them.
Who told you to go anywhere?
You can't read anything here.
I told you to stay put.
- I don't understand anything.
I told you to stay where you were.
Do you have any idea
how big this city is?
How easy it is to get lost?
Hi, Papa.
- Hello.
How was your day?
- So so.
Didn't you go out?
- No.
Know how my cell works?
Look,
here. Just one button.
I saw it. It has a picture of you.
- Right.
Look, that's my phone number.
Did you eat anything?
- Yes.
No, you didn't.
I don't understand where Trudi is.
Where her body is.
My memories of her are in my body,
but when my body's no longer here,
where will Trudi be then?
Papa... Papa,
I'm grieving for Mama, too...
but... really...
Don't tell me life goes on. Please.
Come on, now!
You know, this is Bavarian Style.
This is Bavarian Style.
Cherry blossoms... The most beautiful
symbol for impermanence...
They're only here for a few days.
And then they're gone.
That's it.
Papa, that's my Papa!
Nice, huh, Papa!
Kampai, kampai, kampai!
Don't treat me like a child!
It's bedtime.
This will be the first time
you've ever put me to bed.
You of all people! Hilarious!
How can anyone get so loaded?
Everyone always has to look after you.
- Come on now.
You always have to be
the center of attention.
Give me your arm!
Be considerate of your father!
Your poor father!
Leave your father alone! He's tired!
He works so hard!
Works his ass off in the office!
So, that's enough.
You spent your entire life
hiding in your office!
You never even really knew Mama!
You have no idea who she was!
No idea, you old fool, you.
Get out!
Go back to your garbage trucks,
that's where you belong.
And don't forget to recycle!
"An Apple a day, keeps a doctor away."
So... So.
So, I have to go.
Wait... Here.
Oh, Papa.
Stop. Your apple.
"An apple a day, keeps the doctor away."
...keeps the doctor away.
Bye.
So long.
What is this?
Metal.
Plastic. Plastic. Metal. Metal.
Paper. Paper.
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com