**
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Man: You've probably heard
lots of stories about Indians
riding the plains
in the old days
wearing next to nothing
and shooting off arrows.
But this story's about
nowaday Indians.
(Tires screech)
It happened a few years back.
I had retired as chief
but was still busy
setting a good example
on the res.
(Laughs)
How you doin', boy?
(Chuckles)
**
It was almost Christmas,
but it could have been
any time of year
as far as I was concerned,
because my focus was on someone
who lived thousands of Miles
away.
We had a penpal exchange
the year before
with our sister bingo
on the mohawk res,
and I'd picked a woman...
Christina little hawk...
She'd just been widowed,
poor thing,
and was down in the dumps.
But I found that sending her
two or three wildly flirtatious
letters each week did a lot
to cheer her up.
Soon, she was sending
just as many back to me,
with each one better
than the one before.
By then, she was also
dropping hints like crazy about
wanting to come and visit,
but I'd been stallin'.
Not that I'd stretched
the truth that much
with what I'd told her
about myself,
but she might be expecting
something a bit more impressive
at the airport than some
beat-up old apache.
And so, for the first time
in my life,
I was lusting after luxury.
Visions of heated leather
seats,
rear-window defoggers,
and cup holders...
These were the things that
were keeping me up at night.
But this story isn't
just about me.
No, my son Raymond is the big
success around here.
And he went off to one of them
big shot schools back east
and he got a big shot job
with some big shot company
and he married a big shot woman
too.
But then she ran off
with some other big shot.
So, ray came back here to be
the big shot general manager
of our tribe's new big shot
resort.
Which, if you ask me,
is really how things got
so discombobulated.
Because it wasn't just me
dropping my letter
from Christina on his floor
that day.
It was also ray getting that
letter from that other bunch
of big shots.
"Dear sir, this is"
to inform you that some time
between December 22nd
"and December 29th..."
December 29th.
"A representative from our"
organization will be staying
at the sky Mountain resort
so that we may review
your standards of service
and publish a rating for your
property in the new edition
of the worthington travel guide,
which is published
"every two years."
But that's like no warning.
Great, you know,
another cold winter morning.
Hide the women and children
and they're on their way.
Look, Phil,
I understand how you feel,
but you gotta understand, man,
it is very difficult
to get in this book.
Hoo-boy, you're not kidding.
We've been calling
and writing them letters
for almost two years now.
So, who's coming?
They don't tell you that.
Why not?
Because if we knew,
then we could... you know...
Put on the dog for them.
And Betty...
How's your staff?
Okay.
(Sighs)
Okay, well, good.
Time's a-wastin'.
Let's, uh... let's get to it.
No, I got one other place
to review.
Yeah, that Indian place.
No, no, no, the Indian,
like in teepee.
Yeah, well, they say Jane Fonda
stayed there all the time,
so I guess that gives them
at least one star.
Like in the commie flag.
(Chuckles) Yeah.
Yeah, the day after tomorrow.
Laguardia.
Oh, no, you fathead,
I got that bash at the ritz.
Yeah.
No, I... I gotta go to my house
in Denver,
then I'll leave the car there
first and I'll fly out.
No, I... I'm not gonna be able
to see my daughter this time.
I... yeah, I'll catch up with her
some other time.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, okay.
Oh! Oh, blow it out your ear!
(Chuckles)
What?
You want a tip?
Here.
Go call the hotline
for the half-witted
and report yourself.
Geez.
Tip, tip, tip, tip, tip.
Woman: "Dear Christina",
your letter came today.
It's been cold here, too,
and I've barely had any
time off,
but I did get away for a walk
in the mountains last week,
and as I stopped
to admire the view,
and searched for the right words
"to describe it to you..."
I became aware of a bird
circling overhead.
A hawk... not a big one,
a smaller one.
"A little hawk."
"Just like you."
He knows you're coming.
Hey.
What's with you, ma?
He knows she's coming.
Who?
Her penpal,
that clouds on fire man.
He saw a hawk circling.
A little hawk, like her.
I thought you returned
that ticket, Tina.
I tried, but it was
non-refundable.
Oh, that's just
what they say.
You just need a doctor's excuse.
No, it's okay.
I kinda wanna go anyway.
I thought you were
saving your money.
He's got a red shirt
and a little warrior animal
that protects him.
A little turtle.
No... a hamster.
He could be a total nutcase.
I don't think so.
Honey, he hasn't even
invited you.
Look, I'm gonna be using
my address from Manhattan
and dad's last name.
He's gonna think I'm Italian
and from New York.
He's not even gonna know
it's me.
Oh, yes, he will.
He's got the gift.
He'll think you're
throwing yourself at him.
No, he won't.
You don't even know
what he does for a living.
Oh, he's in charge
of something, that one.
(Chuckles)
And how do you know that?
He's got a laser.
Laser printer, grammy.
And he's probably got a wife
and four kids, too.
Well, then I'll find that
out.
I don't know why you wanna
go out there and make a fool
of yourself.
I'm not gonna make a fool
of myself.
Honey, men usually like
to do the chasing.
They're not all like Henry.
Henry was a good man.
Yeah, he was a good man,
but he should have carried
life insurance.
I'm sorry, grammy,
I gotta go.
I gotta get back to work.
Welcome.
Hi.
Ray...
(Scoffs)
(Whispers) Be sensitive.
(Inhales deeply)
Ray: He's already dead,
you know.
You're just...
Reorganizing the remains.
I'm perpetuating the cycle.
Earl, you're a chef.
Part of your job is cutting up
and cooking dead animals.
They have dreams, you know.
Just like us.
Yeah, I know, I know.
I do, but...
But, you know, that guide book,
if they show up,
and the menu's just vegetarian,
well...
You know, then we're gonna lose
all the skiers
and the fly fisherman.
I mean, all we're gonna
have left is the people
running around with their copies
of black elk speaks,
having, you know,
four or five visions
every couple of hours.
(Chuckles)
Come on, Earl,
you're the only chef we've got.
Look, I don't like this
any more than you do.
We could feed the planet
with all the grain
we feed the cattle.
And people are beginning
to realize that.
But you know what it's like?
It-it's like cappuccino, right?
And espresso.
I mean, they didn't catch on
overnight.
There was, uh... an education
process.
It's a consciousness thing,
Earl.
It just takes time.
And education.
So...
They're just way too thick.
Well, they're Lenin
table cloths.
They're supposed to be thick.
Well, I got two women
working on them night and day
and they're still full
of wrinkles.
Well, did you try wettin'
'em down?
Well, yeah.
How 'bout that stuff
you put in your hair?
(Laughs)
It's a joke.
No, seriously, put 'em
in the freezer.
My grandmother used to do that.
It works like a charm.
What about the kids...
the kids?
I heard that. What kids?
Well, all my girls
have kids, ray,
and school's on break...
no.
And the daycare's...
No. I'm sorry, no.
Oh, come on, ray.
We'll keep 'em outta the way.
You won't even see 'em.
Girls, look,
you know I love the kids.
I love 'em with all my heart,
but we cannot do this this week,
and I'm sorry.
Then who's gonna watch 'em?
I can't leave my two little ones
alone all day.
(Sighs)
Well, what about the seniors?
Are you kidding?
They have the Christmas bingo,
they have the bus trip
to the ice rink...
yeah, and they're all
booked up.
Come on, ray.
We'll keep 'em outside
most of the time.
Please?
All right, look...
I'll think about it, all right?
Here's your credit card back.
Thank you.
We have a Christmas Eve party
with Billy trees
and his big band.
Dancing?
Yes.
Excellent.
I would recommend
that you make reservations.
Would you do that for me?
Yes, I will.
Now, you're in room 140.
It's a standard suite
with a view of the mountains.
Lovely.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
(Rings bell)
Nicholas?
140, please.
Can you manage those?
Woman on phone: Sky Mountain
resort. May I help you?
I'll ring that room.
One moment please.
Oh, my God,
it is so beautiful.
It is amazing.
Thank you so much.
Oh, no, thank you.
Oh, my... oh, my.
(Groans)
Wonder if there's more
like him.
(Strains)
Let's go.
Okay.
Boy: Hey.
(Laughs)
Move that side down.
No, the other one.
Lindsay fortune
and Buffy love.
I smell a couple of ski bunnies.
Brian wescott from Fairbanks,
Alaska.
The vacuum cleaner salesman.
That's right.
I think you're doing
the right thing, Tina.
I think Joe clouds on fire
is a good man.
And don't worry about
looking foolish.
When I decided I wanted to be
with your grandfather,
I took the first step, too.
I made him a pair
of moccasins
and put them by his door.
He could've said no,
but that's the chance I took.
And you know he wore
those moccasins until
he wore them out.
(Laughs)
And, every night,
he thanked me
for the courage I had
to make them.
These are the beads
from those moccasins.
(Speaks native language)
Try to get some sleep
on the plane,
and will you call us
when you get there?
(Turns engine off)
**
Woman: Hey, ed, come on.
Boy: What did you make
for dinner?
(Gasps)
But, buffalo thunder,
what will everyone say?
I don't care, Vanessa.
All I want is you.
All that matters is that
we be together...
Forever.
Hey!
Nope, nope, nope, nope!
Give it!
Reading time. It's reading...
Patience.
It's reading time.
"He held her in his arms,"
the cold rain beating
relentlessly down upon
the teepee.
She tried to pull away.
'No, please, ' she whispered.
'We can't.'
but his eyes were piercing
through her,
and his desire was as hot and
plain as the fire beside them.
Vanessa knew it was no use.
Buffalo thunder would have
"his way... again."
No, no! No! No!
Gimme that!
You're not getting the book.
Hey.
Yep, uh-huh.
Yep. That'll work.
(Sighs)
(Children giggle)
Hey!
Hey, hey!
Hey, hey! Hey, no!
What are you doing?
Computer: You've got mail.
Ray: Am I crazy? Hmm?
Is this just some silly idea
that I've come up with?
Because if it is,
please, let's just forget
the whole thing and we can
save ourselves a lot of trouble.
Ray, the hanford's
in this stupid book.
It got two stars, ray.
Two stars.
Geez.
Yeah.
Yeah, the hanford.
I know all about the hanford,
Phil... the big hanford.
Who cares, okay?
You know what?
Let's take our cue
from the hanford.
Okay?
They wouldn't even let us
in there until a couple
of years ago.
And so what?
So they're big
and they're famous.
Who cares?
I mean, who owns these guys,
anyway?
Some multinational corporation?
Our people... our nation
built this place, okay?
We own it and we run it
and I am damn proud of that.
But you wanna know something?
There aren't a lot
of paying customers who even
know we exist, you know?
And I am sick and I am tired
of watching these tourists
just drive by here.
Now, we need this guide book,
like it or not.
And... I dunno.
I dunno, maybe you all think
it's a waste of time
to even try.
I don't know anymore.
But I'm gonna tell you
something.
If we try, if we really
put our hearts into it,
I think we can get four stars
in this thing,
and I think we can show
those idiots up at the hanford
that we know something!
Now, come on!
Who's with me on this?
I am!
Woman on phone: I'll ring
that room for you.
Please hold.
(Whispers)
Hey, ray.
When's that meetin'?
If we botch this job,
the chief is gonna transfer us
from the raiding body
to the skinning and tanning
pen.
I'm not so sure I wouldn't
like that better.
Never mind.
To capture that wagonload
of guns is gonna take
some real brainpower.
(Mouse squeaks)
If you need anything,
you know, just ask any
of the maids, you know...
maybe help to take care
of my kids sometime.
Yeah.
Yee-hee!
Oh... well...
It's down to this one guy.
Stuart O'Malley.
He checks in tomorrow.
Otherwise, that's it.
I mean, all we got are
family and groups this week.
Unless they're gonna chance it
without a reservation.
Yeah, you never know.
(Sighs)
Sorry about that thing
with Phil today.
I wasn't actually reading that
stupid old romance novel.
It was Betty.
She left it at my house,
so I was gonna bring it
back to her,
so naturally, I brought it...
Into work with me...
And I thought I'd give it to her
after I had my sex change
operation.
What do you think?
Yeah. Yeah, no,
that's a great idea.
(Sighs)
Ray.
We're gonna be just fine.
We're gonna be okay.
You gave a great speech,
and I think it's gonna snow.
Hey, a bunch of us
are gonna go bowling tonight
over in emerson.
You wanna come along?
Yeah, thanks, but, uh...
I got some work I can do
tonight,
and, uh... you know,
a big day tomorrow, so...
Some other time, all right?
Okay.
Hey, mar?
Hmm?
Maybe I can get
the tribal council to help you
out with that operation.
Devil.
**
News on TV: Our top story...
The winter of no snow.
It still looks like some other
time of the year out there,
so folks are starting to wonder
if they should trade in
their skis and snowboards
for Mountain bikes.
We haven't had a winter
this late since...
(clicks off)
Mary: Can you take a look
at these?
Sure.
Hey, mar, have you seen
my father yet today?
I think he might
be downstairs.
All right, thanks.
Do you have a reservation?
O'Malley.
Well, I'll have to check
that file.
Just a moment, please.
I'll check.
Yeah.
(Rings bell)
(Rings bell again)
(Rings bell several times)
(Loudly) Oh!
I don't think so.
Hey, look.
It's warrior mouse.
**
(squeaks)
Oh, no.
It got away.
Here, mousey, mousey, mousey.
Here. Here, mousey.
Boy: Aw, let him go.
You probably poisoned him anyway
by putting all that paint
on him.
Mary on phone: I'll ring
that room for you.
Please hold.
Thank you.
Hi, I have a reservation
under the name of Tina pisati.
Fred, uh, isn't it time
for your break?
Look at that.
What are you doin' here?
Get, get, get, get.
Hi.
Hi. Um, I have a reservation
under Tina pisati.
Pisati. P-i-z?
S... a-t-i.
Okay. Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
And you're from?
New York.
Really?
I'll just check for manual,
here.
Um, I made the reservation
about two weeks ago.
Yeah?
Are you here on, uh,
business, or, uh...
Just vacationing?
Um, I'm just vacationing.
Well... ooh!
Well, aren't you in luck.
We've just had a cancellation,
and the west Mountain suite
is available.
(Chuckles)
It sounds great,
but I'm on a bit of a limited
budget,
and I don't think I can
afford that.
Oh, it's no extra charge.
We do it all the time.
Oh. Oh, well, thank you.
You're welcome.
Ben.
Thank you very much.
Mm-hmm.
In here.
Ray!
It's a woman! It's a woman!
She's a woman!
The guide book...
They sent a woman.
Tina pisan?
Who wants this?
You did.
Tina pisati from New York.
(Sighs)
I asked her if she was here
on business.
She said no.
I know a professional
when I see one.
Ooh, and she's good.
How old is she?
I don't know.
Where'd you put her?
West Mountain suite.
Well, she's gonna know
we're on to her.
No, no, no. No.
It's okay, really.
I told her we just had
a cancellation.
I told her it was normal.
Oh... and I'm gonna ask Earl
to make at least two pasta
dishes. How 'bout that?
Why?
Oh, ray.
Tina pisati?
From New York?
Oh, my God.
What?
Quick, come on, come on,
come on. Come on!
What?
It's her.
Are you sure about this?
Bet you 20 bucks.
Dark hair. Nice coat.
Wow.
It's a woman.
(Phil chuckles)
I wonder if she skis.
No, Phil, she's not
a ski bunny.
Oh, come on, ray.
There's a little ski bunny in...
Well, almost every woman.
Hey, Louise.
Hey.
Gonna be ready to turn off
the hot water for about
ten minutes,
and I was wondering if there's
anybody in the rooms.
No, they're all out
and about.
(Scoffs) Dog.
Hot water.
(Chuckles)
We haven't had a winter
this late since 1945.
Meanwhile, the northeast part
of the country is digging out
from record high levels
of snow.
Airports and highways
are closed from Chicago
to Philadelphia.
In one day, a surprise storm
has dumped as much as
three feet of snow across
the eastern seaboard,
closing most major highways
and virtually every airport...
oh, no.
Between Boston
and Philadelphia.
Oh, no.
No, come on.
Oh, shoot.
And laguardia airports
are all closed.
Amtrak is even shutting down
rail operations...
oh!
Nothing is moving.
All of this has left thousands
of holiday travelers stranded.
Aah! Aah! Aaahh!
What happened to the hot water?!
There's no freakin' hot water!
Oh, goodness gracious!
I'm right in the middle
of the shower
and the water turned off!
You don't call this
hot water?
I don't appreciate people
yelling like that
around my daughter.
Do you have kids? Grandkids?
Do you yell at them like that?
You got a problem, mister.
A serious problem.
Mary: Tell her we get
about a third of our business
from overseas.
We'll get into the international
edition.
Just work it in.
It's 32%.
Look, she's not supposed
to know we know, okay?
Maybe I should talk to her.
No.
I'll handle this.
Mara: 32%!
Hi.
That's a lomahaftewa.
It's incredible.
Yeah, isn't it?
I'm ray clouds on fire.
I'm the general manager here.
You just check in?
Um... yeah.
Yeah, I did... I just checked in.
Well, hi.
Hi.
Welcome.
Thank you.
(Chuckles)
I'm Tina... pisati.
Oh. (Chuckles)
It's nice to meet you.
Nice meeting you.
So, where are you from?
New York.
Wow, you know, we're gettin'
a lot of people from
the east coast these days.
And, um... and Europe,
and Asia, too, as it turns out.
So, you're, uh...
You're an art lover.
Yeah. It's a passion of mine.
Yeah, me too.
This one's pretty, isn't it?
It's beautiful.
Actually, we have, uh...
We have a gallery down the hall,
there.
Oh, you know what?
Listen, I need to take care
of something,
but, uh, let me know if I can
do anything for you, okay?
Okay.
All right.
It was nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Enjoy your stay.
I will. Thanks.
TV: Environmental protection
was the order of the day in
emerson with a groundbreaking
ceremony in a new...
yeah, we're here to talk
about booze, I guess,
and, uh, I'm an expert,
let me tell you.
I was drinkin' about two quarts
a day when I started seeing
things...
Things that just weren't there,
like this one time,
I thought a family of chipmunks
was living with me, man.
I mean, it was crazy.
That's what the alcohol
was doing to me.
And I became friends with 'em.
I was puttin' out food,
I was puttin' out water.
Then they started wearing
clothes,
like little suits and dresses.
Halloween costumes.
I mean, these guys rocked,
you know?
And we'd be partying together
and drinkin' and stuff.
You know, they were mostly
into beer, but that was cool.
And, um, I mean,
it was fantastic, man.
But anyway, um, I knew
chipmunks never wore clothes,
so I had to be seeing things,
right?
But that's when I knew
I had to get help.
I had to stop drinking.
(Applause)
Yeah, and I know there's
a lot of you out there
who are in denial,
and you all know who you are,
man.
You know who you are.
I'm not gonna mention
any names, you know,
but you know who you are, man,
so you should all clean
yourselves up, man.
Take my advice, all right?
Well, maybe his name is Joe.
Yeah, but it's not like
anybody calls me Christina.
No, it wasn't red.
It was a blue shirt.
Yeah, but he actually...
Yeah?
No, but he had my letter
in his pocket.
He was a code writer
in world war ii.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Transcribed all the messages
into our language.
The enemy couldn't break
the code.
Oh.
Hello.
I don't mean to stop you,
I'm just admiring how fast
you type.
It's wonderful.
And you speak your own language,
too, I hear.
(Sighs) Yeah.
I hear okay, too.
My name's mabel,
and I'd love to learn
a few native words.
How do you say hello?
(Stops typing)
(Sighs)
(Speaks native language)
And how do you say thank you?
(Clears throat)
Excuse me.
Could you say that again...
Slowly?
(Chuckles)
Yeah.
Three nights of freezing,
and the snow will stick.
I've used this machinery before.
Yes, I have.
No, this is used machinery,
and this price is ridiculous.
I have the invoice
right in front of me.
'Scuse me.
'Scuse me just for a second.
What are you doing?
I need the wrench.
What wrench, dad?
There is no wrench in there.
Yeah, there's a wrench
in there.
No, there's not.
Ah!
(Chuckles)
I'll... I'll call you back.
You ever gonna spring
for postage there, Romeo?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, no, no, no...
It's... it's complimentary.
But even normally,
the package includes everything.
There's no extra charge.
That's incredible.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
You'll have a great time.
Uh, listen, Mary,
I need you to... oh, hi.
Hi.
How are you?
I'm great. How are you?
I'm fine,
thank you very much.
Oh. Mary, I...
I'm sorry, I was looking
for the, uh...
Mary: Dobson.
Exactly.
I'm still adding it up.
I'll get it.
Okay. Thank you.
So, are you, uh...
Are you settling in nicely?
Yes, thank you.
I was just being briefed
on the activities
that you have here.
Well, there's a lot to do.
It's a fun place.
Mary: I still need this,
though.
Oh, okay.
Thanks very much.
Mm-hmm.
Well, listen.
I hope you're enjoying yourself.
Thanks.
And you let me know if I can
do anything at all for you.
I will. Thanks.
All right.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you.
Can I borrow a pen?
All right.
Give her some gas.
(Engine sputters)
(Coughs)
That's the last damn time
I ever buy an apache!
Oh, come on, Joe,
what do you want?
It lasted 30 years.
Or that cherokee!
Oh, don't get me started
with that stupid bingo,
giving away a cherokee.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
What happened?
Oh, clouds on fire's
old truck's... on fire.
(Explosion)
So, uh... how was shopping?
It was great.
How was your day?
Eh, you know.
Can't complain.
(Speaks native language)
Oh, yeah.
Thank you for sharing.
(Explosion)
(Chuckles)
So, uh, what nation are you?
I'm a mix.
Blackfoot, salish,
ute, and cree.
Sounds like a law firm.
What's your name, little girl?
**
I'm just dropping off
some information.
Uh, sure.
Hi.
Thanks, I'd love to.
Oh.
Oh, great.
So, what do you recommend?
You know, the Turkey
is always good.
This Turkey is so good.
Is it range-grown?
Old Edgar here?
No, no.
He was a pet.
Or, you know what?
You could try the buffalo.
You know, it's kind of
a local favorite.
I think it's best probably
served like, uh, medium...
Medium-rare... "mmr" kind of...
That's the way we put it down
on our tickets, at least,
you know, kind of a short...
Short version.
This particular buffalo
had an onscreen performance
in the movie dances with wolves.
I don't think he ever
got over it,
'cause he used to take pictures
with the tourists,
and let the little kids
ride him.
We called him... Kevin.
(Sniffs)
Actually, you know what?
The rabbit is actually excellent
as well.
I mean, really tender.
I think you'd like that.
This little bunny wasn't a pet.
He grew up in the wild.
I imagine he was quite tame.
It's usually the friendly ones
that get hunted down first.
No, I don't want it.
Thank you.
I don't want it.
(Laughs)
So, when the animal has
completely bled to death,
we rip the flesh from its bones
and marinate it
in a herb seasoning.
Then it's roasted
in our special ovens.
Excuse me just for one
moment.
Sorry.
You all right, sir?
(Vomits)
Hey, where you been?
I thought we said 7:30.
We did?
Ray, you gotta practice
a little if you're gonna
win anything at all.
Oh, man, dad, I'm sorry.
I totally forgot.
It's okay.
I got it all set up.
Listen, I'll call it,
and we'll see how many cards
you can play at once.
No, no... what I mean is,
I'm having dinner downstairs,
and, uh, it's business...
well, when's it over?
Well, I don't know, exactly.
Look, it doesn't matter.
I'm not any good at bingo
anyway.
Listen, you just gotta
practice a little.
Ray, there are families of ten
playin' for that jeep,
and each of 'em is playing
ten or more cards at a time.
Well, we can't compete
with that.
Look, if you want a new truck,
we'll get you one, okay?
I want this one.
Man, I gotta get some
new clothes.
God...
I'm so sorry.
I'm really embarrassed.
Took a lot longer
than I thought it would, and...
you changed your shirt.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I did.
It's red.
Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
How was your dinner?
Oh, it was great, thank you.
Earl, this is Tina.
Au chaunte.
Oh, you didn't have the Turkey,
did you?
No, it was the eggplant.
I'm... a vegetarian.
Oh...
Earl, um, don't you have
a soufflé in the oven
or something?
Oh, yes, I do.
You know,
before he came back,
he actually studied in France
for a couple of years.
Oh, did he?
Yeah.
Well, it was an incredible
meal.
Thank you.
Really? You liked it?
Really. Really.
I'd give it five stars.
Really?
Wow.
Puts out a lot of heat,
doesn't it?
Yeah, that's about 35,000 btus
you're lookin' at, there.
We're pretty proud of it.
We just had it replaced
back in June, so, uh...
It must be really difficult
for you when there's not
a lot of snow here.
Yeah, well...
You know, technically,
it's the lightest amount of
recorded snowfall by this time
in about 55 years, but, uh,
what are you gonna do?
That's life, right?
Yeah.
Hey, thanks for dinner.
I had a really good time.
So did I.
I appreciate you joining me.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Have a good night.
Thanks.
Ray?
Yeah?
So... what do people do
around here on weekends?
Weekends, weekends...
Well, um, I work... normally.
Every weekend?
Yeah. Yeah, pretty much.
Exciting life, huh?
Hmm.
Why?
You have something in mind?
92 degrees year-round.
What do you think?
It's lovely.
(Chuckles)
So... what exactly do you do
in New York?
What do you mean, "do"?
You know, for a living.
Oh, God, don't ask me that.
Why not?
Because I hate my job.
Oh, come on,
it can't be that bad.
It is.
(Laughs)
It most certainly is.
I just took it because it was
the only job I could find
and I really needed one.
But it has absolutely nothing
to do with what I really
want to do.
What do you really
want to do?
I wanna teach.
Really?
Yeah.
I did some subbing last winter.
I try to do it as often
as I can, but...
It's kinda hard to call in sick.
But I decided that I was gonna
go back to school and get
my teaching credential.
You know, my mom
was a teacher.
She, uh... she loved it, too.
She really did.
She taught third grade.
Is she retired?
No.
No, actually, uh,
she passed away a while ago.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Christina: I'm serious.
Ray: You are powerless
against me.
I'm telling you right now, okay?
I really can't.
Try it. Try it.
I can't.
Here it comes.
Into the... ah, psyche.
(Chuckles)
My grandfather was legendary
among our people as being
a great hunter and tracker.
He was called
standing elk shadow
because he crept up so close
to an elk once
he was inside its shadow before
it even knew he was there.
But, uh, one winter,
everyone got sick,
and he had to go off alone
and hunt.
And he was gone for a really
long time.
In fact, everyone thought
that he was dead,
and, you know, that they would
die too because he had been
their only hope.
But, one night, when the sky
was lit up kind of like
it is tonight...
He came back.
He came back with an enormous
bear that he had killed.
And everyone ate and they
got well again.
So, after that, he was called
the man who came back
with the bear
when the clouds were on fire.
That's a great story.
Thanks.
I haven't told it in a while.
So, you're the one
from Greenland, huh?
Yes, I am.
Your aunt's Ruth hepaburtz.
Mm-hmm.
She and my mom
are really good friends.
Good.
Bunny.
Come here.
Uh-oh.
You're a good artist.
Well, thank you.
Is there poison in paint?
That depends on the paint.
You didn't eat paint, did you?
No.
Did somebody else?
Good.
What's your name?
Katie.
Hello. I'm mabel.
Hello, mabel.
Do you like to paint, Katie?
I'm not very good at it.
Well, neither am I,
but you can't let that stop you.
Would you like to have a go?
Yes.
Look...
Here's a nice, clean piece
of paper.
And there we've got
some nice brushes.
You choose one.
(Phone beeps, dial tone)
(Dialing)
(Phone rings)
Hello?
**
(crying softly)
(Birds chirping)
I can always tell
when a big storm is comin'.
I get real sleepy
before it hits.
That day was no exception.
This was the big night.
That cherokee would be won
by somebody, and I'd
seen myself driving it.
But the same event
that made my getting there
more crucial had also
made my getting there
more difficult.
I had no wheels.
And by the time I woke up,
I had missed my ride
to the bingo.
It's snowing, it's snowing!
It's here, it's here!
It's here!
Yes! Thank you. It's here.
**
The big shot
was totally preoccupied.
Mary had just bought
a new used car
and didn't want it driven
in the weather.
And, Phil, he was working up
to another big date
with the ski bunnies.
**
So, things were looking
kind of grim...
(Door closes)
Until I caught sight
of stu O'Malley.
Now, after the night before,
he'd been nicknamed
"spew O'Malley."
(Laughs)
But I'd seen the guy arrive,
and I knew he was driving
a big ol' buick
with some pretty good
snow tires on it.
I made my move.
(Exhales)
People who drink
often enjoy gambling,
as well.
I told him
it was high stakes.
I didn't tell him
it was bingo.
(People chattering)
Woman: Ante up.
(Chattering continues)
Listen, you sit over here,
and they'll tell ya what to do.
Okay? I'll be right back.
Woman: Ante up.
(Chattering continues)
All right.
Okay, can I have
your attention?
Thank you.
How're you all doing?
Tonight we have a special treat.
He's visiting relatives
not far from here,
and he's kindly agreed
to join us.
Calling our holiday bingo,
we have the one,
the only, wes studi!
(Crowd cheers, applauds)
(Crowd roars, whistles)
(Chanting)
It's great to be here!
On my way here, you know,
I had to stop at a couple
of places, and everybody
wants to know what it is
about my outfit here.
(Man laughs)
It's simple...
My wife dresses me.
(All laugh)
Any of you guys
have that problem?
No? In my case,
it's a little bit
more complicated,
because my wife is Scottish.
(All laugh)
But, in any case,
I think maybe we ought
to play some bingo.
Are you guys any good
at bingo?
(All cheer)
Yeah? Well, then
let's play some bingo!
Shake those balls!
I'll see you later, spike.
Whoo! Whoo!
(Woman whistles)
And...
The first number is...
N37!
The second winning number is...
N39!
(Exhales)
Why don't I call room service
and ask them to
send some tea up?
Great.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
Um... yeah, yeah.
Um... but there's something
I have to tell you.
Okay.
(Sighs softly)
Look, I'm really sorry, but...
But I... I know who you are.
You do?
(Chuckles)
Why would you be sorry?
Well... I mean,
I... I wasn't supposed to know
who you were, right?
Right, yeah.
I was gonna keep it
a secret from you
for about another ten seconds.
(Both chuckle)
What, you mean
you were gonna tell me?
Of course!
That is strange, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
I really...
Really wasn't expecting
anything like this to happen.
You know?
Yeah, me neither.
I mean...
I guess I just didn't know...
What I was supposed to think.
You wanna know what I think?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's lookin'
pretty bad here, too.
Okay.
Okay, I understand.
Will be g52!
G52!
(People chattering)
And the next one is...
I'm sorry, people.
That storm's gettin'
really bad out there.
I'm afraid of the roads closing.
This is it.
This is for the cherokee!
Are we ready...
To play for the cherokee?
Yes?
And now the first number is...
N42! N42!
And now we have...
B04!
G50!
Like I keep telling
my sister-in-law,
"gee, you don't look 50!"
And your next
big number is...
G55!
B? What?
Now we have o69!
I18!
Man: Bingo!
All: Aw!
We have a bingo over here!
We have a bingo over here.
Let's verify the card.
(People cheer, applaud)
**
(people cheering loudly)
Golly, I never
even played before!
(Cheering continues)
(Chuckles)
(All laugh)
(All applauding)
(Camera shutter clicks)
(Engine starts up)
You ever win anything,
I mean, big like this?
No.
But I only had one more to go
on at least ten of those cards.
Yeah, me neither.
I never won a damn thing
before.
(Laughing)
High stakes.
(Continues laughing)
You really had me going
on that one.
What?
You mad at me?
For winning?
Huh! Gee.
Talk about a poor sport.
Yeah, well, just take
the next left up there.
It's a shortcut.
**
(inhales)
So how long can you stay?
I have to leave on Sunday.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
That's way too soon.
Don't you have some
vacation time coming
or something like that?
Mm-mm, no.
I don't think
I can change my ticket.
Why not?
It's a supersaver.
(Chuckles)
Oh, really...
Of course, I don't know.
It looks like
I may be snowed in.
Oh... you're...
You're definitely snowed in.
(Chuckles)
You are very,
very snowed in.
**
(sighs loudly)
(snoring softly)
What?
Hi.
Oh...
Hey, there.
How are you?
I'm good now.
(Both chuckle)
(Knock on door)
That must be breakfast.
Oh!
(Yawning) Great.
I'm starving.
(Gasps)
No, don't open the door!
Don't open...
what are you doing?
Just don't open it.
Hold on one sec.
Okay, open the door.
Open it.
Hi.
Thank you.
Thanks very much.
Uh, so, uh, what did she do,
go home for the holidays?
Who?
Your girlfriend.
What girlfriend?
What was all this, uh,
hoopty-doo for?
You don't want anyone
to know you were here
last night.
Well, no, I don't.
I mean, really, Tina,
I... I think we should at least
try and keep this separate,
don't you?
What do you mean, separate?
Well, I mean,
you know, otherwise,
it'll look like this
influenced you.
Look...
I've worked really hard
on this, and I...
I think that what we have here
is very special.
Well, so do I.
Well, good.
So, uh, you know, just,
uh, make your assessments
based on all the other things,
and, uh...
And don't be influenced
by this, okay?
By what?
By this!
By last night!
(Quietly) I can't...
Made it alive.
You do have a girlfriend.
No.
No, I don't.
Then why can't this
influence me?
I mean, come on, Tina.
Would it normally?
Well...
(Chuckles)
God, ray, come on.
This isn't the 19th century.
Yeah, I do think chemistry
should count for something.
Well, yeah, so do I,
but, you know, in this case...
What... what is this?
Is this like
a regular thing for you?
Well, no, but...
but it's happened before?
Huh?
It has... hasn't it?
What is this?
I don't know.
Maybe you should tell me.
Ray, it's not like
it's gonna count against you.
But that's just the point.
I mean, it shouldn't
count at all.
What?
Look, I think the standards
that I've set here should speak
for themselves.
What standards?
(Fumbles for words)
This is a first-class resort.
Yeah, so?
So?
Look, I just want you
to be objective.
That's all I'm saying, geez.
(Sighs)
Why?
Think about my staff here
for a second, okay?
All right? Now think...
Think about their morale.
Your staff?
Yeah. (Sighs)
Look, they know
who you are, okay?
You told your staff
about me?
Well, Mary
figured it out first.
Who's Mary?
Oh... I'm sorry.
She's the woman
at the front desk.
Oh.
Well, how'd she know who I was?
Well, you said you were
from New York and all,
so she just put two and two
together, and...
(Chuckles)
Look, she's my assistant.
She's really helpful to me.
Well, how very nice
for ya.
What'd she do, help you
write the letters, too?
Yeah, yeah,
she wrote some of 'em.
What?
(Sighs)
Look, she handles all
of my correspondence.
Besides, it's...
It's good for training.
For what?
Oh, I don't know.
Um... marketing?
Tina, I can't do everything
around here, okay?
I mean, I have to
delegate some things.
(Scoffs)
Ow!
(Phone ringing)
Your dad's missin'.
He never made it home
from the bingo last night.
**
(snoring)
(Mumbling)
(Groans loudly)
(Snoring continues)
Get off me!
Get off me, God dammit!
Oh! What...
What's on my leg?
On my leg hair...
On the hair! Oh...
I put a splint on it.
You broke it.
(Sighs)
Shh. Shh.
Where are we?
Oh, now you got to
the really good news, huh.
**
(officer sighs)
Well, he hasn't seen him,
but we're gonna keep lookin'.
**
Officer: He's fine, ray.
They're just snowed in
somewhere.
God, I can't believe
he treated you like that.
What a jerk.
Yeah, and I thought he was
writing business letters.
Yeah.
He really has a problem.
He doesn't trust women.
Who could blame him after
what happened with his wife?
Oh, yeah...
What happened with his wife?
Well, she cheated on him,
and he caught her red-handed.
Ugh...
Yeah, you don't know that.
Oh, come on!
Everybody knows that.
Well, something happened.
Yeah, something bad.
He's never dated anyone
ever since,
till you came around.
Yeah, not even that model
last summer.
Oh, yeah!
I forgot about her.
I mean, she was really pretty.
(Sobs)
**
Oh, my God. Dad!
Dad!
They're not in here!
Okay, ray,
this is a good sign.
This means they're well enough
to go get help.
Dad!
("Dad" echoes)
**
You got any kids?
Yeah... one.
How about you?
Yeah, same here.
A daughter.
Any grandkids?
Two.
I never met 'em yet.
Why not?
Oh... my daughter
married an idiot.
Seems happy enough with him.
Oh, I... I don't know.
So, she has two kids, huh?
Yeah, two boys.
(Chuckles)
I saw 'em the other day,
running around.
They're pretty cute.
You saw 'em the other day?
You know, I was thinking,
my daughter went
to an Indian camp
when she was a kid,
in the summer.
"Eagle's nest."
On lake Michigan.
She won a big award one summer.
They gave her a blue feather.
It was quite an honor.
And only one kid got it
every summer.
(Chuckles)
Probably sounds like
a bunch of bullshit to you.
(Sighs)
My son went to camp wakaneeka
at lake Paul.
He won the white feather.
It was a pretty big deal, too.
(Chuckles)
Listen, Katie, I know mice.
If he didn't like that feather,
he'd have found a way
to get rid of it.
And that glue
was not poisonous.
Your warrior mouse is just fine.
Excuse me!
Have you seen a mouse
that looks just like this,
but it's alive?
No, I haven't.
Did you lose your mouse?
He's probably in a little
mouse house somewhere,
all snuggled in for the night.
Oh, I'm sure he's
having a little adventure.
Mice are very adventurous.
Why do you look so sad?
It's Christmas Eve!
We're not gonna get
anything this year.
There's a big party
in the hotel tonight.
There's gonna be lots of candy
and cookies and hot chocolate.
Would you like to come with me?
Mmm?
We'll find you something
pretty to wear.
Okay.
It's a deal.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
Ray...
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
No. No.
Ray, I need to talk...
look, I said no.
I'm dealing with something
that's just a little bit
more important right now, okay?
All right.
(Group sings silent night
(in native language)
(Singing continues)
(All applauding)
(Both chuckle)
(Applause continues)
(Squeaking)
(Squeaking continues)
(Chuckles)
Hey, there.
(Bird calls)
(Engine starts up)
(Engine roars)
Boy: Whoa!
Girl: Cool!
Woman: Oh, look at that.
Boy: Whoa!
Chelsea, have you seen this?
Question... how does it work?
What did you get?
Woman: Oh, look at that.
Boy: That's my bow!
(All chattering)
What is that?
All right, you guys
ready for your gifts?
Kids: Yeah!
I don't hear you.
Yeah!
All right.
Go ahead, get 'em!
Make sure your name's on it.
Will you help Joe
get his gift, please?
Come on.
(All chattering)
Dexter, yours is over there.
(Group singing silent night
(in native language)
(Chattering continues)
(Singing continues)
(Mouse squeaking)
(Sniffs)
(Sighs)
(Bird calls)
What's that?
You got something to eat?
No.
We're running out of wood,
aren't we.
Yup.
Well, what happens
when it's gone?
I don't know.
You turn into a whiskey pop?
(Laughs)
They're not gonna find us,
are they.
(Coughs)
Oh, we'll be okay.
I'm gonna hike out of here
in a little while.
Why don't you do it now?
Because it's better
to stay warm as long
as you can, cowboy.
You always wait a little while
until they come to you.
Gee, thanks
for the safety tip.
Well, why didn't we
stay with the vehicle?
Isn't that what
you're supposed to do?
We did...
Till it ran out of gas.
They only put in
a couple gallons, you know.
You're still mad
that I won it, aren't ya?
No.
I was really tickled pink.
We all were.
The way you charmed us
to pieces with your
sparkling personality there.
(Splint clanks)
(Groans)
(Laughs) Oh, sorry.
**
(engine roaring)
Where you going?
I-it's okay. You just get
a little more rest, huh.
No. That's how you die...
You freeze to death.
No, you're gonna be okay.
How do you know?
Because I'm gonna go get
some help.
I'm gonna go see if
I can find that hawk.
Wh-what hawk?
You just rest.
You'll be fine.
No, no, wait! J-just...
Just listen a minute, okay?
I... I want you to do
something for me.
I mean, if...
If help doesn't come
in time... I...
Look...
You're gonna be fine.
You know, I think
you're gonna be fine.
But, you know, if you have
some kind of fit a- and die
before I get back, well,
then I... I promise I'll tell
your daughter that you
loved her, and the kids, too,
and, uh, that your last regret
was that you didn't
go on in there and visit them
the other day, okay?
Are you makin' fun of me?
No, no.
But that's just exactly
what I'll tell her.
And if something unexpected
happens to me, then I
want you to tell my son
that I, uh... I'm real sorry
that I never got to meet
my grandkids, okay?
I thought you
didn't have any.
I don't.
**
(walela sings the warrior)
* oh, I've been searching
* for my warrior
* I've been walking
* down tracks of time
* it's such a struggle
* to seek forgiveness
* like chains and shackles
* these ghosts of mine
* oh, oh, oh
* crossing over heaven's sea
* where my warrior
* is waiting for me
* crossing over heaven's sea
* where my warrior
* is waiting for me
* LA, LA, LA, LA
* LA, LA, LA, LA, LA, LA
* feels like I'm dancing...
God!
* truth and wisdom
* precious rhythm...
Dad.
Yeah. You okay?
(Sighs)
Can you help me up?
Yeah, uh-huh.
* my heart is humble
* oh, warrior, show me...
(Both breathing heavily)
Woman: I see somebody.
(Groaning)
Are you a doctor?
Well, yes. I only practice
part-time these days.
Oh. Well, he's...
He's been in and out.
It's really been bad.
Um, I... I kept him hydrated,
and I kept the leg still.
You did a really good job.
Mr. O'Malley,
can I call anyone for you?
Any family nearby?
Any friends?
No, just get me
to the hospital!
M- my insurance stuff
is in my pocket.
(Groaning)
(Mumbles)
Really?
Leave it with me.
Psst. You should talk
to this guy sometime.
He's with some kind
of a travel agency.
"A worthington guide"?
(Sighs)
What?
You have to do it again.
Oh, please?
Please, just one more time?
(Sighs)
Okay, but this is it.
(In a deep voice)
It's a good day...
(chuckles)
It's a good day to dine.
(Both laugh, applaud)
I see you had
the tofu tackle.
Lovely choice.
And may I recommend for dessert
the pine nut pancake with papaya
and apricot sorbet.
(Chattering)
Uh, may I recommend
the tahini tamale
or the zucchini cannelloni
or... the Swiss chard lasagna.
Mmm.
Phil, have you seen Tina?
Joe!
Hi, Phil. Hi.
Hey, Joe.
We've been worried about you.
Hi. I'm okay, I'm okay.
Mary, have you seen Tina?
Where were you? Huh?
Come here.
Oh, it's a long story.
Listen, have you seen Tina?
Why, you wanna break
her heart again?
(Chuckling) Gee.
(Vacuum hums)
Betty, have you seen Tina?
No.
Hey!
That's one of my letters!
She's your penpal?
The guidebook woman?
She's with that
guidebook, too?
Tina! Tina, listen.
No, wait, really. Listen.
There's been a really,
really big mix-up.
I thought... I thought
that you were somebody else
and that you were here
on business.
It doesn't matter.
Look, the point is...
The point is that...
That I didn't write these.
I didn't.
Then who did?
(Pants)
Christina?
Joe?
(Chuckles)
I thought you were
a little older.
a little younger.
It's nice to meet you
anyway.
(Sighs)
(Laughs)
Uh, would you like
a cup of cocoa?
Yeah.
Yeah? Come on.
Listen...
W-wait... wait a second.
**
Daddy?
Hi!
Oh, it's good to see you.
Oh...
You, too.
I'm glad you had
that old chief call me.
Oh, yeah.
He's a good man.
I have missed you.
Me, too. Me, too.
**
Huh. Your dad
sure can pick 'em, huh?
(Chuckles)
Strange, though.
When he used to talk about her,
I always pictured
this wrinkled old lady.
I guess that's because
she was a widow.
Mm-hmm.
Want a chip?
(Chuckles)
I got work to do.
(Tina laughs)
**
Why don't you just
write her another one
of those love letters?
Why don't you
just go back to work?
(Chuckles)
(Bell dings)
(Conversing quietly)
Hey, what is this?
Here. It's yours,
for saving my life.
Uh...
(Attempts to speak
(native language)
(Chuckles)
(Sighs)
Thank you.
(Phone rings in distance)
(Bell dings)
Mary: Oh, no,
she's leaving.
(Whispering)
**
(clears throat)
"The pain from his wound"
was enormous.
And the dust from the plains
had kicked up
to sting his face
and obscure all vision.
But buffalo thunder
rode like the wind
after that wagon train.
And soon the pounding
of his horse's hooves
became the beating of.
Vanessa's heart,
willing him closer
and closer.
And all her denials were
"but the dust in his eyes."
(Sniffles)
(Scoffs)
What is this?
The Indian chapter of
the romance book club?
Look, I'm busy here, okay?
I got things to do.
And it's not really
any of your business,
all right?
(Sighs)
Just one of those things.
(Sniffles)
She wants to forget about it...
So do I.
Look, I don't even
have a car, okay?
(Keys jingling)
And so he chased her
to the airport.
And though he racked
his brain and he searched
his soul the whole way there,
ray still didn't know what
he'd say when he saw her...
Or how she'd react
when she saw him.
But as it turned out,
he didn't have to have
any kind of speech
rehearsed at all.
**
Because ray was still
searching for a space
in that parking lot
when her flight took off.
(Airplane engine hums)
And so it was not until
28 letters and 79 phone calls
and 94 e-mails that
passed between them
that Tina finally came back.
**
Of course, stu O'Malley
only gave us three stars
in that dumb guidebook,
which I suspect is more
to keep the prices down
and the tourists away,
because so far,
he's been back here
four times with his family.
**
So, anyway,
that's the story.
That's how I met mabel.
**
(Keith secola sings.
(Indian cars)
* I've been driving
* in my Indian car
* the pound of the wheel
* drumming in my brain
* my dash is dusty
* my plates are expired
* please, Mr. officer
* let me explain
* I've got to make it
* to this pow wow tonight
* singing 49
* down by the riverside
* lookin' for a sugar
* riding in my Indian car
**
* got my t-bird
* on the dashboard
* ain't got no spare
* feather from an eagle
* ain't got no cares
* the road is empty
* in my bottle of desire
* daylight is breaking
* the sun touches fire
* I got to make it
* to this pow wow tonight
* singing 49
* down by the riverside
* lookin' for a sugar
* riding in my Indian car
**
* my car is dented
* the radiator steams
* one headlight don't work
* the radio can scream
* I got a sticker
* that says "Indian power"
* I stuck it on my bumper
* it holds my car together
* we're on a circuit
* of an Indian dream
* we don't get old
* we just get younger
* when we're flying down
* the highway
* riding in our Indian car
**
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/8gema
Help other users to choose the best subtitles