Music's weird.
It calms me down.
You're smoking meth,
and you want to calm down?
I'll be right back.
Got to go do something.
Yes?
Drive! Drive!
Look out, look out, look out!
Crap! My mom's
gonna kill me.
Dude, what did you just do?
I took a leak.
Oh, sweet!
♪ I'm gonna take you
on a trip ♪
♪ Follow me... ♪
Honey?
Hey, hon?
ANNABETH:
Who discovered the bodies?
DRUMMER:
James Prichard.
Came home
from a business trip
to find his wife
and mother-in-law shot dead,
point-blank range.
Ballistics matched .380 caliber,
probably a pistol.
STEVE:
Cheap, concealable, quiet.
Yeah. They were killed
in the living room.
TV was still on.
What are you thinking--
home invasion, robbery, drugs?
DRUMMER:
Well, they're
all on the menu,
but never can tell.
Leads on the shooter?
Uh, there's
one unidentified
fingerprint on the wife's
wedding ring
and a few others
we're still working on.
And the husband was where
when this happened?
Away on business, Chicago.
How long?
Just one night.
He's in financial services.
Any chance
the husband might have...
Hired somebody to kill his wife
and mother-in-law
while he was
conveniently
out of town
with an iron-clad alibi?
I was gonna ask
if you had any thoughts
on who the shooter might be.
No. This guy is in shock.
Um, let's see. Mr. Prichard
checked out of his hotel
11:15 a.m.
on Wednesday.
Flew back to Indianapolis
that afternoon.
M.E. thinks
the shootings went down
Tuesday night.
MAUREEN:
What a horror show, coming home
and finding your family killed
for no reason.
Do me a favor.
Let's keep the press
at bay on this.
We don't need a media circus
until we have somebody
in custody.
And Annabeth?
Get ready to catch this one
when it lands.
WOMAN:
I remember hearing a car racing
down the street,
but I had no idea
it hit my car.
Anyway, before bed,
I let the pupper out,
and that's when I
noticed this mess.
What's strange, I
didn't hear the shots,
but I heard a car.
Yeah, well,
shots were fired indoors.
It came
from a small caliber weapon.
It's quieter than you think.
When did you hear the vehicle
racing down the street?
I was watching one of my shows.
Maybe 8:00, 9:00 p.m.
So, how well were you acquainted
with the Prichards?
MAN:
She was a very
kind lady.
It's just so terrible.
It really just makes you scared.
You think things like this
won't happen
in your own backyard.
Well, did you hear anything,
see anything?
When I got up in the morning,
I noticed
all their lights were still on.
I-I thought it was odd,
but I thought
they just forgot.
WOMAN:
This mirror is
from the right side
of a 1995 Chevy Tahoe.
And from the
paint scrapings,
this particular SUV
is dark blue metallic.
Thanks.
Check body shops,
uh, local insurance agents.
We're looking for a 1995
dark blue Chevy Tahoe,
a scrape on the right side,
missing the passenger-side
mirror.
WOMAN:
I'm so surprised the police
are investigating this.
We just called our insurance guy
yesterday.
Can you tell me what happened?
My son Charles went
to marching band practice,
and somebody banged it up
in the high school parking lot.
May  I speak with Charles?
Sure. Come on in.
Lately, he's been practicing
a couple of hours a day.
Chuckie?
Chuckie, what on earth
are you doing?
What...?
Chuckie, get back
in here!
Chuckie!
Get off of me.
This is Detective Drummer.
I need a black and white sent
to 338 Rosewood Avenue.
I'm very sorry
for what happened Tuesday night.
I didn't know anything
about the murder beforehand.
I thought we were just out
smoking meth.
We? Who's we?
Chuckie wants
to fully cooperate.
He feels genuine remorse.
He's confessed
to being there.
He  admits to doing drugs,
and he's perfectly willing
to tell you the name
of the other guy.
The guy with the gun.
I'm waiting.
We're looking for probation.
Right now,
you're our prime suspect.
You've admitted to
fleeing the scene of
a double homicide.
You're old enough
to be tried as an adult.
But I didn't kill anybody.
I didn't even go in the house.
You have any idea why
your friend shot two women
in cold blood?
He's not my friend.
Then what was he doing
in your car?
He was my dealer.
We were driving around
getting high.
He-He just told me to pull over.
I stayed in the car
the whole time.
I had no idea
what was gonna happen.
Then I heard the shots,
and I drove him away,
but that's-that's all I did.
You drove a getaway car
in a murder.
That makes you just as culpable
as the person
who allegedly committed
the crime.
If he knew a crime was being
committed, which he did not.
ANNABETH:
He just told
me he heard the shots.
At the very least that's aiding
and abetting.
MAN:
Listen, this
is all about
who the other guy is,
and you're not gonna get to him
without making a deal.
WOMAN:
My son has a
drug problem,
but he didn't
rob  anybody,
and he certainly isn't a killer.
He goes to church.
He plays in the marching band.
We're not the kind of people
who do things like this.
He's a scared kid
who made a mistake.
He fled the scene.
He drove the getaway car.
He's doing time.
MAN:
How much time?
ANNABETH:
One year in prison,
five years
felony probation,
mandatory drug rehab.
I want a guarantee.
Two women are dead.
So I'll tell you what.
If he's lying,
if he doesn't lead us
to the killer,
if his testimony
falls apart,
he's doing 12 years, guaranteed.
Does TJ deal meth out
of the apartment?
I don't know.
I always just
called him up.
There he is.
That's him.
That's TJ, the guy.
DRUMMER:
TJ?
Yeah?
Detective Drummer.
WOMAN:
TJ!
Is he armed?
What do you...
what do you mean?
Does he have a gun?
He used to. I don't...
I don't know.
Stay there.
ANNABETH:
Chuckie led us to the shooter
who had stolen goods
in his possession
which he'd taken from the home
of Julie Prichard, one
of the two women he murdered.
So, this Chuckie
will testify
that he saw TJ go
into the house,
that he heard shots
fired, and that
TJ ran from the house
with stolen property?
Exactly.
Chuckie's passed
a lie detector test.
I think he's for real.
He's-He's a 16-year-old kid.
He got in over his head.
And TJ?
TJ's 20.
Is there any
other evidence
to tie this TJ
character directly
to the crime scene?
DRUMMER:
The prints we found
in the house and the
partial print we found
on Julie's wedding band
turned out to be TJ's.
Apparently, he tried
to pry it off her finger
after killing her.
ANNABETH:
That's as cold-blooded
as it gets.
Junkies will take anything.
STEVE:
Okay, so,
walk us through Chuckie's deal.
ANNABETH:
His lawyer wanted him
to walk, but I got one year
in jail,
and five years felony probation.
Sounds about right.
Any lead
on the murder weapon, Lou?
DRUMMER:
We're searching
for it now.
Chuckie claims
that TJ threw the gun out
of the car window the night
of the murders.
And Chuckie's gonna lead us
to where it got tossed.
He threw the murder
weapon out the window?
MAUREEN:
Guy's a
meth addict.
He's not the sharpest knife
in the drawer.
Okay. So, it looks like
Mr. Terrence Jerome Mills
is on the hook for two counts
of murder and armed robbery.
Let's schedule an arraignment,
and find TJ's
murder weapon.
Maureen, I want
you to talk to TJ's
public defender.
Let's see if the boy
wonder has anything
to say for himself.
And Annabeth, I want you
to get a deposition
from the victim's husband.
There's no evidence
that he was involved here,
but let me know if you feel
like there's something
important we're missing here.
MAUREEN:
Chuckie said
you pulled the trigger.
You don't have to
respond to that.
I can respond to it.
Chuckie's lying, okay?
He killed those ladies,
not me.
We were driving around
getting high, you know,
and Chuckie said,
"Let's get some money.
Let's do these people."
Then he just shot them both.
Boom,
boom.
It was sickening.
Any reason?
Just for the fun of it?
Yeah.
Chuckie's a jackass.
TJ, his fingerprints
aren't all over that house,
but yours are.
Yeah,  because
he was wearing gloves.
Uh-huh.
The police found
the murder weapon,
a .380-caliber pistol.
It's  a straight-up
ballistics match
from the killings.
That's not my gun.
Really?
Then why are your fingerprints
all over it?
You don't have to answer that.
I'm not gonna.
Our office is willing to take
the death penalty off the table
if you will plead guilty.
Let's get real, Maureen.
You know the
death penalty
isn't on the table
in the first place.
There are no special
circumstances.
The case
is completely circumstantial,
and your star witness
is a drug addict.
The worst possible
case scenario,
TJ gets life without parole.
Yeah, well, that's more than
he gave those two women.
We're offering nothing less.
Since that's what he's
going to get from a jury,
if he gets convicted,
might as well roll the dice
and see if he gets off.
Yeah, well, let me know
how that works out for you.
Oh, Mr. Prichard.
I'm Deputy Prosecuting
Attorney Chase.
I'm, uh, I'm so
sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Please, have a seat.
I know this is
a difficult time,
but I do have some
progress to report.
It looks like we
may have found
the man who murdered your
wife and mother-in-law.
Who is it?
Does this man look
familiar to you?
No.
Take your time.
Maybe your wife knew him?
No. I'm sorry.
What about the other kid,
the, uh, driver?
Chuckie.
He led us to the shooter
and is testifying against him
in exchange
for a reduced sentence.
How reduced?
One year in jail,
five years probation.
That's all he gets,
for killing my wife?
We believe he only drove the car
and had no prior knowledge
of the murder.
And that he could
not have stopped it.
He didn't even try
to report it.
Maybe if he had called 911.
We need Chuckie's testimony
to put your wife's killer away.
Otherwise we never
would have made the deal.
Promise me this is the guy.
Promise me he's not going
to get off easy, too.
I promise.
If he's the guy,
he won't get off easy.
He'll be charged
with both murders.
I'm just curious.
Does your work take you
out of town often?
No.
But this was the Midwest
Mortgage Lenders Association's
annual conference.
It happens once a year.
I used to like to go
on the thing, you know,
hanging out with the guys.
But ever since I married Julie,
I can't wait to get home.
I just get so lonely
without her.
She doesn't like
to be alone, either.
That's why her mom
was with her at the house.
We kept talking
about getting a dog,
but I figured I'd be the one
stuck walking the damn thing
every day.
Damn it.
I just keep thinking, if I'd
only been there, you know?
If I'd...
ANNABETH:
Who asked for this meeting,
us or them?
His PD,
a career-climber.
I think she staging
a dog-and-pony act
to impress her supervisor.
She knows TJ's guilty as sin,
but she's got to act
like she's fighting for him.
I'm thinking
she'll ask for 30 years.
And we'll counter with two
terms of 60 consecutive?
Exactly.
Hmm.
Oh, man, oh, man, oh, man.
Oh, man, all right,
tell them. Tell them.
Sit down, TJ.
You brought
us down here
to watch your client
go through withdrawal?
I come bearing gifts.
Just get to it, Becky.
Hypothetically,
if TJ were to confess
to killing Julie Prichard
and her mother
on the night of December 6,
and if he were to tell you
that someone hired him
to commit these murders...
You're claiming this
was an execution?
This was not
a random home invasion.
This was a murder for hire.
And you can prove that by...?
In exchange
for giving you the man
who ordered these executions,
TJ will serve 15 years.
Or  we'll investigate
and find him ourselves.
You'll never get
near him without me.
He's one of the biggest
amphetamine suppliers
in the Midwest.
If you could get him,
you would have done so
a long time ago.
You murdered two women in
the course of an armed robbery.
We're not interested in a deal
unless you're giving up
Osama bin Laden.
Well, then,
we're in luck.
How does Richard Wolf sound?
Richard Wolf hired you
to murder these women?
I'm a dealer.
He's my supplier.
Why did he want
these people killed?
I don't know why.
Something to do
with a business deal gone bad.
He was going to give me
a six-month supply.
Ooh, well, that worked out well.
The name doesn't
mean anything
unless he can prove
Wolf ordered the hit.
We're not just going to assume
he's telling the truth.
TJ:
It's all true!
I swear to God.
I can't spend my life in prison.
Look, I'll wear a wire.
I'll get him to talk.
I'll get him to say that he told
me to kill those two people.
How do we know you
can even get near him?
Because I just killed
some people for him!
We have a relationship.
He's expecting me to show up
so I can get my payment.
Richard Wolf
is going to find out
you've arrested TJ
anytime now.
Let's make this deal
and TJ can lead you to Wolf
before that happens.
♪♪♪♪
We can't take this deal.
Oh, we're taking the deal,
Annabeth.
15 years for a
double homicide?
Are you kidding me?
Richard Wolf is
the Moby Dick of meth.
He is the whale.
The DA starts salivating
at the mention of his name.
It's still a bad deal.
If we get Richard Wolf,
we could lose every drug case
we have on the docket
for the next year
and still be ahead
of the game.
Wolf is responsible for a
third of the meth production
in greater Indianapolis.
Meth is tied to 20%
of the murders,
and one in four of
the fires in this city.
What am I supposed to say
to the victim's husband?
15 years is not a slap
on the wrist, Annabeth.
Not in exchange for taking
a drug lord off the streets.
You've got
to think big here.
MAUREEN:
Wait, we have
another problem.
If Wolf ordered the hit,
what did James Prichard do
to cross him?
STEVE:
What was Prichard's
line of work again?
Financial services, mortgage,
lending, that sort of thing.
He could have been laundering
Wolf's money,
hiding it in real estate.
Of course it wouldn't hurt
to confront
James Prichard directly and see
how he responds to Wolf's name.
You think you
can handle that?
It's hard to believe
Prichard's involved in meth.
He's such a straight arrow.
But if he is, then we don't have
to take TJ's deal.
I just... I don't want
to give 15 years
to this cold-blooded killer.
There has to be another way
to get Wolf.
How do we know TJ's
even telling the truth?
I mean, how do we know
he even knows Richard Wolf?
We do need to corroborate
TJ's connection to Wolf.
But we've got to do it quickly.
The minute we arraign TJ,
Wolf's gonna hear about it,
and then we can't send
TJ in with the wire.
Meantime, let's look into
Prichard's business.
If he was working with Wolf,
he must have done something
to make him very, very angry.
Your boyfriend's in
a lot of trouble.
I'm going to need you
to give me the names
of some of the people
he hangs out with.
How's that supposed
to help TJ?
It could help him spend
less time in prison.
What makes you think
I want him out of prison?
He, uh, listed you as
an emergency contact.
He did?
He's not the most
reliable individual,
he stole stuff
all the time.
Like what?
Money, mostly, and...
Drugs?
He ever mention any names?
I don't know.
No, I don't know. Why?
( phone ringing )
I'm coming.
I said I'm coming.
I've got to go.
TJ ever borrow
your cell phone?
Yeah, he stole it
for, like, a month.
Guess who had
to pay the bills?
Allison.
Yeah?
What's your cell phone number?
Thank you for coming in
again, Mr. Prichard.
You can call me James.
You have an update on the case?
Actually,
we are trying to figure out
if TJ had another motive.
Like what?
TJ claims that he was paid
to kill your wife
and mother-in-law.
What?
By someone
who wanted to hurt you,
because of a business deal.
Whose business?
Have you ever seen this man?
No.
Why, should I have?
Does the name Richard Wolf
mean anything to you?
No, and I'm not answering
any more questions
until you tell me
what's going on.
Okay.
I'm going to tell you something
that's confidential, James.
You can't talk
to anyone about this
or it could contaminate
the jury pool
and the judge will be
forced to change our venue.
None of us want to try
this case in another county.
But I think it's only fair
to let you know...
TJ wants to make a deal
with the prosecutor's office.
He'll testify against
a notorious drug lord
if we give him
a lighter sentence.
You promised.
Mr. Prichard.
I can't believe
this is happening.
Nothing has happened yet.
I trusted you.
You promised he wasn't
going to get off easy,
like that other little punk.
Can you think of any reason
someone might want to hurt you,
your wife, or her mother?
You think this is because
something I did?
I approve homeowner
refinancing packages.
I stare at paperwork
all day long.
Julie worked
at the children's section
of the public library,
for Pete's sake.
Her mother made meals
for the disabled.
Do you understand?
Do you get it?
They're both dead now.
You want to use that
to put away some drug guy?
I'm done talking to you.
Please, sit down.
You have the man
who killed them.
Do your job.
Put him away forever.
And leave me alone.
They just got married last year.
They were the same age
as us, Jack.
He's just devastated.
They have any kids?
No, but they were trying.
Jack, that poor man's going
to spend the rest of his life
beating himself up for
not being home that night.
Well,
I would, too.
Who do you think
is more guilty,
the meth head who
shot those poor women,
or the kingpin
who hired him to do it?
What about the kid
driving the getaway car?
He didn't know about it.
He's basically a bystander.
He drove
the guy away.
Isn't that a crime?
Yeah, I could try to nail him.
But he's cooperated,
and he's going to help me
put the shooter away.
So, basically you
got three bad guys.
You got your dumb kid,
you got a guy who
squeezed the trigger,
and then you got the guy
that ordered the killing.
Yeah.
The shooter says
he was following orders.
Yeah, isn't that
what they all say?
They were
"following orders?"
I mean, both of them
had to be willing,
otherwise the whole thing
wouldn't have happened.
Exactly.
You're making
deals all day?
One guy to get to
another guy,
to get to
another guy?
Yeah.
I have to you...
it's wearing me out.
Come here.
Let me see this.
Now, looking at these calls,
when the girlfriend's cell phone
was in TJ's possession,
you'll see a spate of calls
over a two-day span
for the same number.
That would be
a two-day span
right before
the murders went down.
And this number
belongs to?
One of Wolf's
underlings.
Ronny Winkler.
Oh, so it seems that
TJ was connected to Wolf.
What about James?
He's in hell.
I mean, he's grieving
for his wife.
I don't think he knows
anything about
Richard Wolf.
Well, you might want
to rethink that.
Why? What?
Two months ago,
a backup computer tape
went missing
from James Prichard's office.
How could that
tie to Wolf?
The computer tape had
over 30,000 credit
applications on it.
One tape?
Easy.
Probably fetch somewhere
in the low six figures.
Meth addicts steal IDs
for the dealers
who pay them in drugs.
They go through your trash,
they steal your mail.
The dealers take those IDs
and sell them to people
who convert them
into actual cash.
The value of the stolen IDs
are based on
the person's credit limits.
But James Prichard's
not a meth addict.
True, but the big dealers
are now
skipping right over
the addicts
and buying
credit information
from anyone
who has insider access.
Insiders like Prichard.
Dealers are making
as much
or more from ID theft
as from drugs.
That money buys
chemicals,
the chemicals make
more drugs,
which make more drug addicts,
who steal more IDs,
and the circle is complete.
But we don't have any
real evidence that James
was involved in
stealing those IDs.
Only that it appears
that Wolf had
his wife and
mother-in-law killed.
That points to
some kind of
connection.
Maybe he was being forced
into working with Wolf.
Theoretical.
Maybe he decided to quit,
and Richard decided to get even.
Again, theoretical.
Go back to friends,
neighbors,
coworkers.
See if anyone in Prichard's life
found anything suspicious.
Annabeth?
I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to get my head
around the possibility
that this guy's been playing me,
and it's really
hard to believe.
Duly noted.
But remember, we're trying
to get to Wolf without TJ.
Hey--
you're the one who wanted
to have her cake and
eat it, too.
Afraid not.
Never seen him.
Is there anything else
that sticks out
in your mind
from that night?
Well, there was something.
It probably doesn't
mean anything.
It happened the night
after the murders.
After?
See that house across the street
from the Prichards?
That's the Alavi family
that lives there.
Nice enough couple.
Two darling little girls.
The night after the murders,
I took my little dog out
before bedtime,
and I saw them
rushing around,
throwing things
into their car
and then they just
took off.
Kids and everything.
They left when?
The day after
the murders.
ANNABETH:
The woman deadheads
her roses but leaves
the milk out to spoil?
It looks like they
left in a hurry.
Well, there's a week's
worth of mail
left in the mailbox,
and nobody called
to cancel the newspaper.
I talked to the husband,
a Vashar Alavi,
the day of the murders.
He was a little
on edge.
Check this out.
Look at the victim's house.
Okay, imagine the possibility.
TJ's high.
He's wired.
He's been told
5461 Tennessee Court.
5467 is across the street.
Seven looks
a lot like a one.
You think TJ killed
the wrong people?
That's why the Prichard
connection to Wolf
never made any sense.
Richard Wolf wanted
these people dead,
and they knew it, Lou.
They knew
they were the targets.
That's why they left
in such a hurry.
That's why they packed up
their kids and ran.
Well, we still don't know
why they were the targets.
♪♪♪♪
hink TJ screwed up
and killed the wrong people.
The wrong people?
It looks like
the hit was meant
for the neighbors
across the street.
They moved out in a hurry,
right after the murders,
but no one knows
where they went.
If that's true,
then James Prichard
is not
the connection
to prosecuting Wolf.
Correct.
Which you've been
saying all along.
Hat's off.
But that also means that
we're no more capable
of nailing Wolf today
than we were yesterday.
Ergo, we need
TJ's testimony.
Unless we find
the neighbors.
You just told me
you don't know
where they are.
Vashar Alavi owned a dry
cleaning business downtown,
and he's originally
from Iran.
Iran?
Well, then
he's long gone.
That's one of
the few places
that Richard Wolf
can't find him.
You need to talk to TJ.
Steve.
I promised James Prichard.
I gave him my word
I wouldn't let TJ walk.
Annabeth,
you know
you can't promise
anyone anything
in this business.
If we, as an office,
choose to throw
the little fish
back to catch
the big fish,
we have to be able
to do that
without you
getting in the way
with your promises.
The "little fish"
shot and killed two women.
Mrs. Prichard was 29 years old.
You still shouldn't have
promised anything.
You're right, Steve, but I did.
What do you want?
I want TJ to get
what he deserves,
and I want
Richard Wolf.
But to have
any hope of that,
I need time to find
these missing people.
We arraign TJ
at 3:00 tomorrow.
That's all the time
you're getting.
If you can't
find him by then,
we take the deal.
The Department
of Environmental Management
requires every dry cleaner
to keep a purchase log
of this particular
chemical.
It's called "perc"?
Chloral Ethylene.
Also known as perc.
And guess what?
Perc happens to be
the latest craze
among larger meth lab
operations.
It speeds up
the methamphetamine
drying process,
while simultaneously
stretching
the bulk of
the final product.
Basically,
your user winds up
smoking dry cleaning
fluid
with some meth
mixed in.
And, let me guess, it also
makes it more addictive?
Everybody wins.
So, tell me why
this log's important.
Well, about seven months ago,
Mr. Alavi reported
some perc being stolen
right around here.
Who stole it?
Police never
solved it.
But if you notice
from this log,
perc purchases
nearly tripled
immediately following
the theft.
Well, whatever went down,
it sounds like Mr. Alavi's
in the meth supply business.
Well, either that
or he's planning
on opening three more
dry cleaners.
We've got to find
these people.
I've got the paralegals
checking the airlines,
Border Patrol,
State Department.
If they've left, there
will be a paper trail.
So if we don't find anything,
it could mean they're
still in Indianapolis?
Let's hope we come up
empty-handed.
Mm.
Could you check out
the passport info
on these folks
for me, please?
Thanks.
It's a family of four,
two girls.
They would have checked in
last week.
DRUMMER:
They tried to book
tickets to Iran,
Lauren Alavi,
the littlest girl,
she couldn't get out.
She was born
in this country,
so she's never had
a passport.
Now, her parents filed
an expedited application.
But with an
Iranian father...
Well, the State Department
is taking its time.
I figured the guy didn't want
to leave his family behind.
So, they're still here,
we just don't know where.
I had Juliet call every
hotel in Indianapolis.
She found a match of
three families
with two little girls,
but only one paid
for everything in cash,
and only one didn't
provide a checkout date.
You are so good.
I can be.
Indianapolis Police!
MAN:
Open the door
and I will shoot!
Drop your weapon!
It's the police!
Mr. Alavi!
We're here to talk
about Richard Wolf.
Do not shoot!
My hands are
up in the air!
DRUMMER:
We know you were supplying
Richard Wolf
with perc, Mr. Alavi.
Now, that's a felony.
I don't think
you can prove this.
We have documentation
showing that you ordered
far more chemicals per month
than you could
possibly use.
Please, my husband's
health is very bad.
I must think of
my wife
and my children.
If I help you,
they will kill all of us.
Actually, as long
as Richard Wolf is free,
he will try and hunt you down.
If you cooperate,
we can get him
off the streets.
We can provide you
with new identities,
get you in
the Witness
Protection program.
It'll be
a new start.
Vashi-zam, think of
the girls.
Tell me what I can do.
Well, you can start
by telling me
why Richard Wolf wants you dead.
arch,
I see that my storage area
is empty.
Someone has cut the lock
and removed all the solvents,
the perc.
So I called the police.
They make a report,
but nothing happens.
Then not long after,
some men come to me
and say we took the perc,
and now we're going to pay you
to give it to us.
This is bad, I said no,
I don't want to get paid.
But they say they
will kill me if I refuse.
They work for a very big man,
Richard Wolf.
What am I gonna do?
So this goes on for some months
and I don't tell my wife.
And my doctor says
I have a bleeding ulcer.
And one day she asks me
what's wrong and so I tell her.
She tells me it has to stop.
How did Richard Wolf
pay you?
They took my bank account number
and put the money in there.
They told me if I tried to tell
anyone, I will go to jail
because the police will see
that I'm getting paid.
So you think
we got enough?
We got it all.
Mr. Alavi can prove
Wolf was paying him
and when he stopped
supplying chemicals,
Wolf threatened
to kill him.
And the meth labs?
Alavi is taking the police
to where he delivered
the chemicals,
and we expedited
an arrest warrant for Wolf.
So we're hoping these are
his last free hours on Earth.
Becky, I bet
you're looking for me.
You are aware that TJ's
being arraigned at 3:00?
We were just talking
about what we should wear.
I'm in olive, but do you think
pinstripes are better?
Yeah.
Olive brings out
my eyes.
If you want to make this deal
with TJ,
this is your last chance.
Actually, we
found another way
to get Wolf, so...
So don't despair,
you were offering 15 years
if TJ wore a wire.
Yes?
Well, how does
30 years to life sound
if he testifies
that Richard ordered him
to make the hit?
Or?
Or, I'd guess
we'd have to up the charges
to whatever
we're charging Richard with.
So that's him?
That's Richard Wolf?
The one, the only.
He looks smaller
in person.
Drummer.
Rachel, call my lawyer.
Yeah.
They found the meth lab
in a warehouse downtown.
They're going in.
ANNABETH:
Sonya?
What's wrong?
He was fine,
and then...
I saw Richard Wolf
down the hall.
SONYA:
It was just
for one second,
and now his stomach is...
I don't think...
Not today.
Mr. Alavi,
I'm going to be right in there
with you.
There's nothing to worry about.
Do you want me to
get you some water?
I just wanted to thank you
for coming.
Mr. Prichard, I, uh...
How are the girls?
They're well. Thank you.
You know, sometimes
the only blessing
I can think of
out of all of this,
is that your girls
are still alive.
Would you do me a favor?
Sure. Anything.
Make sure you put him away
in there today.
That I will do.
I'm counting on you.
Please, I'm ready.
Okay.
You knew it was illegal to sell
these chemicals to Mr. Wolf.
Yes.
So why did you continue?
He threatened to come
to my house and kill me
if I ever refused.
But you did stop.
Yes, I wanted out of all of it.
What happened then?
Mr. Wolf called
to warn me.
I begged him to
let me out of it,
but he said he wasn't
playing games.
What happened next?
I...
I bought a gun.
You thought
you could protect yourself?
I was desperate.
And we quickly made a plan
to leave,
but then we realized
we didn't have a passport
for my youngest daughter.
And then that night...
the neighbors in the house
across the street were killed.
It was horrible.
The next day
the police are everywhere,
so when it got dark,
we took the girls
and we ran away.
Can you please point out
Mr. Wolf in the courtroom today?
TJ:
That's him, there.
Did Mr. Wolf pay you
to commit murder?
Yes. Not in money, in drugs.
What did he tell you exactly?
He told me to go
to 5461 Tennessee Court.
But you didn't go to that house.
I was high on meth,
and I screwed up 5461 with 5467.
What else did he tell you to do?
( swallows hard )
He told me to...
shoot the whole family,
even the kids.
But there weren't any kids.
Because I got the wrong house.
But I was so wasted.
If there had been any kids,
I'd have killed them, too.
"On the first count
of conspiracy to commit murder,
"we, the jury, find the
defendant, Richard Robert Wolf,
guilty."
"On the second count
of conspiracy to commit murder,
"we find the defendant,
Richard Robert Wolf,
guilty."
JACK:
I like it when you win.
What did Wolf get?
L-WOP.
Life without parole.
I like it.
You know, I'm still
holding you to that deal.
Oh... it was...
it was a back rub.
No, no.
Actually, I think
it was you washing the dishes
in the morning.
Right, right.
Baby, I'd clean the whole
damn kitchen for you.