(Vehicle Approaching]
(Moans)
(Mumbling)
- Ann.
- Hmm? What?
Are you all right?
Yeah. Just a dream.
Go back to sleep.
You wanna talk about it?
Shh. Mm-mmm.
I'm fine.
Mmm.
(Dog Barking]
(Barking Continues]
(Whistles)
(Whimpering)
Attaboy. Hi.
How's it goin'? Hmm?
Aw. Hmm?
It's just me, Pa.
Ain't you out too soon?
It was too crowded.
They had to let go of somebody.
I got picked.
Nice to see you, Pa.
It weren't no mistake,
them sendin' you there.
Lord knows, you needed to learn.
I would have sent half the county too.
- Weren't nothin' to learn at Rafer, Pa.
- Just the same...
it didn't do that Fred Vance or that
snake Eddie any good...
- You goin' in their place.
- That wasn't why I went, now was it?
We made a deal.
I figure they're still good for it.
(Water Running]
Kept your car running.
Not good, but running.
Thanks.
I would have come to get you.
I know.
It wasn't clear what day
they had in mind.
Good night then.
Good night, Pa.
** (Blues On Radio, Indistinct]
All right, Pa. Kill it.
(Engine Stops)
You were supposed to call the office.
I knew you'd find me soon enough.
- Doin' all right?
- Hell, yeah.
just like another tour in the army.
Fully bullshit and no place to go.
I don't plan on ever
bein' inside a cell again.
- I hear you.
- Then you're gonna have to change
a few things, ain't you?
Or next time Dave will bust you himself
right in your own town.
- That's enough, Pa.
- Good afternoon, Mr. Mann.
Might be.
Two kids who growed up together...
You sure turned out different.
Some folks just won't learn,
will they, Dave?
- Leave it alone.
- Whatever you say, Mr. Mann.
- Both of you.
- (Chuckling)
Listen, Sonny, while we're on the straight
and narrow crap, I gotta ask you somethin'.
Got any more business planned
with Fred and Eddie Vance?
- No, nothin' serious.
- They've gotten a lot worse
in the last couple years.
More powerful, more connected,
a lot more dangerous.
You don't need it, Sonny.
I thought you guys were supposed to
take care of that kind of crap.
I don't want back in, Dave.
That's it then.
I just came by to ask you to supper.
Ann wants to see you and be sure
for herself you're okay.
About 6:00?
Hey, you wanna go to supper, Mr. Mann?
Thanks, Dave.
Headin' out early in the mornin'.
All right.
Maybe some other time.
Don't you go, uh,
stealing any hubcaps now.
Too late for that.
Where'd you park your damn car anyway?
Down the road.
Wanted to surprise you.
* I said good-bye *
* Good-bye, baby
Got to go *
* I said good-bye *
* Good-bye, baby
Got to go *
* I ain't hangin'around here *
* Worrying where
there's trouble no more *
* Trouble is knockin'*
* Trouble is knockin'**
(Man]
Oh, the 1 50.
Throttle cable on a 1 50, 1 1.85.
All right.
- Hey, Eddie.
- Sonny.
Goddamn.
(Man]
Come in.
Hey, Uncle Fred.
Hey, look who's back.
(Fred]
Hang on a second.
(Chuckles)
Sonny.
- We didn't expect you back so soon.
- How you doin', Fred?
Good. Man, you look great.
Wonderful.
Hey, it's almost time to eat. Why don't
we go on out to the boat over there, hmm?
jennie, why don't you callJunior Mays.
Get us three lunch specials.
(Fred]
You look like you been liftin'weights, boy.
So then the liquor man says,
"I don't get it.
"Now, you been comin'in here...
"orderin' a five-dollar jug of wine
three nights in a row...
and now you want
an $80 bottle of champaign?"
The drunk, he kinda leans forward
a little bit and he says...
"That's right, Doc.
That cheap stuff's tearin' up my ass."
(Fred Laughing]
(Chuckles)
- You ready?
- (Sonny] You bet.
You better be ready.
(Chuckles)
Well, Fred, it's a nice boat.
Yeah, ain't it though?
We got us a great deal little while back.
Somebody decided
they'd rather be sailin'.
- So how was it in there, Sonny?
- I got by.
I want you to know, you took your bit
like a man, and we're grateful.
You said up front,
"You run dope, you risk gettin' busted."
You know, when you got back, we were hopin'
that you'd wanna come in partners with us.
Discreetly, of course.
Maybe use what you got comin' as
an investment into a real piece of the business.
I'll tell you now, man, those country days
are goin' fast around here.
Outsiders, corporations...
they're movin' in.
Hell, five years from now,
you won't even recognize this place.
I appreciate that, Fred,
but you know me.
Anything on a dare
and nothin' planned.
I'll just take the cash.
You know, we was thinkin' you'd be gone
at least another year.
Oh, hell, don't worry about it, Sonny.
We always come through.
Just give us a day to sort this thing out.
We'll get back to you tomorrow.
- No sweat.
- But I'll tell you what you should be
doin'over there now.
You ought to make your way
over to Eddie's club next door.
Look out that window.
Man, I was there the other night.
They got so many pretty little chickies
a-jigglin'and a-wigglin'over there...
I got me a hard-on
just orderin' up a beer.
(Chuckles)
(Child]
Mom? Dad? There's a man at the door.
(Ann]
I'll get it.
You still got the 280.
Course.
Oh, Sonny!
(Laughs)
- Good-lookin' kids, Dave.
- Oh, thanks, thanks.
- Where'd you get 'em?
- Got 'em on sale.
Come on, kids.
Let's go!
(Singing, Indistinct)
And we come from
the number one school
- Shark bite, shark bite
- Go, you mighty sea sharks
(Together) Ooh, ooh, ooh
Bite their fuckin' heads off
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Go, you mighty sea sharks
(Indistinct)
Ooh, ooh
Go Sharks
- (Laughing)
- Okay, now ready?
- Here we go. Seven up, guys.
- You remembered.
- Ready. And...
- By me, Daddy!
Okay, okay.
Big smile.
Bigger smile.
- Did you set it, hon?
- Big, big smile.
- Bigger.
- There it is.
(Grunts)
Started this... two years ago.
(Laughing)
Maybe someday.
Your daddy wouldn't be too happy
seeing his shop like this.
Yeah, well, my grandaddy
would whup me side the head.
- Mmm.
- And Ann's folks?
Uh, sold the restaurant
and moved back to Chicago.
Now we're all that's left.
Y'all doin' all right?
Yeah. There's never enough time,
but, sure, we're doin' fine.
- (Ann] Dave, you out here?
- Yeah.
Girls are ready for their good night.
I'll be back in a minute.
The famous rocking chair.
(Laughing)
- You look as pretty as ever, Ann.
- Oh.
Run away with me.
Bring the kids. I don't care.
Well, you're as useless as ever.
'Cause you'd still throw us on the line.
Besides...
if I were to run,
it'd be on my own.
That wouldn't be as much fun.
Well...
I think it's time you settled down.
- Ah-
- Yeah. Join the rest of us fools.
Heaven save me from all schemers.
You of all people.
Yeah.
It's nice to have you back, Sonny.
Somehow, even before...
it just seemed, these last few years,
like everyone went their own way.
We've missed having you around
to stir things up.
Well, old Uncle Sonny
will see what he can do.
(Ann Giggles]
Thanks for supper.
- Next time, I take you guys out drinkin'.
- Anytime.
- Good night now.
- (Ann] Good night.
(Car Engine Starts]
(Water Running]
(Spits)
You think that guy's
ever gonna grow up?
Oh, if and when it suits him.
Maybe.
(Chuckles)
Keep an eye on him.
What do I have to do to get a little
of that tender concern, huh?
Wanna put that up?
You take care of everybody.
Not tonight I don't.
- (Clears Throat)
- (Sighs)
- I just hope it can be like before.
- Yeah.
Yeah, that would be great.
** (Band Playing, Indistinct]
- ** (Continues]
- (People Chattering)
(Indistinct)
** (Ends]
(Applause]
All right.
Thanks for comin' out, y'all.
We're the Louisiana Renegades.
We'll be back in just a few minutes.
Are you Sonny Mann?
Effie.
- (Laughs)
- Effie Bender. Goddamn.
Thought you moved to Orlando
and got yourself married.
I did. I mean, I was.
Believe me. I was, but that is over.
Thank God.
Well, I'm sorry to hear it.
Mm-mmm. Don't be.
** (Band Playing]
You really been in jail for three years?
That's right.
What do you do for fun in jail?
You don't wanna know.
That's a long time.
I mean, without...
(Giggles)
That's right.
Bet you got a lot of stuff stored up.
I mean, feelings and all.
Could be.
I went down to the river
But the river was dry
I went down to the sea
But it wasn't the place for me
* Then I tried to climb a mountain *
* Then I waved to the mountaintop *
* Till I fiird me a home *
* Now you know I can't stop *
(Giggles)
(Giggling)
* Oh **
(Chuckles)
I take it you had a good time last night.
You know, Son...
pretty soon you're gonna
have to start figurin' things out.
Now, you can work with me
for a while if you want.
The oystering's been real good this year.
But you never was much of one to...
I'm worried.
The Vances are gonna get your ass
in trouble all over again.
I know.
(Truck Engine Starts]
(Indistinct)
Oh, livin' up to your name again, Bender?
You and Dave were good friends
with Sonny Mann, weren't you?
Yeah. Still are.
- What about Sonny?
- (Chuckles)
All I'll say is, Lordy, can that boy dance.
What's this about dancin'?
Oh, nothin', Doc.
just a happy memory.
Uh-huh.
(Chuckles)
Call the lab, would you, Effie?
See if you can push along
Mrs. Eller's blood test.
- I'd like to know this afternoon.
- You got it, Doc.
Evangelina Ray?
(Gunshot]
Hey.
How's he doin'?
He's completely ripped.
Seems Fred Vance
claimed the note on his boat.
- (Gunshot)
- (Dave] Damn.
He won't let anybody out there.
(Dave]
Is that that old bird gun he's got?
Yeah. Double-barrel.
All right then.
(Gun Cocks]
Henry!
It's me Dave Lockhart.
I'm gonna come on down there.
- Don't do it, Dave!
- No. We gotta stop this right now.
Stop it, Dave!
I'll shoot!
I don't wanna have to dive into this water,
and I know you don't wanna make me.
Get this suit all wet,
county make me pay cleanup.
- I mean it!
- Look. You're gonna miss supper.
Then each of our wives is gonna bawl us out.
Don't neither of us want that.
- No.
- (Groans)
You didn't have to do that.
Henry, this time I wasn't so sure.
(Fred] That $ 1 0,000 is just
a down payment towards the 200.
But you need to know, Sonny,
the I.R.S. and Treasury Department...
they're gettin' smarter every day.
Now we been coverin'our asses
the last couple of years...
and I'd say right now
we're about 90% legit.
And all that old money, we got tucked away
in banks down in the Bahamas.
Now, it's a sweet deal...
but it ain't like no damn pizza parlor.
Can't just pick up the phone
and they deliver.
You tellin' me there's no rainy-day fund
sittin' in a suitcase somewhere?
Come and share with us, Sonny.
It'd be good for everybody involved.
Thank you, Fred, but I just want the money.
Dave and this whole sheriff's department
would love to catch us doin' somethin' foolish.
Mama's boys, the whole bunch of'em.
Come on, Fred. Don't dick around. You can do
whatever in hell you want, and you know it.
Things hang by a very thin thread
around here, Sonny.
We, all of us...
We need to be careful.
I can be as careful as you, Fred.
You know that.
Well, I'm sure sorry you ain't comin' in with us.
I really am.
All right. We'll get your money.
It'll take about a week.
I still say he's trouble.
If not now, then later.
Do you suppose we could
reach Mr. Fig today, Eddie?
Been a long time
since we needed his services.
A damn shame.
(Lawn Mower Running]
(Girl]
How many rats you catch today, Panther?
- (Girl #2] She's already got 'em all.
- (Girl #1] All of'em?
- That's right.
- So what does she do now?
- Sit and feel good for ever and ever.
- Are you sure?
** (Soft Rock On Radio]
(Laughing)
(Squeals, Laughs)
I wonder...
What's that?
If folks like us ever figure life out.
This feels pretty good right here.
(Chuckles)
- * When will I learn *
- * Sweet forgiveness *
* Sweeter than honey *
* Give me that
sweet forgiveness *
* Sweeter than wine **
It's a night for us huntin' dogs,
ain't it, Hound?
It's been a long time.
Can you still do the job?
Shh.
He won't leave.
We ought to get him to the clinic.
This was meant for you, wasn't it?
Sonny, just tell me it was the Vances.
Look, I saw you at their place.
You tell me what the hell's goin' on.
Lay off, Dave.
He's in shock, for Christ's sake.
All right. Go on. Get him to the clinic.
Look, Ann's gonna be there.
She's gonna take good care of you, okay?
I'm gonna take Hound.
(Hound Whining]
(Hound Barks]
We need wiretaps on the Vances...
their office, houses, the works.
- (Sighs)
- Come on, Tate. You know who's behind this.
Hell, the whole county knows. We oughta
just bring 'em in and beat it out of'em.
That doesn't sound like you, Dave.
Big fish take a long time to reel in.
So, you-you-you're not
gonna do squat, are you?
For me, there's two kinds of trouble...
the kind that gets laid on you...
and the kind that you lay on yourself.
Now, Sonny has always been a wiseass.
Which do you figure this is?
That is not the point, damn it.
Somebody just took out Sonny's pa.
We both have a pretty good idea
who it was.
And how many alibis you figure
are already set? Hmm?
I been tryin' to get Fred Vance for years.
Hell, Dave, we're just the janitors here.
We do what we can when we can.
You know what?
I've heard this crap before.
Then maybe you better get out of here
before you say something you regret.
I'm not a janitor.
(Door Opens]
- (Door Closes]
- (Sighs)
Okay. Now that's gonna
hurt for a little bit.
But, all in all, I'd say you were real lucky.
just keep that dressing clean,
and it'll heal up fine.
I'll see to it, Doc.
Give Sonny fiive milligrams of Valium,
and let him rest in the back room.
If there's no complications,
you can take him home this afternoon.
Thanks.
- Can I come in?
- Not now, Effie.
Sonny needs to be left alone for a while.
Do you understand?
Sure, Doc,
whatever you say.
- (Girl] Is your name really Hound?
- (Girl #2] Of course it is. But it's a funny name.
- (Girl #1] Yeah.
- (Giggles]
It is. Hound.
- (Door Opens]
- (Ann] Dave, we're here.
Hey.
Hound's out back.
Oh, Sonny, you shouldn't have that.
You're pretty doped up.
What's gonna happen?
I don't know.
Sonny's hidin' somethin'.
Tate could care less.
I have no idea.
- Look, I gotta go.
- Okay.
- You okay?
- Yep.
Call me if you need anything.
What happened to him?
Well, Sonny's been in an accident.
He needs to rest for a while.
(Girl]
Is he gonna stay for good?
(Ann] For a few days, I guess.
We don't really know yet.
It is beyond our ability or privilege
to understand the workings of our Lord.
But we can rest in the certainty
that this too is a part ofhis plan.
For the dove falls not from the sky
or the ship vanish in the night...
without his knowledge, love
and compassion for us all.
Let us bow our heads in silent prayer.
(Chuckles)
Sonny, you okay?
- Sonny.
- Yeah.
Yeah. I just got one thing I gotta do.
- I'll be right back.
- Nothing crazy, Sonny.
No. Nothing crazy.
(Door Opens, Closes]
(Car Engine Starts]
Why don't you just leave him alone?
King me.
Where are they goin'?
- (Door Opens, Closes]
- I don't know, Rachie.
Sonny's in there!
There's a fight! Hurry!
- (Men Grunting]
- (Clattering]
(Groans)
- Goddamn, Dave.
- No. You stay off!
You get that son of a bitch
out of my store right now, Dave!
- Don't you move!
- I'm gonna kill him.
- No, you're not!
- I'm gonna tear him apart.
Go home, Dave. Get out of here.
- Right now we're gonna
do nothin' but get in your car.
- They're both dead men.
Asshole Eddie.
Anytime I want, I can lay him out.
That's right.
You're too good for them scum.
- Goddamn it, Dave.
- We're gonna get Doc to clean you up...
and then we're gonna take a long ride
to cool you down.
Right now you just sit.
All right?
Now, I'll be right back.
That son of a bitch
is goin' back to jail for good, Dave!
- That's a bad idea, Fred.
- The hell it is.
You know, Sonny usually likes
to keep things to himself.
But, under the circumstances,
he might just decide to open up a bit.
Do you understand?
Yeah, well, I suppose that business with his pa
must have been a terrible shock.
I reckon we can overlook it
just this once.
Good.
Hey, Dave.
You tell Sonny that
as far as I'm concerned, we're even.
He don't think so,
next time we're gonna be ready.
Why can't you just lay off?
Hmm?
Don't you have enough?
(Chuckles)
Hell, there ain't never enough.
Even you know that, Dave.
* I walked 47 miles ofbarbed wire *
* Use a cobra snake for a necktie *
* I got a brand-new house
on the roadside *
* Made out of rattlesnake hide *
* Got a brand-new chimney
made on top *
I'm no good.
You know that, don't you?
* Now come on and take
a little walk with me, girl *
* And tell me
who do you love *
* Who do you love **
Bob!
(Man, Indistinct]
Hey.
What do you say, Sheriff?
How you doin'?
- Look who I dragged in to see you.
- Damn, Dave.
You didn't have to beat the poor boy up
to get him in here, did you?
- I'm gonna use your phone.
- Yeah.
- Roy.
- Yeah?
- Bag of oysters in the cooler.
- Oh, sure.
Bring it in here, will ya?
** (Rock On Radio]
- Roy.
- Yeah?
- Let me see that ball.
- Oh, shit. (Laughs)
- All right. Throw me one.
- Go out.
Boy, you look like you
crawled out of a rat's nest.
Thank you, Bob.
I feel like it too.
Yeah, you know,
I'm sorry about your pa.
So, uh...
you got anything lined up,
any plans?
I can let you in.
Start paintin' some cars.
Get your old touch back.
It seems like you got somebody.
Who, Roy? (Chuckles)
Come on. Roy just a kid.
He about two years away from bodywork.
Look, you know you wasn't much better
when you started out here.
Look, there's a cot in the back
in the storeroom...
shower, everything.
Ain't that bad
if you don't mind tires and paint cans.
- What do you say?
- Let me think on it.
Look here, Sonny.
You the odd man out now.
And Vances rule.
Why don't you just give yourself just
a little bit of time till things settle down?
You know what I mean?
(Dave]
Hey, come on. Over my head.
- Over my head.
- All right.
"She was overjoyed to see her brothers
and crawled out from under the bed.
"The brothers were just as happy
to see their sister...
"but they had no time to enjoy it.
"You can't stay here, ' they said.
"This is a robber's den. '
- "But you can protect me, ' she said.
- (Car Doors Closing]
"No, we can only take our swanskins off
for a little while each night.
"Then we're turned back into swans. '
"The sister wept and asked...
"But can't you be set free? '
- "Oh, no, ' they said.
- (Door Opens]
"There is a way, but it's too hard."'
Daddy, hi.
Hi, Pops.
Well, what happens next?
"But it's too hard.
"You'd have to go without
speaking or laughing for three years.
"'During that time, you'd have to
sew us two shirts of starflowers.
'And if a single word crossed your lips,
all would be lost. '
"When the brothers had said this,
their time was up.
"They were turned back into swans
and flew away.
"The girl decided
to set her brothers free...
"even if it cost her her life.
"She left the hut
and spent the night in the forest.
"The next morning
she gathered starfiowers...
and began to sew."
(Door Opens, Closes]
(Keys Jangling]
Hey.
- Did you get some rest?
- Some.
Where are the kids?
Oh, they have their Brownie meeting Wednesdays.
Dave will pick them up around 5:00.
- Can I help?
- Nope. Just sit and relax.
Thought we'd have chicken tonight.
Sound good?
You bet.
I always like cooking chicken.
It reminds me of my mom.
It was the one Southern thing
she learned how to cook.
That and turnip greens.
Don't.
No. No, stop.
Oh, stop it.
I don't want this!
That's not how it was at the clinic.
You were in shock.
- You didn't know what you were doin'.
- Maybe, but you did.
I don't understand
what you're trying to say.
I'm sorry.
I never know what people
are supposed to do.
It is what we always wanted.
This didn't happen.
But it did.
We dreamt it.
just this once.
- Why?
- Dave and I love each other.
I'm glad.
How could you...
How... How could I do this to Dave?
This has nothing to do with him.
He asked first is all it was.
What would you have done
if it had been the other way around?
Ann...
we'll be dead soon enough.
You gotta go where livin' takes you.
Then I guess it's my problem.
They're gonna be here
in less than an hour.
I have to get supper.
We have to get normal.
(Dave]
Well, the state lab didn't help.
They just agreed it was the same M. O...
as those two bombings last year
in Baker County.
Fred must have hired a pro.
- So, what now?
- We wait until we get a break.
Or until someone gives us a hint.
Bob offered me a job yesterday.
He said I can stay at his place.
- No need to rush.
- You all have been great,
but I need to stop thinkin' for a while.
Be sure and watch those stitches.
You bet.
You'll come by, Sonny. Whenever
you want company, Trish and I'll be here.
Thanks, Rachel. I'll do that.
You see that Mustang
you walked by out there?
Man brung that in last week.
Said he want it brought back to life.
I started, but I ain't got time
to keep it up.
Doors and windows and everything
are all framed out.
I done those.
Man's shootin' for premium grade.
Yellow, black stripe.
I'll tell you what, Rambo.
Couple of weeks, I think.
What you think?
Yeah, give or take.
Everybody's talkin' about the lickin'
Sonny gave Eddie Vance.
Oh.
Seemed like Eddie got his share of licks in.
Sonny looked like hell.
Doc was tellin' me Eddie's uncle
doesn't want...
anybody else seein' Eddie
till he's all healed up.
Folks are callin' Sonny a hero
for stickin' up for his pa like that.
Well, I think Sonny's tryin'
to put all that behind him now.
You reckon he's recovered enough
to see some common folks by now?
Well, you'd have to ask Sonny that.
He moved out
to Bob's paintin' shop out on 65.
Thank you.
just might do that.
** (Blues On Radio]
All right, Roy.
Go ahead and take it.
(Pounding]
So, uh, you've been to jail.
That's right.
I almost went to jail once.
I didn't go.
Boy, I... I came real close.
Then I say you made the right choice.
Nah, Sheriff Dave... he let me off.
Yeah. He's good at that.
(Pounding]
(Cartoon On TV]
- Hi, Dad.
- Hey, guys.
- Poppy.
- (TV. ; Girl] Bubbles!
- Where could she be?
- (Girl #2] Let's keep looking.
(Electronic Voice)
The Powerpuff Girls will save the day!
(TV. ; Sinister Voice]
Now that I have you, my sweet little Bubbles-
(Cartoon Continues In Distance]
There anything I can do?
Nothing.
It's all under control.
(Sighs)
What's wrong?
I walked into the house today
and suddenly wanted to throw up.
Maybe we went overboard
on the yellow curtains.
(Chuckles)
And how was your day?
My day was okay, I guess.
The usual.
The usual?
The normal.
The everyday.
(Chuckles)
Don't you just love it?
What... What is that
supposed to mean, Ann?
I guess...
having Sonny around...
just reminded me of things.
Of how crazy we all used to be.
You know?
Every now and then, just lettin' loose.
I miss that so much.
Well, I don't get that.
You know, three years in prison,
his pa's dead and God knows what else...
and you wanna make him
into some kind of hero?
- Dave, you're such a fucking bore.
- No. You go to hell.
(Rachel]
Mom! Mom!
Can we help with supper?
The show's over.
In a minute, sweetie.
You help Trish get washed up.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah. Go get cleaned up, okay?
Better look out, Trish.
I'm gonna wash your dirty hands clean off.
You're right.
We've got... I've got everything
I ever really wanted...
right here.
(Hound Growling]
(Vehicle Approaching]
(Effiie]
Sonny!
(Banging)
Sonny, you're supposed to be in there!
- Hi.
- Hey.
Thought you could use
a little company.
I even brought along
my inspiration lamp.
You know, all these years,
this is only the second time I've been here.
Seems pretty much like I remember it.
Cheers to you, dancer boy.
- (Clinks)
- Good to see you, Effie.
(Sighs)
I've been missin' you, Sonny,
but now I'm lookin' to do some catchin' up.
- (Laughs)
- It's great to see you, Effie.
But if you don't mind,
maybe we'll go a bit slow...
what with the fire and all.
Is that okay?
Sure.
I've been there.
Only for me, it's usually when
I'm trying to get over some great love.
You ever wish you were a kid again?
All the time.
No, actually, I don't.
(Chuckles)
Seems hard enough just tryin'
to handle the here and the now.
Probably right.
- (Clears Throat)
- (Objects Clattering]
Mmm.
I'm sorry about your pa.
About all of it.
- Call me when you feel better?
- You bet.
The bottle's to get well on.
Bye.
I guess I owe you
an apology of sorts, Ann.
Sonny is worse off than I thought.
I went out there last night,
and I put on the full show.
That poor boy is cold as a dead mullet.
Uh, I hope he recovers soon for his sake.
(Phone Rings]
Health clinic.
- Excuse me, Officer.
- (Bird Squawks)
- But can we get on with this?
- Uh, yes, ma'am.
This is the second time in three months.
Tate said he would put
a double patrol on the island.
We have, ma'am,
but we can't be everywhere at once.
Well, whoever it is
loves liquor and videotapes.
They drank it all as far as I can tell.
The videotapes, well...
Now, isn't that what happened before?
That's right.
Would it make more sense
to take 'em with you when you leave?
But then, Officer,
what would you do for a job?
That's a fine point, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- You're most welcome.
(Buzzing)
- Looks mighty fine, Roy.
- Uh, thanks, Sheriff Dave.
(Buzzing Stops]
You keep sneakin' up on me.
I was out on St. George.
I just, uh, thought I'd stop by.
Listen, I wanted to let you know I had a long talk
with the feds this morning about the Vances.
And finally, they're startin'
to sound interested.
Okay, Roy. Let's take a break.
All right.
Bob has got you workin' already, huh?
Yeah.
It's nothin' he couldn't have done,
but he's letting me feel useful.
Well, glad to see
you're back to normal.
Well, it's a good distraction,
at least till I get things figured out.
Well, you gotta let us handle that,
Sonny, you know.
Is that right?
(Exhales)
Just like before?
just like always?
Can't save us all, Dave.
(Buzzing Continues]
(Tires Squealing)
When can I see you again?
Soon, maybe.
You figure you can keep us
both goin' on forever?
- Sooner or later-
- Then you know what has to happen.
What are you gonna say?
I've been out driving.
I've done it before,
when Dave gets the kids.
It's what the Datsun's for.
Effie told me about last night.
I thought you were always
ready for anything...
and anybody.
Nothin' wrong, I hope.
Oh, what have I let loose?
- (Door Closes]
- (Footsteps Approaching]
- Hey.
- Feelin' any better?
Now. It was a tough day.
Great drive though.
Went almost to P.C. and back.
- Just went to sleep.
- Okay.
Um, I'll be right back
to help put 'em to bed.
Okay.
(Man]
* Money, who needs it *
* Let me live a life free and easy *
* Put a toothbrush in my hand *
* And let me be a travelin'man *
* 'Cause I'm a roadrunner, baby *
(Laughs)
* I'm a roadrunner, baby *
- * Can't stay in one place too long *
- Slow, slow, slow, slow.
- * I'm a roadrunner, baby *
- Right. Set.
* You might look at me
and I'll be gone *
* You can love me if you wanna *
* But I do declare *
* When I get restless *
* I've got to move somewhere *
* I'm a roadrunner, baby *
* Anywhere's my home *
* Hey *
** (Fades]
You got your touch, Sonny.
(Pool Balls Clacking]
Whoo. Get your money ready, Freddy,
'cause it's all but over... now.
Uh-oh.
You see that? Yes, sir.
That boy's a good kid, man.
Wouldn't mind having a son like that.
Why didn't you ever get married?
Man, that garage won't let me.
You know, besides, I got too many kinfolk
countin' on me for one thing or the other.
I guess I just never let myself
get around to it, you know?
But what's your excuse?
(Laughing)
Sonny Mann.
(Laughs)
- Whoa.
- (Laughing)
(Car Alarm Chirps]
- You're that easy, Eddie.
- Fuck off, Sonny.
- Fifty times a day. That easy.
- Just try it then.
You Vances owe me money, remember?
You're like my bank.
And long as a bank pays,
it can stay open.
And if it don't...
well, then somethin' will have to be done.
Now you tell your uncle that.
And tell him I'm feelin' a little weird.
(Birds Squawking)
(Boat Approaching]
Hey, Uncle Fred.
Yeah, I know.
(Ringing)
Grab that phone for me,
will you, Sonny?
And tell 'em we're way past closed.
- Bob's Body Shop.
- (Fred) That you, Sonny?
- Yes, Fred, it is.
- That little debt... I want you to know,
it was a big mistake.
- We wanna take care of it.
- Fine. Mail me the money.
No, we need to talk face-to-face
one more time in private.
- Why don't you come on over to marina?
- I ain't gettin' set up again, Fred.
What do you want me to do? Bring it there
with everybody and his fat cousin...
so you get the change?
No, I guess that won't do.
How about your boat,
out in the channel?
That'll work. Tonight then.
Fine. Say, Buoy 1 2,
Dog Island, in two hours?
That's a long ways out, but...
(Sighs)
What the hell? A nice night for
a pleasure cruise. You got it.
I'll be in my pa's boat.
And, Fred,
I'll know if you try somethin'.
- Don't worry. We'll be there.
- See you.
Important call?
Oh, no. It's this girl I met,
wants me to come over.
I better get ready.
** (Man Singing On Radio, Indistinct]
(Engine Starts]
(Vehicle Departs]
(Phone Rings]
- Hello. Hello?
- Dave, i-it's Bob. BobJohnson.
Uh, look, I'm sorry to bother you.
Um, we were workin' late.
Sonny got a call.
And what?
I think he just left
to meet with the Vances.
- When was that?
- Just now.
And he took his gun.
All right. I understand.
Look, he said he's gonna
meet up on his pa's boat.
Um, I don't know.
Somethin'about Buoy 1 2.
I just don't understand why Sonny
would set himself up like this.
I don't know.
Look, I'm on my way to the marina.
- Anything I can do?
- Yeah, just keep it between us.
All right. Look, Dave,
you give me a call.
Yep.
Damn it, Sonny.
- Stupid bastard'll get himself killed.
- What's wrong? What's happened?
Bob thinks he's going after the Vances.
- This time for real.
- Oh, my God. I'm coming with you.
- No, you're not.
- Maybe I can talk...
- Maybe I can talk to him or something.
- Look, Ann, no!
Sonny's a case now.
Like any other case.
Be careful.
(Engine Starts)
(Objects Clattering]
(Engine Rumbling)
I hear an engine.
How the hell did he get out here this quick?
What the hell? Eddie!
(Bullets Hitting Metal]
(Gunfiire Continues]
I got him.
jesus.
(Groans)
You look just like Pa, Dave.
(Water Splashing]
(Wheezing, Gasping]
(Straining)
(Both Grunting)
(Shouts)
(Engine Starts]
Nobody else? Okay. All right.
Well, phone it in.
Get some help.
God.
Is he gonna make it?
Were you a part of this, Dave?
No, sir.
No?
So how come you were out there?
Why the hell didn't you call in?
BobJohnson phoned sayin' that he heard
Sonny agreeing to somethin' out at Buoy 1 2...
and I just lit out.
- I wasn't thinkin'.
- Well, it's a mess.
A goddamn mess.
- They all have better sense than that.
- Isn't no question.
You figure Fred and Eddie are both dead?
- It was a terrible explosion.
- You think there'll be much out there?
Fire took most of it.
Well, you take a look around tomorrow,
and you file a report.
Make it simple.
I don't want this draggin' on forever.
Thank you, sir.
You gonna be okay?
(Helicopter Whirring]
- (Door Opens]
- (Footsteps Approaching]
(Door Closes]
He's alive, barely.
Where is he?
Flew him off to Tallahassee.
(Exhales)
(Keys Jingling)
(Keys Jingling]
(Door Closes]
(Engine Starts]
(Woman]
Dr. Taylor, this is Drew Hickey calling.
(Continues, Indistinct]
(Indistinct)
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
- Okay, will do.
- (Grunts)
(Handset Settles In Cradle]
Where's Mom?
Oh, she went to the hospital.
Uh, she went to go help someone.
And will they be okay?
I don't know, sugar. I hope so.
- You gotta take a bath, Dad.
- Mm-hmm.
You're a mess.
- I gotta get ready.
- Okay.
(Sighs)
(Phone Rings]
I know.
Even a few hours
in the water can do that.
There any sign of Fred?
From what you said,
he's probably already shark food.
You can never fiigure it. Eddie had to
have floated all the way across this bay.
(Rain Pattering]
(Thunder Rumbling]
Ann.
Hi.
Um, Nurse?
(Sniffies)
Mr. Mann?
It's nice to have you awake.
Can you hear me?
You're in the hospital.
Track my fingers, please.
I'll be right back.
- Where's Dave?
- He'll be by later.
He had to go by the office or something.
(Footsteps Approaching]
Dave?
(Chuckles)
You weren't supposed to be there.
So, what's the law got in mind?
Nothin'.
It's done.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
We need to wrap this up.
Mr. Mann needs his rest.
You take care.
Later, old man.
Love you both.
(Sighs)
Looks like he's gonna be all right.
Looks like it.
- (Door Closes]
- (Footsteps Shuffling]
That was certainly a grand display
of male bonding.
I guess there's nothin' like
owin' a man your life.
You know, too bad
you two aren't one guy.
Then my life would be simple...
and fun.
What?
Sonny and I...
That friend you saved...
has been screwing your wife.
And she loved it.
Uh-uh.
Is that it?
(Slap)
(Sighs)
First you stay away, and now Dad.
I'm gettin' worried.
Don't be, Trishy.
Next time you have to tell us, okay?
Oh, you bet.
Now, finish your supper.
I hope Daddy's all right.
(Sighs)
- (Woman] * Throw all our cares away *
- (Chattering)
* 'Cause it's a ragtop day *
* It's a ragtop day *
* Classy little white and red
turns everybody's head *
For you.
- My baby keeps me at the five-and-dime
- Thanks, man.
He's always right on time
We'll roll all our cares away
* 'Cause it's a ragtop day *
* It's a ragtop day *
* Cruise across the county line *
* A little drink and dine
a drive-in picture show *
- * When the midnight's comin'down *
- (No Audible Dialogue)
* We're headin'back to town
He lets his lovin'show *
Let's go.
Can you believe they let
that kind of mess in here?
See the ring on his finger?
Too predictable.
Let's sit at the bar.
* Feels like we're the only ones
to see the morning sun *
* Don't the stars look bright **
(Sighs)
Speaking strictly as a nurse,
you've gotta stop treating your body this way.
(Chuckles)
- How are you feelin'?
- Better than you, I'd suspect.
How's Dave?
I was gonna ask you.
He hasn't been home or to work in a week.
Not since we were all here.
You know that night was hell.
And for Dave, pullin' me out
of the water was the easy part.
- Eddie... Dave had to...
- I told him... about us.
jesus.
Um, what were you saying?
It doesn't work, does it?
Maybe we're just none of us strong enough...
to all the time stay crazy.
I meant every minute of it.
Run away with me and bring the kids.
Get better.
(Woman]
* Sun shines on Biloxi *
jose Cuervo, straight up.
* Air is fiilled with vapors *
* From the sea *
* Boy will dig a pool *
- * Beside the ocean *
- (Laughing)
I've seen you here before.
That's right.
* And the sun will set *
* Off towards New Orleans *
* Stars can see Biloxi *
You dance?
* Stars can fiird their faces *
* In the sea *
* We are walking down *
* Beside the ocean *
(Chuckles)
* We are splashing naked *
* In the water *
- (Moaning)
- * And the sky is red *
* From off towards *
* New Orleans **
The kids okay?
They'll be glad to see you back.
Ah, yeah.
Where do you think we'd be
if Sonny hadn't come back?
Happy.
Maybe.
And maybe not much else.
I mean, this way, who knows?
What a mess.
You're gonna have some explaining to do
to Tate and the rest.
I'll think of somethin'.
Me too.
Good thing about paintin' cars...
pretty much go anywhere
in the country and get a job.
- One place is as good as another. Is that it?
- That's right.
Mainly, I feel I've caused
enough trouble around here.
As soon as Pa's business is cleared up,
I'll probably head out.
You do what you think.
Don't be afraid to take your time though.
This thing work?
- ** (Rock]
- (Man] * They call me the breeze *
* I keep blowin'down *
- Dave?
- Yeah?
You oughta let me paint somethin' for you.
House, car...
I'll make it look like new again.
** (Fades]
(Hound Barking]
Come on! We've got
somethin' to show you.
Sonny?
- Well, I'll be damned.
- (Bob] All right. Good.
Let's get on outside
before the food gets cold.
- Hey, y'all come on outside.
- Let's eat!
- I need some food.
- Go!
- Got hamburgers up in here.
- And they're good. I know they're good.
- You outdid yourself again, as always.
- You want a hamburger?
- Yeah.
All right. You get a hamburger.
(Chattering)
** (Ann Singing, Indistinct]
* Come from the number one school
Shark bite, shark bite *
(Sonny] * Go, you mighty sea sharks
Ooh, ooh, ooh *
(Sonny, Ann] * Bite their fuckin'heads off
* Go, you mighty sea sharks
Ooh, ooh, ooh *
* (Indistinct]
* Go Sharks **