ASCII code 255 is truly invisible to VLC and Subtitle Workshop 2.5.1
-  -
----- HTML nbsp's are invisible to VLC but NOT to Subtitle Workshop 2.5.1 -----
FIRST russian @ line 285 @ 22:37  - "After the soul is extracted"
SECOND russian line 487 @ 44:16 @ - "What did you write here?"
THIRD russian @ line 545 @ 49:07  - "Have you seen this?"
FOURTH russian @ line 561 @ 49:51  - "You shouldn't judge by appearances."
FIFTH russian @ line 581 @ 51:22 - "Do you have any American films"
SIXTH russian @ line 640 @ 57:35 - "Do you know when she plans to return the soul?"
SEVENTH russian @ line 721 @ 01:06:17 - "You said everything was fine!"
EIGHTH RUSSIAN @ line 762 @ 01:09:05 - "tell him."
NINTH russian @ line 783 @ 01:10:21 - "Get him out of my sight"
TENTH russian @ line 813 @ 01:13:19 - "Sveta, I'm sorry."
Comments have been given time start/stop durations, amounting to 000 secs of duration.
and are usually preceded by a face bracket {
{} RUSSIAN 01 START
After the soul is extracted
in New York.
You'll travel with Nina
and one other mule.
Yes... Dimitri.
I don't get it...
You didn't make the quota
again this month.
Yes.
And the military?
They passed on it.
We have to identify new outlets
and it takes time... Dimitri...
I'm not arguing...
If the US government steps in
we're out of business.
I want my soul back.
I'm sorry, that's impossible.
You signed the NCNR clause here.
It's non-cancelable, non-returnable.
No.
What if everyone was doing that?
We wouldn't be in business,
would we?
{} RUSSIAN 02 START
Nina, what did you write here?
That's the scientist.
He didn't believe he had a soul.
Next!
Sasha, how many poets' souls do we have?
Fourteen.
No... Not enough.
All right.
So the scientist is a poet and...
...this one also...
"Jellybean".
Boss?
20,000?
Have you seen it?
Seen what?
For crying out loud!
It looks like a prune!
Get out!
Next!
Listen up.
We're selling Russian souls to Americans.
What about selling...
American souls to Russians?
Who wants to buy an American soul?
Well, Oleg...
Sveta, to begin with.
Don't you, honey?
She says to have an American soul
will help her acting.
She made a list.
Kevin Spacey, George Clooney,
Robert Redford, Al Pacino...
Baby...
No actresses?
Why don't you pick some actresses too?
You guys add some females in there.
How do you expect us to do that?
You'll find a way, Oleg.
{} RUSSIAN 03 START
Have you seen this?
It's a chickpea. (This line was NOT in Russian)
It's a pea...
For God's sake.
A chickpea.
The shape doesn't mean anything.
It's a beautiful soul.
Does Dimitri know about this?
Get him!
Get him now!
I want him to see what he does to me!
Fellas. I've got a little problem...
{} RUSSIAN 04 START
You shouldn't judge by appearances.
Al Pacino won three Oscars.
But it's a chickpea!
A chickpea!
It'll work fine.
{} RUSSIAN 05 START
Do you have any American films with Paul Giamatti?
Who?
Paul Giamatti. Paul Giamatti.
{} RUSSIAN 06 START
Do you know when she plans to return the soul?
I'm not paying you to ask questions.
{} RUSSIAN 07 SECTION
You said everything was fine!
Yes...
then they found out.
So what?
It's not my problem.
He's here now.
So yes, it's your problem.
How much is he paying you?
I'm doing you a favor.
So you don't lose Flintstein.
You really think I'm an idiot?
You can't trust anyone, can you?
{} RUSSIAN 08 SECTION START
Nina...
tell him.
You tell him.
{}  RUSSIAN 09 SECTION START
Get him out of my sight...
or I'm gonna lose it.
{} RUSSIAN 10 SECTION START
Sir, we're busy here...
you'll have to leave.
I'm sorry.
What are you doing here?
Who is this guy?
He's a famous actor in America.
He came all the way from New York...
Dimitri knows about this?
Please! You're disturbing everyone!
What is she... What are you...
What is she doing?
No need to call him. He knows.
He lied, right?
Not at all. It's not what you think.
{} RUSSIAN 11 START
Is he a relative?
No, just a friend from America.
I didn't know
she had friends in America.
Olga...
two weeks ago...
committed suicide.
She had no family.
Do you want her address?
{}  RUSSIAN 12 SECTION
I didn't know she had friends
in America.
She never paid on time.
Except before the tragedy...
She paid off all her debts at once.
All this is going into the garbage.
Is he your husband?
You can take that.
{} NO FURTHER RUSSIAN LANGUAGE
All English language transcriptions were removed to create this file.
Russian language sections were only retimed and trimmed for (apparent) snugness.
No english spelling corrections required! GRATZ!
Only one english term (extreme pedantry) altered within the text. GRATZ!
Original source file was COLD SOULS [2009] DVD Rip Xvid [StB] complete subtitles, supplied.
Profuse thanks to all the authors and translators who have gone before me on this file.
Daudz paldies visiem!