A dog in golden armor
is still a dog.
What did you say?
- He said, "Caesar is great."
- There's a curfew.
Do not be seen
on the street again, Jew.
But we must buy food
for Passover.
Buy it then,
and get off the street!
Yes. Yes.
- If I were a younger man-
- You surely would have taught him a lesson.
The streets are buzzing,
Caiaphas.
It's this time of year.
Jews come to Jerusalem
from all the precincts.
Did I ever tell you, Caiaphas,
I have a son?
He's three years old.
Back in Rome. I miss him.
I want to get back to him.
It is your job to keep the peace
here in Arimathea.
What are you trying
to tell me?
My soldiers have arrested
four troublemakers-
so-called,
um, prophets.
Do you understand me?
If I hear of someone else,
I'll hand them over to you.
You have...
no power to arrest.
How does it feel,
a Jew handing over a Jew...
to Roman authorities?
It doesn't feel good.
But my responsibility
is to protect the law of our people...
the law of God.
And if I'm wrong...
and one of those prophets
is the real Messiah...
let history judge me.
Let history judge.
Hmm.
Lord, what have we done
to deserve such a fate?
For heaven's sake!
- What's wrong?
- Gamaliel.
Must he be late
on a day like this?
It's not his nature
to be late.
Well, this is not
a day to start.
But the Roman soldiers are everywhere.
Maybe we should consider his safety first.
I'm sure he's safe.
It's just that...
Isaiah prophesied that the Messiah
would come during these times.
Why won't the other rabbis
just accept that?
Do you believe that
this dark-skinned Nazarene is really him?
I-I don't know, Nicodemus.
But one thing
I am sure of.
If this Joshua
is indeed the Messiah...
I fear we may be too late.
Arimathea.
My deliverance
shall happen here, my brother.
Today begins Passover,
master.
The Romans would not dare
violate this holy holiday.
Peter, to those who seek to harm
the Messiah, today is just another day.
I don't believe the Romans
would want to disturb the peace.
I'm afraid Thaddeus
may be right, Peter.
Are we there yet, master?
I'm tired, and I can't journey much farther.
Too much complaining
from you.
Perhaps we should carry
this young girl into Arimathea.
- Come on.
- Let's go.
Hide, quickly!
Rabbi, why hide?
Those dogs are outnumbered.
He who lives by the sword,
Judas, dies by the sword.
Good.
All right.
Up. Up. Let us go.
John, come quickly. Quickly. Quick.
I want you to go down
into Arimathea...
and set up preparation
for the Passover meal.
But, master, the centurion guards
are all over Arimathea.
Shouldn't we have the feast
somewhere more secure?
Do you question
my love for you, John?
Do you think
I would place you in harm's way?
- No. I-
- Then go.
And trust in me.
- I'm sorry, master.
- Good.
Now, when you enter town, you'll observe
a man carrying a pitcher of water.
You will follow him
to his house.
There, you will ask
the goodman of the house.
Tell him that the Son
of God has sent you...
and wishes to know where he shall eat
the Passover meal with his disciples.
Okay, go. Wait.
Leave this.
Quickly, quickly.
Go, go, go.
- Yes, master.
- Quickly, quickly!
My Father will protect them.
Come.
Papa, mother said you'd
have the chair fixed before feast time.
Don't worry. I'll get to it.
By the way, where is your mother?
She's at market, Papa.
But it's almost sundown...
and we have all the chametz
to still remove from this place...
and so many preparations
to do before then.
Lord, the one trait my daughters inherit
from their mother-
- They worry too much.
- Papa, I'm sorry.
Don't worry,
my dear daughter.
Will you be having seder
with us tonight?
No, Papa. Ruth and I must be
with our husbands.
We have only come
to help Mama.
I marry off my daughters, and
now they have no time for me.
Mmm, matzo!
Ezra!
You know that's for seder.
- But I'm hungry now, Leah!
- Ah!
Ezra, what do you think
God thinks of such disrespectful behavior?
- Sorry, Papa.
- You go wash up so you and Father...
can dip yourselves
in holy water before you eat.
That's right, Son. The mikvah,
a very important ritual in our religion.
Hi, Papa.
Where's Mama?
She's out to market.
- May I ask you a question, Papa?
- Sure, Son.
- It's about Joshua.
- Continue.
I am a young man now...
and I know that you have done
everything to protect us.
But I was thinking,
maybe I should join Joshua.
Out of the question.
It would break your mother's heart.
I understand that he has
a prophecy to fulfill.
But why didn't
he include me?
Let me explain, James.
Your older brother
loves you very much...
but these are
dangerous times...
and he understands
his sacrifice is his alone.
Do you understand?
Yes, Papa.
I understand.
In time,
your role will come.
Pardon my delay.
On my way here, I was delayed.
- Roman soldiers?
- Who else?
More came to town,
doubling their numbers.
They're relentless in their search
for the black Nazarene.
Rumor is he's hiding
somewhere in the hills.
- It may take weeks for them to find him.
- This is no good.
- What is wrong?
- We have been informed that there will be...
an emergency meeting of the entire
Sanhedrin body tonight.
- But I was not informed of any-
- Hear me, Gamaliel.
The entire membership
is being contacted as we speak.
They think they're near
to capture this Nazarene.
- It may be as early as tonight.
- But how?
- Caiaphas has eyes everywhere.
- You mean he hired a spy?
Yes. One of
the Nazarene's disciples.
And our fear is that this man's capture
may lead to more violence on the streets.
You both know how I feel
about this carpenter.
I have heard him lecture before.
He knows the Torah
better than most rabbis I know.
I find him to be
a very learned man.
But he's black,
and to say...
that he is the Messiah,
it is blasphemy.
The Torah does not mention
as to what he will look like.
Not to mention that he is still a Jew,
regardless of his skin color.
Passover.
The worst time of year.
What's next for you,
Horatius?
Ah.
Keep the peace for
seven days in Arimathea...
then I go back
to my beloved Rome, eh?
Jews.
You cannot trust them.
- Look. He carries water.
- He carries carpet.
Perhaps our master
should heal your eyes. There.
There is the servant
we are to follow. Come.
In a hurry, citizens?
Only to get my friend
out of this heat.
He sure is to collapse if
I don't get him home quickly.
He speaks the truth.
The feast will bring me welcome relief.
Don't let me see you again,
lest you celebrate your feast in chains.
My friend, might I ask
if we could get a message to your master?
- I'm sorry. I cannot help you.
- Please!
Our master has sent us.
The Messiah.
Wait here.
Yes?
Can I help you?
Our master has sent us
with a message.
And what is the message?
He wishes to know where
he will eat the Passover meal with his disciples.
Come, quickly.
Come!
Please.
Is it all right?
Is it good?
Yes. Thank you for
opening your home to us.
- We apologize for any inconvenience.
- Oh, please, not to worry.
Let the Messiah know
that I am humbly grateful...
that he has chosen
my home for his seder meal.
- I will tell him.
- Thank you.
We camp here.
We camp here!
Why here, rabbi?
Open, clean space
to honor the Passover.
What's wrong, Peter?
I'm tired of running around
like rats...
having to hide
in these mountains...
not being able to sleep in one place
for more than one night.
We knew there'd be
a price to pay for the truth, Peter.
At least if it was Romans,
there'd be some excuse.
But not Jews, rabbis.
Blessed are ye
when men shall persecute you.
We have enough water
to last us till tomorrow...
some sheep,
some dried fish.
Good, good.
Take Simon with you.
Patrol the hillside.
Make sure
everything's safe.
Simon!
- Rabbi, I'm still-
- Not to worry, Peter.
My Father
has led us here.
Fine.
After we have pitched tent,
gather the rest.
Yes, master.
Make sure the sheep are fed.
He's a wild one, master.
Such beautiful fur.
If only mankind would embrace
that which is different-
black sheep.
Bring more water.
Philip.
Thank you.
We've been traveling all night. Who do you
think gets to sleep in the tent tonight?
The sheep, Philip.
- Hold that steady, Matthew.
- For heaven's sake, don't miss!
Your right hand, Matthew,
has always been a bit useless.
Perhaps if I miss, he'll be able
to develop the left.
Real funny, Thaddeus.
Hey, can you people help us?
It is not fair that only two people set up
the tent while the rest watch.
No, Matthew's right.
He shouldn't be the only one
to get his finger crushed.
Two feet, one hand, no brain.
He's a centurion guard.
Thaddeus has a reputation in Jerusalem
for breaking hands.
Look! Even my hand was broken.
That's for not paying
your taxes.
Stay there, Matthew.
I'll crush your hand later.
Matthew is right.
We must all help.
Good neighbors. It reminds me
of a story our master told us.
- The story of the Good Samaritan.
- Oh, come on!
- Get out with the story.
- It worked for our master.
The master's
a better storyteller than you.
Yes, that is true.
But I'm a better cook.
That's not funny.
Why so quiet,
Bartholomew?
I really love these times.
I understand.
You know,
the beauty of family...
is that when I first
started following our master...
I had just one brother.
Now I have 12.
Come. Come on.
Come, quickly.
Hurry.
- Were you two followed?
- We were extra careful and took a back road.
- Good.
- Where is our master?
He's in prayer.
He's waiting for you. Come quickly.
Quickly!
Come.
Sorry to bother you,
master.
My Father...
can be very selfish
with our daily conversations.
What news do you bring?
The goodman has sent word that he would
be honored to have your presence in his home.
Good.
Gather the rest.
If I don't leave now, I'll definitely be late
for Mikvah. Come, James.
- Hurry.
- You all be sure to be careful.
- Please.
- Don't worry. We'll be careful.
- James, take Ezra into the courtyard, please.
- Yes, Father. Come.
Look, Mary, we can't change what is.
I know how you're feeling.
I would like him here as much as you.
But he's not ours anymore.
But I feel it is we
who have led him down this path.
Stop blaming yourself for what is happening.
We knew this day would come.
Nothing can prepare a mother
for something like this, Joseph.
Thirty-three years ago,
you told me...
that you felt something
happening inside of you...
and I truly believe that God
did touch you that night.
Somehow,
something divine happened...
and you were chosen among all the women
of Judea to carry the chosen one.
Do you think they're
doing this because he's black?
No.
They're doing this
because he's the Messiah.
Master, may I ask you a question?
You may, Thomas.
How does it feel...
to be different?
In my Father's eyes, Thomas,
we are all different...
yet we are all the same.
My mother,
a very glorious woman...
when she was pregnant
with child-
With you, master?
I'm afraid so.
She was denied lodging
at a local inn in Bethlehem...
because she was
so different.
She was forced
to give birth in a manger.
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry,
Thomas?
Because I-I understand.
Because I am a poor fisherman...
and I've been mistreated
because of it.
My Father was right.
We are all the same.
But you will find...
that when
you are righteous...
kings will find you...
and kneel at your feet.
Come.
Come. Come.
Master, what if they catch us?
Then it would be
my Father's will, Thaddeus.
Thank you, Messiah, for gracing our home
with your presence.
I am humbled.
You are blessed.
Stand.
- Show me to your master.
- Yes.
A blessing is upon you,
goodman.
Shall you share
a feast with us?
I would like nothing better, rabbi,
but this is your time, and I dare not intrude.
Besides, I must go downstairs
and watch the door.
My servant here will assist
in anything else you may need.
Thank you.
- You see, my brothers, God has provided.
- Yes.
You remember? Like the Egyptians.
Pass him the wine.
Then pass the wine to me.
Today, my loved ones...
we sit together in remembrance
of our exodus as Jews...
from slavery in Egypt.
My Father instructed
the Israelites of old...
to place the blood of a virgin lamb
on their doorpost...
and only then, the plague
smiting the firstborn in all of Egypt...
would pass over them.
Today, and for seven days...
we sit in remembrance
of this glorious Passover.
But there is another reason...
we have gathered tonight.
Verily I say unto you...
one of you shall betray me.
- What?
- No!
Earlier in the garden...
my Father spoke with me
and told me...
that one of you that dips in the sop
with me shall betray me.
No, master.
It's impossible.
Everyone at this table loves you.
- Do you call my Father a liar, Thomas?
- No.
- Master, who is this traitor?
- Is it me, master?
- Who would do this?
His hands are indeed
at this table.
Whoever this traitor be...
let him reveal himself now...
before any harm
comes to our master.
For soon, I promise you that man by whom
the Son of man is betrayed...
will wish he had
never been born.
How do we know
the traitor isn't you, Peter?
Me?
Peter, don't!
I question you, Thomas,
for whom it came so hard...
to accept the Messiah
in the first place.
Do you really wish
to kill me, Peter?
- Master.
- Please stop this.
Peter, enough.
My Father shall deal with
the traitor in his own way.
All I needed was
a little more time.
But my hour draws near.
We don't understand, master.
You have always been
so naive, John.
You will come to understand
that through my death...
will come much life.
The sins of the world
will be washed away.
We all love you, master, and I believe
every man here would give his life for you.
Master, we have all
loved you for years.
What makes you think that we would ever,
ever do anything to hurt you?
Nonsense!
Absolute nonsense!
- Do you think you love him more than us, Peter?
- Not more than I!
I love him more
than any of you ever will.
The black Nazarene
and his followers take a noisy feast.
There is a reward
for his capture. Come.
Tell us, master,
who among us loves you more...
and who in death shall be next to you
in your Father's kingdom?
James, how can you ask
the Messiah such a question?
We've all been
thinking about it...
whispering it among
ourselves for weeks now.
I think we have
a right to know.
Let him speak.
Continue, James.
Master, it is clear
you love us all.
But we wish to know,
who is the greatest among us 12?
Greatest?
For who is greater,
he that sits at the table...
or he that serves?
He who is greatest among you
shall be the one who chooses to serve.
And I will appoint unto him,
that servant...
a kingdom as my Father
has given to me.
After I am gone...
you will continue
to serve mankind...
with the teachings
I have given you.
Then and only then...
will you share
in my glory.
Remove your sandals...
so that I
may wash your feet.
I know you love me, Judas.
Do you not obey
your master, Peter?
Master, I will never
let you wash my feet.
If I do not
wash your feet, Peter...
then you will have
no part of me.
In that case,
don't just wash my feet.
Wash my hands and my head
as well...
so that I may have
all of you.
You need only wash your feet,
Peter, and you are clean.
But some of you
will never be clean.
Some say he shows the tendencies
of a cult leader.
But possibly,
he is the Messiah.
But, Nicodemus, how can you abandon
the teachings of the Torah and even suggest that?
I said possibly.
A prophet he might be...
but a Messiah as foretold
by the Torah?
The very Torah tells us the Messiah
will descend from the line of David.
- And so?
- And this man is from that very lineage.
- As were countless others.
- But he was also born in Bethlehem...
as was foretold
by the prophets.
Rabbis, these two have word
where the black Nazarene has taken refuge.
- It that true?
- Yes, rabbi.
We've seen him
with our own eyes.
- I've already notified the prefect.
- You may leave us.
Tell us what you have seen.
There's a small matter of reward
for information on the false prophet.
Five pieces of silver if your information
leads us to the man we seek.
- The Nazarene travels with 12 followers.
- Are they armed?
Forgive me, fellow rabbis, but perhaps
we should notify Caiaphas immediately.
Caiaphas will be quick
to respond.
We need to know if they are armed,
lest we send soldiers to seize them...
that may be overpowered
and slaughtered.
Do you want their blood
on your hands, Gamaliel?
This day may be
our last Passover together.
It is just a matter of time
before I am captured and killed.
They'll be met with swords
before we let that happen.
It is too late, Peter.
This is the cup of my blood...
the blood
of the everlasting life.
It will be given up for you...
and for all men.
Do this in memory of me.
I shall not drink again...
until it is fulfilled
in my Father's kingdom.
This bread...
is not just bread.
It is my body...
which shall be
given up for you.
Share in my flesh.
Have any of you seen
a black Jew?
He travels with a dozen men.
A black Jew?
I've seen no black Jews.
Search the house, hmm?
Where are they, hmm?
Under penalty of death,
you'd best answer in truth.
If I find
that you are lying-
On my word, soldier,
I've seen no one.
We were just having
Passover dinner.
My Father speaks the truth,
really.
There's no one like that here.
Please.
Horatius, we've searched
the house. Nothing.
I promise to seek you out
if I should see him. Please.
Jews.
Go!
Father, what's so special
about tonight?
'Cause on this night, we celebrate
our freedom as Jews, each of us...
as though Moses had led us
out of the wilderness only yesterday.
Where is he?
We have not seen him!
- You lie!
- He is my son, yes.
But do you see him
here with us?
We gave him up
a long time ago.
- Search the house!
- Yes, Horatius.
It has begun.
Our time left here
is short, my loved ones.
We must leave quickly.
We will see you
safely, master.
Peter. Peter, Satan demanded
to have you...
so that he may sift
through you like wheat.
But I pray for you.
It never will.
You have my word, rabbi.
I'll always be by your side.
What if I told you...
that before the rooster
crows twice tonight...
you shall betray
knowing me three times?
- Peter deny you, Lord?
- How could Peter?
I'd see any of us deny you
before Peter.
Please.
Please, master.
Don't tell me this.
But I shall pray for you.
How can Peter's faith
be shaken?
I don't understand this.
You will all fall away.
Master.
I saw the goodman in the house
allow him in...
with half of his group
still in watch.
Rabbis. They make
their Passover right now.
You must send soldiers for them quickly
before they can escape.
It is true, Joseph of Arimathea,
Nicodemus, we really should.
Must I hear from the Romans
the black Nazarene has been found?
The truth.
Yes, Rabbi Caiaphas.
It is true.
These two have seen him.
- I kept insisting we should bring him in.
- Is this true?
- Yes.
- We believe it is him.
This impostor is a threat
to all of us.
Gamaliel, order the guard
to take five soldiers...
and follow this man to the house wherein
hides this blasphemer.
This way! We are going to get
the false prophet! Hurry!
Quickly, master, this way.
Go.
You'll feel the lash man's whip
for this, goodman. Hmm?
Gladly.
Go.
Go, go, go.
- What's wrong, Judas?
- Rabbi, maybe I should pick up
some supplies for us.
Where shall you and the rest meet
that I may find you?
Gethsemane.
I love you, master.
Judas, your way
is not my way...
but you go do
what you must do.
Go.
Go, go.
Master, is it him?
- Judas.
- Judas!
Yet, you let him steal
all our donations...
and run off
to betray you.
What is to be fulfilled,
we cannot stop. Go.
It is too late.
They've disappeared into the darkness.
Marcus, you take several soldiers.
Head towards the east, the hillsides.
The rest of us will go north!
Let's go!
Disperse!
They will be found tonight.
We must put them all on the cross!
Breathe a sound, traitor.
Even in betrayal,
he is glorious.
And if it was not for our master,
I would open your throat.
- Judas!
- What are you doing here?
The streets are dangerous.
Come with me quickly, lest you be discovered
as one of Joshua's followers. Come.
I hold you both accountable
for allowing this heretic...
to slip through our fingers!
- Herod will know of this.
- We are keepers of the Torah.
We should not involve Rome
in a strictly Jewish issue.
This carpenter has incited difficulties
ever since he came to the district.
The Romans will
make it their problem.
As if their presence in Judea
wasn't enough already.
I have seen the centurion guards march about
this place as if it was their own backyard.
Let's give them
no more reason.
Gentlemen, I'm not convinced this Joshua
of Nazareth is the threat he's purported to be.
It's true, rabbi.
We've seen so many false prophets.
What makes this man different than any man
who claims to be the Messiah?
Surely. How many such men have
we seen in recent years?
Ten? Twenty?
What makes this carpenter...
and his army of 12 fishermen
such a terrible threat?
You wish to see
the difference?
Go. Look outside
and see the difference!
Now's not the time, Judas.
- When is it ever the time?
- Where are the others?
- Is Joshua all right?
- As best I know, yes.
He and the others escaped into the hillside
towards Gethsemane.
Why did you not go with them?
Joshua sent me
for supplies.
If not for you stopping me,
I'd be at the marketplace-
Mary Magdalene,
why do you stare at me so?
I know Joshua
loves you greatly.
Why would he risk
sending you into town?
I told you,
he sent me for supplies.
- Where are your supplies?
- I had no time. The crowd- I feared for my life.
If you're on your way
to the temple precinct-
Would you betray him, Judas?
My actions
would never betray him.
- Only force his hand.
- To following your way?
It is the only way.
Violence is the only language
these Romans speak.
It is foolish to think
we could drive them out of Judea...
by spreading word ahead
and performing miracles.
They laugh at us!
Trust me.
They will not laugh when they feel the sting
of a thousand Jewish swords.
And then what? They will send
a whole army to overpower you.
Then we'll raise
a bigger army.
His way was foretold
by the scriptures, Judas.
Do you doubt
he's the Messiah?
I believe him, maybe.
But it is his passive ways
I find fault with.
Judas, he is a man of peace.
Peace won't drive out
the Romans!
His way will succeed much faster
than your army of zealots.
You say that...
only because it is easier to love the Messiah
than a fisherman.
What is it you see in him
that is not in me?
The truth.
Well, here is my truth.
Fine.
Would you like a feast
your master has yet to enjoy?
Yes! A feast with bread!
And power!
Absolute glory!
Yes!
He will come as a mighty king
arriving on horseback...
leading a great army
of warriors!
Where is this Nazarene's army?
I see only an army of fishermen!
Who does this
black Nazarene think he is?
Oh, he proclaims that he rules
over the kingdom of heaven.
A kingdom of
dark-skinned Jews!
Well, I will be a part
of no such kingdom!
- Yes!
- Nothing good ever came from Nazareth.
Who comes?
Go, Abaddon! Go!
Go tell them.
Tell Caiaphas what you know
about this false prophet.
Tell him! Tell him everything!
Let him know!
Tell him, Abaddon.
He blasphemes.
- Papa!
- We returned as soon as we heard.
- Where's Mama?
- Shh! Mama is resting.
- Come help us.
- Oh!
What business
do you have here, woman?
- I wish to speak to you.
- What does she want?
Tell her to go. There is no room
for sinners here.
- Go tend to your mother.
- But, Papa, she's-
Now!
Speak.
I have come in hopes
of saving the life of your son.
- What about my son?
- Judas goes now to betray him to the Sanhedrin.
Judas!
By my own hands, I'll-
There is no time.
We must hurry and warn the Messiah.
He and his followers have seeked refuge
in the mountains of Gethsemane.
- How do you know this?
- I was with Judas tonight.
You did what?
Only to delay the pig so that Joshua
would have more time to escape.
But I cannot stand in judgment
of the profession...
by which you've chosen to live your life,
Mary Magdalene.
But my son did forgive your sins,
and he is greater than us all.
- Thank you.
- We must hurry.
But I will get noticed.
Mary will accompany you.
My mother is hurt the most.
She understands the journey
I have taken...
the journey that I must take...
because I love you.
I love you too, Thomas.
And my Father loves you.
But she is a woman of old...
and I'm her youngest son.
I hope she doesn't think
I'm a disappointment.
A disappointment, Thomas?
You have been chosen
to carry my message.
How can that be
a disappointment?
It is my Father's message.
And when I am long gone...
men will speak of us-
how the Son of God came
to fulfill a prophecy...
with the help
of 12 chosen men.
But, master,
my mother thinks...
I've left my fishing nets behind
to take up with a false prophet-
that I have given up
my real service.
Is that what you believe,
Thomas?
No.
Master, I believe in you...
with every fiber that is me.
I know you've all been under
a great deal of strain-
the running and hiding.
There are rumors that they are looking for us,
and we might be killed.
Are you afraid, Andrew?
I am.
Who else among you
is afraid?
This grain of wheat...
if I throw it on the ground,
there it will lie and die.
But only when it dies
can it bear fruit.
In my death,
there will be life.
Have you brought all of us here
to die, master?
They are looking for us,
but they only want me.
- Master, it is not safe.
- Master, do not leave us yet. It is still early.
I have to go speak
with my Father.
Perhaps I should
accompany you, master.
Tonight, much danger
lurks in the darkness.
And we'll go as well.
Come.
Tell us about this Joshua,
since you speak so publicly of him.
My neighbor is a blind man
and has always been so.
This Nazarene came upon him
and laid hands on him...
and all at once,
my neighbor could see.
- This is sacrilegious!
- He should be arrested!
There's no crime
in restoring sight to a blind man.
- It is a blessing that the man received.
- Shh! Continue.
After restoring
the man's sight...
the Nazarene told him
of a kingdom in heaven...
where he would have
everlasting happiness.
See? This Nazarene speaks
nothing against the Torah.
I profess to you, Caiaphas,
this Joshua is nothing more than-
Forgive me.
Forgive me, rabbi, but there's more.
Let him speak.
Continue.
This Joshua from Nazareth,
this false prophet...
said the only way to enjoy
the kingdom of heaven...
- is through him.
- Through him?
What, he is the gatekeeper?
- He said through him
because he is the Son of God.
- The Son of God?
- He blasphemes!
Are you sure those were
the Nazarene's exact words, Abaddon?
I swear on
my own life, rabbi.
You see, rabbis, this is
what was meant by the vision...
had by Isaiah in the Talmud.
You are most insightful,
young Joshua.
Yes. Tell us, Joshua.
How is it that a boy of 12
could have so much knowledge?
My knowledge of the scriptures
is granted by my Father.
It could be said that all
knowledge is granted by God.
How is it that your knowledge
rivals the wisdom of rabbis...
who have devoted their
entire lifetimes to study?
Because I am the Son of God.
You may speak.
Rabbi...
I-I know three men that this so-called king
laid hands on.
One of them, Lazarus,
brother to Martha and Mary of Bethany...
was supposedly
brought back to life.
I've heard the rumors.
But there is but one
who has the power...
to summon a cold body up from the grave
and breathe life into it.
Satan.
He speaks the truth.
No godly man would awaken
a body from its grave...
after the almighty God...
in all his wisdom,
has taken him.
It is bold, brazen.
And there are more stories like this.
And what do you think now?
I thought so.
Blasphemer!
Clear the way!
Here he is.
He is named Judas.
Well, we have been waiting
for you, Judas of Iscariot.
Have you come
to tell us their location?
I have.
Where are they hiding?
In Gethsemane.
Gethsemane? A dozen poor fishermen
hiding in Gethsemane?
Tell us, Judas.
Gethsemane is a place of rest and relaxation
visited by only the wealthy.
Why would fisherman
hide there?
Maybe he figures it's a place
where we wouldn't think to look.
He is very clever.
You've done very well,
Judas of Iscariot.
The agreement was for
30 pieces of silver, correct?
Master, are you all right?
Just a little tired.
Weary.
Can we help, master?
When the soul is tired,
my love...
only prayer can bring about
some helpful relief.
Well, I can't stand this.
I can't stand it...
watching you
go through this.
Can't we just make our way
over the Kidron Valley?
Leave here?
And then what?
If only I could.
I don't want any part of it...
sitting here like sheep...
waiting for them
to take you away.
Do you really love me,
Peter?
With all my heart.
You know I do.
Here.
You take this
while I go pray.
Master?
What has happened to you?
Do you really care, Peter?
I don't understand.
I ask you to wait for me...
to watch over me
for one hour...
while I go speak
with my Father...
and you couldn't even
do that.
- We were just a little-
- Excuses.
All I ever hear are excuses.
Don't you think I am tired?
But you have to fight off
the sleep.
Beware of the flesh and anything
that is tempting.
Because the flesh is weak...
even if the spirit
is willing.
Beware, Peter.
Beware of temptation.
- Wait. Somebody comes.
- It's Judas.
- Judas!
Well done, Judas!
Yesterday, they cheer
a fisherman prophet who rides a donkey.
Today, they cheer
the man who betrayed him.
Who can understand
these Jews?
As a man, I must have
my views heard.
This Joshua of Nazareth
is nothing but a carpenter...
with a gift of the knowledge
of the scriptures.
Perhaps he is plagued
with a mental deficiency...
which causes him to think
that he is the Messiah.
Where is the harm?
He's able to convince only his fisherman
followers and a sprinkling of others.
A sprinkling of others?
Rabbis, I fear that you have both
spent far too long in this temple.
The Nazarene
and his disciples-
they are known
far and wide.
He is turning
the opinion of thousands.
He is just one man.
You speak of him as if he is the King of Jews
he professes himself to be.
- Maybe you dispute what's written in the Torah.
- What?
- Why, Joseph of Arimathea-
- Shush, shush, shush! Quiet!
Rabbis,
get hold of yourselves.
We merely sent for him.
- We're not sentencing him.
- It's one and the same.
It is my wish.
If I may suggest, Caiaphas, that whatever
are the opinions of us in here...
we bring him in
for his own safety.
The crowds would kill him
if they found him first.
How much further?
I hope we're not too late.
The Romans, in their heavy armor and boots,
cannot get along these paths as easily as we can.
They must travel a different road.
We will get to Gethsemane before they do.
How is it that
you know of this path?
Many wealthy men
spend time in Gethsemane.
When they desire my company,
they'd much rather be in places unseen.
Go.
- How armed are these fishermen?
- His men have but four swords among them...
but they will not fight.
A group of fishermen with four swords
and no will to fight?
I could have carried this mission out myself.
Horatius, do you remember Marias-
large man, red hair?
- He trained us in the lance.
- Oh, yes. I remember him.
Always joked about
killing Jews with his lance.
He washed over
in our journey here.
A shame. He was a man
who was born to his work.
Lucky he did not live
to see this day.
Roman officers being sent
by Jews to capture Jews.
What has our
Empire become?
No.
Having second thoughts,
Judas?
Hmm?
Always happens to traitors.
What is it, Jew?
- What is it?
- I know a shorter way.
Go.
My time draws near.
But, master,
what can we do?
I will issue one last
commandment to you all.
Anything, master.
After I die...
my work and message
must not die.
They will win...
only if they succeed
in silencing my message.
But they are mistaken.
What do you want us to do?
James, John, my sons of thunder...
you will speak in my voice...
and you will tell the others...
that they must sell
everything of value...
so that they can
spread my message.
All of you.
Outside Jerusalem...
towards Syria,
Asia...
past the Black Sea,
the Mediterranean...
and so on.
But how?
There are only 12 of us.
Twelve...
shall become a thousand.
And a thousand,
10,000.
And a million
and more.
We will do this.
Good.
My message will not die.
Drop your weapons!
Which of you is
Joshua of Nazareth?
I am he.
He lies.
I am Joshua.
You are not black enough, Jew.
Arrest them all!
- Protect yourselves!
- Enough! Enough!
I will come peacefully.
You betray me
with a kiss, Judas.
Enough!
The prophecy
must be fulfilled.
I will come quietly.
- Master, please.
- You will not go with them.
Messiah.
Time to meet your future,
Nazarene.
Let's go.
Join me.
Join me in paradise.
Master, may I ask you a question?
You may ask.
How does it feel to be different?
In my Father's eyes, Thomas...
we are all different...
yet we are all the same.