Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
"This film does not claim
to depict real events.
Any resemblance to persons,
living or dead,
is, as they say, coincidental."
Yes.
No.
Maybe. I don't know.
Get the papers to me
at the Hotel Meurice bar by noon.
Hang on.
Hello, darling?
Goddammit!
Okay for the Meurice?
Fine. See you there.
Le Figaro wants an interview.
They can attend
the press conference.
They all ask the same questions.
One answer will do.
My mother!
The French Open.
Get her a seat.
She needs to get out more.
Hello, darling?
We were cut off.
I don't know why.
I'm listening.
How much?
We'll see.
Meet you at the airport.
See you on Monday, sir.
Sir?
Evelyne, did you reserve
the kids' trip?
Yes, the apartment's all theirs.
What about the tickets?
Have them sent to their mother.
See you on Monday.
Try to get some rest.
Michelle, did you do as I asked?
Yes, sir.
You'll be in the royal suite.
It's been entirely renovated.
I saw the photos. It looks...
- Sensational.
- Good.
- How are the mattresses?
- I'll find out.
- I'll mention your allergies.
- Yes, thank you.
See you on Monday, sir.
Police.
Come with us.
What is this?
Jean-Noël, my briefcase.
What's going on?
You know who I am?
COMEDY OF POWER
What's going on?
I want to see my lawyer.
He's been notified.
Everything's legal. Go on.
My watch, too?
Good idea.
Undress, please.
Are you out of your mind?
You know who I am?
Your jacket, please.
Now your pants.
You must understand.
There must be advantages
on all sides, or some get resentful.
In the sixties,
champagne blowjobs were the thing.
Here's how it worked:
The person giving it made out well.
For the receiver, it changed nothing.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Senator Descarts,
the phone call you were expecting.
Yes, indeed.
I'll only be a minute.
Be my guest.
Don't you have a cell?
Only for outgoing calls.
I'm no greenhorn!
What do you think?
It will go fine, believe me.
I've known him for 30 years.
He has friends in high places.
Even now?
This mustn't hurt my country.
Don't worry.
If you play fair, so will he.
Pardon my ignorance,
but what's his constituency?
The North, despite his accent.
Here's a humdinger.
Our friend Humeau got caged
this morning.
- Isn't that a problem?
- Not at all.
That will keep them busy.
He'll be interrogated later.
He's in for it.
It's Charmant-Killman.
You know what they call her
at the courthouse?
The Piranha!
The Piranha.
- Is it all set?
- Hope so.
I'll know soon.
Do you have the diskette?
The diskette?
The CD Rom.
It's all there.
Sweep it under the rug if you like.
Not a chance. I hate rugs.
I thought so.
Thank you for trusting me.
It's mine.
Hello?
Indeed. Let's say around 3:00
this afternoon.
Then bring him in at 2:30.
But notify his lawyer.
Okay, but make sure anyway.
Thanks, see you later.
I shouldn't tell you this,
but I'm seeing our friend.
Then don't tell me.
Straight from a jail cell.
Maybe it will help his skin cells.
That wasn't nice.
Not very nice, no.
- Hello, Madame.
- Hello, Benoît.
- Your customer's here.
- Since when?
A good 15 minutes.
Bring him in.
You can remove the handcuffs.
Hello, Mr. Chairman.
Benoît, a seat.
Thanks.
No one taught you manners?
We're off to a good start.
Thank you.
We started ages ago,
Mr. Chairman.
May I introduce myself?
I'm Jeanne Charmant-Killman.
I'm the investigating judge.
Jeanne Charmant-Killman!
I pictured you taller.
Let's hope competence
isn't a matter of inches.
Where's my lawyer?
- What time is it? They took my watch.
- I have mine.
He must be stuck in traffic.
This is an outrage!
I was arrested and put in prison!
That wasn't my doing.
What do you want?
That I can tell you.
To charge you
with abuse of public funds,
abuse of trust, account-rigging...
The rest when your lawyer arrives.
How is that?
You're the group's CEO.
So you open the festivities.
Then I'll question no. 2,
no. 3 and so on.
What's wrong?
A skin disease.
I need medication.
Come in.
Hello, Mr. Parlebas.
Hello, Madame.
This is a bit last minute.
But you're here.
Please, have a seat.
I won't last without medication.
- My client needs his medication.
- I heard.
A prison doctor will examine him,
as is the rule.
I haven't read the file.
You're in luck.
You have all afternoon.
To read all this?
Your client's kept me very busy.
Well, I'm done for the day.
You'll have time to catch up.
Your glove.
I saw it, thanks.
- See you tomorrow, then.
- I'm spending the night in jail?
As I said, not my doing.
But it's an experience.
And you're in the VIP block.
- You don't miss a trick.
- She wants her name in the papers.
Try another tack.
Benoît, you'll handle it?
I will, Madame.
See you tomorrow.
What's this?
You're in good spirits.
What's up?
Humeau.
I think I've got him.
He thought he'd slip
through my fingers.
Jacques Sibaud's been a great help.
He doesn't beat around the bush.
I said you ran a medical lab.
What's it to him?
It just came out in the conversation.
And how was your day?
The usual crap.
Five HIV positives.
And three new cases of salmonella.
Isn't life wonderful?
At least your work is useful.
What's the bag in the hall?
Your worthless nephew.
That worthless nephew
is your brother's son.
Since I stopped talking to my family,
what's mine is yours, my dear.
I took a shower.
You did well.
Did Uncle explain?
Can I crash here?
No, but crash as long as you like.
A little youth will do us good.
Right, darling?
Of course.
Like I said, make yourself at home.
Careful!
You should find a job. How could you
quit civil service school?
- It was the highway to success.
- I doze off on highways.
And I was fed up.
And exhausted
like you wouldn't believe.
A lack of ambition?
Sorry to change the subject,
but where do you stand?
- Where do I stand?
- What case are you on?
A whopper.
I'll tell you about it.
- What did I do wrong?
- It's backwards.
You're right.
No time to shop.
I'll order pizza.
What would you do if you were rich?
The issue has never come up.
I'm asking. Simulate expenditures
to define the buying impulse.
- That's all they do in school.
- They do that in school?
Jeanne Charmant-Killman.
The usual address.
Three Margherita pizzas.
Four Seasons for me.
Sorry, one Four Seasons,
two Margheritas.
Nice and hot.
Thanks.
Up early? Any dates?
At noon, with my ex.
Ex, already?
Not very serious.
Nothing is serious.
- What do you mean?
- Everything is tragic.
But I can still love life.
Can I have another pillow?
What are you doing?
Stop smoking and come to bed.
Jeanne.
Jeanne!
Take out your earplugs.
Humeau's mistress...
The clothes she wears!
I'll check the prices.
That will make his day!
No kiss?
Tonight?
How about tomorrow?
We'll be less tired.
I love you, you know.
Good night.
Good night. See you tomorrow.
I'm listening.
I'm not sure I've seen
all the documents.
I seem to know less than the press.
No smoking in my office.
Go on, counselor.
What are you after?
- The end of my client's career?
- I'm just doing my job.
Sibaud replaces me,
badmouths me...
Change your tone of voice.
Two governments trusted me.
- And you've abused that trust.
- In what way?
You know as well as I do.
The commissions.
I can't check everything.
But I can.
It's not that simple.
It's not that hard.
In macroeconomics,
there are different sectors.
Is that so?
Back to reality,
I'll tell you what I think.
I think you shamelessly
used your situation
for your personal enrichment,
to benefit your family and friends.
Not true and grotesque.
It shows you don't know me.
My family knows
the value of hard work!
I didn't go to a big school.
I rose through the ranks,
thinking only of my profession.
At least,
you left patriotism out of it.
That's you, isn't it?
- Who is she?
- My former assistant.
I'll be more precise.
She's your former mistress,
whom you made your assistant.
That dress looks nice on her.
- How much is she wearing?
- How much what?
The dress, the jewelry...
Do you know what it all costs?
No. Why?
You dress her from head to toe,
you wine and dine her,
and you don't know the cost?
Good thing I'm here.
Here's a statement of all the bills
paid with the company credit card.
- This is absurd!
- You're telling me!
If I may, Madame.
Regarding the company credit card...
You know as well as I do
that it's an old custom.
The private sector has bonuses
and stock options.
The public sector compensates
with the company card
for minor expenses.
- May I keep this?
- Sure, if you like.
May I have a glass of water?
Of course.
But first answer my question,
Mr. Chairman.
How do you justify these expenses?
Your group, as I recall,
was founded after the war to ensure
France's economic independence,
the hub of this independence
being francophone markets.
Jacques Sibaud, does your recent
nomination imply a new direction?
Most likely a new identity.
Governments come and go,
structures remain.
- Who is this jerk?
- Sibaud.
Not so "beau."
Could you hit the switch?
- What are you doing?
- Changing bulbs.
- The others were dead?
- I think they were about to blow.
- Your mom called with congrats.
- I know. She called me on my cell.
And what do you think?
Do you know my new name
at the lab?
No. What?
Can't you guess?
I answer riddles all day long.
I guessed.
- Shoot.
- Mr. Jeanne Charmant-Killman?
That's stupid.
Totally stupid.
It's really... Stupid.
What do you think?
I think it's funny.
Me, too.
He's edgy. It happens
every time I'm on a big case.
Take a vacation,
go relax somewhere.
You think that's the answer!
A slacker's idea, right?
I'll say no more.
- Is this the family silver?
- A wedding gift from your grandma.
Knives only.
No surprise. She hated me.
- Do they cut well, at least?
- Not like they used to.
Sharpen them.
Can you take off my glasses?
They're fogged up.
You approve of these frauds
lining their pockets?
It's only normal.
Fraud has to be profitable.
Humeau dipped in the till.
It's easy to produce the figures.
You could do better.
Where do the knives go?
In the drawer.
Do better?
Put the knives away right.
That group has often been accused
of bankrolling friendly heads of state
or opposition leaders,
sometimes both.
- That's the real scandal.
- First things first.
I can't play the bull
in the china shop.
What's surprising
is that your pal Sibaud...
Oh, please!
He went after his predecessor.
That's unusual
in such a big corporation.
You're right.
So he winds up in court.
They expect that to keep me busy.
Wrong.
When a door opens, I go in.
Who is "they"?
I'll tell you when I find out.
First, I'll get Humeau to confess.
He can't handle prison.
If he wants out...
Hello.
This is for you.
Have a nice day.
It's time.
Out you go.
You have 10 minutes.
So I'm free?
I wouldn't know.
10 minutes.
Could you hand me
that pair of clean pants?
Get them yourself.
Why are you staring at me like that?
You want tickets to Disneyland?
Hello.
Are you busy, my dear?
No, no.
I hear you're on the warpath.
You could say that.
I just wanted to wish you the best
on your saint day. Am I right?
That's sweet, Jacques.
No one else remembered.
Really?
Are you free for lunch any time soon?
I've got amusing stories for you.
You're putting me on the spot.
I'd love to,
but it's not very orthodox.
Of course,
if you look at it that way...
Let me finish with Humeau...
Certainly. I'm unforgivable.
And I know you're
a stickler for principles.
I just hope you wrap it up soon.
I'm doing my best.
I have to go.
My customer is here.
Thanks again.
See you soon.
See you soon, Jeanne.
Hello, Mr. Chairman.
I brought you here
to check a few things.
Are these plantings recent?
Fairly recent.
53 orange trees and 29 lemon trees.
You do have the invoices, right?
- That's why you brought me out?
- It wasn't to get some fresh air.
- Take these handcuffs off, please.
- Not until I check a few things.
Nicole Humeau?
Why? What time is it?
Justice Charmant-Killman.
It's 9:30 a.m.,
and I have a search warrant.
Don't worry, darling.
Are the kids home?
They're asleep.
They got in late.
We won't search their rooms.
I don't see your suits or shoes.
Don't you live at home?
Sorry if your husband
leads a double life.
- This is vile.
- You don't say.
You're vile.
My husband lives here.
He always dresses casually.
In photos, he always wears a suit.
Never the same one.
Not to mention the shirts,
ties, cufflinks.
A vast choice for telling time.
An Omega, two Cartier...
A must!
Company gifts.
You don't say.
My husband did nothing wrong.
His colleagues, other CEOs,
influential politicians,
all expressed their support.
He has an admirable wife,
in any case.
Back to the courthouse.
So, no tree nursery invoice.
Now, this flat where
you set up your mistress,
5830 sq. ft.
in the most expensive part of town.
Do I give you the price?
I didn't buy the flat.
You can't prove it. You're bluffing.
I'm bluffing and you're lily white.
- Next question.
- I won't answer.
I'll wait for my lawyer.
He's on his way. Sit down.
I can't sit still!
I'm ill, you know!
The ball's in your court.
Some people have done
much worse than I have.
- Those who back you?
- I never said that!
Why are you hounding me?
To set an example, once and for all.
You won't come out too badly.
And it will do the nation good.
You know what I think?
Tell me.
There's hot coffee in the kitchen.
This year we'll rent
a house on the beach.
We'll be happy.
We'll be...
What did you use to say?
- Visible for each other.
- That's right.
Visible for each other.
Is Felix home?
He just got in.
He spent the night out.
Really?
Look what I found in a drawer.
This really takes us back.
Remember?
I made this in a jiffy out of nothing.
You could always make things
in a jiffy out of nothing.
You don't lack talent.
What do I lack?
I'll tell you some day.
See you tonight.
I don't intend to smear their leaders.
Still, the interrogations
and indictments keep coming.
Michel Humeau's in a bad way.
I don't intend to intimidate
or destabilize anyone...
I hear you there, see you here!
Turn it off. I can't stand it.
So, you spent the night out?
To my great benefit.
What's that?
Poker.
I cleaned a few people out.
It won't hurt them, as my aunt says.
You intend to earn a living
playing poker?
Get angry. I love it.
How about lunch,
a place with good wine?
Quick, then.
I'm seeing bigwigs at 2:00.
What are they doing?
Playing soccer.
Only 12?
They don't have enough players.
I'd better fix that.
I'll show you his cell.
- Isn't that what you wanted?
- Absolutely.
When you're used to 5 stars,
it's a little barren.
That's an understatement.
Who is in charge of keeping
the place clean, warden?
We had it repainted not long ago,
but we're short on funds.
Ah, funding problems!
Beware of lawyers.
They tend to slip in treats
during their visits.
Do a search after each visit.
That's just what we try to do,
Madame.
The other cells are identical.
That's worrying!
So, who won?
No one. We play for fun.
Then enjoy!
I don't have a Swiss bank account.
I have no foreign accounts.
- You're not taking it down?
- Your lawyer's not here.
- Why isn't he here?
- Ask him when he arrives.
That doesn't mean we can't chat.
How about those huge commissions
you've always paid left and right?
The Herod file.
Is the sum right?
Could be. It's common currency
in our business.
Common currency.
A charming term,
but not for the Revenue Court.
It seems you shamelessly
squandered state funds.
How can you say that?
I brought in huge sums.
The payments I made
enriched the group and the nation.
And yourself as well.
Using front men.
All because of a woman.
But you loved her?
We broke up, you know that.
You'd be the only one not to know.
She's an ocean away.
An ocean away,
in a sumptuous flat you bought her,
overlooking Central Park.
She wrote you a letter. Shall I?
Please, don't.
She's thirsty for blood.
She's a compulsive liar,
and she's jealous, you see?
See what?
I was crazy about her.
I gave her everything.
Then virtually overnight...
What happened?
I don't know.
My desire for her died.
You got hot for something else?
Here's what she cost you:
Swimming pool vacuum,
latest model.
4,000 euros.
Swimming pool, 50,000 euros.
Not including the pool-house and spa,
which she had moved.
Two spas, two drillings.
But I don't mean to scare you.
All from the group's coffers.
You know how many people earn
minimum wage in France?
You know this man?
René Lange?
Are you on good terms?
He's a politician.
Politics isn't business.
Some people think so.
Got a bone to pick?
Absolutely not.
He does as he wishes.
He dumped me, like the others did.
- What others?
- Those I did favors for.
Delombre, Holeo, Boldi.
They answered to you?
They dumped you, too?
They all dumped me.
Isn't that how it goes?
It's that prison...
You should hear the screams
at night.
The new guys, the young ones...
As soon as they get there...
They're in for it.
Not in the VIP block, I hope.
I've had it.
I can't take anymore.
I'm exhausted!
I need treatment!
I do what I can, try to keep busy,
but I can't take anymore.
Please, I'm begging you.
I'm begging you.
Okay, permission
for outside hospitalization.
Don't worry about it.
I still have work to do.
- I'll do room 220, then.
- Okay.
I won't be long.
Good night, Madame.
- You can do my office now.
- Thank you.
Hello?
Christ almighty!
What?
Was it an accident?
Christ almighty!
What is this?
What moron thought that one up?
It could be just an accident.
Looks more like a fuckup
than an accident.
What a bunch of clowns
we're surrounded with!
Is she badly hurt?
According to my sources, no.
Pathetic.
Pathetic!
Let's go. She's starting again.
They said you were unconscious,
they'd sedated you,
but that it's not serious.
I know all that.
You never know when to quit.
You work like a lunatic.
You fell asleep at the wheel.
Imagine!
I imagine very well.
I think they rigged
my brakes and steering.
Don't be silly.
You were just tired.
Get me some hot chocolate.
I'm craving hot chocolate.
I can worry, can't I?
We have the right to live normally.
You're out of luck with me, honey.
I'll never give up.
They won't get away with this,
believe me.
- You're crazy.
- Maybe, but I'll go all the way.
I'll let you rest.
I'll be back later.
Ah, Felix!
- You're sweet to visit.
- I love hospitals.
- Your hot chocolate?
- Black, no sugar.
What a gorgeous bouquet!
We'll ask for a vase.
I'll get one.
Black, no sugar.
Thanks, sweetie.
Who are the guys outside?
My bodyguards.
So you won't worry.
- You're hard on him.
- Me, hard?
I don't think so.
I was thinking earlier...
Do you have a picture of your son?
I've never even seen him.
He's awfully cute!
- How old is he?
- Three.
- Why don't you bring him over?
- He's always with his saintly mother.
- Yes, and so?
- I'm not wild about saints.
Me neither.
I'm in good company these days!
Could you get me the papers
over there?
- Do you want your glasses?
- Yes, please.
Thanks.
Boy, he doesn't waste any time.
I get it now! It was him.
- Who?
- Humeau.
I let him out for first-class care,
and he has my car rigged.
And I wind up in the hospital, too.
Why him?
He was weird the last time.
He didn't scratch.
He gave me shifty looks.
He was plotting it.
- You're paranoid.
- Maybe, but I don't think so.
- Humeau's an underling.
- That would surprise me.
It surprised him to be the tree
that hides the forest.
- What forest?
- The one growing silently.
I've had a feeling all along.
I hate to say it, but I know them.
The big scams are elsewhere.
I'll haul them all in.
Right-hand men,
coworkers, advisors.
They haven't seen the last of me.
But...
Why do you think they
gave me those bodyguards?
Well chosen, aren't they?
Strong, impressive.
- They're looking after you.
- To throw me off track?
If they're smart, and some are,
they'll take extra-good care of you.
I'll take advantage of it, believe me.
Come in.
Aren't you spoiled!
- Who brought that?
- Some florist.
I've been outdone.
Shall I open the card?
Sure.
Jacques Sibaud. There's a note.
- I told you he was a part of it.
- Of course! You think I'm stupid?
Did you send those flowers
to charming Mrs. Charmant?
You're sure she got them?
Always send flowers
to the unfortunate.
You plan to let her go on with this?
I think we should use
the promotion ploy on her.
There's no promotion possible.
I didn't say, "Give her a promotion,"
but "Use the promotion ploy."
Come to think of it...
They're supposed to move from
the courthouse to a new building.
Perfect!
Is it spacious?
There's lots of room.
She'll have a large office.
That's always appreciated.
She also asked for an assistant.
Good idea.
After this incident, and with all
those cases she has to deal with...
But we mustn't end up
with two snoops instead of one.
Got any women in stock?
Why a woman?
Because women love to do
dirty tricks to other women.
"Justice Charmant promoted..."
How big is the new office?
It's a surprise.
- Can we help?
- You must be joking.
We worked well here,
didn't we, Benoît?
This is from everybody here.
How sweet.
It was a toss-up with "Aubade"
but we chose "In Love Again."
Smells nice.
You made the right choice.
Thank you.
They're all expecting you.
What flight are you taking?
None.
I'll send it all by email.
Holeo will stand in as usual.
That's his job,
and he loves hot weather.
Very well, Mr. Chairman.
Yes, Mr. President.
Experts are already
assessing the project.
It's too early to say.
These are high-risk countries.
Naturally, I'll gladly make the trip.
I just cancelled my flight
on Holeo's insistence.
I'm on top of it all.
Thank you.
Good-bye, Mr. President.
Jeanne.
I've been thinking of you too,
Jacques. Quite often.
You once said
the only goal in life is excellence.
I'm trying to be a worthy disciple.
Yes.
The Presiding Judge is here
But...
I'm very busy these days,
and I need to get my bearings.
I'm sure you're running
the show just fine,
but I miss our lunches.
So when you have a minute, call.
It won't take all night.
I'll leave you
to your territorial stake-out.
One more thing.
That black suit looks great on you.
Jeanne!
I'm so glad to see you.
Thanks for putting me here.
It's sumptuous.
- Big enough?
- Almost too big.
And the design is superb.
- So are you. You look great.
- I feel great.
- Hello, Mr. President.
- Hello... Benoît, right?
- As loyal as ever?
- Yes, sir.
- Glad you like it.
- You know me. It's all ready to go.
- Can you find your way in this maze?
- With my eyes closed.
- I want a word with you outside.
- Certainly.
You'll be glad to hear
you're no longer working alone.
I've assigned you someone.
She has plenty of experience,
especially with politicians.
"She"? Who is she?
I'll introduce you.
What do I care about this trivia?
Question me about
my international role.
About how you fleece
friendly nations?
Or fund parties?
You're obsessed.
Let me tell you...
Excuse me a minute.
Erika Eymard. Jeanne Charmant.
My two favorite judges.
We're on the same floor.
- How long have you been here?
- She just arrived.
Adjoining offices will make
communication easy.
René Lange is mine.
I'll continue what I started.
We can share him.
You want to sink him, so do I.
Sink those who think they can swim.
- Great. I'm going back in.
- Work hard. I'll see you later.
I work alone.
Why didn't you warn me?
I need you both.
You'll suit one another.
It's good for the image of justice.
It's not the image of justice
I care about. It's justice.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, Madame.
Madame Killman!
- Ground floor or parking lot?
- Ground floor.
By the way,
I didn't ask to work with you.
I figured as much.
But I agree with you, it's not clear.
Someone thinks we'll hurt each other.
That's what I think.
We'll prove them wrong,
that we're equal to them.
We'll get those machos by the balls.
See you tomorrow.
"We'll get those machos
by the balls!"
"See you tomorrow."
- Alone today?
- My colleague's at your place.
- May I?
- Thanks.
Don't mind me.
Everything's fine.
- I'll be back in two hours.
- Fine.
I owe you one.
What are you doing here?
Philippe isn't home yet?
Not yet.
I've had your keys for three weeks.
They're on the kitchen table.
I'm exhausted!
We moved today.
They stuck you in a closet?
Not at all.
A sumptuous new office.
It's very nice.
Like everyone,
I read about your promotion.
It worried me.
Me, too.
It smells fishy, but I'll show them.
Do you like your apartment?
Great! I call it "Flat Out".
I need some tea, or I'll collapse.
- Want some tea?
- No, thanks.
Tea!
- They're nice, but there's no privacy.
- I have nothing to hide.
What's this about crosswords?
Tea's a good idea after all.
Want some?
I devise crosswords. It's fun.
I've being cranking them out
for ages.
I have a daily, 2 weeklies,
and 3 pseudonyms.
And, of course, three casts of mind.
I work when I want,
and I'm having fun.
- Make any money?
- Enough.
- Any time for your son?
- Sure.
Is your case going that badly?
No, but the situation is annoying.
They stuck me with an associate.
Do you know who did it?
Officially, Martino,
the Presiding Judge.
I've known him for years.
A nice guy.
I doubt it was his idea.
If only I could flush them
out of their holes!
The creeps!
With a little luck and lots of grit...
- What's your colleague like?
- Hard to tell.
She's nice enough,
young, competent.
She has a good reputation.
Pretty?
I suppose. Depends what you like.
You want me to introduce you?
If it will help, I'm all yours.
I'm going to betray
a judicial secret.
Tomorrow I have to play
my cards right.
I'm questioning Holeo.
You know who he is?
He's a head honcho.
Friends with everyone.
Old playboy type. Got any cookies?
As you must know, Madame,
our group makes
all sorts of investments.
Major companies use our services.
There are three
or four hundred of them.
You misunderstand, Mr. Holeo.
I mean your special relations
in countries
where the group has interests.
I fail to see the connection
with your investigation.
I just want to make sure you're not
behind the disappearance
of large sums of money.
That again!
Mr. Humeau, the former CEO,
had several audits done.
He found nothing wrong.
He chose to ignore it.
You know where he is now.
But...
There are several foreign accounts
in your name, Mr. Holeo.
Perhaps, but they're not mine.
I simply manage them.
I'm a middleman.
For whom?
No one in particular.
Certain sums transit
through those accounts.
To whom?
That depends.
There are all types of subsidies.
I know that, and oddly enough,
some subsidies look like kickbacks.
You overvalue an operation,
then help yourself.
So I'm asking you,
who is the money for?
- What money?
- You don't remember?
I must admit, I don't.
Do you remember him?
Delombre? Sure.
He smokes cigars in the morning.
It's very unpleasant.
How well do you know him?
I know he works hard.
But our activities
are completely unconnected.
Things are very compartmentalized
with you, Mr. Holeo.
Where is Delombre hiding?
I couldn't say. All I know is
he wanted to take a vacation.
You think he's basking in the sun?
I advise you not to do the same.
I don't intend to, Madame.
- You also know Mr. Boldi?
- Yes, of course.
I suppose your activities
are also unconnected.
Yes, of course.
They're unconnected.
Thank you. I won't keep you.
Please sign your statement.
Of course I might... In fact,
I probably will question you again.
Don't go too far.
Holeo will talk. He's petrified.
Any headway with Lange?
None. I'm afraid he's way down
the totem pole.
Give me one more shot with him.
No, keep him.
I'm pulling on another thread.
Benoît, did you listen to us
on the radio last night?
Sure.
- Was it good?
- As usual, Madame.
- Was I good, too?
- Very good, Madame.
It arrived this morning.
It's a letter of denunciation.
Again?
It never ceases to amaze me.
- Humeau's babe.
- I recognized her. But why you?
- To save you work.
- But I'm interested!
I like Humeau.
Let's go check out the slut's flat.
- Up for it?
- It will be a nice change.
You're still here?
Orders, sir.
Sorry.
Come to bed.
What are you doing?
This can't go on.
- You hear me?
- I hear you.
I hear.
What you say and don't say.
It's my job.
You're investigating me?
What's in my head?
You don't give a shit about anyone.
That's the truth.
- Are you nuts?
- Either they go or I go!
They protect us.
Spare me your fantasies.
You're perfect.
Smooth as stone.
Who do you think I do this for?
For who?
Sure, don't answer.
It's much easier.
The ivory tower.
That's your mother's stare.
You've become a stranger.
So have you.
We're shadows who sometimes meet
in a guarded flat.
Who am I to you?
Do you know?
Stop playing with your wedding ring.
Take it off, if it bothers you.
What are you doing?
Do you know what you're doing?
Do you know?
This is your house.
It's your house, so I'm leaving.
Let's go.
- Do you want me to drive?
- No, it's okay.
Where to, Madam?
Where to?
The office, as usual.
It's 4 a.m.
Yes.
Let's go to the office.
Where else?
Get down!
All clear.
You can get up, Madam.
Sorry.
DIE BITCH
- You okay?
- I'm okay.
- Where did you find that?
- In the clerk's closet.
- Did you find what's missing?
- How can I, in that mess?
- Here, this is real coffee.
- That's sweet.
I called the agency.
They have a 700 sq. ft. rental nearby.
Too big. I just need a studio.
We'll find you one.
Good morning.
- You're already here?
- If you only knew, Benoît.
Thanks for everything.
Now I have work to do.
- You'll manage?
- I may not look it, but I'm strong.
We'll find you a flat.
Looking for a flat?
That's my coffee maker!
I never handled commissions.
So, I don't know
about suitcase sizes...
Don't play with me, Mr. Holeo.
It's beneath you.
So, how did the money
move around?
I have no idea.
I talk with leaders,
to find out what they want.
Now I get it, you do the haggling.
The chit-chat.
Down there, a good chit-chat
means a good deal.
You chew the fat to make a deal
for the group.
Different customs.
How do the secret funds work?
That's what you call it.
They're funds made available
by heads of state.
It's normal.
It's the same everywhere.
Some are transferred
to various organizations,
usually charities, or organizations
that help themselves.
Great, in countries where
you can die of appendicitis!
I deplore it as much as you do.
Believe me, I'm sincere.
Excuse me.
Could we postpone this interview?
I'm not well.
I have heart trouble.
Of course.
My clerk will see you out.
There's no need.
- Thank you for your kindness.
- I don't want to kill the sinner.
- I was awful.
- You're tired.
Marco told me about last night.
Never a dull moment!
- Did Holeo break down?
- It's rather me who broke down.
He's tougher than he looks.
- He did the dying man number.
- Everyone knows he's sick.
We located Delombre.
- Where?
- The Caribbean.
We'll have to forget him
for the moment.
I'm so tired, I don't give a damn.
Marco told me you're flat-hunting.
It's none of my business,
but you can stay at my place
in the meantime.
Sorry, gentlemen.
A flat tire.
Just my luck.
I'll go wash my hands.
Why did they put this one in charge?
I preferred Michel,
but Sibaud has certain qualities.
Be serious, Boldi.
He's as stiff as a board.
They'll soon pay him off
with a pad of stock options.
What a shame!
- A flat, the one time I drive.
- How unfortunate!
- Champagne?
- I would love some, Boldi.
- How did it go with the judge?
- Your girlfriend?
I cut our conversation short.
I wanted to see you first.
Did you read the rants
of our friend Humeau?
You have my complete trust.
I'll talk to the press, too.
That's kind of you,
but I wanted to say...
I believe you've offended
our friends.
They would have preferred you
to go down there.
You can't settle everything
via your computer, Mr. Chairman.
Don't worry, old man.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Taittinger!
We're spoiling you.
I can see that.
Did Jean-Baptiste tell you
about the CIA?
Yes, the CIA was there.
Everyone was, in fact.
Look, I know what I say.
And I know what I'm doing.
Nice of you to visit!
- Good timing.
- As usual.
- What's the box?
- I'll explain.
- Smaller than my place, but nice.
- Enough for me.
- You didn't like your friend's place?
- Sure, she's sweet.
But a week was enough.
So what's the box?
I don't know.
It came two days ago.
Philippe asked me to bring it to you.
How is he doing?
Not too cheerful.
It's understandable.
Where do you stand with him?
Nowhere. I'm waiting.
I won't force him to take
the first step, and yet...
What do you think?
I don't want to interfere.
Guess who it's from?
Jacques Sibaud.
He's bullshitting me.
No, he's not.
He's backing Holeo.
He still trusts him.
He's just trying to use me.
I'll send back his wine.
Don't do that.
I'm thirsty all of a sudden.
We'll see. Anyhow, he's late.
I had Boldi arrested.
- You did? He's in jail?
- Yes, he is.
While they plot behind my back,
I'm pulling out the heavy artillery.
Look.
Isn't he cute?
You're right.
They'll be careful.
I've gone into high gear.
You know, Boldi...
He's the kickback king.
If it's done right,
it's overhead and tax deductible.
Or in a Swiss bank
where names become numbers.
That's what I'm after.
The names behind the numbers.
They'll never let you poke around.
Too risky.
I have certain powers, you know.
- The powers you're granted.
- I don't care.
I know I can smoke
the poachers out of the woods.
What are you looking at?
You. I'm looking at you,
and listening.
You look like a shrink.
Try it. You'd make a mint.
You're nuts.
I'd spend my day on the couch.
Snoozing, of course.
What a shame.
You're the only one I can talk to.
I can't with others.
I can't give you much.
I'm not asking for anything.
I just need you to listen.
- Okay, but I'm thirsty.
- Shall we open a bottle?
You're nuts!
It needs to rest at least two weeks.
I'll take you to the local bar.
You're a good boy.
If politics involves
pressing on soft spots,
you have to expect turbulence.
This judge is impossible.
She doesn't get
the rules of the game.
When you know how she started!
How?
As a student, she boarded
with the Charmant family.
I heard she cleaned their house.
Must have done right,
since she married the son.
- A successful takeover.
- She moved out.
She rented a studio.
- How do you know?
- I just know.
Anyway, I'm sick of her
snooping around.
We didn't expect Sibaud
to be useless.
He's totally inflexible.
He can't move his ass.
I hope the others hold out.
The natives are up in arms.
Have a seat. My colleague
will take your statement.
Here we go, sir.
The last act.
We can't reach your wife.
Is that normal?
My wife?
You can talk with your mouth full,
Mr. Boldi?
It's to quit smoking.
No, thanks.
Tell me, Mr. Boldi, does an envelope
of $800,000 ring a bell?
Madam, money is the oil you use
to grease the gears
so that the market runs properly.
An envelope of $800,000...
It doesn't mean a thing.
It's peanuts!
I put myself in your shoes.
All this work, all these files,
these thousands of pages.
And I'm told you keep office hours
at the courthouse on weekends,
as well as your time in court.
I wonder how you manage.
Answer my questions,
and I'll tell you.
Frankly, I admire you.
I've thought it over.
Never mind a change of cell.
I want to get out.
I understand.
Prisons aren't up to snuff.
Understand me, Mrs. Charmant.
I wouldn't want
to be taken for a ride.
I don't intend to take you
for a ride, Mr. Boldi.
My power lies in my address book.
Big deal.
I know them all.
They've all been indicted.
Delombre hasn't.
He's on the run in the tropics.
The party funding, that's him.
Not to mention...
A lot of other things.
That's why he's lying low abroad.
Official secret.
Does Sibaud know?
Sibaud!
He knows.
Without knowing,
even though he does know.
He's the one with signature power.
So he gives his trust.
He doesn't look, he just signs.
He forks out like everyone...
Or else he's dead.
Excuse me?
Humeau, for instance.
He's dead.
Where did he go wrong?
Him...
He's special.
It's more a matter
of personal incompatibility.
But getting back to the cash...
Before you extract,
you have to grease palms.
We grease the leaders' palms,
they take the cash,
and they do what they want with it.
The books are separate.
But it's not against the law.
It's even endorsed by customs.
No one talks about it, that's all.
It's taboo, but normal.
And Jacques Sibaud does the same?
The same procedure?
Sibaud!
He is a spectator.
Give him a desert,
in six months the sand's gone.
When you do business,
you move, you take risks.
Sibaud's hopeless.
Madam, squealing on people
at my age feels very strange.
I understand you, Mr. Boldi.
But if you can't stand prison...
I saw that poor Humeau.
I feel sorry for him.
He's like a zombie.
He took it hard.
But let's not dramatize.
He'll get over it.
My colleague is signing his release.
You made the right decision,
Mr. Boldi.
Go on. I'm listening.
- Search warrant!
- You can't.
I can.
Glad to see you!
What are you doing here?
Give that back.
- No way. It goes under seals.
- I bet.
- That's illegal.
- Think so?
This is entirely legitimate.
I only enter golf scores on my
computer, to calculate my handicap.
How is it?
You have to sign.
- No way.
- Don't be childish. It could cost you.
The key to the safe.
- I said, the key!
- I don't have it.
As you like.
- What are they doing?
- Their job.
Behind the panel.
- This is ridiculous.
- I agree.
- Two black books.
- You can't. They're confidential.
You're overstepping
your prerogatives.
Look, Mr. Sibaud.
You're the one who came to me.
Frankly, we're a long way
from where we started.
We both knew that,
right from the beginning.
That's why I won't allow this.
Jeanne!
- Sorry. Did I scare you?
- No, it's me. I'm silly.
A pan bagnat, from my region.
That's sweet of you.
I'm so tired.
We're here, Madam.
We'll always be here for you.
That's sweet of you.
Didn't I already say that?
- You overslept?
- Sorry, I broke down.
- How did Sibaud take it?
- In his own way.
- He'll use his golden parachute.
- The poor thing.
How much?
That much?
- Hello, Madam.
- Hello, Benoît. Did you sleep well?
Very well, thanks.
More hate mail, two letters today.
Only two?
At times, I think I'm being followed.
- Isn't it flattering?
- You're out of control today!
That's good,
because we've got work to do.
Let me guess.
Delombre's back in town?
You got it. With his lawyers,
Wogner and Parlebas.
- I like him.
- Good.
We see them at 3:00,
with their tanned client.
They're usually tanned, aren't they?
How will you handle it?
Very simply.
I let him do his spiel, then I read
the charges, and I book him.
From sun to shade.
I was amazed when he swallowed
his cellphone chip.
What a nutcase!
No, like all crooks,
he's done his thinking.
He figures they'll be grateful.
The rabble fears oblivion.
- Martino!
- Where?
Your Honor,
will you toast the outcome
of this investigation with us?
Temper your joy.
I'm glad the law is the same for all.
There are journalists upstairs.
Celebrating an arrest
is bad for our image.
- See you tomorrow.
- Tomorrow is Sunday.
I'll see you on Monday.
Your friend will talk.
So will the others.
They'll tell all and drag you down.
I have to tell you.
I'm not part of their schemes.
The judge will say
you didn't stop them.
What will you reply?
I have other options.
- We've gone whole hog.
- Oh, please!
Your group is bled white.
You can't say no.
I understand how you feel,
but it's true.
You've hit bottom.
Don't kid yourselves.
We're all in the same boat,
and we've hit a storm.
But the wind is dropping, and
the ship has held up rather well.
Senator, I don't know if your optimism
impresses or worries me.
It's an objective analysis
of the situation.
- What do you think?
- Things are settling down.
- The group's getting devoured.
- All because of that jerk Sibaud.
So let's think positive, as they say.
- At least Sibaud's off our back.
- At what price?
True, he did get
a golden handshake.
- As you say.
- Good for him.
But otherwise,
the system held up well.
And I'm sure our friends in trouble
can withstand the pressure.
- Boldi, for instance.
- Oh, him!
That's another story.
We'll deal with Boldi later.
The group may have been
gobbled up,
but our structure is intact.
For now!
Don't be so negative.
Your father's bank
changed names, didn't it?
You got swallowed up, too.
Did it change anything?
You got reorganized.
We'll reorganize, too!
What about that woman,
that diabolical judge?
Will she keep making trouble for us?
I understand
she's getting a promotion.
Again.
The last one was a disaster.
I admit it was something
of a shambles, and we got taken.
We were wrong to give her
that associate.
This brandy is excellent.
Your file says,
"He sent his boy for caviar."
I'm not going down over caviar!
The lifestyle doesn't go
with the official salaries.
What do I plead?
Tax exemption, reinvestment...
It's pragmatic.
It's legal.
What isn't legal?
Who cares what they do!
Let them keep fighting it out.
They're animals.
Elephants dance together,
you dance alone.
Merge while there's still time.
Not credible. Too small.
I'm warning you,
there's a facelift in the offing.
Sounds like the BBC during the war.
"London calling."
What does he mean by a facelift?
That they're on the alert.
They're selling off.
And to avoid an audit,
they buy off sleazy politicians.
So what do we do?
Everyone's controlled.
- It's the rule.
- What is?
Invoke state security
to let your pals get rich?
I'm not saying it's moral,
but it's the rule.
The Presiding Judge
wants to see you.
Damn!
Time flies with you.
- Yes?
- Madam Charmant-Killman.
Send her in.
- You don't look so good.
- I'm okay. Just a little tired.
How are you coming along?
I contacted my Swiss counterpart.
He explained the system.
The funds go through various money
markets, then they end up in London.
You're moving fast!
I have to.
I'm counting on you
to contact the Chancellor.
Look, calm down and listen to me.
You look really beat.
- You should take a vacation.
- Not until the Swiss banks answer.
The situation's changed.
The new group intends to start
on a new footing.
I don't believe a word of it.
It will be the same, the same
schemes and new expenses.
You lost your objectivity.
I need a fresh eye.
What do you mean exactly?
I'll be honest with you.
I don't want you to run into trouble.
So listen to me.
There are too many vipers involved.
Let it rest for a while.
If you won't take time off,
I can have you transferred.
A real promotion, something good.
Don't they call my post
the most powerful in France?
They say lots of things.
Think it over, my dear Jeanne.
You know I'm very fond of you.
I'll take care of your bonus.
You can keep it, Your Honor.
To buy yourself a pair of balls.
What did he want?
- He thanked me.
- It's the least he could do.
I mean, he said to take a vacation.
He's cutting me loose.
Got a cigarette?
He said it like that?
He was a little uneasy.
I sent him packing.
What are you going to do?
He said he needed a fresh eye.
I may be paranoid, but I feel
like the victim of a conspiracy.
So, what are you going to do?
Would you take over for me?
If you asked me to.
- If I didn't?
- I'd refuse, of course.
Then I'm asking you to.
I'm not sure they'll want me.
They have to watch out.
The case has made too much noise.
So, again, what are you going to do?
I'm going home.
- What's the matter?
- I tried to call you.
I turned off my cell.
What is it?
Bad news.
Your husband
jumped out the window.
- He's dead?
- No, hospitalized.
I came for you.
The cops called.
They couldn't reach you.
They located your nephew.
Then I told them I'd find you
and bring you over.
Did they say how he is?
Vaguely.
But he's alive.
Alive?
Yes.
You were right.
Martino hinted I'd probably
take over the case.
For the moment, anyway.
- You okay?
- How is he?
Out of it.
They say his condition is serious,
but not critical.
- Can we see him?
- Right now there is no point.
But he might wake up any minute.
Erika, this is Felix.
Philippe's nephew.
I work with Erika.
Those two hoods are cops.
They want to question you,
but you scare them.
Let's go see them.
- Gentlemen.
- Madam.
Sorry, but we need to know...
Do you know of a gun
in your apartment?
A gun?
No. Where?
In a shoebox,
wrapped in tissue paper.
I knew nothing about it.
What's the link?
We wondered why
he jumped out the window
when he had a gun handy.
Maybe he was reluctant to die.
What I liked right off was his smile.
Amid all those hypocrites,
he had that smile.
He said I lacked something.
That he'd tell me...
Some day.
What do I lack?
Ask him.
You think he'll pull through?
I think so.
I'm not ready to grieve him.
Madam Charmant, things look better.
His condition is stable.
- Can I see him?
- He's asleep.
Just a peek?
Come with me.
- I can't let you go in.
- I just want a peek.
I'm sorry.
Madam.
Mr. Chairman.
I heard about your husband.
I'm sorry.
What are you here for?
Are you ill?
I went into a depression
after I was released.
Really?
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
You weren't the cruelest
in this affair.
I hope it all works out, Madam.
So do I, Mr. Chairman.
Good-bye.
Excuse me, I must return to my flock.
Funny doctor.
People used to say that priests were
soul doctors. He's a body priest.
- Or a soul cop!
- What?
We used to say priests
were soul cops.
Only God can judge.
The real question is, what is God?
Another time.
I'm going to bed.
You should, too.
Go on. I want to stay.
You should go rest.
Erika's right.
If you stay,
Philippe will sleep, but you won't.
You always know
how to convince me.
My dear aunt, I'm a great Cartesian.
I feel like I'm in a dream.
- You want a ride?
- It's too far.
I'll take care of you.
You have a car?
I'm off.
Sleep well.
You have work tomorrow.
- Hope to see you soon, Erika.
- See you.
I forgot to tell you.
Your trusty clerk Benoît
is a real bastard.
He's the mole.
I caught him calling
a guy named Le Blanc.
- You know him?
- Yes, vaguely.
I'll explain tomorrow.
Good night.
She has a nice ass,
but I bet she's a bit loony.
- What makes you say that?
- Her profession.
- Why not say I'm loony, too?
- I almost did.
There's no job without risk.
What's that?
Not bad.
Three jacks against two pairs,
aces high.
They didn't do you any favors.
What are you going to do?
Three jacks!
What a world!
You plan on continuing?
I don't know.
You did your job.
You cleaned up good.
You're naive, nephew.
There's still a lot of dirt
left and right.
Believe me.
So...
Will you keep going?
To hell with them.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/48mk4
Help other users to choose the best subtitles