[Male Voice]
Have you had enough yet?
[Exhales]
[Groans]
Are you ready now?
[Birds Chirping]
[Audience Applauding]
Thank you:
And every single
free choice you make: : :
Arises from either a thought of love
or a thought of fear:
- There is no other choice:
- [Shutter Clicks]
And if I had one thing to say
about what we're trying: : :
To understand here tonight,
it would be- it would be this:
That feeling inside of you: : :
That love inside of you-
that's God: : :
Expressing through you as you:
Yes?
- [Microphone Feedback]
- My name is Daisy: : :
- And I just wanted to say I loved your book:
- Thank you, Daisy:
And I'm-I'm feeling like I finally understand
what it means to be awake in my own life:
- Feels good, doesn't it?
- It's totally amazing!
- Mm-hmm:
- I walk around feeling like I've been given a secret:
Well: : :
- The secret is out!
- [Laughing]
- [Applause]
- The problem I've been having: : :
Is that some of my friends,
even my family-
If I say anything remotely spiritual,
they get this glazed look on their face:
- [Man] Ah:
- And I know that look: : :
Because it’s the same look I’ve had,
or used to have, every day of my life:
I know exactly what that feels like:
And the good news is,
you're not crazy:
- Good: [Laughs]
- 'Cause we're both crazy:
- [Laughing]
- And if that's the case: : :
- We're in very good company:
- [Laughing, Applauding]
Instead of worrying about
what people think about you: : :
Concentrate on
what you think about you:
- [Applause]
- That's important:
Any regrets?
- Many:
- Care to name a few?
- You're not a lawyer, are you?
- [Audience Laughing]
I wish that I could have come to
this point in my life without hurting-
Wish I'd come to this point
in my life without: : :
Hurting so many people-
especially the people I’ve loved:
But without them: : :
I might not have come
to this point in my life:
See, it’s important
for all of us to remember: : :
That the universe
is conspiring in our favor-
always, and in all ways: : :
Despite circumstances
and appearances: : :
Or most importantly,
our perception of them:
- You've got a lot of nerve!
- I'm sorry?
- You're a hypocrite:
- It's all right: It's all right: It's all right:
Standing up there preaching
about God and love:
You've been married
and divorced a lot:
If you talk to God, how come you can't
keep a commitment with a woman?
[Man] I can’t tell you how many times
I’ve asked myself that same question:
The women in my life: : :
Are all wonderful:
They treated me a whole lot
better than I treated them:
I betrayed them:
I let them down:
I let my kids down too:
I admit that:
More than that I cannot say
without invading their privacy: : :
And that I am not gonna do:
What I can do is love
as much as I can from where I am:
To make every gesture and action
sponsored by love:
- Sounds to me like you've written a book of lies:
- [Audience Murmuring]
If what you’re asking me is, did I make
all of this stuff up, the answer is no:
I've wondered what you're wondering:
"Will anyone believe me,
believe what I'm saying: : :
Believe where this came from?"
And I guess that
that's up to you-
to each of you:
I only hope that you don’t
disqualify or marginalize the message: : :
Because it’s coming through
such a fallible messenger:
My name is Kay,
and I just wanted to thank you: : :
For admitting your mistakes:
[Man] Well, thank you, Kay-
um, and all of you:
But the truth of it is, I'm still making
those mistakes to this day:
That's why these conversations with God
are such a miracle for me:
They-They came out of a need-
a desperate personal need-
for me to change my life:
And, um, you know, uh: : :
If I've been successful
at it in the way I'd like-
I don't know,
but-but it's the way it happened: : :
And it's the way it's-
it's still happening:
[Kay]
My question is: : :
If God has one message-
his most important
message to all of us-
and you could put it in one paragraph,
what would it be?
[Man] Well, I could fit it
into five words:
"You've got me all wrong:"
- [Cheering]
- Thank you:
Thank you:
Good night:
[Crowd Chanting]
Neale! Neale! Neale!
[Rain Falling]
[Woman]
Here's your plane ticket: You're on the 10:00:
Thanks for everything,
and I'll see you in New York:
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Tires Screeching]
[Siren Wailing]
- Still nothing, huh?
- I'm trying, honey:
You could have fooled me: Look,
I don't get this: I've got experience-
Your experience has nothing to do with anything:
And we've been over this, Neale:
- [Groans]
- As long as that bow tie's around your neck: : :
Nobody's going to take
a chance on hiring you:
Really?
So, what is it exactly: : :
That you people do around here?
Mostly we hand out checks to people
who blame us for their problems:
Sorry:
What did the hospital say?
Well, they said I should start
feeling better in a few days: : :
But, uh, it's been
almost a month now:
Wow: They seem
to have missed something:
- What?
- Neale: : :
You have a broken neck:
[Lighter Flicks]
- [Knocking]
- [Man] Mr.: Walsch, it’s Michael:
[Knocking]
Come on, Mr.: Walsch:
I know you’re in there:
[Neale]
No, I’m not:
- You're three months behind on your rent:
- [Door Closes]
I told you: I lost my-
- Your job:
- Job, yeah:
Yes, I know: And I'm sorry
about your accident, Neale:
But I’m not gonna lose my job
because you lost yours:
Come on: I'm out there:
Every day, I am:
I'm trying:
Isn't there someone you can call?
No: Those calls were made
a long time ago:
I mean, I got-
I got nowhere to go:
5:00, Neale:
[No Audible Dialogue]
- [Thunder Rumbling]
- [Blows]
[Inhales, Groans]
[Children Chattering,
Laughing]
[Child Babbling]
[Woman]
Okay, who’s ready for bed?
I’m coming in there:
I hope you got your P. J: "s on:
[Chattering,
Laughing Continue]
[Woman]
Brush your teeth?
[Child Babbling]
[Woman] Yes? How about you?
Did you brush your teeth?
Oh, looks to me like
somebody had an extra cookie:
- [Children Laughing]
- Am I gonna have to tickle you
to get you to go upstairs?
[Children Chattering,
Laughing]
[Dogs Barking In Distance]
[Woman]
I’m gonna get you!
[Children Chattering,
Laughing]
[Thunder Rumbling]
- [Woman] Hurry up:
- [Child Laughing]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Panting]
- Come on:
- You're doing it wrong!
It's the way I did it
on the other side!
Nope:
That don't go there:
You're doing it wrong:
Let me show you how to do it:
- That's not what the instructions say:
- Nope: That don't go there:
Let me show you how to do it:
Tie the line to the tree:
Make it high enough: : :
So you don’t kill yourself
in the middle of the night:
I kind of wish I had
one of those old canvas jobs: : :
That you pitch from the inside!
I take it this isn't
your first time pitching a: : :
Tent:
[Groaning, Panting]
[Wind Whistling]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Sighs]
Please, God: : :
Don't let me die here:
[Audience Applauding]
[Neale] To God,
there is no separation: : :
Between financial abundance
and spirituality:
In fact, they go hand in hand:
Don’t you find it odd
that we live: : :
In a society that devalues
our most important jobs?
- What do you mean by that?
- [Neale] I mean, we have no problem: : :
Giving a football coach
five million a season: : :
Or-or an actor
10 million per movie: : :
But somehow we've got it wired: : :
Where people involved
with spirituality: : :
Should be penniless,
celibate and-and abstinent:
[Applause]
- And preferably all three, you know?
- [Audience Laughing]
- [Woman] Yeah: Right:
- I mean, I don't know about you: : :
But l-I don't- I don't remember
voting for any of that:
- [Audience] No:
- So imagine a world: : :
Where money was given
to people who give us the biggest gifts:
- Teachers:
- [Woman] Oh, yes:
- Artists:
- [Audience] Yes:
- Nurses:
- Yes:
Uh, firemen:
You know, policemen:
- Writers:
- [Laughing]
- And mothers!
- [Audience Affirming]
[Woman]
Mothers: That's right:
Yes:
People who connect us,
not disconnect: : :
Or-or-or distract us, you know:
Imagine that world:
And we can have it,
because, people: : :
We're the ones:
We've always been the ones
that we've been waiting for:
We are: We are:
- [Applause Continues]
- [Woman] Yeah!
[Applause Fades]
[Wind Whistling]
[Birds Chirping]
[Male Voice]
You awake in there?
I said, are you awake in there?
Just a minute:
[Groans]
- Morning:
- Uh, good morning:
Name is Oscar: How about you
step out of that tent for a minute?
Uh, what for?
I know you got in late,
but I run things around here: : :
- And you should be aware of the rules:
- Uh, rules?
Yeah:
I'll walk you through them:
How about you come a little bit
closer so I don't have to yell?
- Okay:
Rent is $25 per week:
Over there
you've got your bathrooms:
Now, our maid quit
about a month ago: : :
So we'd appreciate it
if you would clean up after yourself:
- Okay:
- Those cabins back there-
- freight on them: 75 per week:
- Right:
Now, down by the water
you've got another picnic area:
Those are reserved for real campers
and real campers only:
Uh, real campers?
They usually arrive by automobile:
- They tend to stick around
a couple of days, then move on:
- [Groans]
Guy like yourself-
comes up in the rain: : :
With a tent and a bedroll-
we call them professional campers
around here:
- Yeah?
- You professionals have a way of lingering on-
kind of like those guys over there:
[Chuckles] I should be back
on my feet in a few days: : :
As soon as I, uh, find a job:
Because you got in late,
last night's on the house:
But collection for the week
starts on Friday at 3:00 p: M:
If you're here, I expect payment on time:
There's no exceptions:
Okay:
If not, you're out:
We understand each other?
Uh, yes: Yes, we do:
Well, good morning to you then:
And by the way?
- Yeah?
- If I were you, I would put that cover: : :
- On top of your tent:
- What's it for?
It's for the rain:
- [Vehicle Door Closes]
- [Engine Starts]
- [Vehicle Pulls Away]
- [Man] I see you have lots of experience:
Radio:
That says a lot:
Uh, why don't you have a resume?
Doesn’t matter:
How about you tell me: : :
Why Osborne and Associates
should hire someone like you?
We have over 20 applicants:
Why you?
Well, uh, despite
outward appearances: : :
I've held supervising positions
for three companies:
Which makes me wonder
about your work ethic:
Or maybe you're on some type
of desultory path:
- It means "lack of purpose:"
- Uh-huh:
Yeah, well, the truth of it
is I was laid off: : :
When the stations were
bought out and consolidated:
I mean,
everything's corporate now: : :
And I'm nearing 50
and so overqualified: : :
That you're probably
not going to hire me, are you?
Well, the thing of it is, most applicants
carry a master's degree: You don't:
No, I don't, but I still think I can do
a good job for Osborne and Associates:
Well, around here, we demand excellence,
Mr.: Walsch, not good:
I'm sorry:
Okay, listen: L-l-l-
I really need this job:
You're: : : Overqualified:
[Oscar]
Next:
Chef, let's go:
- Hey, don't let them get to you:
- [Men Chattering]
Outsiders make them
a little bit jumpy: That's all:
So I'm guessing you're gonna be
sticking around for the week?
- There we go:
- Thanks, Daddy:
- I'm sorry?
- It's harder than you thought, isn't it?
- [Objects Smashing]
- [Man Grunts]
[Oscar] Look, there’s
a convenience store on the corner:
They’ve got a recycling center:
That’s how these guys pay their rent:
You get yourself a bag of aluminum cans,
you're halfway to making the week:
Bag a day, you get your food,
you get your drink:
No, l-I don't drink:
Thanks:
Yeah? Stick around here
long enough, you will:
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Siren Wailing In Distance]
[Dishes Clacking In Distance]
- [Siren Wailing]
- [Vehicle Approaches]
[Vehicle Passes]
[Siren Fades]
[Sighs]
- God: You scared me:
- What the hell do you think you're doing?
- Well-
- These are mine:
This is my area:
[Groans]
I'm sorry: I didn't know:
Well, now you do:
Okay:
[Man]
I see you met Oakley:
- I didn't know there were territories:
- Well, we call them areas:
Yeah, well, he could've
just told me:
I'd have- thanks-
given him the damned cans:
Yeah, when a man relies on threats to
communicate, it usually indicates a weak cause:
- Hey, don't let it bother you:
- Okay:
- [Man] Sure is pretty, isn’t she?
- [Neale] Who is she?
- That’s Sunny:
- [Chef] Yeah, I wouldn’t mind: : :
Changing her tire,
if you know what I mean:
How long you been saying that?
Dreams don't have deadlines:
I got a better chance
than you do, you old fart:
- I beg to differ:
- Then you keep on begging:
- Hey, thanks:
- You okay?
Well, compared to what?
[Chuckles] That's a-
That's a hell of a point:
Here:
What happened to your neck?
Oh, that's a: : : Bull-riding accident:
Wasn't pretty:
Well, then I'd say
today's a better day:
It ain't Irish, but it's effective:
[Sighs]
No, thanks: I don't drink:
Something wrong with you?
- I just never got around to it, really:
- Huh: Hell of a thing:
Yeah:
Here you go:
No, you, uh-you keep 'em:
I'll help you get going:
All right, what's the catch? Yesterday
you looked at me like I ran over your dog:
I don't have a dog:
Something you'll soon
figure out-
People on the street?
Hardest friends to make:
Even tougher ones to lose:
- Does that mean we're friends?
- [Laughs]
Not yet:
[Man Shouting] Give me those pallets
right now! Come on! Let's go!
[Shouting Continues,
Indistinct]
Catching up on your reading?
Oh, it's, uh, padding
for under my sleeping bag:
Neale, come on in here:
Come on: I'm not gonna bite you:
Come on in here:
- All right:
- You boys hungry?
- Neale?
- You sure you have enough?
Son, the right Dumpster
always has enough:
A man’s just gotta know
where to look: That’s what it is:
- Any guacamole?
- Sometimes I wonder:
I'm not in the mood, Chef:
I'm really not:
- [Chef] Monday-now that’s
gonna be your slow day:
- Here we go:
Tuesday and Wednesday things are
gonna pick up, but only just a little:
Now, your fast food,
you’re gonna see that on Thursday: : :
Mostly 'cause folks
racing around like a bunch: : :
Of crazy rats trying to make it
through the work week:
Why?
Because Friday's payday:
Now, you take Saturday night,
your date night-
that's when folks
pay the most for their food: : :
Which is why you'll see
the guacamole on Saturday:
Why, you ask?
It's because of the-
Help me out here, Fitch:
- Discretionary:
- Income: Exactly:
This is almost done:
And Sunday’s gonna be your slow day
because most folk eat at home:
Okay, boys, get your plates:
- Neale?
- Come and get it:
Uh, no:
Uh, but thanks:
- [Chef] Boy’s still wet behind his ears:
- Ah, let him go:
You'll be back:
- [Horns Honking]
- [Vehicles Passing]
Yo, Do you need something, buddy?
- Yeah, the bathroom:
- Yeah, we-we got two bathrooms:
- Thank you:
- Where you think you're going?
- Uh, to the bathroom:
- Oh, you need to use the head?
- Mm-hmm:
- Right: Tell you what: You see across the alley?
- That tree over there? You see it?
- Yes:
Good: Then go lift your leg up
on that with the rest of the dogs:
You people make me sick:
Why can't you get a job like everybody else?
- What's the problem?
- He thinks he's coming inside
to use the bathroom:
- In and out, okay?
- Thank you:
[Insects Buzzing]
[Groans]
[Vehicle Door Opens]
- [Moans]
- [Door Closes]
[Engine Starts]
[Truck Pulls Away]
[Neale]
Excuse me?
Hi:
Oh: [Chuckles]
Hello:
Uh-
I'm Neale, and, uh,
I think I'm a little-
Harry: Yeah: I'm the, uh-
Uh, I'm the janitor:
- Hi, Harry:
- Hi:
Um- Harry, how do-
how did you like the book?
Oh, oh: It's-It's- It's wonderful:
I've been waiting
for this day ever since: : :
Your name came
on the schedule months ago:
Oh, well, here: Um, let me, uh-
let me show you to the- to the greenroom:
Yeah: Um-
Listen, Harry, um-
Uh-What did you like
about the book?
Oh, l-I don't want to bother you:
Oh, not bothering me at all:
I'm, uh- I'm interested:
I spent a lifetime in anger-
toward my father:
I'm not gonna stand here
and drop sugar all over this: : :
'Cause my old man
was a mean old cuss:
I hated him:
Strong words, I know, but true:
And this book-
your book-
helped me finally, after 20 years
of that anger, that-that hatred, to-
well, to forgive my father:
What I was feeling about my father was
really what I was feeling about myself:
And I had to forgive myself
for the feelings I had- the anger I had-
toward my father:
That's the first time
I think I've ever said that out loud:
Well, here, here:
Page three:
I know your book:
- Sure do:
- [Chuckles]
"My most common
form of communication: : :
"Is through feeling:
"Feeling is
the language of the soul:
"If you want to know what's true
for you about something: : :
Look to how you're feeling
about it:"
[Sighs]
[Groaning]
- Fitch?
- [Groaning Continues]
Fitch: Fitch?
- Can you hear me, Fitch?
- Jesus: I'm drunk, not deaf:
- [Coughs]
- Why are you doing this?
I'm not doing anything:
[Coughs]
That damn pancreas has got
a mind of its own:
I'm just playing the hand I'm dealt:
Don't start with me:
- You're killing yourself: You know that?
- Don't ask me to stop drinking:
I can't do that:
You're gonna be a real
pain in the ass, aren't you?
All right:
[Coughing]
- [Scanner Beeps]
- [Woman On P: A:] Cleanup in aisle three:
Cleanup in aisle three, please:
[Bag Rustling]
[Coins Rattling]
Um-
Thank you:
[Groans]
[Exhales]
Good morning:
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Laughing]
[Crowd Chattering, Laughing]
- [Crowd Applauding]
- [Camera Shutter Clicks]
[No Audible Dialogue]
- [Cheering]
- Ho, ho, ho! Merry-
[Child]
Hi, Santa!
[Cheering]
[Camera Shutters Clicking]
I'm not gonna die in that park:
[Wind Whistling]
[Dog Barking In Distance]
[Dial Tone]
[Beeping]
- (music)(music) [Rock]
- [Woman] Good morning: Programming:
- [Neale] Yes: I’m calling about the ad:
- Come again?
[Clears Throat]
Excuse me:
Um, could I speak with
the program director, please?
He's on air at the moment:
What can I help you with?
Well, I'm calling about the ad, uh,
for the weekend radio deejay:
Hello?
That ad wasn't supposed
to run until next week:
Well, I'm holding the paper
in my hand:
Which paper?
The Ashland Daily Tidings:
I'm sorry:
What is the date today?
Today?
November 7:
[Woman]
Hello?
No- Uh, no:
I'm-I'm still here:
Sorry: Um-
Is there a position available?
Yeah: It's been a revolving door
around here for the last six months:
Tell you what: How 'bout I take
your name and number: : :
And I'll make sure Roy
gives you a call:
Is there any chance I could
converse with Roy today?
[Imitating Neale] He's extremely
preoccupied at the moment: : :
But I'll see what I can facilitate:
At what number can he reach you?
Uh, yes, y-yes:
He-He can reach me at, um-
He can reach me at 555-7507:
And my name is Neale:
[Imitating Neale]
Hello, Neale: I'm Leora
Nice chatting with you:
Yes, well, it's been nice chatting
with you too, Leora: Thank you: And bye-bye:
- And look forward to the call:
- [Laughs]
[Groaning]
[Jackhammer Rattling]
Hey-
[Jackhammer Continues]
[Neale]
Excuse me!
Uh- Do you know how long
this is going to be?
I'm-I'm, uh-
I'm expecting a phone call:
- It's- It's sort of important:
- What the hell now?
- [Ringing]
- I don't know: It just died:
Figure it out: We got two more stops
before quitting time: You, come here:
- [Neale] Hello?
- Neale?
- [Man] Scrap that there:
- Uh, h-hello:
Hi: It's Leora:
- Hi, Leora:
- Did I catch you at a bad time?
- [Shouting]
- No, no, no, no: It's perfect: Perfect: I'm good:
- How are you?
- Good: Listen:
I told Roy about you:
He'd like to have you come in: : :
- Tomorrow, say around 9:00?
- [Man] What’s happening there, Dennis?
Uh, tomorrow would be great:
Yeah, sure:
- Just bleed the line!
- That would be good:
- [Shouting Continues]
- Okay: Uh, you know where we are?
- K: Y: O: L:
- I'm sure I can find you, Leora:
- Okay: Then we'll see you tomorrow:
- Right: Okay:
- Bye-bye:
- [Hammering Resumes]
Thank you!
So let me get this straight:
What you’re saying: : :
Is that we're all having
a conversation with God all of the time:
- Of course:
- Can you give me an example
of what you mean by that?
Sure: Um, do you ever pick up the phone
to call someone, and they’re already on the line?
Or, uh, do you ever drive down
the road feeling as though: : :
Nothing makes sense of your life: : :
And the next song on the radio
speaks directly to you?
It’s as if the lyrics
were written specifically for you: : :
And suddenly everything
falls into perspective:
Or, um- Or what about
when someone enters your life: : :
Seemingly from nowhere,
and you wonder why they are there: : :
And then one day
it all makes sense: : :
And you wonder how you ever
got along without them?
Of course:
We've all had those moments:
[Neale]
That is God:
[Woman]
Well, it happened to him: It can happen to you:
- Is happening to you- and you:
- I stand corrected:
We'll be right back
with Neale Donald Walsch: : :
And his book Conversations With God:
[Birds Calling]
[Rooster Crows]
I knew I had something
back there that would work:
Great:
And, uh, thanks for- thanks for
cleaning up- the shirt as well:
I'm gonna look employable:
It's only fear:
That's easy for you to say:
You're not the one going back out there:
What if it doesn't work?
What if it does?
Neale, you're afraid: : :
To give up the very thing in yourself
that brought you here in the first place:
Give up?
I'm running on empty:
And that's why you're here:
Uh, well, no: I'm here because-
because I lost my job:
You're here
because you lost yourself:
Well, right now I just want
to get this job:
You will:
You're ready for that now:
This is your opportunity
to experience real love:
What did you have in mind?
For you to be a man:
A real man, Neale:
Not a predator:
How many women is it going to take?
How far do you need to fall
before you realize that your behavior: : :
Is an attempt to destroy yourself?
Heal that: : :
And you'll be free:
[Sighs]
[Chef] Come here, Neale:
Let’s have a look at you:
[Fitch]
Come here:
Didn't I tell you
she was some miracle worker?
- [Rooster Crows]
- [Fitch] So how'd it go?
I don't know:
Son, we've been trying to get a look
inside her trailer for years:
How is it?
- It's good:
- She make your head spin?
She made his head spin:
- How we doing on time? Fitch, you with us?
- Yeah: Yeah:
Neale:
We know, uh,
what a big deal this is for you:
Help you with the bus fare:
And you got enough time
to get a hot breakfast too:
Maybe some bacon, eggs,
pancakes with syrup:
And toast: Don't forget the toast:
And some jelly:
Grape if they have it: And some biscuits:
Maybe some biscuits with-
- You eating this breakfast, or is he?
- [Laughs]
- Guys? Thanks:
- [Fitch] Go on now:
Yeah, go on, Neale:
- My man is stepping up:
- Yeah:
Funny, huh?
What's the big deal if someone wants
to look at your watch, right?
Hey, have we met before?
Uh, uh- No, I don't think so:
- I'm Carly
- Hi:
Uh, "You come here often?"
- [Clears Throat] Name's Neale:
- Neale:
I'm kidding, of course, because if you had,
I would have seen you, right?
I'm like a fixture on this bus:
Whew: That's me:
You'd think one of these days
I would buy a car:
Nope:
I love people too much:
I'm a receptionist: I work for
a construction company up in Medford:
We are getting
crazy busy lately: Yeah:
No: 'Cause the thought of sitting in a car
by myself all day long? Not for me:
I love people:
- Wait: I said that already, didn't I?
- Yeah:
[Laughs] Yeah, well, it's true:
Call me crazy:
- [Laughs]
- It's nice meeting you:
- Oh, are you getting off?
- Uh, you know, l-I think so:
- [Bell Dings]
- Shoot: God, isn't that just how life is?
I mean, people just moving in
and moving out, and you never know why: : :
Or if you're ever even
gonna see them again:
- I never thought about it that way:
- Makes you think, doesn't it?
- Well, good-bye:
- Oh, no, no, no, no:
You don't get to say "good-bye:"
"See you later:" "Till we meet again:"
Anything but "good-bye:"
I mean, "good-bye"
is something that you say: : :
When you walk out on a bad job
or you leave a bad lover:
- Yeah: Yeah:
- Yeah:
Well, um, see you later:
[Chuckles]
- Later:
- [Carly Laughs]
Hey: Now that's
what I'm talking about:
[Man] We’re talking to
dead people, folks: Spooky stuff:
You’ve been listening to
Fat Friday Morning Freak-out Show:
Bob and Jane will be here
with me on Monday:
They got a new book called
Breaking Up With Mommy-
or Daddy or Your Cousin
or whatever the damn name is:
And they’re gonna be
doing a book signing: : :
At Medford Pegasus Bookstore
starting at 7:00 p: M:
On Monday, I will be talking
to an angry deli worker:
He’s mad at you idiots who go
and order sliced turkey breast: : :
And then at the last minute
change it over to sliced ham:
And then for coming in
at 8:00 at night-
- [Neale] Good morning:
- You must be Neale:
- Yes:
- Leora:
- We spoke on the phone:
- I'm Rockin' Roy, the Morning Boy-
- Of course: Thanks for getting me in:
- You're not in yet:
- [Roy] Stay young: Stay cool:
- You still have to meet Roy:
- (music)(music) [Rock]
- He's a handful:
You tell Jainey I wanna talk to her:
I don't remember approving this, uh,
drunk Russian guy for tomorrow's show:
Nobody cares about this: I mean,
so what if he drank too much vodka: : :
And fell out of a six-story building
and lived to tell about it?
That-That's actually pretty funny:
Okay, yeah, we go
with the drunk Russian guy: : :
But just get me a list of backups
in case he turns out to be a dud:
And make sure that he is not drunk,
because l-Who the hell is this?
This is your 9:00:
For the weekend slot:
Oh: Yeah, yeah:
Okay: Hi: Hi:
- Hi:
- Uh, just head in: I'll be right in:
- You got it:
- Okay?
Listen, next time I'm talking about
my personal affairs: : :
It would be nice if you'd let me know
there's someone standing right there:
If you'd take a breath once in a while,
I would be happy to:
Just get me the files, all right?
Cancel this lunch:
Oh, man: I am sorry
about all these delays:
I have had
just a crazy month: Uh-
So, how are you, uh, Nick?
- Uh, Neale:
- Neale: Right: Okay:
Uh, Leora is very
impressed with you:
- She says that you have some good experience?
- Mmm:
Well, um-Well, I was on the air
for a while in Baltimore: : :
And then down south
for a few years after that:
I've always been around radio
in my career-
You know what? Listen:
I can make people enjoy the sound
of leaves falling on the radio:
How do you do that?
You're gonna have to hire me
to find out:
What are your Saturday
afternoons like?
Saturday afternoon would be okay:
It's a four-hour slot:
Is that gonna fit in your schedule?
- Yeah, that'd be good:
- Yeah?
Mm-hmm:
Yeah:
Okay, good:
You're hired:
- Great:
- I'll see ya on Saturday:
Yeah:
And shut the door:
Thank you:
[No Audible Dialogue]
Oh:
So I'm gonna call you, um, about the-
about the new mix:
I think that sounds great:
And your ideas were perfect:
Hey-
[Laughs] See ya:
And my ideas were perfect:
And my ideas
were perfect:
And my ideas were perfect:
My ideas were-
[No Audible Dialogue]
Perfect:
[Chef] Man, hot, fresh pizza
tastes a heck of a lot better: : :
Coming out the box
than it does the Dumpster:
- Neale, you want another piece?
- Yeah: Yeah, I want another piece of pizza:
I brought it, didn't I?
So anyway: : :
I look out the window,
and she's got this guy, you know:
And I think, well, maybe
that's not such a bad thing:
- [Chef] Right!
- So, you know, that's where I am right now:
You know what? I'm with
great friends right now and l-
- That's what I'm happy about, so cheers:
- Yeah!
- To great friends:
- Gettin' the best cabin in the park:
That's right:
Gettin' the best cabin in the park:
Bon appetit:
[Laughs]
Good morning:
- Good morning to you too:
- [Fitch Coughing]
[Leora]
Hello, Neale:
Hey, uh, Leora:
What are you doin' here?
- Well, nice to see you too:
- I'm sorry:
I thought you lived in Medford
for some reason:
Born and raised right here in Ashland:
And you? Do you live around here?
Neale, ol' boy!
How ya doin', buddy?
- Look at you: Mr.: Big Time now:
- Yeah:
Neale, you gonna introduce me
to your utterly gorgeous lady friend?
Um, uh, Leora, this is Fitch:
Fitch, this is Leora:
Nice to meet you:
Nice to meet you too:
Aren't you easy on the eyes?
Uh, Fitch, can we
talk later, do you think?
Oh, don't be silly:
I'll join you for a drink:
Oh, don't worry: Even though you're
the only friend I know with a job: : :
- I brought my own:
- Fitch-
Unless you'll be moving this little gathering
back to your new cabin?
- Fitch:
- You sly older:
I see how you operate:
My friend here's- has got a nice cabin:
You really must see it:
It comes with a nice cot:
Probably fit the two of you in a pinch:
- [Laughs]
- [Screams]
- [Fitch] Oh! Geez:
- I'm sorry:
- So sorry:
- It's okay:
- I'm sorry: Here- Here, let me-
- It's okay!
- I'm an idiot: I'm- I'm sorry:
- Please stop!
And down he goes:
[Coughing]
- I should go:
- I'm- I'm sorry:
Sorry:
- [Oakley Groans]
- [Cans Smashing]
[Oscar]
Rent, $25 per week:
Over there you've got your bathroom:
Now, our maid quit
about a month ago: : :
So we’d appreciate it
if you would clean up after yourself:
Thought I should come by,
see if you needed any help:
- Is that it?
- Yep:
Strange to think everything I own
fits in a duffel bag:
There's nothing wrong
with traveling light:
We should probably
talk about the other day:
- No, it's not necessary:
- It is:
From what I remember, it is:
Sunny seems to think it happened
because I wasn't prepared: : :
For you to get
out of here before me:
And since I’ve never known the woman
to blow smoke- Amazing, huh?
Make it all the way
to 60 years old-
one moment I'm back
to being a jealous kid:
Stupid:
Must feel good to be gettin' out:
It's like you said- friends on the street,
hardest ones to make: : :
Tougher ones to lose:
Does that mean we're friends?
Not yet:
[Door Closes]
[Doorknob Clicking]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Hmm:
Leora!
Roy!
Anybody, it's Neale!
Hello!
[Coins Dropping]
[Doors Close]
[Bus Pulls Away]
[Wind Whistling]
Hey: What are you doing
sleeping on a bench?
Looking for you:
God, that’s a trip:
Everyone was gone?
Yeah: Just when things
were getting better:
What do you mean?
Well, I mean- I mean, look at you:
Wow: I don't think I've ever seen you
out of work clothes:
Yeah, don't I look good?
Oh, yeah: You look great:
It's a- It's a great look on you:
Yeah, I'm headin' over to the Black Sheep
for happy hour with the girlfriends:
- Oh:
- They have killer drink specials:
Jimmy the bartender-
[Shudders]
Makes the best
Long Island iced teas in town:
Oh, God, I look like hell:
I think you look beautiful:
All right, Neale, what's up?
- Nothing: Why?
- Come on:
First you tell me I look nice:
Now I look beautiful? Spill:
I don't know:
I just-
I've just been, you know,
thinking about: : :
You, us: : : A lot:
- Neale-
- When I'm with you: : :
I feel like things just-
things just fit:
I mean, I like myself, and it's like you're a-
you know, you're a best friend:
- You gotta feel that too, right?
- Neale-
Okay, fine: You're in your 20s,
I'm in my 40s: What's the big deal?
Are you nuts?
That's a driver's license and a nine year old:
Don't get weird on me:
You okay?
Yeah: Just out of sorts:
I'm gonna-
Just gonna sit here and think for
a little bit: I'll take the next bus:
Good-bye, Neale:
Right:
[Answering Machine Beeps]
Hi, Neale:
It’s Leora:
Thought I'd try you again:
I've been thinking about you,
wondering if you need anything:
Things are good with me:
I got a new job:
Nothin' fancy: Office manager
for a medical practice up in Medford:
And I moved in with Tommy: He just bought
a really cute fixer-upper in town: : :
And it needs a woman’s touch:
Anyway, give a call when you can:
Miss talking with you:
[Beeps]
[Male Voice]
Have you had enough yet?
Are you ready now?
Do you really want to know the answers
to the questions you’re asking?
Are you going to answer me?
You’ve asked a lot of questions:
You’re angry:
And now I ask you, do you really
want to know the answers: : :
To the questions you’re asking: : :
- Or are you just venting?
- This is crazy:
I know what you’re thinking:
And I talk to everyone: : :
All the time in their own voice:
The question is, who listens?
From the highest mountain
it has been shouted:
In the lowest place,
its whisper has been heard:
And through the corridors
of all human experience: : :
This truth has been echoed:
Love is the answer:
You have projected
the role of parent onto God: : :
And have thus come up with a god
who judges and rewards or punishes:
You have created a fear-based
reality around love:
And this fear-based love reality dominates
your experience of love:
Indeed, it actually creates it:
Is it fear that you need
in order to be, do and have: : :
What is intrinsically right?
Must you be threatened
in order to be good?
And what is being good?
Who gets the final say about that?
I tell you this:
You are your own rule-maker:
You set the guidelines:
Love is all there is:
Yes, you’ve heard it before: In fact,
I’ve even put it on a bumper sticker for you:
But in times of trouble, in
times of worry, doubt or fear: : :
You choose to forget:
What you should do is answer
the simple question-
what would love do now?
To live your life
without expectation: : :
Without the need
for specific results: : :
That is freedom:
Remember: You are constantly
in the act of creating yourself:
You are, in every moment,
deciding who and what you are:
You decide this largely through
the choices you make: : :
Regarding who and what
you feel passionate about:
Gotta tell ya, I'm a little worried
about what people might say: : :
When I tell 'em I'm having
a conversation with you:
Worry is the activity of a mind: : :
That does not understand
its connection with me:
- Hmm:
- Do you remember the question-
what would love do now?
- Of course:
- Answer that question, Neale: : :
And I will be there,
always, in all ways:
[Chirping]
[Male Voice] Suffering has
nothing to do with events: : :
But with one’s reaction to them:
What’s happening is
merely what’s happening:
- How we feel about it is another matter:
- I just want my life back:
- You can’t have anything you want:
- I'm sorry?
Well, what are you sorry for?
- You said I can't have anything I want:
- That’s right:
- What?
- You can’t have anything you want:
- I can't have anything I want?
- Correct:
- Well, that doesn't make sense:
- Sure, it does:
Your very request is one of lack: : :
And you saying you want a thing only works
to produce that precise experience-
- wanting-in your reality:
- Yeah:
Should I therefore punish you: : :
For making a choice that I myself
have laid before you?
This is a question
you must ask yourself: :
Before you would assign me
the role of a condemning god:
Unendingly have you
beseeched me, show myself:
Explain myself:
Reveal myself:
I am doing so here
in terms so plain: : :
You cannot misunderstand:
I am here:
Right here:
Right now:
Now is the time to go to
your god space, more than ever:
It will bring you
great peace of mind:
And from a peaceful mind
do great ideas flow: : :
Ideas which could be solutions: : :
To the biggest problems
you imagine yourself to have:
[Female Voice] Do you imagine
this is too big a problem for me to solve?
Is getting out of this jam
too big a miracle for me to handle?
I understand that you may think
it’s too big for you to handle: : :
Even with all the tools
I’ve given you:
But do you really think
it’s too big for me?
[Chirping]
[Blows Nose, Groans]
Sometimes you frustrate
the hell out of me:
[Male Voice]
I would think that would be a good thing:
Is this supposed to be funny?
Well, who do you think
invented humor?
- [Sneezes]
- Bless you:
I just-
- I don't know what you want from me:
- Neale:
- Mm-hmm?
- You’ve got me all wrong:
And you’ve got you all wrong too:
I don’t want anything from you
other than for you to be happy:
But you think you are below me,
when in truth we are all one:
There is no separation:
I want for you what you want for you-
nothing more, nothing less:
I am not concerned about
your worldly success:
Only you are:
You are not to worry
about making a living:
True masters are those who have chosen
to make a life rather than a living:
Go ahead: Do whatever
you really love:
Do nothing else:
You have so little time:
How can you think
of wasting a moment: : :
Doing something for a living
that you don’t like to do?
That is not a living:
That is a dying:
[Leora]
Neale?
Neale:
What are you having me type?
Oh:
I'm still trying to figure that out:
What time is it?
Neale: : :
- It's amazing:
- What's-What's amazing?
- This stuff is distracting me while I'm at work:
- Oh-
And I love it:
I don't care if this
is gonna sound weird: : :
Or what people might think about me
for saying something like this, but-
I've been asleep: : :
Stuck in this perpetuating
nightmare of a life: : :
Primarily built on fear and doubt:
Do you really want to know
how much time I've spent in my life: : :
Worrying about
how I was gonna make a living: : :
Worried about making ends meet?
I don't want to spend my life
making a living, Neale:
I want to spend my life: : :
Making a life:
A life that makes a difference:
A life built on love and compassion:
And this stuff-
Neale, I'm even rereading
things I've already finished:
Do you hear what I'm saying to you?
I do: I do: Listen,
I gotta tell you, it's-
It's like I'm just standing by:
I'm just taking dictation:
- L- I can't stop:
- Why would you?
Leora, this is gonna be a book:
Not just one book:
This should complete Book One:
I've already got, uh, six more
filled with material for Book Two:
Well- I better get busy:
Thank you:
Uh, listen, I know
I'm not paying you:
- Stop:
- I don't expect you to work for free:
Neale, we're friends:
Besides, just think of all the money
I'll be saving on therapy:
Okay:
I want to make a deal:
If something does
happen from this: : :
Uh, I want to share some
of the profits with you:
If you want to create
abundance for yourself: : :
Create it for someone else:
Did I write that?
My friend, you got yourself a deal:
[Chuckles]
Doesn't fit into your line of books:
Well, that's the point:
It's not supposed to fit into
anybody's line of books:
Okay, Bob:
Let's see: : :
If you actually read your own mail:
[Birds Chirping]
[Lawn Mower Whirring]
[Lawn Mower Stops]
- [Sniffs]
- [Phone Ringing]
- Hello:
- [Man] Neale Walsch?
- Yeah, used to be:
- Bob Friedman, Hampton Roads Publishing:
Hi, Bob:
You took the dare:
Yes:
And I like your style, Neale:
Don't get what you want,
go right to the top:
Exactly what I would do
if I was a man in your position:
What-What exactly is my position?
You're about to become
a published author, Neale:
- You're-You're kidding:
- I never kid about money:
We're gonna start out
with 5,000 copies:
Okay, what happens after my family
gets done reading it, Bob?
[Laughs]
Optimism: I like that:
- I believe in the book:
- So do l:
Which is why we're putting this
on the fast track:
- Okay:
- My office will call your people:
- They'll work out the details:
- Okay: Well, um, um, ju-
Uh, Bob, I am my people:
Not anymore, Neale:
Now you've got yourself a partner:
I'll be in touch:
Yes!
[No Audible Dialogue]
The woman's name is Sharon Parker:
She's a pro: Trust me, Neale:
It shows: Just let me do the talking:
Okay: What about Warner Books?
We still gonna meet with them?
Well, I'll circle back next week if I have to,
but Putnam- Putnam is the future:
Remember, don't react to
anything Sharon says:
This game is won without emotion:
- Yeah:
- All right? Okay?
Now, let's go have some fun:
[Bob] I’m sure you’re very aware
that we’ve had numerous inquiries: : :
From other majors
about Neale's book:
- Any offers?
- Aren't there always, Sharon?
[Laughs]
Well, that's what makes life interesting:
Don't you think, Bob?
Did you have an offer
in mind, Sharon?
Well, before
we get to that-
I've been in this business
for over half my life:
And with the exception of four years
at one of the giant firms: : :
I've been with Putnam,
and I think even Bob will agree: : :
That that is pretty rare
in our business:
People have no loyalty:
Truth is: : :
The world we live in
is getting tougher:
Times are changing:
- How much, Sharon?
- Now, you probably wonder why
I am telling you all of this:
- How much, Sharon?
- I am telling you all of this because: : :
There is at Putnam, I believe,
a soul behind the company:
Yes, we have a lot of titles:
But we also have the ability to maintain
the soul of a small press like Bob's:
And when I heard that Hampton
had your title, I was pleased:
Sharon, how much?
We are prepared to offer you
one million dollars: : :
For the worldwide rights
to Conversations With God:
[Bob] Thank you
for the nice words:
I really appreciate them,
as I'm sure Neale does:
And I agree with you:
Putnam does have a soul:
They also have
buying power:
And unfortunately at that number,
Hampton Roads will have to pass:
Thank you for coming out:
- Neale? Shall we?
- Mm-hmm:
You know, I thought we were coming here
with a very generous offer today, Bob:
So did l:
This guy is booked back-to-back solid
for the next two months, Sharon:
I can’t print the book fast enough:
And I think we can both agree,
this is merely the tip of a very big iceberg:
Come on, Sharon:
- I thought you said you liked the book:
- I do like the book, Bob:
And I'm prepared to give you
one million reasons why I like it:
- We can do a million on our own:
- Oh:
In fact, we'll send you
a postcard when we do:
- Neale:
- Mmm:
Time to go:
[Clears Throat]
Uh, thank you:
Thank you:
[Whispers]
What, are you crazy?
- Wait for it:
- That's a lot of money:
- I said-
- Bob!
Wait for it:
[Sighs]
[Clears Throat]
One-five: Take it or leave it:
So, why do you want the book?
Well, you might think this is
a little old-fashioned: : :
But I think your book
could change the world:
- It’s-
- Yours:
It's hers, Bob:
- It's mine:
- Of course:
- At 1:5 million:
- Yes, Bob:
At 1:5 million:
Neale, why don't you pick up
the check for us?
I'm gonna walk Sharon out,
tie up a few loose ends:
- I'll be back in a few minutes:
- Okay:
Bob, thank you:
Thank you, Sharon:
Congratulations, Neale:
Michael:
- Okay, now, listen-
- Nicely done:
I’m so glad you think so:
The book cover, we’re keeping that:
I have some very
definite ideas about it:
I’ve got the artwork
already laid out:
I think you just need
to take a look at it:
[Continues, Indistinct]
Uh, could I have the check, please?
- Sorry about that:
- Not at all:
- What're you reading?
- Economics:
- I have a test in 45 minutes, and I'm dreading it:
- Oh:
- You in university?
- Twelve credits to go, and I'm done:
Just in time for summer, I guess:
Well, maybe by next summer
if I'm lucky:
I have a son: Between day care
and my other job and class: : :
Things, uh- they move
a little slower in my life:
Well, good luck on the test:
Thank you:
More coffee?
No, I'm, uh- I'm so very good:
- Thanks:
- All right:
Thank you:
- Oh, my God!
- My God too:
This is a small percentage?
It was a really big check:
Neale, forgive me:
I don't wanna seem ungrateful:
But this is a lot of money:
I thought you could use it for the-
for the remodeling:
- You know, you could do it up right:
- Neale, I can't take this:
Leora, I want you to have this:
- Also, by the way, we did make a deal, right?
- [Laughs]
Hmm?
Tommy, Neale's here!
- Tell him to come in:
- You're staying for breakfast:
- We need to celebrate:
- Okay:
What are you having?
[Birds Chirping]
Come on, Neale: It'll add one,
maybe two days in Russia:
- That's all they're asking:
- Well, I don't care what they're asking:
I'm not gonna do it:
I haven't been home in two weeks:
- I'm tired:
- Just think about it:
"Just think about it:"
Whose side are you on anyway?
God's:
[Neale]
You know, I wish l-I wish I knew:
Um, maybe it’s because
I’ve screwed up so much of my life:
I don't know: What I do know
is that this is not about me:
It's- It's about Leora, I think:
- Um, what-
- I've been to your lectures, Mr.: Walsch:
And I read your book: : :
About how God is this friendly god
and the universe is a friendly place:
And you don't-
you don't believe that:
I believe your god
is a vengeful god:
I adopted my son
when he was six months old: : :
Because I was told I could
never have children:
And we never told Jimmy
that he was adopted until, um: : :
He was old enough to
understand what that meant:
And at 14, we decided it was time:
His grades fell off:
His whole attitude changed:
I mean, he got
in trouble at school: It was-
It was a big mess: And he was angry
at his mother for giving him up:
He was angry at us for-
for telling him:
And he was angry at
everything in his life:
The only way to calm him down: : :
Was to promise that
when he turned 18:: :
We would find his mother:
No matter the cost, no matter
how long it took, we promised him: : :
That he would
get to meet his mother:
[Neale]
And: : :
Did his attitude change?
Marginally, but, um: : :
The son we once knew,
the son we loved so dearly was, um-
was gone:
And he never
called me "Mother" again:
And on Jimmy's 18th birthday: : :
He was killed on a motorcycle:
A drunk driver killed my Jimmy:
So please enlighten me on your definition
of a friendly god, Mr.: Walsch: : :
Because I don’t see a friendly god
putting parents who...
who love their son unconditionally
through something like this:
What does your god
say now, Mr.: Walsch?
Um-
[Wind Whistling]
[Birds Chirping]
I'm sorry, baby:
You'll never love anyone:
[Exhales, Inhales]
What is your name?
Georgia:
Um-
Your son: : :
Died so that you could
keep your promise to him:
His mother: : :
Died a few years ago:
His passing was the only way
that he could be with her:
See?
[Sobbing]
So, where did that come from?
- Neale-
- Honestly, Leora, I don't know
what just happened in there:
What if I made all that stuff up?
Did you?
I don't know:
I don't know where
any of that came from:
Yes, you do:
- Neale-
- Yeah?
[No Audible Dialogue]
Okay, go ahead:
Book the extra days in Russia:
I already did:
You were right about me, Mom:
But I am learning:
[Rain Falling]
[Thunder Rumbling]
Here's your plane ticket:
You're on the 10:00:
Thanks for everything,
and I'll see you in New York:
Just a minute:
[Male Voice] Do not feel abandoned,
for I am always with you:
I will not leave you:
I cannot leave you, for you are
my creation and my product:
My daughter, my son,
my purpose and myself:
Call on me, therefore-
[With Female Voice]
Wherever and whenever you are separate: : :
From the peace that I am:
I will be there:
Do you have a book for me to sign?
No, I don't: But I wanted to
thank you for writing it:
Reading it didn't convince me
that you're having conversations with God:
It convinced me that I am too:
- Thank you:
- Oh, no:
No, thank you:
5@y3