Hector, are we spinning yet?
Nice.
Chelios! How we doing, baby?
And you never call me no more.
Come on, what is that?
Where's the love?
How are you feeling?
I guess you're feeling like
shit, right about now.
Now you can't..
You can't move too good, huh?
You can't breathe too good.
What's wrong with you?
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
What is this?
Oh, fuck!
Can you guess what this is?
I bet you can, Chelios.
Hold on, check this out.
Oh! This is plain sick, man!
I must be the motherfucking
genius of sick!
Poison Chev Chelios
in his sleep?
That's like some
Shakespeare or some shit.
You knocked this dude
out pretty good!
About to get you a spot
on the Dodgers, son.
Maybe you don't understand
what just happened.
I just fucking killed you.
Try not to embarrass yourself
because you're on 'Candid Camera'!
This shit here I gave you!
This is some..
high-tech, sci-fi, Chinese
synthetic bullshit!
I don't exactly know
what's in this shit, dude!
All I know is that once this shit
has binded with your blood cells,
you're fucked, baby, and
believe me it's binded.
Yeah, you got yourself about
an hour, max. Tick-tock.
This shit has been real.
You probably should've thought
twice before you whacked Don Kim.
Experiencing a little
20/20 hindsight?
You know what? Thought so.
Now, you have yourself
a nice death.
Asshole!
You like that, huh? Home run!
It's Eve. I'm glad you
called, but I'm not here.
Leave a message,
unless you're selling
something 'cause I'm
not interested.
If you're not, then just..
Wait, time's up.
Get a cell phone, honey. Please?
Come on.
Come on, come on.
- Dr, Miles office, may I help you?
- Yeah, let me speak to him.
I'm sorry, but the doctor isn't in.
May I take a message?
- Where is he?
- I beg your pardon, sir?
Where the fuck is he?
No.. yeah! Wow!
Where you from?
I don't know, sir. This
is his answering service.
- Jesus fucking Christ.
- Would you like me to page him?
Yeah, fine.
Please let the doctor know that
Chev Chelios is a dead man,
- if he can't call me back within the hour.
- Could you spell that?
- Yeah, D-E-A-D! Chelios.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- Kaylo, where were you last night?
- What's up, Chev?
- I said, where were you last night?
I..
- You want to know what I was doing?
- What?
- Getting killed, you plum.
Yeah, you heard me.
Ricky fuckin' Verona..
- Ricky Verona?
- Who thought..
that little bitch had the stones
to wet me in my own crib?
- I mean, it's inconceivable.
Yet, here we are.
Where are we?
I'm dead and you're simple.
Now listen to me.
Put the word out I'm
looking for Verona.
- Anyone sees him you call me, understand?
- I..
I'm gonna get that fucker if
it's the last thing I do.
It may actually be the last thing I do.
You understand that?
- Ricky Verona.
- Copy me on that Kaylo?
Find him!
- Hey, man!
- What the fuck you doing?
What the fuck you doing?
Where am I going?
Fuck you!
Bathroom don't work.
What you doing?
- Yo, Chevy..
- Where's Verona?
- Talk!
- What about?
- Don't fuck with me!
- I'm not! Just calm down!
Don't tell me to calm down!
- Fuck, man!
- Orlando? You all right?
Hey, there's a white nigger
with a gun up in here!
Just be still, motherfuckers!
You see that? I'm trying
to help you here, man.
I gotta find Ricky Verona.
- Why would I know where Verona is?
- Yeah, yeah.
You don't know, but
you're gonna tell me.
Or I'm gonna blow your brains
into the fuckin' toilet!
I'm gonna fucking kill him!
Whoa! Put your guns down!
The white man is cool!
The white man is.. The
white man is cool!
Y'all like them Somalia niggers.
Now look, Chevy came here
to discuss something.
We gonna discuss this shit in
a civilized manner. Chevy?
- You had a question? Or a point to make?
- Where's Verona?
Okay, I'm not affiliated
with Ricky Verona.
You pulled the Anselmo job together.
Don't fuckin' bullshit me!
Easy! Easy! Easy!
All right?
Look, you're operating
under a false pretence.
Ricky and I did not pull..
the Anslemo job together. Ricky
fucked me on the Anselmo job.
In fact, Ricky Verona
still owes me $7,5000.
- Not how I heard it.
- But that's the way it is.
So, you see, I don't know
where Verona is. If I did,
I'd probably be there right now,
beating the Gucci off his ass.
All right.
That's what I'm talking about.
That's almost civilized.
Shit, dude. What's
wrong with you?
- Just give me some coke.
You got any coke?
Now you're gonna insult me.
Come on, I don't have time!
Just give me something.
- I'm really dying, here.
- I can see that.
I'm really fucking dying!
- You saying this is medicinal -use coke?
- That's right.
Well?
- What?
- This shit ain't free, nigger.
That's enough.
What, you gonna do the shit right here?
Chevy, come on, man!
Oh, God!
Chevy..
Oh! What the..
- Oh, that's good. That's good.
- That's good, right?
Why you looking for
Verona, anyway?
Some Chinese assholes
hired him to kill me.
- This is about Don Kim.
- What do you know about it?
- I know you pulled the trigger.
- Of course, I pulled the trigger.
Why wouldn't I pull
the fuckin' trigger?
Whoa.. Yo, Chelios, you good?
- This shit ain't working.
- Excuse me?
I know what I have to do.
Well, shit. A man's got to
do what a man's got to do.
- What is it you gotta do?
- I gotta kick some black ass.
What?
- Shit!
- There he goes again.
Who wants white meat?
You ain't got shit,
motherfucker!
- Put that fuckin' twig down, bitch!
- Faggot!
Get the fuck out of here, bitch!
- Doc?
- What's up, Doc?
- You motherfucker!
- Why aren't you dead yet?
- What the fuck you doing?
- Coming for you.
- Fucking believe me.
- Whatever.
I'll be waiting, but
you won't make it.
You should know that I'm
all about hooking up
with that mystery girl,
you've been banging.
Soon as you're underground.
I forgot to say so on that
gay James Bond tape I left.
What, and then you're gonna
rape my grandmother?
Bla, bla, fuckin' bla.
You listen to me.
What do you think Carlito will do
when he finds out what you did?
Your whole crew is history!
- Driver, pull over!
- Fuck!
Great.
You talking about Carlito? Because
me and Carlito, we're boys now.
We're tight.
Tight, like when your brother
fucked you in 3rd grade?
That's snappy. But I did you
pretty good, didn't I Chelios?
- Admit it.
- We'll see.
Pull over!
- Know what the best part is?
- Sorry, must go. Bye-bye.
- Yeah.
- Doctor Miles.
Fuck! What took you so long?
Jesus Christ.
- Sorry, Chevy, I
just got the message.
- Okay. Forget it.
Listen, I'm dying!
I've been poisoned with some
Chinese synthetic shit.
- What?
- You've gotta fucking do something for me.
- What are your symptoms?
- It's like I'm slowing down.
- Stuck in tar.
- Blurred vision?
- Yeah.
- Dizzy?
- Sure.
- Any pain in your chest?
Not really. I feel
good, right now.
- What are you doing?
- Driving through a mall, cops chasing me.
The adrenaline is what's
keeping you alive.
- Having a little trouble
hearing you, Doc.
You got to keep moving, Chevy.
Explain.
If I'm right, they gave
you the Beijing cocktail.
It's very nasty shit.
It works on the adrenal
gland, blocks it's receptors.
The only thing you can
do to slow it down,
is to keep the flow of
adrenaline constant.
Meaning, if you stop, you die.
Hang on.
Jesus! What..
Are you there? Are you okay?
- What'd you say, Doc?
- If you stop, you die!
That's what I'm trying to do. Keep
moving, keep the blood pumping.
Chevy, you there?
Every time I slow down, it's
like my veins start to rust.
- Did you take anything?
- Couple grams of coke.
That's a start. I'll be in L.A.
in an hour.
I'll call you as soon as I get there.
Do not stop moving!
Taxi! Yo, yo, yo!
- Go!
- Where we go?
Just drive!
- Would you mind?
- Where you want to go, man?
Right.
- Oh, shit!
- Go right!
- Okay! Yes!
- Go fucking right!
Crank the music.
Crank it!
But don't tell my heart,
my achy breaky heart
I just don't think
he'd understand
And if you tell my heart,
my achy breaky heart
It might blow up
and kill this man
Pull over, pull over.
- Thanks, mate. I'll be back in one minute.
- Okay, cowboy.
Hey, buddy!
You move, you die.
- Hey, it's Eve. I'm glad you called..
- Fuck!
Where to, man?
Beverly Hills.
- Chevy!
- Hey, boss.
- Something urgent has come up.
- So I've heard.
Word travels fast.
Carlito, I need your help. I
don't have a lot of time.
No, not much.
We've gotta find an
antidote, or something.
- What's the matter?
- That shit they gave you..
It's that Chinese shit.
- There is no antidote.
- What, that's it?
Honestly, you should
be dead already.
- It's a miracle.
- A miracle?
We give that shit to horses.
You don't have to be so
damn fucking cool about it.
What do you expect me to do?
Find that punk Verona,
and his whole fucking crew, and
feed them to a cage of wolverines.
What is this? What, are you
boys now or something?
Verona?
That's a small time punk.
Not to say that this
isn't an opportunity.
Opportunity?
Everyone knows the love
I have for you, Chev.
But maybe this makes up for
the Don Kim hit which was..
- perhaps ill-advised.
- Ill-advised?
The heat from Hong Kong was
much more than we anticipated.
Well, that's outstanding.
Glad to know my death can
be of some use to you.
- Don't be difficult.
- I'm not being difficult.
I don't know if you noticed,
but I'm having a difficult
fucking day, brother!
I'm out of here.
You're not getting
in my cab wet!
- I just gave you $200
to wait for 3 minutes.
- You're not getting
in my car, no way!
Yeah, you're right.
Al-Qaeda! Al-Qaeda!
I love America! I love Bush!
I Voted Bush!
- Yeah.
- Hey, Chev. My flight's delayed.
- Shit!
- It's all right. Relax.
I mean, don't relax.
That shit they gave you is
cutting off your adrenaline.
Excitement, fear, danger.
It causes your body to make a
chemical called ephedrine.
They introduced an
inhibitor to your system.
Fuck!
Dude, you've got to
massively increase
the ephedrine levels
in your body,
to force out the inhibitors.
Go to a hospital.
Get epinephrine, an
artificial adrenaline.
It comes in
10-milligram syringes.
It's potent, so don't overdo it.
A 5th of an injection will do.
Chevy? Did you get that?
- Did you get that?
- Yeah, epi-something.
Okay, okay. I've gotta go.
Now, I'll call you
when I get there.
- Yeah?
- Chev.
Yeah?
- Chev?
- What?
Hello?
Come on!
Mother!
- Chev?
- Yes, fuck?
I just saw Verona's brother
walk into the Prince.
- The Prince.
- Yeah.
I was just down here getting a taco,
and he walked in, 2 minutes ago.
- Where are you, now?
- Across the street, getting a taco.
- Where are you?
- I'm there. Meet me on 7th and Catalina.
Is he in there, now?
Did anyone go in with him?
Right, wait here.
How'd you like that one, tough guy?
How frickin' awesome was that, huh?
Well, well, well.
You feel like talking? Where's
your fuckin' brother?
Doing your mother like
a whore, you bitch!
Nice. I wonder how many steaks
I could carve out of you.
You died, motherfucker!
Yeah, wanna fuck with me, ese?
What, you rolling
pin mighty good?
What the hell you
think you doing, huh?
What, you want to dance
with me, motherfucker?
I'll fuck you up! Come on!
Jesus! Nothing's easy.
Wanna hold hands?
- Hey, talk to me, bro.
- Hey, Ricky.
You in the mood for
sucking me off?
Maybe let me lick your
ass or something?
Who is this? Shit! Chelios?
- Is this fucking Chelios?
- That's right, bro.
Guess how I got your brother's phone?
I'm sure you have it all figured out.
Looks like you should've cut
me up when you had the chance.
I'm having a little
trouble hearing you.
You experiencing a
little 20/20 hindsight?
You're supposed to
be fucking dead!
You know, I kind of like
that shit you put in me.
Gonna give me some more?
- Well, I'm.. I'm..
- I know, I know. Hey..
What's this?
A necklace! You guys really
are faggots, aren't you?
You motherfucker!
My grandfather gave that medallion
to my father and then he..
Fuck!
Fuck you, man! Shove
that thing up your ass!
No thanks.
You know, I think
I'll hang on to it.
You'll have to come
find me, after all.
Fucked up that you
killed your own brother.
You..
What's that shit? Epi..
10 milligrams?
Good work, Kaylo.
Doctor Sing to the labor room.
- Asshole!
- No need to push.
I'm looking for something
that starts with "E".
England?
Very funny. No. Some kind
of artificial adrenaline.
- Artificial adrenaline?
- Yeah, I've got heart problems.
- Epinephrine.
- Yes! Epinephrine.
I love you. Epinephrine.
I can't give you epinephrine.
- Why?
- Just a minute.
Oi! What do you mean..
- What is this shit?
- Nasal spray.
Miserable bitch! What?
Nasal spray. It's got epinephrine in it.
It'll get you tweaked, man.
Hey!
- Sure that's the guy?
- Yeah.
This room's clear.
Could anyone speaking
Korean please come to ER?
Anyone speaking Korean..
Yo, yo, yo!
Yo!
Stop!
Jerk-off!
Coming through!
I know you motherfuckers
have epinephrine.
- Clear the hallway!
- Corner. Is the OR ready?
I'm having a bad day. Tell me you've
got epinephrine on this cart!
You all right?
Tell me you've got epinephrine!
- Motherfucker!
- I don't know. I'll check.
- Get back!
- Take it easy!
- Do you understand
fucking English?
- Yes, I just don't know
which draw it's in.
Come on, look!
- Give me the fucking epinephrine!
- I don't know where it is, man!
What is this, a rest home?
What are you doing?
Hurry up!
- Get back!
- We can't treat without insurance.
- I don't know if I have
it, give me a second!
Put the weapon down!
What the fuck! Where
the fuck is it?
- My heart!
- What?
- Yeah, yeah.
Drop your weapon now!
- What do you think you're doing? This is..
- Shut up! You!
Gimme the epinephrine?
Don't even think about it!
Albuterol.. Flortab.. Epinephrine!
Here it is! I've got it!
- Here you go.
- Gimme that.
- Asshole.
- I'm not gonna tell you again.
All right? Just be quiet.
Juice me.
Juice?
Do it.
- All right.
- Come on!
I haven't got all day.
Okay, I need both of them to..
Give them to me.
One.
Two. Clear!
Get the fuck back!
Get out!
How much of this stuff
did he say to take?
Chevy, we're in the air, man.
- Did you get the stuff?
- Got it.
- Did you take it?
- Yup.
- You took the whole thing.
I said one 5th. The
shit's gonna kill you.
Right.
- Chest on fire?
- Check.
- But you're cold.
And you've got a steel
hard on, don't you?
Let me check.
- Check.
- Your blood vessels are stimulated.
Urinary sphincter's so tight, you
couldn't piss to save your life.
Urinary sphincter, check!
- Get some Vicodin. You at the hospital?
- Negative.
Get some grass.
That shit'll be out of your system
in 30 minutes, or it'll kill you.
This is costing me a fortune. I'll
call you in 20 minutes when we land.
- Copy.
- Hey, Chevy?
You're a good dude.
Been nice knowing you.
Copy, out.
Some medical emergency.
Police have declined to name the
man they say is still at large,
on a citywide rampage that
has left one man dead,
dozens injured, and hundreds of
thousands of dollars of damage..
in it's smoking, bloody wake.
The suspect is a
professional killer..
with ties to organized crime
and a long police record.
He is considered armed
and highly dangerous.
We now continue with regularly
scheduled programming,
but stay tuned for
continuing coverage
of this bizarre
story, as it unfolds.
What your saying is that next to
olives, onions, lemons and limes..
Oh, shit! Take it easy.
Get back, pig!
I.. just give me the..
Come on, then. Let's
see you run, piggy.
Come on, piggy.
Give me the gun. Let's
talk this over.
Yeah, you want it? There.
- Let's go, come on.
- Be careful.
All right. I'm gonna get
some help, all right?
Yeah.
- Hey, did you try to call?
- You've been home all day?
- I was sleeping in.
- Sleeping in. That's great, Eve.
Super great.
You all rested, now?
Glad to hear it.
Listen, I've been
fatally poisoned.
A psychopath's on his way
over to torture and kill you,
but don't get out of bed,
I'll be over in a flash.
Could you fry up a waffle?
- Sure, yeah. Come on over.
I'll be here.
Right, you'll be there. Okay.
Bye.
So, let's go get the bitch!
Come on, please!
All right, all right. Jesus!
Oh my God!
- Is this your new look or something?
- Yeah, you into it?
It's gross.
Are you looking for
my other boyfriend?
Yes!
- You haven't watched TV today, right?
- No, why?
- Didn't think so. Come on, we're leaving.
- Don't be such a freak.
Get dressed.
Actually, can you change the
clock on the microwave?
I never changed it back.
- What?
- The microwave.
Can you change the clock?
The daylight savings time,
I never changed it back.
- The microwave?
- Yes.
Listen. I bought some flowers. They
got fucked up on the way over.
That's sweet! You okay? You look
like you're on drugs or something.
You love me, yeah?
Yes.
- Then I need you to do something for me.
- What? What's wrong?
I need you to put some clothes
on and come with me, right now.
- No.
- I'll change the clock on the microwave.
Okay. All right.
Shit's wearing off.
The waffle iron's on
if you want to make one.
Great.
You're so stressed out. Want
some pot, or something?
Yeah!
- Ready! What's wrong?
- I burned my hand.
- Oh, my God! Let me see it!
- Don't worry about it. Hey!
What the..
- I'm sorry.
- That was completely uncalled for.
Can we just..
Fine.
Parked out the back.
- Darn! That.. thing.
- What thing?
The waffle thing, I
gotta turn it off.
Hello?
All right, very funny.
God, I hate that.
Do you want to burn
the building down?
- Ouch!
- Sorry, honey.
Nice on, Chev.
Oh, there's my Tiger Balm.
I swear to God, Chev.
I don't know what you're on,
but it isn't working for you.
My hand cream! That's
where you went.
Chev? Can I have
some help, here?
- Where's your car?
- Actually, I took a cab.
This isn't gonna be.. This isn't
gonna be easy, as they say.
Oh, fucker.
- All right, here it is.
- Sorry.
- I told you I was a video game programmer.
- Yeah?
That was a lie.
Actually..
I kill people.
Professional hitman. I freelance for
a major West Coast crime syndicate.
Last night was a job like 100 others.
High dollar hit, nothing special.
The Triads from Hong Kong had been
moving in on the local drug cartels.
My target was the
number 1 man in L.A.,
Don Kim.
Well?
What are you waiting for?
Then, this insane idea comes
in the back of my head,
like a.45 slug at close range.
Congratulations.
- Did I win something?
- Your life, jackass.
100 grand wants you dead. So,
sooner or later it's gonna happen,
but I'm not doing it.
I see.
Instead you're gonna
do something for me.
You're gonna get out
of town, disappear.
I don't care where you
go or what you do,
so long as you're invisible for 48 hours.
That's all I ask.
48 hours?
Or, if you prefer, we can
do it the other way.
The way where I go to work,
and you meet Buddha.
See..
I quit.
I quit the business for you.
- For me?
- Yeah.
I figure I call you that night
and tell you everything.
We get on a plane, leave
this shit, never come back.
Pretty crazy, huh?
You are so weird.
- Are we going on a trip?
- Well..
I might be going on a trip, but
you're not coming with me..
- Please! Wait, please!
- Mob hits, Chev?
Chinese poison? Do you know
how ridiculous you sound?
If you're gonna break up with me,
at least you can tell me the truth!
What's wrong with you?
- Wait a minute, you trust me?
- No.
- Make love to me.
- What?
- I think it'll help.
- What? Are you kidding? Get off me!
- Take your clothes off.
- No!
No!
You said you wanted
to be more spontaneous.
You're crazy!
You're an adrenaline
junkie with no soul!
- Save me, Eve. Save my life!
- Stop it!
I'm sorry. Oh my
God, are you okay?
Are you okay?
No! No!
Shit!
Get off!
You filthy animal!
Take me right here,
in front of everyone!
That's it!
Come on! Do it!
- What are you waiting for?
- Jesus!
- Come on!
- I'm trying! Shush!
Oh, God! Now you
can't get it up?
- Come on, get it up!
- I'll fucking get it up!
- Goddamnit, Chev!
- Shut up!
I'm alive! I'm alive!
I'm alive, you motherfuckers!
Oh, my God! Wow!
Oh, my God! Yes!
- Yeah?
- What are you doing?
- Yeah.
- I've got Verona.
- Kaylo?
- I've got Verona, man.
- What?
- No shit?
- Where are you?
- Don Kim's shirt factory, upstairs.
- What's the matter with you?
- 5th and Alameda?
- Who's at 5th and Alameda?
- Don't let that fucker out of your sight!
Hear me? With you in 10 minutes.
You got it?
Yeah, Chev.
Honey, I gotta go.
I'll call you!
Oh God, what are you looking at?
Hey man, what's the matter with you?
You a crackhead?
- Right, just step
on it, all right?
- You're won't die in
my cab, crackhead.
I got something for you.
Take this Haitian shit.
This shit is some hardcore shit.
It's made from plant shit.
Hey, what are you laughing at?
Look at this. You see that?
That's what a man look like, crackhead.
That's power.
Now look at you.
What the hell.
Yeah.
It tastes like ass.
That's right, devil. You wait.
- Shut the fuck up!
- No!
Whoop, there it is! Fuck him!
We're here.
- What'd you say was in this stuff?
- I told you, it's hardcore.
It's $5.55.
- It's all you, man.
- Have a nice day, devil.
This is fucked.
Hey, where's he going?
Yeah, okay. How the fuck you
going to call me, talking shit?
I'm gonna smack the hell out of you.
I don't know where he at..
Fucking call me talking shit!
I'm doing my job.
I'm doing my shit.
I'm up here chillin', doing what I do.
I'm a rooftop mother..
Hey, Chevy! What's up, dog?
You chillin'? You good?
- What a coincidence!
- What do you mean?
- What, you waiting for a bus?
- Actually, I thought a helicopter..
- What is this?
- What?
- You working for the Chinese?
- The Chinese?
- You crazy? I wouldn't
do that to you.
I am crazy. Where's Kaylo?
- Okay, ding. Time's up.
- What do you mean, "ding"?
What do you mean, "ding"?
Where is that motherfucker?
Chev.
- What the fuck is this?
- Chev, baby. Take it easy.
Oh, you mean like this?
Now you tell me where that little
toe-rag motherfucker is. Verona.
Verona's got nothing
to do with this.
What?
- Don Carlos wants you off the streets.
- Carlito?
You've totally lost
your shit, dog.
You're all over TV. Destroying
property, making unauthorized hits.
You're causing the organization
a great deal of embarrassment.
- You're telling me Carlito wanted this?
- Look.
Don't worry, we'll
take care of Verona.
The best thing for you to do is find
some nice, dark, quiet place and..
just die.
Just die. You think I've got
"cunt" written on my forehead?
Maybe you're right.
- We all got to die sometime, right?
- Yeah.
We all got to die sometime.
So, I'll just die.
What the..
- What the..
- You got shot!
Mother..
Jesus! Eve, move!
- You, asshole!
- Don't talk to him like that!
- My boyfriend kills people!
- Nice.
Oh, God!
I had to see if you
were telling the truth.
Come on.
No, wait!
Now come on.
Oh, God!
Oh, dammit!
- I forgot to take my birth control pills.
- What?
- Where are the keys? The keys!
- Here.
- Come! Come!
- My stuff!
All my stuff!
- You weren't lying!
- Welcome to my life.
No, I mean.. that you would
give it all up for me.
Yeah.
- And the other part?
- The poison's true, too.
Then.. that means..
Pretty much, Eve.
- How can we stop it?
- Only adrenaline can slow it down.
- So, when we were in Chinatown?
- Yeah. Sorry.
What are you doing?
- This'll get you going.
- What?
- Come on, let's finish what you started.
- Oh, boy.
Oh, that's it. That's
really working for me.
- You like that?
- Stay down!
Motherfuck!
Jesus! Yeah, that's it, baby.
Just a little more.
Stay down, Eve.
- Jesus.
- Oh, you're so big!
Oh my God!
Just a touch..
- What's that matter?
- So you can fall asleep like always?
I don't think so.
Jesus! Fuck!
Are they really..
They're dead.
How can you do that?
I told you, baby. I quit.
Yeah.
Shit! I've been trying to
call you for a half hour.
- Where the fuck have you been?
- In my office.
- Can you make it over here?
- Why not?
Chocolate?
What's this fucking receipt from
Gold Foods Market for $254?
Snacks.
I owe you again, Doc.
Chevy, you're my best customer.
What is this stuff?
Synthetic epinephrine..
- diluted with some saline.
- Feels sort of good.
Well, I got a little meth in there, too.
You're feeling the endorphins.
Wait a minute. I'm not better?
No, you're not better.
You're in such shit
shape, it's stunning.
I can't believe your
heart's beating.
You should be in a
fucking medical journal.
So, what are you going to do?
- The solution acts as
a competing inhibitor.
It's pushing the poison
out of your receptors,
and replacing it with a chemical.
It's just a temporary fix.
Then what?
Then you're fucked.
I can put you on life support and
string this out for a few days.
But you're going to go into
a comma at some point.
Does she know?
Why don't I load you
full of something?
You can go out in a
beautiful dream.
A dream.
Can I do that for you?
No, no, no. That's
not what I want.
What do you want?
One hour.
I want one hour.
Give me a fuckin' break.
So, the wild rampage that
began 9am in L.A. continues.
The suspect, still at large.
We didn't give him
enough Chinese shit.
You think?
Dude, it's him!
- What's up, corpse?
- Bonjour, douche bag,
Thought you might be
interested in a deal.
Oh, you a dealer, now?
Don't you worry about what I am.
- Listen, I want the antidote.
- Oh, the antidote?
- That's right, the antidote.
- What you prepared to give me?
How about that jewelry
I got off that faggot
brother of yours,
you cocksucker?
Don't pop a blood
vessel, you little penis.
Okay.
- You like the deal?
- Whatever!
Be at the downtown
Lint in 20 minutes.
- You know the spot?
- Yeah.
Don't be late, or I'll trade the
thing to a whore for a hand job.
Look, I said I said I'd fuckin' be..
Fuck!
See you later, sunshine.
Dammit! Fuck!
Yo, it's Verona. You won't
believe this call I just got.
It's gonna be all right, baby.
- But you said..
- No, no.
Things have changed.
There's an antidote. I can make a
deal for it, but I got to go alone.
- I'm scared.
- Of course.
You'll be safe, now.
And I'll be back.
Promise?
I promise.
What's happening, bro?
- Where did I go wrong?
- You fuckin' just say something?
It's like talking to the wall.
Mom?
I'm amazed you remember
you have a mother.
- Please, I haven't
got time for this.
You got no time, period.
Orlando?
- You're a persistent
motherfucker, Chelios.
I give you that. They pop you
and you keep getting up?
- I'm the terminator.
- You was, but here's a new gun in town.
You know, I just don't get it.
Why didn't you cut me up
when you had the chance?
Too easy, motherfucker.
Look at you.
- Bi-polar, sadomasochistic
tendencies..
- Adrenalinejunkie,
addicted to violence..
Carving up a guy
while he screams in
his own blood and
excrement, would be like..
like a gift. A warriors death.
- Hell, you'd probably get off on it.
- Who are you, anyway?
- I think I'm starting to figure it out.
- Better late than never.
You know you're
gonna die up there.
Yeah, maybe. But I'm
taking you with me.
Some pills, Doc.
- Chelios?
- Hello, girls.
Hold up.
Give me the piece.
- Now, isn't that a fucking picture?
- Chelios.
What a fucking
nightmare you are.
No shit.
Sit down.
Whoa! Wait a minute. You
pat him down, again.
I know he's carrying something.
Let me see that.
Motherfucker.
Clever. What is this,
an insulin pump?
Basically.
What the fuck is insulin?
Ephedrine, right?
- Yeah.
- You're very resourceful.
- Found a new master, little bitch?
- I'm nobody's bitch.
You'll be a bitch when Carlito hires
you for half what he paid me.
That's enough.
You'll throw boss a reach-around,
show him you're a good bitch.
I'm nobody's little bitch!
You fuckin' hear me?
- He'll pay me what I tell him to pay!
- That's enough!
Sit down!
It's been a long fucking day.
In the end, you have to admit,
it all works out quite nicely.
Don Kim gets his
bullet, thanks to you,
and Hong Kong gets a
goat to take the fall.
- Please understand, it's nothing personal.
- Speak for yourself.
That what I think it is?
It's the Chinese shit.
Hold him down.
Not so fast, motherfucker!
He's gone dipsy-do, yo!
Whatever, psycho.
I'm afraid the Houdini
act is over, my friend.
- Our Father, who art in..
- Shut up!
So, this is how it is.
- It's Don Kim! He's supposed to be dead!
- Presto.
Police have moved to
surround the Hotel Lint,
where the madman behind
today's mayhem..
is holed up and making a
desperate last stand.
Officials have confirmed
gunfire on the sundeck.
Our news chopper
will bring live,
uncensored coverage
from above the hotel.
Again, this coverage
is uncensored,
so any small children present
should leave the room.
Get me out of here!
I'll kill you, Chelios!
Too late!
Look out!
Thanks, boss.
Let's get the fuck out of here, now!
Let's go!
Present from Kaylo.
Now what? Now you say shit!
Where the fuck were you?
Who's the bitch, now?
No, no! You fly, motherfucker!
Motherfuckin' fly!
You're dead!
Oh my God!
You're dead! You're
dead, motherfucker!
I told you I'd kill
you, you little bitch!
Hey, its Eve. I'm glad you
called but I'm not here.
Leave a message,
unless you're selling
something 'cause I'm
not interested.
If you're not, then just..
Wait, time's up.
Hey, doll..
Looks like I let
you down, again.
Seems like all my life
I'vejust been going.. going..
going..
I wish I'd taken more time to stop
and smell the roses, so to speak.
Well, I guess it's too
late for that now.
You're the greatest, baby.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326