Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
This "Madonna and Child,"
like the painting I just compared
with the one from St. Bernard
and St. Lucilla,
was in the main chapel
of San Donato al Ponte
and until recently was attributed
to Agnolo Salimbeni.
But Miroslav Kostivitz's studies
published in 1974
in the third issue
of "The Burlington Magazine"
show that the artist from Arezzo had
nothing to do with this work.
I think it could actually be
Boniforte da Barga's work,
with whose paintings
this "Madonna and Child"
shows, in my opinion,
surprising affinities.
Take for example
"Saint George and the Dragon,"
which critics attribute
to Boniforte.
Notice the landscape,
the attitude in which
the figures are portrayed,
and, above all,
the princess's face.
As you can see, her features
and those of the Madonna
resemble each other so much
that it's probable Boniforte
used the same model
for both works.
Certainly, during that time,
Boniforte was in contact
with the Annunziata
Convent prior,
as we can see
from a document
dated March 13th, 1426,
which orders
the payment of 200 genovini
to Magister Boniforte da Barga,
painter.
Without detailing
all the transformations
this historic building
has undergone,
I wanted to show you the plans
of what remains today
of the ancient convent's chapel.
Right now, I'm collaborating
on restorations
that have uncovered a fresco.
If we're lucky, it might turn out
to be by Boniforte.
This is a truly exhaustive study
that the candidate
has carried out seriously,
courageously venturing
into the complex field
of the attribution of artworks.
DAYS AND CLOUDS
Good girl.
I think they realized
what was going on.
Of course not! I didn't.
I was in total panic.
Luckily, I remembered a little detail...
what are we doing here?
You always liked it.
Yes, of course, but...
It's always nice.
If I were 20, I wouldn't have
graduated with outstanding praise.
Stop going on about your age!
You were simply great.
All right.
What's this?
We're going to Cambodia.
That's my gift.
So what? Besides,
I don't know if we'll
be able to fly on the 27th.
Isn't it already organized?
There's a problem at work.
Anyway, we're going. Open it!
- What's the matter?
- Nothing, we're definitely going.
Come on, open it.
We're going.
- They're antique.
- They're lovely.
- Hold this.
- Beautiful, aren't they?
Fantastic! Look.
You're beautiful, Professor.
Thank you.
When do Nadia and Fabrizio
expect us?
Around 9:00
at the restaurant.
I have to take these shoes off
and have a shower.
- I'm so proud of you!
- So that's why you disappeared.
- Hi, Jacopo.
- Congratulations!
- Daddy, why did you invite Jacopo?
- He's a friend.
It's like a high school party.
That's great.
You're an accomplice too.
- I was the first one!
- You bowled the examiners over.
- You always exaggerate.
- Come and change.
- See you later!
- Later.
# I was asking my mother
about you... #
- You're here too!
- Could we have missed out?
Your favorite ex-coworkers.
- You shouldn't have!
- Your sister from Hamburg...
- she swore she was coming.
- Thanks, it's really beautiful.
You're nuts!
Look what you've done.
Dori!
- Good evening.
- Hi.
- Where were you?
I got out late.
For your mom.
She's over there.
- Hello, Riki.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- This is for you.
Thank you.
- Aren't you going to open it?
- Later, when it's quieter.
It's okay,
the battery's charged.
#... The moon hanging
on the wall #
# I get thirsty at night... #
Now it's time.
# Let me drink, my love,
let me drink. #
Will you excuse me?
I've been told
that our hostess
wants to sing.
Why don't you sing
something for us?
- # I'll hug you hard... #
- Whoo!
# I swear I'll hurt you bad #
# And at night
I'll start to burn #
# I'll be your star #
# Start walking, hurry, go! #
# 'Cause now I'm coming too #
# Darling, go, step on the gas! #
Good job, Elsa!
# The heat under my skin #
# Makes me see the stars #
# Burst together with me. #
- Fuck!
- Elsa? Everything okay?
Damn it!
What are you doing?
Come on, sweetie,
let's go. Let's go.
Be careful.
Thanks, darling.
It was a wonderful party.
All my friends were there,
all our friends.
I had a great time.
Everybody we know was there.
Roberto didn't come.
- He couldn't make it.
- How come?
I don't know, Elsa.
I don't understand why.
Are you offended?
Come on, he must have been busy.
Let's forgive him.
# I'll hug you hard! #
# I swear I'll hurt you bad. #
Shall we go to sleep?
- Are you sleepy?
- It's very late.
We stayed up very late.
# I'll hug you hard! #
Oh God! Shit!
You could have just turned it off.
- Come here.
- Tomorrow I'll glue it all together.
Oh, man.
Ow!
Oh, fuck.
- Good morning, Daisy.
- Good morning, ma'am.
- Did you hurt yourself?
- It's nothing, just a scratch.
What a mess. Sorry.
We'll get it all cleaned up.
Shall I make coffee?
Mr. Michele already made it.
- My husband is still at home?
- Yes, in the study.
Really?
Michele, you don't feel well?
No, I'm fine.
Why are you here?
What happened to you?
I cut myself
on the glass from the lamp.
- Does it hurt?
- It's nothing.
What's going on?
I have to tell you something.
I waited till now 'cause
I didn't want to distract you,
- 'cause I didn't want...
- Tell me.
We can't go to Cambodia.
Why not?
I haven't worked for two months.
Weren't things going better
with this new partner? What was his name?
You don't understand.
They got rid of me.
What do you mean?
Morelli agreed with Roberto
and they pushed me out of Miramar.
The company is yours.
How could they do that?
No, it belonged to the three of us.
You know Roberto is weak.
Since Morelli arrived,
everything has changed.
He convinced Roberto
to fire people,
diversify and move
all the production abroad
against my own will.
Roberto and I have always
done things a certain way.
You know how I feel about things.
I found myself isolated,
disagreeing on everything.
And by being in the minority,
the company is in their hands.
- They can't do that!
- Yes, they can.
They resigned, we voted
for a new board of directors
and they only re-elected themselves.
That's absurd!
How could Roberto agree to that?
Did you speak to him?
Have you two talked alone?
I don't see him anymore.
- Don't you meet him in the office?
- I don't go there anymore.
- Since when?
- Two months!
But I'm looking for another job,
I've had interviews, sent CVs.
I'm looking around.
You didn't tell me anything.
It's absurd!
- Now what?
- Nothing.
I'll find a new job
and I'll take care of stuff.
That's it.
Then...
Then?
Then there is the issue
with the house.
- What house?
- This one.
Remember I used it
to guarantee the bank loan
when we increased
the company capital?
More or less. So what?
The lawyer suggested
that as long as
I'm in debt with the bank
my hands are tied
and I can't even sue those assholes.
Wait a minute.
What do you mean?
Do we have to sell
the house?
We'll find another one.
We can rent one.
Forgive me, Elsa.
I wanted to wait until you graduated.
It's late.
Elsa, don't worry.
It's just a bad time.
It's very late.
I really must go.
Hi!
Good girl!
So?
What did I tell you?
Congratulations. You must tell me
everything. I'm so scared!
You'll do well too.
How's it going here?
Come and see.
Look what we found
while you were getting
your degree.
Look at these areas of color.
Beautiful.
Too bad you're leaving,
this is the best bit.
I don't know if I'm going now.
Really? How come?
- Aren't you taking the trip?
- We may put it off.
I'll continue up there.
Are you going to tell me
something about your exam?
I was really scared!
What was the board like?
Michele?
Good evening.
Mrs. Oliveri?
Nice to meet you.
Buoncompagni.
I'm showing the apartment
to Mr. and Mrs. Melzi.
It's very well kept.
My compliments.
Good evening.
Allow me to introduce you...
Mrs. Oliveri, the owner of the house.
Yes, we agree.
- You could've warned me.
- Fine, thank you.
By tomorrow, yes.
Certainly, thanks.
Goodbye.
I've had a job offer.
A radiator company
is looking
for a production manager.
I don't know much about it,
but for some reason
they trust me.
Good.
The salary isn't amazing...
more or less half
of what I used to earn...
three weeks of vacation a year,
my boss is
15 years younger than me.
15 years younger.
Isn't there anything better?
It's the first real offer I've had.
I have to give an answer
by tomorrow morning and I can't decide.
What do you think?
What do you want me to say?
You're wasted in a job like that.
At least if it was
in the boating business...
True, but I know it'll be tough
to stay in that business.
I've already tried to talk
to all my competitors.
They pat me on the back
but no definite offers.
I don't know, let's wait.
There'll be other offers.
It must have been
a horrible day for you.
You could've warned me
about them.
I should have told you earlier.
You are right.
You should have told me
two months ago.
right away, because this way,
all of a sudden,
all at the same time...
- I'm sorry.
- I don't know anything
about the house,
the mortgage,
how much money we have, if any.
I've been thinking
about it all day.
How much do we spend?
- How much do we need a month?
- Calm down, Elsa.
I hate not knowing things.
You must tell me everything.
Excuse me, we're done.
- Is tomorrow at 3:00 all right?
- Yes, I'll show you the way out.
It was a fund, Elsa.
I sold it a long time ago.
We had to give Alice her share
for the restaurant, remember?
Okay.
So all we have left
is 21,575 euros?
There's also the house
and I know there's the mortgage,
but the sale price is good.
You should not worry.
I should not worry.
You haven't earned
your salary in months.
We kept living
as if nothing had happened.
We went to Tunisia.
We bought another computer.
We lived like we always have!
Why didn't you tell me?
If I'd told you before,
would we have solved anything?
Okay. Now tell me.
These are our expenses, right?
Yes. So 850 euros
for the mortgage,
then service charges, cleaning lady,
various expenses totaling 4,000 euros.
- 4,000 euros?
- Everything included...
bills, cell phones, car, dock fees,
the boat and also
my father's expenses.
That's a lot of money.
In five months we'll be broke.
Try to at least be
a bit more optimistic.
So I am a pessimist now.
Am I a pessimist?
No!
I'll find a job.
Meanwhile we'll move
and cut expenses.
Things will work out, you'll see.
I have to go back
to work, right?
- You are already working.
- Too bad I never get paid.
You will soon.
You even graduated.
Maybe in a year, maybe never.
Alice is here.
- Hi.
- Hi, Alice.
- Is she sleeping here?
- I don't know.
What's this,
the five-year plan?
With all those children
dying of hunger in the world...
If you feel like preaching,
start with Riki,
Mr. Indifference,
or have you already decided
he's a lost cause?
Are you nuts, Dad?
I was kidding.
What the fuck do you know
about Riki anyway?
He's worked since he was 16,
and he doesn't owe anything to anyone.
The shop is
his father's, isn't it?
If it weren't for Riki,
his father would still be selling blenders!
A real child prodigy.
- He's not an intellectual. So what?
- So nothing.
But you gave Jacopo a hard time 'cause
he didn't read Thomas Bernhard.
Forget Jacopo!
Enough, both of you.
You bore me to death.
Mom, he started it.
I was fine when I got here.
What would you have done
if you weren't fine, throw a grenade?
I think it's better
if I stay at Riki's for a bit.
That way
we're all happier, no?
You'll be happy.
If you want to go to Riki's, go,
but don't act like the one who
got thrown out of her parents' place!
Fine. And excuse me
for saying so,
but you could have been
more enthusiastic about his gift.
Do you know how much
the UMTS cost?
- The UM... what?
- The cell phone.
So what?
I did thank him.
Do you have to thank
more or less now
depending on the price tag?
He didn't even buy it...
he sells them.
You really are
an asshole, Dad.
- She doesn't know, does she?
- Alice? Are you nuts?
- We'll have to tell her soon.
- We won't tell her anything.
Bye.
Alice doesn't live
here anymore.
Let's eat something.
Wait, there's something I don't get.
The party, the group,
the waiters, these earrings...
- how much did you spend?
- All that was left!
Tomorrow, bread and onions.
All right?
Hi, Roberto.
Elsa, how are you?
That was Morelli, wasn't it?
Yes.
How's Michele?
What do you think?
I know what you're thinking.
We started when we were 20,
and it's not easy for me either.
I can imagine.
Do you know for how long we hadn't drawn
our salaries before Morelli came onboard?
Michele told me.
He wanted Morelli onboard too.
You know that, right?
Yes, but he didn't think
you'd turn against him.
He said no to everything!
He said things would work out,
that it was just a matter of time,
but he knew that
if we didn't find a solution,
- we would have gone under.
- It depends on what solutions, right?
It depends who is involved.
It depends on if friends are involved.
I'm sorry, no.
If he would have had
some ideas... but nothing!
If it was up to him,
everything would have gone to hell!
How can you say that?
You know Michele,
you know what he thinks.
I have two families
to support, remember?
Luisa, the boys, the house,
Giovanna, Matteo, another house.
I can support shit with his ideals!
- So that's a possibility?
- Yes, it is.
The savings, as I told you,
would be around 30%.
The trouble is that
it would be difficult, knowing him,
to share his space
with someone else.
- Okay.
- Let me know.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Hi.
- Is everything all right?
- With me, yes,
but Sara is on her way out.
Which one is Sara?
I can't remember
who was my second mate
on the Victoria.
- Wasn't it Pozzati?
- No.
The truth is that
when you're born,
all they teach you is
to mind your own business.
There's no civic sense.
- No manners either.
- Are you talking to me?
Yes, Fabrizio was telling us
something and you interrupted.
- That's not true!
- Actually, it is.
- I believe she's right.
- Come on, tell us.
We got a new system
for cataloguing the warehouse
and the warehouse clerk,
Antonio...
- remember him?
- Yes.
- he's never learned
how to use a computer.
He does everything with pen and paper,
if you can believe that.
- Do you have to fire him?
- I'm afraid so.
But he'll get a big severance check.
He's going into early retirement.
If I could find him a little job,
even part-time...
maybe you need
an odd-job man?
Maybe you could talk
to the others.
I can ask them, of course.
Yes, but no obligation.
Antonio's a really valuable guy.
If we don't give him a hand...
No, Michele.
No way. Come on!
Why should you always pay?
In fact.
Let's split it in half, please.
- Michele, next time...
- Okay.
...it'll be on us.
- Shall we go by Porta Soprana?
- No.
- It's nicer there, come on.
- I said no.
- Why?
- Because I want to go home.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
Is it because
I paid for dinner?
Do you think we have
money to throw away?
Let's stop eating out then.
Who organized
the evening? Me?
Now it's my fault?
What do you want me to do?
Tell Fabrizio and Nadia that
they have to pay because we're broke?
Do you want me to do that?
I don't want us to do
things we can't afford.
190 euros won't solve anything,
or do you think they will?
Stop it!
I don't give a damn
about the 200 euros.
What I care about is that you don't have
a job and I don't earn anything,
and that soon we won't have
a house anymore.
And we cannot
even talk about it with our friends.
I told you
it'll all work out.
How the fuck can
you be so sure?
I can't go on pretending.
I'm scared.
- Don't be.
- I'm terrified.
If we pretend nothing's wrong,
others will pretend too,
- like that asshole Roberto.
- What's he got to do with it?
- I went to see him.
- What?
Why didn't you tell me?
Look who's talking!
- When did you go?
- I don't know. Tuesday.
Why, Elsa?
I wanted to look him in the eyes
and understand what happened.
Do you think it was my fault?
Do you really want
to hear what I think?
You're a pain in the ass
and that we should have accepted
that ride that Fabrizio offered,
because my foot still hurts.
- Still?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Are you nuts?
- Put me down!
- So I'm a pain in the ass?
No no no.
Put me down!
Michele.
Daisy's leaving.
Permanently?
Yes, she's already
got another job.
They need her full time.
She wants her severance pay.
She's right.
I know.
I told her to get it calculated.
It's about 6,200 euros.
Fuck.
I'll ask if I can
give her some now
and the rest in a month.
Maybe you'll have
a job by then.
It's all right.
Let's sell the boat.
Let's give her her money, period.
Do you really
want to sell it?
You told me we won't
make much by selling it.
True, but there's
no sense keeping it.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
Elsa, about the dinner
at the Marinis...
I don't want to go.
I don't want to pretend.
I don't want to lie.
Okay.
What's up, Dad?
How come you're not at work?
I've taken a sabbatical.
And you?
I had a fight with Riki.
Are you glad?
You don't get it.
You think I'm glad if you're unhappy?
I think I should be happy
- the way you want me to be.
- Alice, what should I do?
Act like people who say,
"If you're happy,
that's enough for me"?
Do you want
a dad like that?
I will admit, though,
I imagined someone different for you.
You always have to imagine
everything for everyone.
Why don't you relax, Dad?
You'd live better
and make others around you
live better too.
What does "better" mean:
superficially,
without accepting
your own responsibility?
That's the result of never opposing
anything in this country.
Not the political speech!
I haven't even had my coffee.
Oh, sorry.
The political speech. Sorry.
Want some too?
Well, maybe half a cup.
With that disgusting sweetener?
Not the health speech.
What's there?
There is...
There's something
underneath here.
Elsa, come and look at this.
What is it? A dolphin?
No. It's a little bird,
can't you see?
- It could be a goldfinch.
- So?
So there could be
a Nativity under here.
How come?
Sometimes it appears
as a Nativity symbol.
Well, it certainly appears
in the Madonna and Child.
Wait.
It could also be
an Adoration of the Magi, no?
Let's first try to understand
what kind of bird it is,
and then we can start guessing, okay?
My role evolved
in the last 10 years
as the firm expanded
and the turnover increased...
in production, obviously.
The commercial side
is not for me.
I'd say it's all clear.
I don't have anything suitable
for a man of your experience,
but your details will be inserted
into our database.
I guarantee that you'll get
special consideration.
- I have a question.
- Of course.
I realize my age
might be an obstacle...
That's no longer true.
Excuse me for interrupting.
Companies look for experience
when filling certain roles.
You might need
to be flexible
where salary is concerned,
of course.
I kind of wonder if I should lower
my expectations.
In my situation,
maybe I should be happy
with a bit less.
No, you shouldn't, believe me.
It would be a mistake
to voluntarily undersell yourself.
Also remember that firms
aren't interested
in hiring someone
who could eventually cause trouble
because they're dissatisfied.
Among your personal
characteristics
you indicated mental flexibility.
Can you give me an example?
Well, in my previous job
there were many kinds of problems...
in an airport, emergencies are
the order of the day.
Listen. How about
doing a trial call?
What do you mean?
You call me at home and try
to sell me a subscription
to a women's weekly
at half the newsstand price.
A pretend call?
Yes yes. Ring ring.
The phone's ringing.
Okay.
Hello. Good morning, ma'am.
I'm calling to offer you
a subscription to a women's weekly,
"Snow White Today."
I'm not interested
and I don't want to spend money.
It's very reasonable,
half the newsstand price.
Michele.
Here you are.
Jump in,
I'll take you for a cruise.
- Don't we have to move?
- There's time. We're going out now.
They hired me
at a call center...
a month's trial.
It's only three hours a day,
and I can fit in
the restoration too.
I'll get 500 euros a month.
Is it really necessary?
Yes, it is.
How about these?
Well...
throw them away.
They're old.
The pictures?
Better keep them.
So you came here
instead of going to work?
Yes, here too...
my floating office.
That's why you always told me
to call your cell phone.
What an idiot!
Why didn't I understand?
I only did it
so you could study in peace.
Do you know what I thought
when I saw your face that morning?
What?
"Here we go again...
another woman."
Not again.
It was six years ago.
I remember your face clearly...
it was identical.
Actually,
maybe I'd have preferred it.
I don't believe you.
Well, I wouldn't have preferred it.
Shall we go?
Sir! Mr. Olivieri!
Oh... Vito, good morning.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Do you remember Luciano?
- Of course.
- Hello, sir, everything okay?
- My wife Elsa.
- How do you do?
- Good morning.
- How are things going?
- So-so.
Luciano found a job but...
but it didn't work out.
It lasted a month.
The owner's brother-in-law arrived
and he told him,
"What can I do?
He's my wife's brother."
Sorry to hear that.
Nothing else has turned up?
We're on unemployment.
How come you're out here,
loaded down like that?
I'm selling my boat.
It's getting a bit old
and these aren't exactly
times of plenty.
Sir, we wanted to call you
several times.
We heard you left
the company
and that you didn't agree
on lots of things
and we wanted
to thank you.
I only did what seemed right.
Do you think
that counts for nothing?
Not that it helped much.
Can I buy you a drink?
- No. Not now.
- Maybe some other time,
- duty calls.
- Do you fish here at the port?
The mullet bite like
a dream here.
You have to leave us
at least one pleasure in life!
Please come in.
Mr. Oliveri?
Good morning.
Please sit down.
A wonderful bath with essential oils,
a wide choice of treatments.
For example, balsamic, relaxing,
energizing, winding-down.
So you don't have
a bathtub?
Mrs. Donata, if you look
on the next page of our catalogue
I'd advise you
to try our body creams.
They're full of dietary minerals
to keep your skin soft and supple.
I guarantee that after
a shower, they're ideal.
I'm starting to hallucinate.
- Bye, Elsa.
- Bye, Cristina. See you tomorrow.
Can I borrow
your car then?
Don't you want lunch?
- I have to go to the restoration.
- Not even half an hour?
Absolutely nothing happened.
It was as if I hadn't gone.
Why? What did they tell you?
First, he was impressed
with my tie,
then he asked me if I thought
I was satisfied about my life,
and then...
listen to this one...
"How big should the slice
of life dedicated to work be?"
What did you say?
It depends on the cake.
Are you crazy?
Anyway, the morning's over.
Now I have to survive the afternoon.
It's Nadia.
She keeps calling me.
Elsa, do you remember Claudio,
my friend, the architect?
Yes.
Remember that I loaned him
6,000,000 liras?
Yes. Didn't he give them back?
No.
I know it wouldn't help much,
and it also makes me feel
very embarrassed...
But it's fair, though.
There's nothing wrong
with asking for it back.
I know.
Going to a friend to ask for money
after so many years,
for 3,000 euros.
But we need them, Michele.
I know. I know.
Do you feel like coming
to see the fresco?
Come on. I'm late.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- Here's the coffee.
- Thanks.
We work like slaves.
You too, I guess,
like everybody else.
Thank God I like what I do,
otherwise I'd die.
On holiday I sleep
for the first three days.
I might as well leave
three days later.
Listen, Claudio,
do you remember that
I lent you some money a few years ago,
- 6,000,000 liras?
- Of course I remember,
when I opened my office. Why?
I wondered
if you could give it back to me.
I already gave it back.
- You're kidding.
- No.
I gave it back to you
about a year later.
I remember it well...
I was working
on Bortolotto's house.
I may have given it
to you in cash.
No, you didn't pay me back.
I assure you
that I gave it back.
You're wrong.
You gave me nothing.
No, you are wrong.
For example, we have
several vacancies for hotel work,
even spot contracts
for two days,
like Monday, Tuesday.
Take a seat.
Front office, phone operator,
receptionist.
Giving out room keys?
Everything that has
to do with the desk.
But if you don't like that option,
you can indicate it on the appropriate form.
But consider that since
we're the first ones to be flexible,
we insist
on a certain flexibility as well.
I understand.
Only hotel work?
No, also data entry,
accounting, sales,
administrative, secretarial,
doorman in buildings or firms
or private chauffeur, courier.
- Do you drive?
- Yes.
I'm not clear about something though,
have you lost your job?
You found a parking space
right in front of the house.
That's a dream nowadays.
Yes. The view
sure is marvelous.
Excuse me.
So is the heating autonomous?
Yes, and the boiler was
upgraded less than a year ago.
The kitchen is over here.
Nadia, how are you?
Yes, everything's fine.
No, forgive me.
My cell phone's faulty...
it doesn't show
who's called me.
I feel much better.
It's just that the restoration's
going really quickly
and I've no time
for anything.
- Good evening.
This is Mrs. Parodi.
Mr. Oliveri, the owner of the house.
- Nice to meet you.
- We were just about to leave.
I need to talk to you
for a moment.
Sure. I'll finish with the lady
and be right with you.
- All right. Bye.
- Bye.
- What's happening?
- What do you mean?
Why can't you manage
to sell this house?
A lot of people are interested,
but they balk at the price.
You made the estimate.
It's also a question of time.
If you need an urgent sale...
How much should
we lower the price?
At least 100.
100 what?
100,000 euros less.
Maybe you'd like
to think about it.
Good night.
Bye.
Why don't we eat out?
Yes.
This is for Mom
and this is for you.
Didn't Jacopo
take your wine order?
Not yet, but don't worry.
You look cute
in the candlelight.
It feels weird. I cooked her meals
for years, now she's serving us food.
Feels weird to me too.
Actually, it pisses me off.
Don't start.
To think of how hard
you worked for your degree
when she could
take it easy,
she could study,
travel, have fun,
but she's waiting tables here.
She's not a waitress,
she's half-owner.
Please, stop it.
I've brought you
the wine myself.
That's enough.
- It's very good.
- I brought the most expensive one.
Serving tables in an apron.
That's my daughter.
Then there's my wife,
cooped up in some dump
with loads of people,
selling ham, creams
and who the fuck
knows what else.
That's enough.
You're right.
Enough.
At least you two do something.
You do what you can.
I haven't done a fucking thing in months.
I don't earn. I don't produce.
Michele, you're looking for work.
Cut it out, please.
Eat. Alice is looking at us.
I'm an idiot.
That radiator company job...
I shouldn't have said no.
We said no.
It was a mutual decision.
You weren't involved.
Keep your voice down.
Rosemary.
How do we cook it?
Poached squash with garlic.
Look at the TV camera, chef,
don't look at me.
Poached squash with garlic...
Give me something, anything.
What have you got
available today?
- Yes?
- Parcel service.
I have an envelope to deliver.
He's always there, every time!
I just don't understand.
It's like all of a sudden
I decided to open
a store with my ex!
You'd jump for joy, right?
Michele, Alice is here.
- Is she?
- She says she saw you on a scooter,
delivering packages.
Was it you?
Yes, it was me.
Why?
They offered it and I accepted.
That's all.
- Where's Alice?
- In there.
I told her everything.
I couldn't stand it anymore.
- How did she take it?
- She's shocked.
We should have told her right away.
She's very worried.
I want to give back
the money you lent me.
I'll sell my share
of the business.
Not gonna happen. It wasn't a loan,
it was for your studies.
You decided to open
a restaurant. End of story.
You won't even let
anybody help you.
Right, let's see
how you'd help me.
- I could ask Riki, he's bound to have...
- Great!
I'll be a salesman
in Riki's shop,
your mom can dress the window,
then all of us together,
you, me, Riki,
Riki's grandfather...
He can't treat me like a child.
He always makes cracks
about Riki.
He's my boyfriend.
I don't care if you two don't like him!
I like him. Dad!
Riki would never get himself
into this kind of mess!
- You can cope by yourself?
- Stop it!
Mom working in a call center
and you delivering packages!
- Wow, you're doing a great job at coping.
- Alice!
And let's not tell anyone
or we'll look like idiots.
- Don't talk to me like that!
- I'll say what I fucking want!
Fuck you!
Alice! Wait, come on!
Michele.
Darling, please don't do this.
I've messed everything up.
Please, stop it. Stop it.
Nice place, isn't it?
Ever since you called me,
I've been waiting to hug you.
Forgive me, Nadia,
I didn't want to lie to you.
I just thought...
it would all work out.
Of course it will.
Everything will be all right.
I asked to do an extra shift.
Why did you wait so long?
Why didn't you ask me for help?
I was ashamed, Nadia.
I'm sorry.
Sir?
Please.
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com