DAYS OF GLORY
ALGERIA - 1943
We must rid France of the German occupation!
Come along! Come with me!
We must wash the French flag with our blood!
Come with me!
Let's have the men out!
We must liberate France.
Liberate her!
We must save France from this situation.
Come on!
Saiid!
Come back!
Be reasonable.
Come back inside.
Your grandfather never came back.
Don't worry about me, Mother.
I want to help France.
I can manage.
They'll kill you!
I prefer the worst poverty to losing you.
You put up with too much.
Please, let me go.
It will be all right, Mother.
Pray for me.
Get in.
Move!
Long live France!
Get in.
MOROCCO - 1943
Left turn!
I know that you Ait Tseroucher.
the mountain men,
are the French army's best fighters,
better than the other Berbers,
and you'll prove it!
Listen carefully now.
We permit raids in enemy territory for food,
but hands off the women or you'll be shot.
In France, no raids at all.
We show discipline!
It's our home, our motherland!
Left turn!
Yassir, they make us march like mules.
Let's go back home.
Serve France with pride.
Why did you get us enlisted?
For the money.
So we can marry you off.
Forward...
march!
The sergeant communicates with his men...
through verbaI orders...
and through signals...
through verbaI orders
and through signals... used simultaneously.
We're the mer of Africa Come here from afar
We've come from the colories
To save the fatherlard
We've left behird Our families ard homes
Ard our hearts are full Of irvircible fervor
For we wish to bear high ard proud
The cherished flag of sweet Frarce
Should someore try to part us
We're here tode at herr feet
Drums roll to mark our love
For our courtry ard lard
We've dcome fromn afa rtode
We're the men offA fridca
At ease!
ITALY - 1944
Company...
halt!
Left turn!
Don't salute me here.
They always pick officers as targets.
CorporaI Abdelkader, 2nd Company,
7th Algerian Infantry Regiment,
reporting, sir!
What can your lads do?
No idea, sir.
They're my first group.
You got your rank how?
I passed the exam, sir.
I took mine with the Krauts.
CorporaI Leroux reporting, sir.
You can go.
Praise be to God.
Take this. It's a German rifle. The best.
You'll be the marksman.
Take it.
Hit the ground!
Don't blame him, sir.
They're still green.
I have the power of life and death over you!
Starting with you.
Yes, sir.
The Germans are dug in up there. At ease.
Our mission is to climb up to the Krauts
to flush them out.
We have to do it.
It's a light infantry job.
You'll lead the men.
Any trouble, take out a cigarette.
Before you light it, it'll be over.
Yes, sir.
It reassures the lads behind.
Hitting a soldier isn't allowed.
I know the sergeant well.
He's a good man.
He knows his job.
Where are you from, Saiid?
From totaI poverty.
Listen...
in that uniform,
you're like me now.
You're like all of us.
We're the same family.
The army means equality.
Wait a while.
You'll get your share of bullets tomorrow.
CorporaI,
are you afraid?
Enough talk.
Tomorrow, you'll know...
if you're soldiers or not.
Your coffee, Sarge.
Thank you, Ali.
CarefuI, it's hot.
We'll be in for it tomorrow.
Yes, we'll be in for it.
hrch' Allah.
O mercifuI, compassionate lord of the worlds,
mercifuI, compassionate king ofjudgment day,
you alone we worship and seek help from.
Guide us along the right path...
I declare there is no deity but God.
I declare that Mohammad is his prophet.
Move forward!
Abdelkader, move!
Abdelkader!
CorporaI!
What do we do?
Shut up!
Move.
We'll die if we stay here.
Messaoud!
Ahmed!
Saiid!
Let's go!
ColoneI, the artillery!
Battery number 5.
938-991.
Position 938-991.
- Copy.
- 903-940.
Battery number 4. Position 903-940.
Bearing 1400, order 340.
Charge 5. Loaded.
First gun ready.
Second gun ready.
Attention!
Fire!
Stay down! That's our side.
Larbi...
Don't be afraid, little brother.
We're not going to die today.
Let's go
Messaoud!
Move forward! Keep going!
Sergeant!Stay behind me.
Ali, are you hurt?
Ali
Keep going!
Come out of there!
Open his mouth.
Stop that!
What are you doing?
We're soldiers, not savages.
Fuck you!
Scum!
We're pulling out!
Long live France!
ColoneI...
how many casualties?
How many dead?
It's a magnificent victory.
For the first time since the 1940 defeat,
our army has defeated the Germans.
France has regained glory
and the Allies' trust.
A photo, ColoneI.
Write what I said.
Let's go.
Lower.
That's it!
Yes?
At ease.
What do you want?
I come to say thank you.
You save my life, Sergeant.
You want to thank me?
Make some coffee. You can replace Ali.
I'll make you a private if I'm pleased.
Well? What did he say?
Are we going home?
- Soon!
- Is it true?
Thank you, my friend.
Where's my chocolate?
Here.
Thank you.
No tomatoes for you.
Why?
They're not for you. Move!
What do you mean?
Let go of him!
You're cooking while he fights.
Yes, sir.
Move.
Why aren't the tomatoes for everyone?
He's right.
We want tomatoes too!
He's right!
Shut your mouths!
You're not happy?
No one will have any now...
They're ready to die for us,
but any injustice will cause mutiny.
You know the natives, Martinez.
Avoid that term, sir.
The Muslims
That's just as bad.
So what do I call them?
The men, sir. The men.
What's going on here?
Sir,
we fight alongside
our French brothers in arms,
on the same terrain, against the same enemy.
We must share the tomatoes too.
German bullets don't pick and choose, sir.
Sergeant, when we have tomatoes,
let everyone have them.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
My boys. my dear boys!
The dream for which so mary have died
is coming true at last!
Your wounds and suffering,
all the pain
ard bloodshed
are the price to pay to be or this jourrey.
We shall soor see Frarce agair!
The motherlard!
We are going home!
PROVENCE - AUGUST 1944
Smell it.
It's not like at home.
No.
French soiI is better.
Look!
Long live France!
France!
Do you speak French?
Yes, I understand it.
What's your name?
Messaoud.
And what's your name?
Irene.
The sergeant says,
"Go up the mountain. "
I was scared,but I go up the mountain.
I go up the mountain,I run and run,
Messaoud to my right,Abdelkader to my left.
I'm not scared then.
But Germany shoots at us.
Left, right, everywhere it shoots.
Messaoud says,"Lie down in the hole. "
I don't speak. The sergeant looks at me,
I look at the sergeant.
I know what he wants.
I take the grenade,
pull the pin,and throw it at Germany.
All of Germany, they die.
I free a country, it's my country.
Even if I never saw it before.
It's my country.
Your country's all you like?
hrch' Allah. we'll beat Germany.
Thank you very much.
Look.
Iron Cross. German.
Very beautifuI.
Dangerous soldier.
Take this.
Good quality!
Iron Cross.
"Urlucky"
Why unlucky?
I didn't know you.
Sorry.
Good night.
Why were you scared?
The Germans won't be back.
You wiped them out.
It's not that.
But...
in my country,we don't go with French women.
Leave it!
Don't touch it!
It's a sin!
I swear in God's name.
Aren't you ashamed?
Why, Yassir?Is it God's?
Don't touch it.
All right.
Look.
Their God suffered a lot.
A lot.
Tell me, Yassir...
when I was little,
the French soldiers killed our whole family.
Did they massacre them?
What did they call it?
They called it...
pacification.
Pacification?
CorporaI, can you read?
Yes.
I can't read.
I never went to schooI.
You can learn.
Listen, Saiid...
CorporaI, come here!
What's that?
It's a military handbook, sir.
The hrfartry NCO's Hardbook.
You want to be a coloneI?
A sergeant first, sir.
Let me read you an extract.
"In theory,
no soldier should return home
illiterate from the army.
Classes are obligatory for all men
on their enlistment. "
Yet none of these African troops
can read or write.
Saiid!
You want to learn to read?
It's too late, sir.
And to read what?
Give me a clean shirt.
Messaoud
You'll come back?
Yes, I promise, I come back.
You wait for me?
Yes.
RHONE VALLEY - OCTOBER 1944
I never loved a girI like this.
I want to marry her,
have kids, and make a family.
You get worked up fast.
Marseilles is paradise. Here, CorporaI,
they respect me. I'm not a wog.
I swear!I make my life in France.
You'll always be a wog.
Shut it!Ever slept in sheets before?
Saiid! Get in!
Get in.
Aiicha!
"Me and mother 1903"
What is this shit?
Only you French guys get leave?
We've fought since Marseilles.
Us, Italy.
We're off to Paris.
You need to get back to wog land.
The wog fucks you.
You miss home?
Your family?
Why speak Arabic?
Me too.
I like to go leave and see my mother.
Any maiI for me?
There's no maiI for you.
You must look again.
It's not normaI.
I wrote three times. Messaoud Souni.
Or maybe I'm listed as dead.
I said no.
Private!
There's nothing for you.
Here's Aiicha!
How is she?
Has Sergeant Martinez repudiated you?
Marrying a Moroccan?
Why are you getting at me?
Go to your Marseilles girI.
An American's probably banging her now.
It doesn't matter.
You know why?
Here...
you're the one we want, Aiicha.
Our beautifuI Aiicha.
She takes care of us.
As God is my witness...
Saiid, calm down!
...if ever you call me Aiicha again...
If one of you...
No problem, my brother.
Everyone has understood.
Stop it.
Leave him be. Calm down.
If anyone calls me Aiicha,
I'll kill him.
Let go of him.
I'm not a child!
Let go of him!
SAID
You're mad!
Are you soldiers, idiots, or what?
Get out of here!
Get out! Go on!
Hurry it up!
Don't try that again!
Listen to me, you.
You're not a slave.
There are no slaves here!
No one has bothered about me here,
except the sergeant.
Learn your book by heart and become a coloneI.
Who's becoming a coloneI?
This donkey?
This mule?
Why wouldn't they become colonels?
Why not him?
And even him?
We can try.
So try!
It's over!
Get to your bunks!
Do it!
I want no more trouble!
THE VOSGES - NOVEMBER 1944
Yes, it looks ugly!
It'll be even worse in there!
It'll be tougher than Italy.
But I have faith in you.
I have faith in you to liberate your homeland.
The French have placed their fate in our hands
and are watching us with eyes full of hope.
We have to be up there by dark!
And, even dead, we shall be! Even dead!
Is it Omar, sir?
Sir...
I've taken the position.
I'm here, sir.
I'm in charge here!
I ordered you to regroup,
not to head off on your own!
I give the orders. Look where it's got us!
We've lost Omar!
Go to say we've taken the position
and request orders.
Yes, sir.
Sir?
I have news for you, Saiid.
You're promoted private.
You're transferred to HQ.
Take your pack and go there.
I don't want to be private, Sarge.
I'm fine like I am now.
I was kidding!
SAID
Learn to fend for yourself.
I might die one day.
You're not going to die, Sarge.
You not say that ever.
You're going to be alive
to become captain, irch' Allah.
Captain's too much paperwork.
Are French girls like this, sir?
She says she's with you
for life and then forgets you.
Is that how it is here?
When you get promoted,
pick a rich, pretty one.
She's beautifuI, CorporaI.
Look at the photo
and tell me what you think.
Tell me the truth.
Is she serious or not serious?
What's her name?
Irene.
Irene's a pretty name.
We have to see this war out.
We'll return in honor.
Irene will be proud of you.
Listen to this.
"After the war, I return, Irene.
I send you kisses. I think of you...
day and night. Messaoud. "
Pretty, huh?
It's like a song.
CENSORED
They're not idiots, sir.
They've been away 20 months,
they're freezing here...
I know, Sergeant!
The French get leave.
No ships!
There were ships to bring them,
but none to send them on leave?
We'd like to see our families,
like the mainland French. It's unfair.
And the French get promotion
before anyone from North Africa!
You're doing good work.
I'll put you up for promotion.
I don't want it.
My men deserve it as much as me.
CorporaI Abdelkader, for instance.
Don't sleep.
Wake up! Get up!
God rest his souI.
What's this?
What does it say?
Read it.
"Muslim soldier...
"know that you can cross to the German side,
"where you will be warmly welcomed
"and your life spared.
"Your leaders send you
to die rather than the French.
"Muslim soldier,
"you weren't born into slavery.
"Germany will give you your freedom.
The day of independence has come for Africa. "
What would you do with us,Abdelkader?
You have something in mind?
Out with it,
man to man.
De Gaulle said we're fighting for liberty.
I'm fighting with France against Nazism.
Come out of your holes!
We have leave!
Come out!
We're going home.
"Labor Exchange Office for German Workers"
Those aren't to go home in.
There'll be dancers tonight!
She hasn't written back.
Be patient.
There's a war on. The maiI hasn't arrived.
It has. There was nothing for me.
Leroux! Martinez!
Martinez,
you're promoted to staff sergeant. Bravo.
Thank you, sir.
And you're a sergeant now, Leroux.
Congratulations.
Try to find stripes.
Well done, Leroux.
Thank you, Staff Sergeant.
Messaoud!
The girls will go wild for you in those boots!
Do you like your coat, CorporaI?
Yes, I suppo se.
God preserve you.
Amen.
He's wearing me out!I have to go.
Here I am!
Sit yourself down.
Whisky?
Like America.
Sorry, Sarge, it burns!
Just a second.
Have a cigar.
Is it for me?
Of course it's for you.
You know...
I don't unusually smoke cigars,
but I will now.
I like you, Saiid.
Me too, Sarge.
I like you.
You deserve promotion.
The whole unit does. But they can't see that.
They can't tell. They don't know us.
We'll liberate the country and go home.
But, Sarge...
here too is our home.
It's France.
We're fighting for her,for the motherland.
Here is our home, and I know...
you're like us too...
an Arab.
What did you just say?
I see the photo of your mother in the shirt.
It's incredible.
Put the photo of your mother
next to the photo of my mother,
they look like two sisters.
You searched my things, bastard!
Shit-stirrer! Scum!
Never talk about that again or I'll kill you.
Get lost!
Fall in! Attention!
At ease!
What is this shit?
Sit down!
I'm taking my leave!I'm off to Marseilles.
With her potatoes Ard moldy bears
Frarce is our mother She feeds us
Listen!
Listen to me, my brothers!
When I enlisted,I listened to De Gaulle.
He said France was fighting for
freedom around the world.
I thought the war would give us
the rights of our French brothers.
We're all fighting against Hitler
for liberty,equality, and fraternity.
It's high time they gave us
some of that liberty,
that equality and,above all, that fraternity!
We're changing the destiny of France!
Things must change for us too!
Stand aside!
You're asking for it!
You keep stirring up shit all the time!
The French reward themselves,
then you French North Africans,
and the Africans are forgotten.
There are quotas.
Quotas?
Why didn't you tell us?
You can't understand,
so shut up and step down!
Why can't I understand?
A wog has less of a brain than you?
Wogs aren't cut out to lead men.
That day will come, Sergeant.
Sorry, Staff Sergeant.
What are you doing here?
I tried to get to Marseilles.
The French get leave,we get nothing.
Is that normaI?
Is it normaI?
You tried to desert.
Are you crazy?
I have to see her.
Why are you here, CorporaI?
I had a fight with Martinez,the staff sergeant.
Got a Gauloise?
Yes.
They're on the front.
Their position is top secret.
Write to him.
I already have, severaI times.
There's been no reply.
Tell me...
is he dead?
Give me his name. We'll find out.
Messaoud Souni.
He's with the 7th Algerian
Infantry Regiment.
If we hear anything, we'll let you know.
Thank you.
ColoneI, we must be firm with the Muslims.
Punish this corporaI as a warning.
Rambert, tell me something.
Yes, sir?
Before joining De Gaulle at the last minute,
what were you in Vichy?
Martinez.
Yes, sir.
You know the Muslims. What do we do with him?
He's loyaI to France, sir.
All my men are patriots.
You risk being court-martialled!
There's injustice, sir.
Silence!
We must strive together
towards one goaI: victory.
France needs us, all of us.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Yes, sir.
In Alsace, the 37th U.S. Division
has broken through.
They're under attack and require
reinforcements and ammunition.
We must hold this bridgehead
untiI the generaI attack due any day.
Captain Durieux needs brave men,
men of experience.
It's a very dangerous mission.
I'll volunteer for it, sir.
CorporaI,I give you my word of honor.
The rewards for yourself
and all the brave men
who contribute to this exploit
will be worthy of the feat.
You will be the first to reach Alsace.
All of France will watch and remember you.
I shall fight with my body and souI,
as I have always done.
CorporaI Abdelkader.
He's a man of his word.
There's no time to lose.
Get your unit's ammunition.
Sir...
Private Messaoud is in jaiI.
We need our marksman. I'll see to it.
Thank you, sir.
Tell the men to keep quiet.
Quiet!We're nearing the German lines.
Keep quiet and controI the mules.
Larbi!
Why?
Why, God? Why?
The captain and Leroux are dead.
We've lost five men too.
You're the one in charge now.
It's your decision.
Either you help the Americans
hold the position...
or you turn back.
Fetch the mule. We're carrying on!
We're out of ammunition!
He's right.
Silence!
We'll be the first French in Alsace.
If we manage to hold
the American positions, believe me...
we'll get what we deserve.
You'll get nothing.
Haven't you realized yet?
I've given my brother for France.
Enough!
CorporaI! Be reasonable!
Be reasonable!
You want to kill each other?
There have been enough dead!
CorporaI, pull yourself together!
Our comrades are dead.
Thanks to God,we're still alive.
God bless your family.
He's right.
It's no use anymore.
What's wrong with you?
You want to be a sergeant?
Too late.
You don't understand a thing!
We're doing our duty by going to Alsace!
Even if we pay 10 or 100 times more,
we'll pay!
And they'll recognize us for it.
What's wrong with you?
Listen.
You want to go home empty-handed?
We see it through to the end.
Larbi, rest his souI, won't have died in vain.
Saiid, please go.
Bring the mule back!
Don't fight anymore.
It's over. Hurry!
Come here.
Come here, beauty!
Don't make things worse.
I'm tired.
Be good.
I can't run after you.
For the love of God!
Yassir, round the back.
The French!
You're alone?Where are the others?
We'll defend the position, sir.
We'll hold it untiI our troops arrive.
I would have done the same...
CorporaI.
I have to go and see the men.
I hope you're going to die...
Sergeant.
Staff Sergeant.
It's as if there was no war on.
What are we doing here?
When the war is over,you'll stay in the army.
You'll rise up through the ranks to sergeant.
I don't want to be a sergeant!
Some have the right to it and others don't.
God has forgotten me for now.
Have you ever given an order to anyone?
Never.
Tell me frankly.
Will we get through this?
Listen, Saiid...
we've always got through it...
together.
Have you forgotten?
Everything's in God's hands.
Thank you, ma'am.
Enjoy your meaI.
Who can live in this cold?
The French.
Can I fetch milk?
Does she give a lot of milk?
Two or three buckets.
Want to try?
Yes.
You're never afraid?
Sometimes I am...
but I'm not afraid tonight.
come here
I don't want to die here.
Lord...
I declare there is no deity but God.
I'll fetch Martinez.
Wait, Saiid.
Listen to me.
Messaoud is dead.
Be carefuI, my brother.
Wait.
Yassir!
Cover us!
One, two... go!
Sarge, get up!
Get up, Sarge. Come on!
Yassir!
Cover me! Here I come!
Get out! Hurry!
Come on, let's go!
Move it!
Get up! Get up, Yassir!
Get up, for pity's sake!
My brothers...
I'm with you!
Don't shoot!
Okay.
Don't stop! Keep going!Move it!
ColoneI.
ColoneI!
Stop!
Let me see the coloneI.
What?
Let me see him.
See your sergeant.
He's dead. Captain too.
So where's your unit?
I don't have one. They're all dead.
Sergeant!
You needed a corporaI?Here's one.
Get your pack and follow us.
Look over here!
The French forces free Alsace!
This way!
Smile!
60 years later
MARTINEZ, Roger - Staff Sergeant
Died for France 15-01-1945
Messaoud Souni
at 1959. a law was passed to
freeze the persiors of irfartrymer
from former Frerch colories
about to become irdeperdert.
hr 2002.after erdless hearirgs.
the Frerch government
was ordered to pay the persiors ir full.
But successive governments