Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
THE DEAD GIRL
They burn
.Estas there?
EXTRA.O
It begins
There.
.Por here?
Oh shit...
...we find the body at 11:45 o'clock.
Did .Qué tell you?
Anything
- Twenty-five minutes
and they didn't say anything.
There is a dead youth...
...they need to ask some questions.
.Por what they have to wonder to you?
...your you don't know anything.
I found it.
And you called to the police...
- For your blame those
idiots are out...
...for all my garden speaking to me
as if they knew me...
...before you realize
they will be climbing the stairs
- I only spoke to them
on the dead youth.
Did .La find and what?...
...it continues walking and
maintain the closed mouth...
...stupid.
- Did .Tu find the body?
- Did .Cómo find it?
Was .Qué making in that place?
Did .Lo know?
Oh yes what fear...
...she looks he/she found it.
.Puedes to imagine it?
60 cents of change...
...Does .necesita help?
- Not this well.
.Dónde this your car?
- You are pretty in TV.
.Eras your certain?...
...to some people not him
it cares, you can notice it...
...but you shine really sweet.
- He/she leaves... .los wants
behind or ahead?
Behind please.
You have to open it.
I would like to go out with you some day.
No, I don't believe.
Does .No want to go out with me?
We go, salt with me...
...it will be amusing, I leave at eleven o'clock.
I am not able to.
.Por what you have boyfriend?
No.
I won't injure.
Thank you.
Does .te see then at eleven o'clock?
They burn.
Did .Qué make you in the face?
Anything.
Is .Qué that stain?
The milk this conquered one.
Take off that.
No.
Take off it.
Luz like a damned prostitute.
You seem a clown.
- The competition already
Miss passed America...
...jumping up and
below look at me, look at me...
...he/she should give you shame
to put on all that garbage...
...you look at yourself in a mirror
lights like a prostitute...
...ohhh jesús... the one
he/she chose to the mistaken one...
...it should have taken you
to you and not to my ni.o.
Don't speak of him...
...don't dare.
It was, there is what you can...
...you don't have to where to go...
...Does .me leave? nobody will love you...
...you don't have anything...
...veto, veto.
Was .Cómo?
Was .Cómo what?
The dead girl.
I don't know it... sad I believe.
Short .Le the hands certain?
He/she didn't know.
To defend it can cut them...
...insurance was naked.
He/she had on clothes...
...Will .Qué reasons have had the murderer?
I don't believe it...
...they cut them
without any purpose...
...four or five murderers
they made the same thing...
...to their victims and the policemen
they cannot be explained to it...
...because he/she doesn't have any
sense to cut those...
...hands to the women...
...When finally him
they caught they were given...
...it counts that it was part
of their erotic games.
- And then when they looked
in their registrations...
...they found that him
he/she was stealing clothes...
...of the women from
when he/she had 12 a.os...
...and with what you/they found
they asked him/her...
....Por what he/she made it?...
...he began to cry,
and he/she caught a backpack with...
...the underwear of
the women, you already know...
...supports, shorts, stockings...
...and there it is where those
policemen discovered...
...to the murderer in series,
fair among their fingers.
.Por what him ago?
For that felt better...
...it was frustrated by something...
...somebody made him/her something.
.Por what to kill a woman?
- Probably something
that he/she made him/her their mother
It is a little extra.o.
Everything can happen.
.Sí?
For something he/she made it.
- I have begun to read something
interesting, when somebody...
...he/she dies, you would rot the
ball of the eye and you reveal...
...as negative of pictures
and you see the last thing that vió.
The trees, the sky.
He/she looks at this.
I can load it.
This is something very pretty.
- It belongs to her.
- I know it.
I sit down it. I sit down it.
.Por what you believe that I brought you here?
I don't know it.
- .Crees that maybe
be because I like?
I don't know it.
.Quieres to kiss me?
This well.
Then make it.
Does .No want to kiss me?
I don't know it
.Quieres that I kiss you?
And that we make all those things.
This well.
.Quieres that ties you?
Maybe.
.Quizás what?
Maybe should tie me.
Or maybe you should only allow yourself to take.
This well.
Does .No want to tie me to my?
.Por how not?
.Para what that is?
I don't know it.
Is .Esto what you want?
- Probably can
to come unfastened if this this way
Shit.
Does .Qué happen?
It is that I cannot make this way it.
.Por what?
- Not even me
you kiss, you only throw...
...and you want him to violate you.
This well.
.Esta well? .Quieres that violates you?
I will kiss you a little.
And take off the gloves.
You need points for that
It doesn't hurt a lot.
Does .Ahora want to kiss me?
- Some murderers in
series uses objects when...
...they want
to kill, you already know, as...
...bottles, knives...
- No longer quiereo to speak
of murderers in series
911. Is .Cuál its emergency?
Hello. 911.
There is a woman that needs help.
Hurt .Esta?
Their daughter left it.
.Esa woman this there with you?
- Hello.
- No.
.Dónde this her?
This in the house...
...where they found the dead youth.
THE SISTER
It should have something that we have not made...
...He/she thinks of something that we forget.
- Your father believes that we would should
to choose that of caba.a...
...but to my I like it
the navidad tree...
...we have used this so many ones
times, your you know, me...
...the target and black he/she doesn't fall me well...
...and I believe that the color would be better...
...so, yes, I choose that of colors...
...I don't know it, we would maybe should
to choose the one that reflects the age.
The one that seems you.
- .Cómo believes that
would it be to continue ahead?
- My mom, my dad and
me with things that you...
...they can pack in my
room and we take...
...all the boxes with those
inform of the newspaper...
...and posters, and we burn
everything in a great bonfire...
...and later we cry and us
we support in one another...
...and later we leave
to sleep for 1000 a.os...
...and a ma.ana us
we will wake up and the sun...
...it will be shining and my mom will go...
...to the kitchen and he/she will make
the breakfast for him...
...and my dad will say enrolls
for the school, and he/she smiles...
...everything would be well another time...
...not so well, but
we would have the opportunity...
...of he being. This
lost 15 a.os ago...
...I will never be I will very never overcome it.
I already leave.
This well
- We have to make that
the siguente ma.ana...
...it is part of the work
that we make together.
Sure.
- My compa.ero of
room and I will be...
...together ma.ana in
the night only for...
...to pass the while, to throw the
computer for the window...
...as a celebration
if you would like...
...to fall of visit.
- Perhaps this in the
library, but thank you
You can come later if you want.
I will try.
This well
Don't work a lot.
12:13, RABBIT MARK OF BIRTH
IN THE HAND RELATIVES DON'T KNOW EACH OTHER
GENESIS 12:13 "PRAY. YOU
I SAY, YOUR YOU ARE MY SISTER"
- .Tu mates it has not been
lost a long time?
- If but we have been
looking for it from then on.
But I need current pictures.
- I know it, but this
girl has a mark...
...from birth in
one of their fingers that...
...he/she resembles that of Jenny.
I want them to examine their denture.
This well.
Is .Quién?
- The detectives sent
this picture that is possible...
...that it agrees with
that of the youth that...
...we have in the morgue.
- No. They are not their eyes.
Their eyes are clearer.
- He/she has the mark of
birth in the hand...
...left among those
fingers the same as Jenny.
No. It is not Jenny.
- He/she looks at the report, they don't have
found any relative.
- Those are not their eyes.
- This well.
It is difficult to believe that he/she ended.
Só, I know it.
- You came.
- Yes.
This well. .Quieres something of taking?...
...beer, soda, champagne.
- Champagne.
- This well.
Then, .Por what tonight?...
...you have been
inviting to my parties...
...by three a.os.
Has .Lo made?
- I don't know you, but always
you saw yourself as if...
...somebody dead huibiera.
Yes, I believe.
It seems that it was not so much.
That is good.
You don't know what can happen
Nobody brought gifts.
No. .Tu yes?
I believe that you didn't wait this.
But it could be amusing.
I don't believe that it is that type of gifts.
- Yes, it is good to be
outside of the bed...
...from time to time.
Only in my friends' house.
And your dad.
Yes.
Or maybe nr.
Your eyes are beautiful.
They are it.
Not this well.
- I sit down as if you
I allow to leave you will go far.
Then don't allow to leave.
Hey. Hello.
- Once again, I promise
that it won't be a lot.
No, no, I am not able to. I have to leave.
But you could stay a while more.
I love you to come.
To my also.
- .Sí?
- Yes. He/she wanted to make it...
...a long time ago.
- Serious .En?
- Yes.
It is good to know it.
Good I have to leave. I should leave...
...I see you then.
Good-bye.
- Hello.
- .Derek?
Hey .Cómo these?
Well, very in fact.
- Because your work
it can be very boring.
You have one minute.
I should leave I call later.
He/she waits.
.Hicieron the tests?
It is not her.
Non concidieron.
They gave negative in the comparison...
...in ma.ana the detective called me...
...and they found to the
the girl's mother...
...and he/she said that it was
managing Washington.
This mistaken one, has he to be.
- The woman's name
he/she is Nora Kritcher...
...and that of their daughter is Krista Kritcher...
...she confirms that for the picture.
I sit down it.
I am not, he/she leaves your message.
- Leah is me, .estas
there? .Estas well?...
...this well tries of
to take care and you call me...
...only tell me what he/she spends,
everything will be well...
...good good-bye.
- It has spent 3 thousand dollars
for a couple of squares.
- Me dió the name of its
investor, somebody...
...with a wallet of clients.
- I want to have a mass in
honor to the memory of Jenny.
.Qué?
- Jenny this dead one and
I want to have a mass...
...in their memory.
.Por what you say that?
Because it is the true.
Cari.o, we don't know that.
Her not this dead one for what we know
Her this dead one...
...she didn't escape...
...she was not attacked by the wolves...
...or the head was hit
and he/she forgot their name...
...and not you this being
with a family...
...that it picked up it.
- Some hobre caught it and
he/she made him/her horrible things...
...and it hid their body
so well that never...
...we would find it
and it doesn't care how...
...let us be about looking for it
or peticines that we make...
...or that picture puts
in the newspaper...
...because nobody goes to reconcerla
because her this dead one...
...and it will never return.
- If it was dead,
.no believes that he/she would know it...
...in my heart? I know that this alive one...
...I know that this there
out in some place...
...and the only way for
that we see it again...
...it is that we never give ourselves for conquered.
...Somebody out knows to
my he/she drinks, they know it...
...only they don't know
that we are looking for it.
I will never give myself had conquered by her...
...as well as never me
he/she would give for conquered...
...with you, never, never.
Hello.
Please help me.
THE WIFE
.Vas to leave?
Yes, only to manage a little.
- .No believes that I could
to sometimes want to leave?...
...Does .No think of that?
- Yes.
- Good I want to go...
...to some side and your not
you want to go if I go...
...to the skittles, to dance.
- .Bailar?
- I am a good dancer...
...you don't know it because you never take me.
We Go Ruth.
Will .Cuando return?
I don't know it.
Tonight, ma.ana, the weekend.
Be not this way.
I only want to know...
...to make my own plans.
I will no longer make never this more...
...Waits that I stay
here and make your matters...
...but your these it was,
without keeping me in mind...
...without you care it,
that type class.
Jim will work ma.ana.
- Because I won't be here
when you decide to return...
...And .Quién will wash
your clothes and to feed?...
....Quién will call to your
boss when you cannot go...
...because these drunkard?
- I only said that
Jim will work ma.ana...
...You will be here.
But not you.
I don't know it, maybe.
- Do I see you then, .esta well?
- No.
We go. Ruth.
.Por what you hate me so much?
I don't hate you.
- Then .por what
you are about taking away from my...
...the whole time?
I don't hate you.
- Lie.
- I don't hate you...
...I only want to leave
a while, jesucristo...
....qué has to make
so that you understand?
- This well, make it
that you want, only veto.
- Jesus.
- Don't take again...
...their name, don't take
their name in vain...
...in my house.
- .Quién is believed that it is
to make me feel...
...this way and to leave me?
I told it to him...
...Not the he/she doesn't have idea
of the afortuando that is...
...the fortunate ones that we are both...
...that it is the door. I have to leave...
...if something happens do you call me well .esta?...
...I will thank you for it. No
I can support more this.
.Puedo to help them?
- Yes, we are looking for
space to store.
- It is supposed that
we went to the one of there...
...but there is not nobody.
.Jim not this there?
Not there is not nobody.
Good I don't have anything to make...
...that it is my husband's work.
Good, the this here maybe.
We go.
Yes.
Somebody this there.
No, this empty one.
Because not him this.
Good somebody made an error.
Better gives us another space.
It is not supposed that they have energy
- It is supposed that this
hole, not with this.
Does .nos give it then?
No, I will give them another space.
MURDERERS KILLED AT EIGHT.
THE END COMES CLOSER
The car failed again...
...I don't want to return
to see that it passes that...
...he/she already has more than an a.o.
Did .Qué happen to you in the neck?
A type treatment of looking for fight.
Did .Te fight?
I already got tired of this...
...to be I and your faces what you want...
...you prefer to leave without my and to be with...
...any prostitute, to arrive
to house an entire disaster...
....Crees that not what happens?...
...I called to my niece,
this with their children...
...and it would be happy of having me...
...then you will see what is...
...that there is not nobody
when they come home...
...and when you come
drugged and be old.
I sit down it.
So you went to the bar.
Good in fact it manages over there...
...I went to see Ray.
I called to Ray and he/she has not seen you.
When you called it it was no longer there.
You left to see the prostitutes again.
No.
- I will no longer support
that the policemen and those...
...sew they come here to sniff...
...Did I already get tired of this, does .Me listen?...
...I already got tired of this...
...you have been with the protitutas...
...wetting your peque.o egg.
Be quiet.
You don't like Ohh him to speak to you dirty...
...but .Qué faces you, uh?
putting your language in those prostitutes.
It is it is my problem.
He/she stops to speak this way to me...
...I already see because these
this way. I know that faces.
Thank you.
Does .No know anything on those girls?
No.
POLICE STATION
THE MOTHER
- It would have been for the 90...
93. No, it is not correct...
...16... she left the
he/she marries when he/she had 16...
...and that the last time that I saw it was...
...I left him/her messages
because he/she had a number...
...it was very bothersome,
he/she left very undoubtedly...
...he/she didn't want or that their father
we entered in their life.
He/she knew that she moved to Los Angeles.
- I thought that he/she would go to Holliwood
she always spoke...
...of leaving in Television
when it was peque.a...
...he/she didn't wait for me this,
all their sue.os, goals.
Wait for me there one minute.
KRISTA ANNE KRITCHER
LAST ADDRESS
WELL-KNOWN SILVER SADDLE
MOTEL 31613 WASHED BLUD
.Estará in the city another day?
Ma.ana will leave home but...
...if you need me.
- There are some things
that probably nr...
...we can try for telephone.
This well.
I wondered if...
...if Krista Kritcher lives here.
He/she lived.
He/she hoped to be able to see their room.
This busy one.
.Ve to that girl in the telephone?
She will want to be shown it, that believes.
.Por what you don't come to pick up me?...
...rot Tommy.
Excuse, excuse.
Does .La know?
- I sit down it. Me only
he/she wanted... I spoke with the woman...
...that he/she assists and I wondered
Could .si see your room?
.Conocías to the girl that lived here?
Yes, he/she knew it.
.Eran friends?
We lived meetings.
It is a pretty picture.
She knew it.
.Qué type of things faces?
.Qué?
The man that pays you.
- .Me these asking
does that make in an appointment?
- When he/she pays you.
- That is an appointment.
- I don't know it, that that him
want, them escojen.
- Does .Cuánto pay you?
- .Eres reporter?...
....Quieres to make one
history on me?...
...let us see, my mom this dead one...
...he/she entered a shot in
a parking lot...
...to my father I never met him...
...I have two means siblings
that they are very paid in L.A...
...but I have to be sucked it
to some idiots for money...
...Does .Qué think of that?
I believe that it is sad.
Yes, good.
- .Kriste spoke to you
at some time from where he/she came?
- Washington or some
place this way, I don't remember.
Did .Te say why he/she left?
Because it was not happy.
Did .Te say why?
- Maybe because their father
it stopped it harassing...
...I believe that yes.
I had made the...
...same, he/she wanted to catch it
at least here they pay us...
...damned men always make that...
...it is typical, the husband or the children...
...esogió the husband.
Did .Ella tell you that?
.Qué?
- What their mother knew
and that he/she chose it to him.
She probably left it.
Maybe if .no?...
...it can happen when one of your...
...children this in the laundry.
.Eres their mother?
He/she didn't know it.
This well.
He/she didn't have idea.
Good now he/she already knows it.
- Maybe it sounds funny but
I will end up late working.
Maybe he/she can invite you to eat lunch.
I don't believe it.
I will pay you.
- A time Kriste
it was fed up with everything...
...your you know you don't drug, non amusement...
...he/she wanted to make the things well
and he/she wanted to bring to their daughter...
...but he/she didn't have a lot
money for that...
...for what had to pay more...
...so it got
three works and it was...
...working and working
and he/she made it because her...
...he/she wanted manternerse
awake because he/she didn't go to be able to...
...to get up for the day of their wedding.
I sit down it. Kriste has a son.
- Yes, later the
they discharged of their work...
...and he/she became a disaster
that he/she could not believe it...
...I didn't listen again
of her in two weeks.
.Era a ni.a or ni.o?
Ni.a, wanted that ni.a a lot...
...it took out it to go for a walk a lot,
they had a good time a lot...
...and then I didn't know anything about her.
- .Dónde this?
- .Qué?
.Dónde this ni.a?
Hello, they come here.
Ashley, hello cari.o.
He/she wants money.
- I only have 200. .Esta
well?Enough .Es?
Give it to him.
Thank you.
- Good-bye Ashley, I am your
grandmother. .Quieres to come...
...with me, cari.o? This well.
Mommy.
You have to sit down behind with her.
Her this stinking.
It is that a ba.o needs.
Tell him/her that you caye.
.Quieres to please help me?
- .Qué doesn't have those
seats for babies?
- For that reason I am requesting you
that you feel with her.
- And if we have an accident
and it leaves for the window...
...waits that it catches it.
Would .Qué be better? That I left it here...
...Would .eso be better?
What is, only said it.
- I not even know where
to get a seat...
...for baby in this neighborhood.
He/she is not my daughter.
I will buy one ma.ana.
Will .Se be her?
Will .Te be her?
- I only need to know it
.Vas to stay it?
I believe that yes. I have to discuss him...
...with the father.
Good luck. They could be as a...
...million of different types...
...he/she would take care of it, almost
I take myself charge of her...
....cómo is supposed that me
do position of a ni.a make?...
...if you decide to stay it you only take care of it.
.Querías to my daughter?
She entrusted me that he/she took care of it...
...and I didn't make it...
...he/she wanted but, I ruined it.
- .Puede to wait one minute?
- This well.
- She told me that if the
it located that him of this.
- You don't have to make it.
If you want you can come...
...and to stay with me.
Only if your you want...
...you could not be better in my house...
...you only have to decide.
I don't believe it.
He/she waits, he/she waits.
Here you have my address...
...you can visit him some day.
I will see it if I can...
...I never had something as that.
THE DEAD YOUTH
Hold, veto. You are so stupid.
Demons, I sit down it...
...that hurted...
...that was not very kind.
Does .Qué pass with you? Get up...
...get up of the floor,
Did .Qué make this time?
Anything.
- Did .Qué make?
- Anything.
I am fed up with this.
Brilliant, .Qué rays that is?
It is for my daughter.
- .Crees that you can
to take to NorthWalk...
No, I have to work.
- Until tonight. Ma.ana
it is my daughter's cumplea.os.
Go that good.
You could be of turn in two hours.
- You don't want that you
catch for the bottom.
Yes.
Me these making a proposal.
Clear. Open it.
Take me to NorthWalk and you come with me.
Take me to where your you want.
Free.
Open it.
He/she would prefer you to take me to NothWalk.
Only taking the damned necklace.
.Por what these eating your hair?
Because it is delicious.
.A what he/she knows?
To strawberries.
- .Sabes what?
- .Qué?
You lie.
- .Sabes what?
- .Qué?
I don't believe you.
Because you don't believe me.
- .Sabes what?
- .Qué?
Marcy, comes for here cari.o.
Making some friends.
To all place that I go.
We go.
Does .Qué age have?
3 a.os and half.
- I have a daughter that
three ma.ana will complete.
- It is a great age.
- Yes.
Does .Te like to make parties?
Good it is a ni.a.
- Each cumplea.os goes
to see their friends and...
...a fantastic day we happen,
and we look at each thing...
...each thing and we say what
it is it that more we want...
...once I decided that him
that more wanted it was a...
...box full with mu.ecas
and they told to my mom...
...and it was excited
for this box of mu.ecas...
...it was my cumplea.os and
my mom gives me that great one...
...box jousts front
to my it was brilliant...
...and I opened it, and it was
as an extra.o clown...
...I felt bad, and finji
that it was well, brilliant...
...and he/she wanted it each
a.o and he/she always gave me...
...something that didn't want
the mistaken gift...
...no, no, I had to give myself
it counts that my damned mother...
...he/she could not buy something
that this in sale cheap...
...he/she thought that it didn't care
that I give he/she gave me...
...which the best was, which he/she wanted...
...he/she had to choose the mistaken one.
Maybe it is for that reason that you are jodida.
- I don't only want that
my daughter grows this way...
...I will give him/her what she wants...
...I don't want to ruin him
and sometimes, sometimes...
...you should obtain the
that your really wants...
...for your cumplea.os.
Jesus Christ.
I will take you to damned NorthWalk.
You are the best man. Yes.
- Is .Eso what you want?
- Yes, I don't know it, I thought...
...that you would not make it.
I will make it to my way.
I don't care it.
- To my yes. I don't want
to have to wash it again.
- It is supposed that he/she makes it
after three days.
Don't wash it.
I have to wash my hair.
That this brilliant one.
For the following type...
...your you are the best my love.
ASHLEY SUCKLES YOU HE/SHE LOVES AND YOU EXTRA.A A LOT!
- I have leave to work
or that shit won't work.
- You told me that me
you would take to NothWalk.
I don't have time to make it today.
You promised it.
- I don't have time for
to only make those foolishness...
...you have to make it
your same one in your car.
You are an idiot.
Give me time, we can go ma.ana.
Ma.ana is its cumplea.os.
- Because it will be the day
following of their cumplea.os.
You are an idiot.
Your problem.
Give me my money...
...I want my money.
- There this your damned one
money, and you don't bother me.
- You are an idiot,
.sabes? demons. Damned.
It goes up you I will take until the corner...
...rot dog.
.Puede to lend me your moto?
.Quieres to escape from my?
- It is seriously, we go
.puedes to lend it to me?
If I don't have left remedy.
- Gracais.
- Yes, you owe it to me.
- It returns in a piece.
- I see you then.
I sit down it baby.
.Qué carajos?
Did .Quié make you this baby?
Tell me and I will kill him to prostitute's son.
- Did .Quién make you this?
Did .Quién make you this?
Tell me. Was .Quién?
This pretty one.
- Yes, I bought it for
you, it is very beautiful hey.
Don't have it your, you have left it well.
Is it for Tom .cierto?...
...I will kill that idiot.
- No, you cannot make it.
You have to stay with me.
No, I am not able to baby, I have to leave...
...I have to see my ni.a,
I said that I have to leave.
- When it returns you will feel
well, .esta well?...
....esta well? I will make
that you feel better.
Demons.
IMBECILE
Damned dog.
- Rot.
- I will kill you...
...release you, damned you are
release you, I go to ense.arte that that-
Rot imbecile.
- If you play it another again
time I will kill you, does .me listen?...
...I will kill you...
...Does .Qué look at me dogs?.
Prostitute Mother.
- I won't leave that
nobody plays you again...
...believe me baby.
- I have to leave of here
- .A where you will leave?
- I don't know it some place,
trees, the sky, to breathe...
...and damned air. Some pretty place...
...I will do myself with my daughter ma.ana
and will we leave well .esta?
- Is .Hola there?
- I only want that this well.
- Bothersome .Estas
with me? Don't bother you...
...because I love you. Does .Me want?
- I only want you to know it.
I really need you.
I have to return to the bed.
This well. I have to leave.
Damned... damned... damned.
.Sabe if there is a store here?
- I don't know it. At this hour
they should be closed.
Shit.
.Puede to take me to NorthWalk?
- .Dónde?
- NorthWalk...
...I don't believe that this very far from here.
Does .Allí live?
- My daughter lives there,
ma.ana is its cumplea.os...
...in fact already it is today
she was born at this hour...
...it is supposed that this is for her...
...but I cannot be given it.
I have to make a stop...
...but later probably
it can take you to NorthWalk.
Serious .En? God is brilliant...
...I can be there when he/she wakes up...
...we can eat chocolates and cake...
...to have a son is something beautiful...
...their father is an idiot,
the whole time she tells me...
...that he/she is afraid that you
wake up and me not this there...
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com