A virus, a selective virus.
Release it near the aliens.
They can take the sneakers
you are wearing off you.
They check the brand and take them.
They take whatever you have on you.
Your cell phone or anything.
After that, they kill you.
Fuck off!
No, it's not my house.
I don't live here.
Yes! It is my house!
What is eviction?
You put the money here first.
You don't get anything until you pay.
What are you trying to do?
I'll chop your balls off.
Some of the guns are small.
But if it shoot you, it make a big mess.
No, not them!
Look! I found some!
I told you before,
this is human technology...
...it is useless.
Only our technology
contains the fluid.
That is not our technology?
No, it's junk.
Keep looking.
I find something.
Yes. This is what we need.
Good, little one.
Get down.
Careful. Wait.
There.
Why must it take so long?
Because it is very difficult...
...so much can go wrong.
Twenty years of work.
Our plan is ready now?
Quiet. Listen.
They are coming.
You must hide this...
...they must not find it.
Answer the door and be polite.
No! You take it.
This place is swarming with MNU.
I will be searched.
I must get back to my son.
Don't make them angry. Be polite!
Nobody is here.
No.
That's not mine.
No. No.
Look, I fix it...
...l make it work.
I told you not to touch that.
What is wrong?
Nothing. Go outside
and watch for humans.
Where is your friend?
He's gone.
Inside, go! I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
What do you want?
I know.
Why am I being evicted?
Yes?
It says you must give
me 24 hours notice.
This isn't legal.
No.
Yes.
You keep away from my child!
It's a silver cylinder.
I can't find it.
We must find it.
It contains the fluid.
It's not here.
It has to be, keep looking.
We trade for 10,000 cans.
Give them one hundred cans.
Yes, yes, but we take all of them now.
Get them the cat food. Hurry up.
Fuck off! Go!
Hey, friend, not you. You stay here.
- What do you want with me?
- We just want to talk.
Talk about what?
Stupid prawn.
They'll believe anything.
I pay you next week, I promise.
No money, you get nothing.
Fucking prawn, this isn't a charity.
You!
What do you want?
You have to go.
Yes! Yes!
No, get back.
Please, just go. Leave us alone.
Nothing. You must hide
somewhere else.
Only one thing that
could make that happen.
Quick, we have to hide him.
Now you, get down there.
Where's the fluid?
What did you do with it?
You took it.
I know you did.
I can see what's happening to you.
Tell me where it is.
Yes, that's it. Yes!
You ruined everything.
Fuel goes in here!
That's enough! Quiet!
Then we fly away.
I said quiet! We cannot trust him.
Never mind.
Too bad. I could've fixed you.
Forget it.
It doesn't matter, it's too late.
We have medical machines on the
mother ship that can fix you. Yes.
We can use this ship to fly up there.
I don't have fluid.
I could fix you and I could fly away.
But I don't have fluid.
It took 20 years to
collect that amount.
Yes.
He likes you.
We are the same.
There is a way out of this.
We get the fluid back from MNU.
The transformation is accelerating.
You do not have much time.
How many moons does our planet have?
Seven.
This planet only has one.
I can't wait to see our planet.
It is bigger than this one, isn't it?
Enough.
We go home now?
Not home. No.
This is where we must go.
See that tent there?
That might be ours.
I want to go home!
We can't go home. Not anymore.
We go up to the mother ship.
Yes.
You said it was a suicide mission.
Maybe you were right.
We have no weapons.
They'll shoot us on sight.
I want the arm. Cut it off.
I understand.
Fuck!
I thought you said not to kill them?
What is this place?
What do they do in here?
What do we do now?
I thought you had a way out?
I have an idea.
Follow me.
Making a bomb!
Let's go!
Go! Drive!
Go down and initiate
the binary commands.
To do what?
It's going to take a bit
longer than I thought.
Three years.
Yes. Three years.
I will fix you but first
I must save my people.
I will not let my people
be medical experiments!
I must go home and get help.
I must use all the fluid
to travel quickly.
I will come back. I promise.
Father!
In there.
Father.
Father!
My son!
My son's in there!
Bring him to me.
I can't, it's too far.
Are you hurt?
No, we stick together.
I'm not leaving you here.
I will come back for you.
Three years, I promise.
We go home now?
Yes.