Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
You can't go lower?
Easy!
Come play Mommy's guitar.
- You wanna play guitar?
- Yeah.
You wanna play?
"It's too bad, really.
I loved listening
to the Dixie Chicks.
I love their music.
Even this new
angry song is good."
Who is this?
Rightwingsparkle blog.
Sparkle!
"Country music is a 90%
Bush-supporting bunch.
These lamebrains
are talented, sure,
but they're sticking a finger
in the eye of their own customer."
"Dixie Chicks?
Are they still around?
I thought their 15 minutes
were up a long time ago."
Oh!
I'm not gonna
read the next line.
- Come on!
- No no no no...
- We don't get our feelings hurt.
- No no no no.
"Who are the Dixie Chicks,
anyway?
I mean, they're not like
an important band
where you know all their names,
like the Beatles.
The Dixie Chicks suck. They don't know
what they're talking about
and should
shut the fuck up."
It's easy for people
to feel a sense of anonymity
behind their computer
and write ugly things
and hateful things.
And, you know, a lot of that stuff
you don't take seriously,
but when somebody
hates you so much for what you say
that they want
to kill you...
I think if you walked
out on the street right now
and asked, "What did Natalie Maines
of the Dixie Chicks say?"
I don't believe that they would
know what I said.
But it is a part of...
who we are
as a band now,
whether we asked for it
or wanted it or like it.
I feel like...
people relate to us
because we're real.
And when you're real, you stick
your foot in your mouth sometimes.
People don't understand
how tight we are.
We're a sisterhood. We go through
the good, the bad and the ugly
all together.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Grammy Award winners,
the Dixie Chicks.
The Dixie Chicks
are returning to the road
on their
"Top of the World" tour
which kicks off in London
on March 10.
And after only three albums,
the Dixie Chicks
are now the best-selling
female group in history.
The Dixie Chicks' music
is rooted in tradition but,
just like the Dixie Chicks
are redefining the traditional
conventions of country music,
we're going to redefine tea
and serve it up in a way that's new,
full of energy and, frankly,
is really refreshing.
So, Lipton is proud to be
the official beverage sponsor
of the Dixie Chicks' 2003
"Top of the World" tour.
USA! USA! USA!
Go for it.
Hi, I'm Simon Renshaw.
I'm the Dixie Chicks' manager.
And I just thought
I'd take this opportunity
to say hello to all of you
and welcome you to the tour.
And we're looking forward
to a good one.
- Who's online?
- I am.
What's the war update?
Richard?
They're moving troops
but they haven't crossed yet.
Army units are now
moving into positions
at the border, battle-ready.
The feeling here--
war may be only hours away.
Calling them facts
and not assertions,
US Secretary of State
Colin Powell today
presented what
he says is evidence
that Iraq is hiding
weapons of mass destruction.
Simply stated, there is no doubt
that Saddam Hussein now has
weapons of mass destruction.
We know they have
We know
they have active programs.
There-- there isn't
any debate about it.
The danger is clear.
Using chemical, biological
or, one day, nuclear weapons
obtained with the help of Iraq,
the terrorists could fulfill
their stated ambitions.
Saddam Hussein
and his sons
must leave Iraq
within 48 hours.
How's it looking?
Are you sure it's not too much?
- No.
- Hmm.
Okay, let's walk. We've gotta go.
Can I have someone take her baby?
Martie, we've gotta hit the stage.
- Martie, we've gotta go.
- Grab Martie, let's go.
Behind the growing buildup to war
there's also a growing
antiwar movement.
This may have been the biggest
political rally in UK history.
Perhaps as many as a million people
converged on the center of London
to march and denounce
American plans for war.
You know what?
For a first show, it was awesome.
It was definitely
mission accomplished.
Audience loved it,
it looked great.
You know,
one down, 99 to go.
If you want to feel some good
old-fashioned American pride,
look no further than the uproar
over the Dixie Chicks.
And how they can say, 'I'm ashamed
that the president's from Texas'?
Come on, man. That's crazy.
The comment was quoted
by London newspaper "The Guardian."
In a matter of days, the London story
was picked up by the Associated Press
and printed in newspapers
all over the United States.
Personally, I hope
you don't play their music again
for quite a while.
I think that was very disrespectful.
Natalie's comment,
especially on foreign soil,
just was a slap in the face.
The American media is picking up
from the-- from the--
from the UK media,
you know, "Dixie Chicks diss
the President" kind of thing.
Everyone's calling.
Everyone's looking
for the statement.
And the area of concern is actually
what's coming out of country radio,
which is a far more
right-wing Conservative--
Really?
- Uh, yeah, that's right.
- Yeah.
So what I just did was,
I just closed down
both the websites, all right?
- Oh my God!
- Hold on, hold on.
- Just let me--
- Was the chat room a part of it?
- Closed.
- Both of the chat rooms?
Yeah, so the idea is
we need to put a statement up
on the website.
And in terms
of the American media,
we need to have a statement
to release to the American media.
What if you just go
something like, you know,
"I apologize. We were
at a smoky bar gig
and I got a little carried away."
You know, play it down instead of...
But it's more serious than that.
- ..."This is what we really--"
- It is more serious than that.
But it was meant--
it was amidst kind of a joking thing.
But it was true. Here's
We have never been-- or "I"--
if y'all don't want to keep saying "we."
It should be "we."
- Sorry...
- Sorry, girls, but it should be "we."
Well, if anybody
asks me personally,
I'm gonna go, "Hey, I didn't say it.
Go talk to her."
Thanks for the support.
No, but I'm not
gonna try to dig you out.
I mean, I would end up saying
something totally wrong.
Like, I would like to say
that my comment was made...
In reference to--
...in reference to
the disappointment I feel--
- or the something I feel--
- Frustration.
--the frustration I feel
as an American citizen
for being ignored.
All right, so-- I mean, I don't think
that we should shy away
from controversy.
I mean, so-- I mean,
wouldn't it be great
if we could get them,
like, burning CDs
and banning you
from the radio...
We're gonna
boycott them for their music
and we're gonna boycott you for
playing it if you don't stop playing it.
Well, ma'am, that was
the last one you're gonna hear.
The Chicks' number-one hit
"Travelin' Soldier"
quickly fell from the top of the charts.
They had
the hottest song in the country.
All this stuff started, and it died.
We've never been a political band
and now we're thrown
into the middle of this
political whirlwind.
The radio station set up
these garbage cans
for people to come by
and throw out their CDs.
I liked them, you know,
but for what they said, it's trash.
They didn't only
whack "Traveling Soldier,"
they whacked all the play.
You've been really targeted
by a couple of groups out there.
I mean, you've been
really targeted.
American bombers
dropped a series
of 1000-lb bombs
on the compound.
Now who was the one
who talked about the war?
- Do you regret it?
- The thing is,
it wasn't even
a political statement.
It was a joke made
to get cheers and applause
and to entertain.
And it did.
But it didn't entertain America.
Some protestors
used a tractor and their feet
to smash the group's CDs.
Martie, have you
talked to Mom?
No. I left a message
and then I was sick all day
so I didn't call her again.
And I think that's all
she wants to hear from us--
is how much we know
it's affecting her.
The people who got it all started
was a right-wing group
called the Free Republic.
An extreme right-wing group
for their own political reasons
are attempting to manipulate
the American media,
and the American media
is falling for it.
The Free Republic
is very well organized.
There's definitely
a Free Republic hit list
with all of the radio stations
they're trying to affect.
And they are totally focused.
And the girls
are gonna get whacked.
Good morning.
61 Country.
They should send
Natalie over to Iraq,
strap her to a bomb
and just drop her over Baghdad.
A million things
have really pissed me off about it.
And I'm ready to go home
and set the record straight.
It's not about, necessarily,
our point of view.
The story's how out of hand
it's gotten, isn't it?
The-- the issue's not that--
what-- what has happened is
that the issue is not what was said.
It's how it's being reported
and how it's been turned
into something that it's not.
- It's snowballed.
- It's all about
you were not patriotic.
It's got
- nothing to do with what was said.
- We're not making excuses.
- We're not making excuses for beliefs.
- Because she didn't show support
- for the president.
- It doesn't matter--
- Support for the troops.
- It doesn't matter what was said.
- No, that's--
- But that's bullshit!
That's bullshit! Who has my statement?
They take what they want.
- Exactly!
- Correct. That's the point.
- I already said I'm patriotic.
- Absolutely.
- In my statement, I said I'm patriotic.
- Exactly.
In my statement,
- I said I support the troops.
- Exactly.
But I don't support the troops
and I'm not patriotic?
- Exactly, so...
- There you go.
- That's exactly it.
- That's it!
Look, hang on, let's start by looking
at some research,
because one of the things
that was very interesting
when Lipton brought
Michael's company in was--
Was Lipton about to pull out?
Uh, I think Lipton is concerned.
They are looking
for a reason to do it.
Everybody on the Lipton team
is saying, "Give us
a reason to go forward."
I think part of the reason that
they brought me to you guys
is to help you
manage through this,
because at the end of the day,
while you're great musicians,
you are a brand.
And if somehow your brand
is-- is-- now has
issues circulating around it,
you know, do they want
do take that sort of risk?
I-- I personally...
think we should
let Lipton off the hook,
saying, "We're backing out
because, you know,
we don't want
to hurt their product"
and that's it.
But that's a whole other story.
To me, that's-- that's what
- snowballs. We've been away.
- Right.
People have not been
able to see our faces,
hear our words. To me,
that is the greatest advantage
of doing an interview-- is that we--
I feel like we are endearing people.
- Absolutely.
- I feel like we will win people over
just by sitting there and looking--
saying honest things.
It's fine. I think this is better
for our career.
I think we've gotten more attention
than we ever were going to get.
We were never gonna be on the cover of
"Entertainment Weekly."
We were never gonna be interviewed
by Barbara Walters.
75% awareness?
We were never gonna have
these people...
It's insane.
...who never even knew who we were, care
to listen to our music, listen to it.
But hang on--
And that's fine. I think
when we apologize and we tell,
blah blah blah, then our fans--
and that will all be smoothed out
- and worked out. Do I believe--?
- I've got one thing--
- But I do think this could affect tea--
- Do it on your terms.
Don't-- you're
reacting to the reaction.
And all I'm saying is,
carry on as you want,
but do it on your terms.
I think people
are gonna say, "Oh my God!
What happened to them?"
- But they say "traitor," so...
- It's not we say about ourselves.
- It's what people have imposed on us.
- It's what you've been branded.
I-- I'm sorry.
I just-- I don't like--
that is going to be
so prominent on the cover
that my concern is
the average person isn't gonna get it.
They're gonna be horrified
when they see that.
It's not ridiculous
to call you opinionated.
to call you brave.
Like, we've got
to show how cruel--
It's not ridiculous
to call you a big mouth.
No, that's true.
Truth hurts.
This is a brilliant artistic shot,
but just to see "Dixie Sluts"--
- Jesus Christ!
- What?
You need something
to counterbalance it--
"Proud American." Yes, they've
been branded, but I don't think--
I think you're giving too much credit
to the American public.
They're not that smart.
I don't think the average
person's gonna get any of it.
Then we're fucked,
if that's the case.
Don't-- I-- I'm not--
I'm not gonna go there.
This is about fixing it.
Well, that racy magazine cover
on the stands today
pretty much sums up
some of the names
the Dixie Chicks
are being called
in America these days--
"Traitors," "The Dixie Sluts,"
"Anti-American"--
all because of one
split-second comment
aimed at President Bush
right before the war with Iraq.
Maines says she was
just trying to fire back
when she shot
herself in the foot.
She apologized to the president,
but it only added fuel to the fire.
We've analyzed
the way that Diane Sawyer
and Chris Willman-- what they've done
in previous interviews,
and we'll give you
some examples.
Uh, it's likely to start
- with a real hard punch.
- Absolutely. It will.
You know, what you said
and why you said it--
you know, you don't rehearse
what you say in between songs,
and sometimes
it doesn't come out
the way that you intend it.
I'm not saying I support
their commander-in-chief,
but I'll say
I support the troops.
That-- that's fine.
But try-- try not
to be judgmental
of the president.
I'll tell you why:
He's got sky-high approval.
The war couldn't
be going better.
By the time
this interview airs,
he's likely to be
at the highest point.
Remember,
this is two weeks out.
The looting will be done.
The rebuilding of Iraq will be started.
Saddam Hussein will most likely
be dead or found out.
It-- I'm just telling you,
two weeks from now
it's gonna be even
a more positive situation.
Are you ashamed that the President
of the United States
is from your state?
No, I'm not truly embarrassed
that, you know, President Bush
is from my state.
That's not really
what I care about.
It was the wrong wording.
Am I sorry
I said that? Yes.
Am I sorry I spoke out? No.
But you can't tell me
that at no point
the two of you,
however much you love her,
however much you
understand her--
that you didn't say,
"Why did she do that?
Why did she do that?"
Why can't you say that?
Partially why our audience
has allowed us to get
to where we are today
is because they like her
the way she is.
Hi. Rudy Blair, 680-News.
I guess I'm gonna
have to be the evil one on this one.
I gotta ask,
how have things been going
since this whole
Bush controversy?
How are things going
for you guys now?
Our album sales
are definitely down
and we don't get
played on the radio.
We heard they've turned
what happened to us into a verb.
You can get
"Dixie-Chicked."
And if we had to be
the example, that's fine.
We don't want this
to be our legacy.
We want
our music to be our legacy.
And one positive with that is
it's sort of opened the door for us
to do anything musically
that we wanna do now
without feeling any pressures
that we have to please,
because we don't really
have anyone to answer to,
as far as radio
is concerned.
Oh yeah, baby.
That's a nice touch.
Doing good. We moved out to LA
just for a little while,
just for Emily
to have the babies
and us to write
some music and stuff.
Well, first of all, I think
there should be some "we's," like...
That's hilarious.
- Wouldn't kiss all the asses...
- Oh-ho-ho!
...that they told me to.
Is that good?
Gave a lot of blowjobs,
but wouldn't kiss all the asses?
'Cause you did
kiss some ass.
That's good.
I don't know if I could sing that,
but if you could,
more power to ya.
What-- what about,
"I fought with a stranger"?
- Fought with a stranger, yeah.
- Kinda like the stranger is Bush.
- It's not--
- Good, Emmie, good!
Big money, big money!
I mean, we've never been able to write
a whole album of songs.
And when you're
writing so much,
you start noticing just things
in your everyday life
that are worthy of a song.
And almost anything
that isn't written by us,
now, at least on this album,
seems a little bit false almost.
This record is, like you said,
our therapy, in a way.
This is what we wanna say.
- That sounded great.
- Yeah, come in.
How do y'all--
do y'all all write your songs?
Yeah. I mean,
we'll just get in the room
and we'll just jam and improvise.
And something will start
from a drumbeat or a bass line...
Does everyone write equally
on everything?
- No.
- But you split writing equally?
- Yep.
- Wow.
I wouldn't feel right if I was...
The guy doing all the--
...you know, the bass
player or whatever--
I wouldn't feel right taking
writing credit or money.
But he's smart to
keep them happy, in a way,
because band members
tend to start resenting
the lead singer no matter what
- because they get more attention--
- Oh, really?
No.
- In male bands.
- Female players--
I mean, band members...
But you know, it can breed--
But that's why bands
break up, because...
I think so too--
...the members of the band
start resenting that...
But I'm saying he--
this band could break up
because the lead singer resents.
That's what I'm saying.
It's a chemistry thing,
you know.
Well, he could go solo.
That's the thing that the lead singer
could hang over
the band's head.
Yeah.
You know why she
picked up the banjo?
Because we all played violin,
and I started playing fiddle
and I was really jealous
of her playing the fiddle,
because whatever I would do,
she would do better--
- like sports, whatever.
- Yeah.
And so when she
would play the fiddle,
I'd go in and I'd, like, beat her
over the head with my fiddle.
So you drove her
to the banjo.
So mean. So I was like, "You have to
pick another instrument."
Wow.
I don't know
why she picked the banjo.
It worked out good.
It's a good combo.
Yeah.
Oh, she was just--
oh, just that little sister
that just-- anything you did,
she just had to one-up ya.
Check check.
Did we do as long an intro on the real
version as we did the demo? Okay.
- Should we try one?
- Yeah.
All right, here we go.
- That's incredible.
- Thanks.
Now this-- do you wanna
know what this is about?
- Sure.
- It's about Lubbock, Texas.
I remember there was the line
about the statue.
- And Buddy Holly.
- Yeah.
They hated him
when he was a star
and they thought he was
evil and rock 'n' roll and,
- you know...
- It's Natalie's hometown too.
- And they basically turned--
- Oh, Lubbock?
--the whole city basically
turned on her,
and all the radio stations
were horrible and...
It's like Buddy Holly all over again.
Seems much more
ordinary right off the bat.
Yep.
This line...
Good change.
In this chorus, the melody is good.
The chords
and the melody are strong.
Do you not like the words?
It's worth pursuing
even though you don't like it.
But I would rewrite
all the words.
I think-- I think
the pre-chorus and chorus,
musically and melodically,
are really strong.
I'm just missing
a connection to the lyrics.
Just rewrite--
rewrite 'em for yourself.
Yeah, easy for you to say.
You rewrite. No I'm kidding.
Then you won't
feel a connection.
I'm still a little confused.
I'm still having
a hard time hearing,
like, our role
in some of the songs.
Because at the end
of the day,
you know,
what's best for the song
has to be best for the song.
It can't be a forced--
"Let's slap some
fiddle on there
just because I play the fiddle,"
you know?
I-- I--
at this point,
I-- my interest
is just any way
we can get great songs,
from any direction.
And then we'll
put it through
whatever the Dixie Chicks'
filter is gonna become,
which we'll see.
It'll-- it's gonna reveal itself
- as we work on the songs.
- Mm-hmm.
See, I'm nothing but
a glorified lackey...
waiting on her hand and foot.
"I can't believe
she made me carry this..."
Oh, sorry.
Uh, was that solo too country?
I like the nut choices.
I don't know if that would be one
- but it was good.
- I was just kinda--
That one sort of weird thing you did--
I wish it was more of that.
All right. Got it.
But everything you're doing
is awesome.
Quit sucking up.
We did a demo tape for Natalie
for her to get into Berklee
School of Music up in Boston.
And I was playing a gig with the Chicks
in Dallas or somewhere,
and I just gave 'em
a cassette.
You know, it wasn't really pitching her
at all. It was just like, "Hey,
check this out.
It's my daughter."
I think it was about a year
before they even heard it.
I mean, they kind of left it
in their motor home--
the pink motor home
that you hear about.
But, apparently, Martie and Emily must
have kept it in the back of their minds,
and when they decided to change
lead singers,
they called about Natalie.
That was an incredible
song, man.
Oh, good.
You just blew everybody
else off the record.
I was barely trying.
I met the Chicks in 1994.
There they were,
and they had their hair really big,
and they had
the hoop dresses on
and the spangles
and the cowboy hats.
And they went on stage
and they performed these songs
which were pretty bad--
basically, Western swing,
very old-fashioned,
very not contemporary.
But the one thing
that was very very clear
was that they were
three beautiful girls,
and incredibly talented,
and they could really play.
And if they had a willingness
to kind of like change direction,
moving more into a contemporary
country music space,
there actually could be a really
interesting slot for them.
We had to go out,
we had to find the right material
and we had to develop it
into something new.
But anytime
the girls say to me,
"You know what, Simon?
We can't believe
that you booked us here.
How could you have
let that happen?"
I go, "How could I
have let that happen?
Just remember
who booked this show"--
oh, yes.
This is 1996.
This is the Pillsbury Bake-Off.
And that's in the--
which department is this in?
Oh, that's the produce
department they're playing in--
a fantastic booking,
one that I had nothing to do with.
The girls handled this
all by themselves.
Could it be something about
maybe the fear of
losing that one person
that you know you can go to,
and sort of your salvation,
or your sanity?
- Oh, hi!
- Hi!
I missed you!
I missed you.
He looks so big.
I haven't seen you in so long.
You look so different.
You look like more of a boy.
You look like you've been eating
nothing but ribs and Cheetos with Dada.
Gussie, what's in Mommy's belly?
What's in Mom--
What's in Mommy's tummy?
- Whales.
- Two of 'em!
- Whales!
No, Mommy's as big as a whale.
Take it-- yeah, I'm--
he calls me "Shamu."
Is there a baby in there?
Are there babies--
are there babies in there?
- What about babies?
I love you.
- So how you feeling?
- Uh, just ready.
- Soon.
- Very ready.
All right, guys.
This is-- whoo!
- There.
- Scariness.
Let's go peek.
I think--
obviously, before we got married,
we knew we wanted children.
But then, you know, all of a sudden,
we start trying,
and nothing's happening.
You know, you start to get
a little nervous.
It was about two and a half years
of just nothing,
and going through
fertility treatments--
everything from
artificial insemination
all the way to what eventually
ended up being in vitro.
Tell me if something hurts.
- Does that work?
- Sorry, I went to the wrong note.
My sister and I both
went through in vitro.
Emily started trying
first and,
oh, I watched her do it all.
And it just went on and on.
It's an expensive process.
It's hard on your body
with all the hormones,
all the injections.
You have to take a lot of drugs
and alter your cycle,
alter your chemistry
in a lot of ways.
- And it's a huge deal.
- Yeah, but we just assumed
that we would get pregnant
straightaway.
- We were like, "Okay..."
- Yeah,
but when Emily started having problems,
I started thinking
it could happen to us.
But we were
very lucky, very fortunate.
We just did in vitro
and it worked.
Hi!
We knew there was a 30% chance
of having twins.
We went in
and he did the sonogram and,
just very nonchalant and calm,
just goes,
"Well, there's the heartbeat."
And we were all excited.
And then he moved it over and said,
"And there's the other one."
And Gareth and I
just... screamed.
He said,
"Don't scream, don't scream,"
like I was gonna
hurt the baby.
Okay, how's she feeling?
She's comfortable.
She's had her epidural.
And her contractions are moving,
you know, slowly along.
There's not much progression.
- There's not much going on.
- Does she want magazines?
Does she have the "US Weekly"
with Brad and Angelina?
They're on.
Oh, there's you. I was like,
"God, that looks like Natalie."
Ew, I was hoping
that didn't wind up...
Why? You look good.
And Emily looks
skinnier than me.
Emily could use a little eye makeup.
I could use a lot of everything.
Oh, ew!
Ew!
Look how big my boobs look.
They've done something.
- Bill Maher's tomorrow night, right?
- Yep.
But Bill Maher has been
pissing me off.
- I know. He is so--
- Unfortunately,
I agree with him.
I'd rather--
- See, I don't.
- I'd rather it go well in Iraq
and then they be right...
No, I know that,
but let's back up
to "We should not be there."
Of course, now that we're there--
yes, make the best of it.
But we should not be there.
It was still such lies
and bullshit.
She's having a baby, by the way.
The kids are, like, listening
to what we're talking about.
It's like, "I ain't fucking
going out there."
Oh...
Oh, two of 'em.
What am I gonna do with two?
Sore nipples are on the way.
They are so beautiful.
Say, "We squeezed before,
we can squeeze again," right?
I think now that we're
making music again,
I'd really be sad
if this didn't have--
- if it didn't get heard...
- An audience.
...and we couldn't continue our careers
effortlessly as we have in the past.
I mean, it's just been
a way of life, part of our life.
Emily and I started in a band
when we were very young.
I started when I was 12,
and then she joined the band I was in
when she was 10.
And the Dixie Chicks started
in 1989.
I mean, this is
more than just a job.
This is a lifestyle.
It's-- it's part of our lives.
So I think-- just recently
I've thought,
"God, I just really hope we can
get our career back on track.
'Cause I need it."
I thought it was probably
a good idea
for us to start
talking about
what a schedule might look like
for the next couple of years.
What's your strategy on,
like, wooing MTV
and VH1 and...?
VH1 will-- VH1 will gladly
air your videos.
MTV's not your--
you're outside--
you're too old for
where MTV is at.
We're too old?
You're just too old.
Even if we get cool,
we're too old already?
You're still too old already.
Can't I-- can't I sort of
lead them?
- I'm not old yet.
- Hey, you're 30 now.
- You're in the same bracket.
- You're too old.
Shit.
To be honest with you,
I'm not sure yet
what method we're using
to get music out there.
- I mean, the traditional--
- You don't want a single
- before the end of the year?
- Well, the traditional method is--
is you take a cut off the album
and you service it to radio.
Right? But we've got to
assume right now
that, you know, we're not dealing
with the country format.
I think you still
let Sony do what they want there.
- We just aren't involved.
- I don't. I don't.
You release the single;
they play it;
the campaign starts up again--
"I'm never listening
to your station";
it's plummets to
"We want that"
before our album comes out.
I didn't mean for us to do anything
for country. I just thought--
I am just not willing
to work country radio
because I think it's
gonna be a huge disaster.
- And we shouldn't.
- I don't think we should, either.
But having said that,
if country radio embraced it
and turned around,
and all of a sudden
you're sitting in number one
on country radio,
I think it would be crazy
not to go back and go,
- "We're glad you like the new record."
- Water under the bridge.
So we're all gonna be
friends again now.
We're gonna have to deal
with some more redneck bullshit.
But I think it's at a point
where you cannot go back
and put yourself
in the crosshairs.
Be proud of your
country. Be ashamed of the Dixie Chicks.
The controversy from the
country music world has landed tonight.
The Dixie Chicks
launched the US leg
of their "Top of the World" tour
in Greenville, South Carolina.
They're ignorant, and they don't
know what they're talking about.
If you support the Dixie Chicks,
you're supporting communism.
You're supporting traitors.
We're tired
of the anti-American voices.
of the antiwar voices.
Tickets for the Dixie Chicks
concert went on sale months ago.
We did buy the tickets
before they said these things.
We couldn't get our money back,
so that's why we're here.
But these South Carolina fans
had no idea
that the show they were paying to see
would end up becoming
much more than a concert.
I think we in South Carolina ought
to say goodbye to the Dixie Chicks,
and anybody going to that concert
ought to be ready to run away from it.
God Bless GW!
When Natalie Maines made
her comments on the eve of war,
most of us recognized
that was reprehensible.
It hurt our men fighting overseas
who think their cause is just.
Is this a matter
of free speech or bad manners?
Their opinion is so ignorant.
They don't know what
they're talking about.
I think they are the Ditzy Twits.
These are the dumbest,
dumbest bimbos, with due respect,
I have seen...
These are callow, foolish women
who deserved to be slapped around.
Absolutely.
The Bi-Lo Center is working
with Greenville police
to provide extra security
surrounding the Dixie Chicks concert.
Sit.
Bomb-sniffing dog.
I mean, the Dixie Chicks
are free to speak their mind.
They can say what
they want to say.
And just because-- they shouldn't
have their feelings hurt just because
some people don't wanna buy
their records when they speak out.
You know,
freedom is a two-way street.
"They shouldn't have
their feelings hurt"?
What a dumb fuck.
You're a dumb fuck.
Of course, everyone anxious
to find out here what happens
when the Dixie Chicks go before
a live audience for the first time.
14,000 Dixie Chicks fans
ready to go.
It feels real good.
Deafening cheers and a standing ovation
greeted the Dixie Chicks as they
opened their first US tour
since Maines made her
controversial comment.
The down-home greeting came
just as President Bush
addressed the nation
aboard the USS Lincoln.
America is grateful
for a job well done.
They said you might not come,
but we knew you'd come.
Because we have the greatest fans
in the whole world.
Oh wait, I hear some boos.
We have a plan for this.
If you're hearing a boo,
we welcome that...
because we welcome
freedom of speech.
So we're gonna give you
15 seconds
to get whatever you have out.
So here we go,
on the count of three,
you can start your booing.
One, two, three.
- Ladies...
- Was there boos at the end?
...that was fucking brilliant.
- It was. It felt like...
- Oh, it was brilliant.
Oh, that was brilliant.
All the media people
are just like, "Oh--" I mean--
- Simon, you're our manager. Shut up.
- Okay. Sorry.
This sucked, actually.
It was really fucking lame.
Whoo!
Cheers, you guys.
So being the pain in the ass
that I am,
we've gotta do a little
radio thing now,
- so...
- Aw, come on!
But what made it tough
was it wasn't your normal call,
"I wish you wouldn't play that song,"
or "I don't really like what you did."
It was, "I will never listen
to you again.
I will drive to the station.
I will," you know,
short of threats, to us,
it was like, "I will never
listen again." That was just weird.
We have this audience,
and we wave
that country flag all the time,
defend country music,
and in an instant,
they turned
their backs on us.
No, I mean, you being the biggest
ambassadors for country radio.
No bullshit, how do
you all feel about country radio?
The people who abandoned us,
I'll never talk to them again.
And the people who've
supported us are gonna
get more love
than they've ever seen.
Can you say, "Hi"?
Say "Aghhh!"
- Sneak attack!
- Aggh! You scared me.
Freedom of speech is fine,
but by God, you don't do it outside
of the country, and you don't
do it in mass public place.
"Being ashamed of our president
means being ashamed
of our country.
Move to France, Dixie Chicks."
Screw 'em!
Right? Say it.
Did Simon tell you all
the American Red Cross
wouldn't take a million dollars
from us?
Well, you do know
that George W Bush
is the honorary chairman.
This whole week they didn't play us.
- This whole week they didn't play us.
- That's one song.
- No one boycotted you.
- This is a boycott.
- That one did.
- That is not a boycott.
How is it not a boycott? They haven't
been playing our music for a few weeks.
A boycott is when someone says,
"We are not playing--"
Simon, actions speak louder
than words.
What's the difference?
You tell me the difference.
All I know is all these radio stations,
they pretend to support 'em,
but they won't play 'em.
We call and ask, and they won't.
No other artist that we play
on the radio
would get the kind of hate mail
and complaint calls,
and "I'm never listening to you again.
I'm never doing business with you."
No one gets that. I could probably put
Marilyn Manson on the radio station
and not get that kind
of negative feedback,
even though we're
a country station.
These people
haven't "boycotted" us,
but they haven't been playing
our song
and are partially responsible
for our number-one single to plummet.
I'm just trying to find
some medium ground here.
- Ignore it.
- It's up to them to do the right thing.
We have not done anything wrong,
and there's nothing
- for us to climb back from.
- I agree.
- Where are our record sales?
- Near the shitter.
- How much?
- Right now you're down to 56
on the top 200.
But yet--
- Is that the lowest ever?
- Yeah.
I think time's
the greatest healer of all.
Listen, they'll give Tracy Lawrence,
who's a wife beater, another shot.
I don't want another shot.
Until the mood of our
audience changes,
we're not going
to play them anymore.
It'd simply be financial suicide.
Keep playing, keep making music.
And keep your mouth shut.
Now that we've, you know,
fucked ourselves anyway,
I think we have a responsibility
to continue to fuck ourselves.
I am so-- I just-- the rest of our
career just better not be overanalyzed
like this because of this
one episode.
USA! USA!
USA!
I almost started crying
out there tonight.
Why?
All these people
in this huge arena,
and I thought,
are we ever gonna be
at this level again?
It made me so sad.
I thought,
"Is this the top,
you know, and everything's
downhill from here?"
Today's country, KJ97.
Good morning.
It's Randy Carroll and Pam Tyler.
It's 8:54.
Their career is a lot bigger
than the country music core.
Now as a radio station,
we can't afford
to lose the country music core.
As entertainers,
they obviously feel like they can,
and I think that's probably the thing
that bugs me the most
about the whole thing--
not so much what they say,
but in the things that they've said.
And several different things,
not just the comment
about the president,
but some of the things that
they said about Toby Keith's music
and about him
and people that believe that way
shows a real contempt
for what a whole lot
of country-music listeners
believe.
I just have a quick question regarding
things that have been happening
with Toby Keith lately.
He was in town a couple of weeks ago
with a little bit of a video
poking fun at you.
What are you thoughts on that?
Is it all just in fun,
or is there any seriousness
to what's going on?
It's not in fun for me.
I don't appreciate
what he does in his show
with my picture,
and he has not been banned for that.
You have had a famous feud,
and does it bother you
that you are sometimes linked
with this simple-minded redneck?
And by that, I mean George Bush.
You're getting us in a lot
of trouble, Bill.
- I don't think we can get in more.
- What is the status of that feud?
You don't mind if I wear a shirt
that says "Fuck Toby Keith"?
I think it's cool.
I bet you $1,000 that you
won't wear a T-shirt that says,
"Fuck you, Toby Keith"
in three-inch--
I should wear a T-shirt
that says "I love Toby."
"I love TK."
"FCTK."
Ooooh!
- What is that?
- FUTK.
What does that mean?
Fuck you, Toby Keith.
And then when people ask
about it, what's the line?
Use your imagination.
It means something different
to everyone.
I'm gonna do that.
That's so safe.
Fans United Together
in Kindness.
Personally, I wish they
would just shut up and sing.
About the time
things start dying down,
somebody else says
something stupid
and gets everybody
all riled up again.
Dixie Chicks rule!
Fuck you, T.K.!
F.U.T.K.!
My shirt means "Freedom,
Unity, Truth, Knowledge."
Oh sure, it says "FUDC." You can infer
whatever you want from that.
I don't know what it means.
I'd say it's "Freedom
for the United States
which is a Democratic Country."
You see that person
shaking their sign with so much energy
- that said "FUDC"?
- Yeah.
- You should have said--
- I almost said--
"Hey, that's not nice
of you, crowd."
"We love you all's signs, but what
do you have against Dick Cheney?"
The Committee
continues its series of hearings
examining media ownership
by returning to the topic
that started it all-- radio.
As a result of statements made
by members of the Dixie Chicks
at a concert,
two radio networks--
Cox and Cumulus--
banned the Dixie Chicks
from their playlist at a chain level.
Mr. Chairman, first of all,
Mr. Renshaw refers to our
radio companies as networks
and we are not networks.
We are a confederation of 270
individual stations in 55 cities--
You made a decision
from corporate headquarters
that was binding on--
on your DJs.
- Mr. Chairman--
- And just prior to that,
you said that you are a group
of independent radio stations.
See, that's a total contradiction,
Mr. Dickey.
I think that mischaracterizes it.
As I mentioned,
this was a collaborative
decision-making process.
Everybody fell in line.
This was not--
this was a unanimous
overwhelming decision.
"Fell in line,"
I understand this.
Do you think what you did
sent any type of a chilling message
to people
that they oughta shut up...
and not express their views
one way or other?
- I would hope not.
- Okay.
Let me conclude--
Mr. Renshaw, do you think
that program directors
ever have the right to select
the programming
based on the actions,
activities
or public statements
of the entertainers?
I believe that they have the right
to make the decisions
about whether they do play something
or they don't play something.
But I think that what we were seeing
that was going on at the time
was people were
making decisions
in a politically-censuring mode,
despite what everyone says.
Not very many managers
would be so brave.
They had-- they had unwittingly
entered into the world of politics.
It just seems to
me that when people get into politics,
even if they're entertainers,
it has consequences.
She made a decision,
politically, to speak.
It had a business
consequence to her.
And I think entertainers,
increasingly after this conflict,
are now recognizing
that their involvement in politics
does have a political fallout
in terms of business to them.
Oooh, did you see that?
If we give VH1-- if we're
doing the VH1 thing,
and we give them the remixed
version of "Top of the World"--
- Yes.
- Can we give CMT
simultaneously
- the country version?
- Why are we beating a dead horse?
- CMT viewers, I don't think, want--
- Well, that's--
I don't think we should penalize--
if they want to try--
penalize CMT when they have
done nothing but stand by us.
I don't want to be in a market and
industry that doesn't want us right now.
I just feel like...
"Let country music rest."
- Just not wanting to go--
- We're not going to the CMAs.
- We're not--
- You're not?!
So, uh--
You mean we can't-- uh...
So I'm just gonna tell them,
"No, pass. Forget it. We're over it.
- See you in a couple of years."
- Maybe.
Well, "Whether you like it or not
is gonna be irrelevant,
but we'll see you
in a couple of years with something."
- Maybe.
- You may never make another record?
- It may not be a country record.
- Oh, I know that.
- It works--
- It could be.
I'm assuming
that it-- that--
I'm assuming there will be
another record at some point. All right.
Yeah, but they're not--
anyway, we can argue about it
- in two years.
- Yes, oh yeah.
Here we go.
I'm probably
totally outnumbered,
but I think this is a country record
in a lot of ways.
Knowing country
through and through
because that's what I listened to,
you know, most of my life,
I don't think this is that far...
- I don't think so.
- ...from country
There are songs like "Lubbock"
where it's hardly kind of country,
but it's kind of like--
I don't know,
I really haven't heard
a band that sounds like that.
The last thing I wanted to do
was for Rick to come in
and say, "Okay,
we're making a rock record."
That would've scared
the crap out of me.
He hears something different,
Natalie hears something different,
Emily hears something different,
I hear something different,
but to me this is reminiscent
of the country I grew up on
which is why I love it.
I feel like
I just decompress
the second I go through the gate.
It's just like I can just relax,
you know?
Being on the road's one thing,
but LA is a whole other thing.
It's just not my cup of tea.
I don't understand
how people can live
in a place like Los Angeles.
When I'm out there visiting her,
I'm just pissed off the whole time.
He is-- he's literally pissed off
the whole time. I'm like, "Go home."
I've always been able
to separate work and family
and I've never had to do that
as long as I have this time
with this project, you know?
I've never had to relocate.
It was a hard year.
You know, being split up like that,
especially, you know--
with our son being two and a half.
Yeah, he'd get to fly back
and be with Dad for a week,
but for a two-and-a-half-year-old
to conceptualize,
"Why aren't you together?"
That was really hard.
Hey, Mommy.
Stop.
- He's pretty good.
- Gimme.
- Got him!
- Shoot.
Dance in circles,
do your hands--
Where's jazz hands?
I don't know
too many women who get to bring
their husband
and two children to work.
Yummy yummy?
I'm so lucky. My husband
travels everywhere with me.
He's like a Mr. Mom
and he loves being a dad
- and travels on every tour.
- I love being there for her
when she comes in in the evening
from the studio.
You know, the babies
are there and I'm there.
Dinner's on the table--
sometimes.
And uh, you know,
it's-- it's good.
It really is, it's great.
No matter where we are, as long as
we're together, I feel like we're home.
Happy Halloween.
- I don't want it, I don't want it.
- We'll do it loose.
- Huh-uh, huh-uh.
- Do it. Watch.
If you don't like it,
we'll take it off.
Trust me, man.
I have to wear one all the time.
You know, Daddy plays lawyers.
It's all I do.
Look at me--
do I look like a lawyer?
It's the tie--
it fools everyone.
Aw, it's so cute though.
Girls are suckers for boys in ties.
- I don't want my tie.
- Hey, you know what, buddy?
I don't blame you.
Ties suck.
Who wants to tie a noose
around their neck?
This is basically like this.
So in corporate America you go,
"Come on. Let's go. Come on.
Come on, come on. Another couple
hundred million dollars.
Come on, come on." This is how
they walk around the halls at Exxon.
Just like this. Come on, let's go,
come on, chop-chop.
Okay, so I don't blame you.
You don't have to wear it.
What else do we need?
Oh!
You're beautiful.
Look at Kathleen.
Beautiful.
I think we're ready.
- Happy Halloween!
- Hey, you ready, Harry?
- This.
- Mama, look, a graveyard.
I know.
Look at that scary guy.
Where is Kathleen?
- Ta-dah!
- Dah!
I feel like I've aged
five years
since I had my twins.
I just look in the mirror
and think I look so old,
and the other morning
I was so tired.
When you're just so tired, you'd give
anything not to have to get up.
I offered Adrian a thousand bucks to get
up once, and he didn't do it.
A thousand...
I was like,
"I'll give you $1000."
I was so serious.
What does that mean
to the person you're married to, though?
What's it mean
that he didn't get up?
In our world,
okay, we give you a blowjob.
"All right, you have to give me a
blowjob." I was like, "No, I'll do it."
"I'll get up.
Never mind.
You drive a hard bargain."
We need to find
a way of introducing people
to the new sound on the new album,
and I think we go out
and we do four shows.
I think we should go
and play in LA,
New York, Chicago and Austin.
It would be more industry?
It would be more industry, fans.
That's too soon, Simon.
And especially for industry people,
I don't think our first time performing
these songs need to be in front
of industry people
while we're still feeling out
how we are gonna--
- How are we gonna do that?
- --move and look.
If you want it to be really good,
all we have to do is start early enough
to make it good, so I don't understand
what your problem is.
I don't think we're being
cautious enough.
I think it should be
very calculated.
I feel like we're treating this
like every other record,
and we all agreed that
that is not the way
this needed to be treated.
It scares me.
There's a lot of people out there
who already have their minds made up.
- It doesn't matter.
- What's that gotta do--
We have never gone into a record
being judged the way
we are gonna be judged
this time. Never.
After the comment,
when we got all the criticism,
it was just a really scary time.
It was just wrong what happened,
not only to us,
but other people that were,
you know, shut up
or made to feel threatened
for feeling a certain way,
you know, about the war or whatever.
Everything was so bizarre,
it was almost humorous.
I just could not believe
people cared what I said.
But it had to be somebody
or some group
that seemed like
the all-American girls.
It was perfect.
It had to be
the unlikely voice
from what looked like
the conservative heart
of America saying it.
That was perfect.
To me, it was something
really just an episode,
and okay, we're gonna lose
some record sales,
and it's more important
to stand up for what's right,
and be a strong unit together
and support each other.
But then when the death threat came,
I thought,
"Okay, this is different league.
It's a totally different league."
Thank you, Los Angeles!
That was the envelope tonight.
It says, "Natalie Maines will be
shot dead Sunday, July 6th,
in Dallas, Texas."
- You know the Dallas threat?
- Yeah.
They have a guy, the police have,
reason to believe he might be the guy.
- Really?
- Because he's made other threats
against senators
in the same way--
Can they make sure
he's nowhere near Dallas?
I'm gonna have a policeman on him
for the whole time we're in Dallas,
and outside his house, and just so
they're always on him the whole time.
They think this is the person.
God.
The handwriting sort of matches.
The FBI had some intelligence
on this guy
with some other threats,
possibly to you guys,
but they didn't share it to anybody.
We're trying to get
more info on it,
but we're gonna have people
watching him during the show.
He's kind of cute.
He is.
He's a good-looking guy.
The hairspray's got you.
When we start Texas,
we're in serious danger territory.
So get your shit together
because--
It's very scary.
As I said, we're making
some changes with security.
This should be
a Texas Rangers issue.
No one fucks
with the Texas Rangers.
Do you think the National Guard
should be in Dallas?
The National Guard?
What, like tanks?
Armored personnel carriers?
- Like they do at the airports.
- Inside the building?
Keeping an eye
on the section?
If I was a person bringing
a gun into a show,
I'd bring the smallest
possible gun
and probably put it
in my crotch
because nobody is gonna feel
somebody's crotch up.
I wouldn't.
I'd put it up in my ankle.
- They wand your feet.
- They don't get down that far.
And you expect us
to want to play a show in Dallas
and you're telling us
they don't feel people's legs.
They can't touch people.
They cannot touch people.
Okay then, at Dallas
we have metal detectors.
I know how vulnerable I feel.
I can't imagine how Natalie feels.
Standing up there,
you feel so naked.
So naked.
Hello.
The last thing I said to Charlie was...
"I'll call you tonight
if I don't get shot."
Oh!
Say, 6:30,
we walk out the door at 6:45
and we fly in,
and then when we land,
the cops are gonna take us
right to the stage.
There's never any time where
we're stopped inside the venue.
Hi, Asvia, this is Natalie Pasdar.
You gave me a reading
about a year ago, probably.
I just wanna know
if you feel like
I'm in any danger
or if I'm safe.
So please give me a call.
Thank you, bye.
Be right there.
Come in, Mindi.
I'm not expecting to look at anybody
before we walk out of the room
and say, "Is it clear?"
I'm just expecting it to be clear.
And I want someone in front of me
when we're walking, and I want
someone to be sitting there
waiting for us
when we get there.
Number two check.
I had proposed a song idea
to them called "Undivided,"
'cause I thought that people were
being divided by politics
and being like,
"Okay, you have to be on this side,
and you have to be on this side. Now you
all go ahead and hate each other."
And be about also how the girls
have dealt with controversy.
Instead of being divided
and conquered,
they stuck together.
Natalie thought about it for a second.
Then she said,
"Well, does that mean
that in the song I would have
to forgive the people
who did all that to us?"
And I said, "Maybe it would
for the song. Maybe it would."
And she went, "Nope."
That's just the most
emotional song on the record for me.
It took about, I'd say,
a hundred listens
before I didn't get choked up,
literally, just every time I play it
for somebody,
or heard it in the car
or whatever,
it made me realize how raw
the emotions still were.
The Dixie Chicks may soon
cause a stir with lyrics
from their upcoming album.
This single
"Not Ready to Make Nice"
is not big on the radio,
and is really not big
on country radio.
The Dixie Chicks have all
but challenged
country music stations
to stop playing their music.
Joanne's e-mail this morning
was the south of the Mason-Dixon Line.
We have no one
other than one station--
So lose a few.
Miami, LA and Knoxville.
At least the album's
fucking delivered.
Mind your step, ladies. I know you're
having fun, but mind your step, please.
So, girls, one thing that did
come up today in my meeting with Sony,
the big concern
that they have is
we really don't know
what's gonna happen on radio.
They wanna have us doing
as much TV
as we can get done.
So let me throw out some TV ideas
and get some feedback
from you:
"The View," if it was
just an interview
with Barbara Walters,
and if we went in
and we did the production as opposed
to "The View" doing the production.
"Regis and"--
Kelly?
Now tell us, first, with each show
what's the mandatory performance?
Okay, can I just throw
this out there?
Why can't we...
can we decide what kind of artists
we want to be right now?
Sure.
Can we be the Bruce Springsteen
and the Bob Dylan--
not that I'm comparing our music
and ourselves to them--
but do we have to be
on everything
that they'll let us be on?
I just don't care.
Here's what everyone
is wrestling with.
You are the biggest-selling group in
North America in the last eight years.
No one has sold, combined,
more records than you have.
I don't give a shit what Sony wants
We know what Sony wants-- money.
We've always been a cash cow.
They're worried we're not gonna be that.
I think what
they're wrestling with
is they're wrestling
with expectations.
They look at you
as the act that they expect
to drive more sales with
than any other band on Columbia
releasing an album this year.
Hey, Natalie, Natalie.
I read that you all
felt like this album was
a rebirth or kind of like
starting over.
Everything seems like
the first time again.
- We knew it had to be personal.
- It feels really good.
As we expected,
Dixie Chicks album debuted
at number one on the Billboard 200
and on our country albums chart as well.
Everybody is talking
about the Dixie Chicks.
They're right there
on the cover of "Time" magazine.
Does it still surprise you
what went down?
The biggest surprise to me
was how many people were terrified
to even be associated with us.
Public opinion has changed
so much in the last three years.
Bush's approval rating is kind of down.
Does that impact on you?
We just made the album we'd--
not even wanted to make,
but needed to make.
The new poll is certainly
a blow for the president,
showing a public fed up with the war
and his handling of it.
Tonight questions about
claims the president
and members of his administration
made in 2003.
There are a lot of legitimate
questions about this president,
how he misled the public on the issue
of weapons of mass destruction.
We did not find the weapons
of mass destruction
and that's raised questions
about whether the sacrifice
in Iraq has been worth it.
59% call the war
in Iraq a mistake.
Why did you lie to get us
into a war that was not necessary
and that has caused
these kinds of casualties?
As we mentioned earlier,
the number of US deaths has hit 2500,
and so far, 18,490 troops
have been wounded.
The president has
completely blown it with this war.
I am sorry about what I said,
I'll tell you the truth.
'Cause they took a very bold
and brave stand.
You guys were absolutely right.
Right now you're not wearing panties.
- Is that a political thing?
- Is that a Dixie Chick thing?
I won't wear panties
until the war is over.
They got a number-one-selling album
and didn't have to depend
on radio to do it.
Does it matter to you
how this album does?
I'm more scared about
if the tour will sell
- than the records.
- Yeah, than buy the album.
No matter what,
we will always make music,
but there's a certain energy
and just that adrenaline
when you go out onstage
and you have those fans
that are there. The live show,
for me, is the-- is the total payoff.
When you have seven kids,
you can't go back to the RV.
You can't--
you can't pile everybody in and,
you know, go play small clubs.
I won't go out without my family.
And so I think
you have to maintain
a certain level of touring.
So, you know, to me that's--
that'll be the measure of success.
Arenas or nothing.
There's a whole
new deal that's been proposed.
AG will make an offer
for the entire tour.
The guarantee is basically $26 million,
versus a 90-10 deal.
You keep saying the word
"risk-- we're covering our risk."
What it comes down to is
if we want to take that risk.
- Absolutely.
- Maybe I'm bass-ackwards here,
but I would rather know
that we took the risk
and had faith
and lose out on money
than to do what I think
it's gonna do and sell out
and have that feeling of "Why didn't we
fucking have confidence in ourselves?"
You know what? If we're
gonna have this conversation,
we should involve Al in it, and we
should just look at the economics.
You're not
gonna sell out in Nashville,
you won't sell out in Memphis,
you won't sell out in Oklahoma City.
Now, I mean, we can lose
money really quick.
I know we can.
Here was an option
for you to hedge your bet.
If you don't wanna hedge,
- you don't wanna hedge.
- I am-- I am saying I get all of this.
I'm totally
with Natalie.
- And it's--
- And as hard--
as hard as you think it is for us
to work, it'll be harder for me to work
with a tour that sold out
in two fucking days
and I didn't bet on myself
when I knew I should
and I'm taking--
and it's not even about the money!
I'll be pissed at myself.
That will make me unhappy.
It's almost like if you don't sell it
and you took a gamble on yourself
just like how--
it lights a fire.
It makes you fight.
- Just like--
- I'm not--
I mean, they love the--
listen, I love the fucking attitude.
- Bring it on!
- Nat, don't get me--
Isn't that what Bush said?
"Bring it on!" Exactly.
Listen, and you and Al
are either with us or against us.
Unfortunately, we're with you.
- Whether you like it or not.
- Whether we like it or not,
we're in.
Okay, according to Ticketmaster,
time-- one minute away
from the on-sale start.
- Good morning.
- Okay. Ah...
- Philadelphia...
- Okay.
...sold, 69; open, 7942.
Toronto?
Simon, uh...
- Toronto needs to roll right now.
- That's too bad.
Can you roll Toronto
to the second show?
Definitely.
I will send it off right now.
Thank you.
Philadelphia, pull back.
Pull back, Atlanta.
So don't roll any of them
with the exception of Toronto.
Really?
Okay, bye-bye.
So we rolled Toronto.
What else is happening?
Toronto rolled right out.
The other ones--
you still had open seats.
- It's the South.
- Atlanta is definitely slow.
This is not good.
I mean, I hate to throw
a dose of reality on this.
- I don't disagree with you.
- Even in Boston--
those aren't good counts.
We've gotta be honest with each other,
- they're not good counts.
- No.
Can I throw
a radical idea out here?
Do we take Milwaukee, KC,
Saint Louis, Indy, Des Moines,
literally move them back
into October
and try to just slam Canada
in-out of Chicago and Minnie
and go spend our time
up in Canada?
That's a great idea, I think.
'Cause Canada seems
to be really strong.
I'm talking about playing
Kamloops, Moose Jaw--
everywhere there's a hockey arena,
let's go play.
- Moose Jaw.
- Yeah, there's a town called Moose Jaw.
- And it's got a hockey arena?
- Yeah.
And that's where we're at.
We are not selling to country right now.
- We are selling to a new audience.
- Well, we're not-- yeah.
We're a new band.
And the next tour we do,
if this record is a hit
to the new audience,
we're back playing-- that's where
we're rebuilding a career
with a whole new-- it's a new band
and a new audience.
It feels like
we've been beat up
and then we've been pushed
back in the ring.
It's just emotionally draining
and-- and--
And the tour,
I think it's the first...
non-success we've had.
People ask
about sluggish tickets...
there's no denying
we have sluggish tickets.
I'm not-- and I'm not
embarrassed by that.
So I don't feel the need
to put a spin on it.
But I think it had gotten to the point
where it was just kind of scary--
when the ticket sales
were sluggish--
that we had committed
to a lot of people.
You know, these people depended on us
for the next six months of their lives.
It's a huge burden and,
at the same time, it's a lot of stress.
We know everyone's been hearing
a lot of rumors about the tour...
what's happening,
and we just wanted
to settle all the rumors,
just saying that we will be starting
the tour on the 21st of July as planned.
Oh-oh--
we did want to say though
we are having to cut corners
in places and meat's expensive
and y'all drink a lot of beers
so both of those are off.
If you gauge your career
by how many people buy
your albums or are at the concert,
I don't think we'll ever be
in that place again.
But, you know,
it's giving us this fire back.
I don't know, there's just
something to say for--
having that back,
that want to...
garner new fans,
or uh...
just prove yourself
all over again.
I think Natalie still feels
pressure about what's happened,
even though we say
over and over and over again,
"It was the best thing"-- I can tell her
that and shake her all day long.
"It's the best thing that ever
happened to me. It's the best thing
that ever happened
to our career.
We'd never change it.
You're fine.
You didn't do anything."
And I just think she still--
she still, um...
feels responsible.
And if she came to me
tomorrow and said,
"I don't want to tour.
I don't want to record anymore.
I don't want to do this,"
I care for her. I'd say, "Okay."
I'd give up my career...
for her to be happy,
be at peace.
It's great to be back
at Shepherds Bush.
The return to the scene
of the crime.
And all week, the only thing
people keep asking is,
"What are you gonna say?
Do you know what you're gonna say?"
As usual,
I didn't plan anything,
but I thought I'd say
something brand new
and just say,
"Just so you know,
we're ashamed the President
of the United States is from Texas."
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com