Like so many epidemics before,
the loss of so many lives began
with a single microscopic organism.
It's human nature to seek even
the smallest comfort in reason
or logic for events
as catastrophic as these.
But a virus doesn't
choose a time or place.
It doesn't hate or even care.
It just happens.
Go back to your homes!
The Reaper virus spread among
the population of Glasgow
like a common cold.
There was no stopping it.
- No cure.
- No vaccine.
It claimed the lives of thousands in the
first week. This is the end of the world!
In an attempt to quell the outbreak,
martial law was implemented.
Roadblocks set up. Come on, darling.
Curfews enforced. We have to walk now.
The airports, seaports
and borders were closed.
Scotland was placed
under quarantine.
The people were ordered to stay in their
homes, to avoid travel, avoid contact,
to sit it out and wait
for help that did not come.
Stay back!
You got to let us through!
Get out of the way! Move! Move!
Get out of the way! Walk on, will you?
Hey, you! You! I am talking at you!
Get down on the floor now! Everybody, down!
Don't shoot!
You fucker!
Fall back! Fall back!
Get out of the way!
Please let us go!
Onward!
Are you all right?
You bastard!
Look at me, darling.
Look at...
Go! Go! Go!
Hold the line!
Gas!
- Easy, girl.
- Come here.
Help me!
Please! Take us with you!
Get back!
We're too heavy!
We have to get off now!
Step away from the helicopter!
Give her a chance!
No, wait!
What are you doing?
Get back in the helicopter! Now!
Take the girl!
We have to go now!
Hold tight, sweetheart!
Everything's going to be okay! Come on!
Stay back!
Take this!
So she will know!
Hold on tight, sweetheart!
Eden!
The wall stood 30 feet high,
clad in steel armor plating.
It followed the line of the ancient
Roman frontier, 2,000 years before,
spanning 18 miles, east coast
to west, cutting Britain in half.
Coastal waters were mined and patrolled.
The skies were declared a no-fly zone,
and orders were given to shoot down any
aircraft in violation of the quarantine.
The idea was simple.
Nobody came out, and nobody went in.
They needn't have worried
about the second part.
Those abandoned within the
quarantine zone were left to die.
Social order decayed
along with the corpses.
The streets ran with blood as
the people fought to stay alive.
The bodies burned in their thousands.
Looting, rape and murder became rife.
Fire spread as the cities were
plundered, and the last to die
became primal savages,
feeding on dogs, rats
and finally, on each other.
As the weeks turned to months,
the funeral pyres faded and died.
In time, all the lights burned out,
consigning the country north of the wall
first to memory and eventually to history.
But just as the government had
turned its back on the hot zone,
so the rest of the world
turned its back on Britain.
With hundreds of thousands
unemployed, homeless and destitute,
the situation has reached breaking point.
It now remains only a matter of time
before the laws of nature
seek to redress the balance.
- Targets are in play.
- Start recording.
Sinclair, Richter is the biggest slave trader
in the city. I want him alive. Your call.
Me and my boat, marooned on
this fucking island 25 years.
It's a full-time job,
trying to prevent it falling apart.
Come. Mind your head.
Best I could find.
Straight from the ghetto. Cheap. Clean.
Happy?
Very.
Shh.
What the fuck is this?
You prick!
Get the case.
Drop the gun!
Fucking nancy-boy!
Where's your partner? Tell me!
I am getting off this boat alive.
You go to hell.
Get back! Don't you come any closer, or I will
blow his fucking brains all over this boat!
Sinclair, whatever you do, don't shoot.
What the hell are you doing? Sinclair!
She's fucking nuts!
Tell her to back off!
I am ordering you not to shoot, Sinclair!
Richter, you have got one way out of this!
Put the gun down, or she will kill you!
You haven't got a chance!
I will kill him, I swear!
Sinclair, do not shoot! Do not....
Shit.
I will never get used to that.
I don't suppose you got a cigarette?
When are you going to buy your own?
Do you know how much these things cost?
Why do you think I smoke yours?
Michaelson was a good man.
Not the greatest
copper on the beat, but....
...a good man.
What happened in there?
See for yourself.
Whatever happened to a good cause?
Can't remember what she looked like.
All I have is a name on an envelope and
an address of a place I can never go to.
I have watched you fight your way
through the ranks, tooth and nail.
And it's made you so
full of piss and vinegar.
You carry on the way you're going,
you're going to wind up one
seriously fucked-up individual.
Now, do me a favor.
Please, go home. Get some rest.
Okay, let's do it!
Get back!
- Thank you, Captain, that will be all. Sir.
- Canaris. Prime Minister. How long? 2 hours ago.
Well? DDS were carrying out a routine drugs
raid when they found the infected victims.
- It's the Reaper virus.
- Oh, my God. It's back.
Bloody Hell, George.
What's got your knickers in a twist?
National emergency, I am afraid.
Briefing for the PM in 5 minutes.
Let's keep this informal and to the point.
We all know what's at stake,
why you're here.
Jane.
In 2023, when the rising tidal waters
were threatening to flood London,
we extended the Thames flood barrier.
Like a castle moat, this system of canals
encircles the entire capital
north of the river.
Our immediate plan is to flood the canals
blockade all bridges, tube lines
and rail links, in and out of the city.
You want to put 12 million
people under lock and key?
Containment is our absolute priority.
We must implement martial law now.
Keep the people off the streets
while we secure the blockade
and set up medical stations.
- Only then can we begin the evacuation.
- Do it.
It's all very well packing people into
their homes like so many million sardines,
but you drop a killer virus into that mix
and this town is going to go
tits-up in no short order.
Once you start stacking bodies
in the streets, there will be panic,
public disorder, looting, rape, murder,
and that's just for starters.
The death toll will be unimaginable
and by that time, there will be absolutely
fuck-all we can do about it.
You have to think of the
millions that we will be saving.
Are you talking about people?
Or pound notes?
Chief Nelson, would you join me in my office?
If this is a bollocking, make it quick.
I have got a job to do, I need
to be out there on the streets.
Michael.
What we're about to show you
is highly confidential
and potentially volatile material.
When the wall went up....
The government at that time, naturally, wanted
to know what was happening on the other side.
So they re-tasked one of
their military satellites
to provide coverage of
Edinburgh and Glasgow.
For the past 30 years,
it's carried on taking pictures,
sending down what you'd expect.
Empty cities, deserted streets.
That is, until 3 years ago,
when these turned up.
People.
On the streets of Glasgow.
- Survivors?
- What else could it be?
And if there are survivors,
there must surely be a cure.
What we have to do is get our hands on it.
We already have a team standing by.
All we need is somebody to lead them.
Someone to take them in, find the cure
and deliver it into our hands before
it's too late to turn the tide.
You don't know how many survivors there are.
And the team might not find them in time.
They might not find them at all.
And they could still be contagious.
That's what the team's going to find out.
You have known for 3 fucking years that they
were up there, but you swept it under the carpet.
Scotland's dead have long
since been laid to rest.
Yesterday, if I turned up on the
6:00 news with a survivor in tow,
they'd have strung me up from
the nearest lamp-post by the balls.
But if, in 48 hours, I arrive
with a survivor and a cure,
sure they won't give a flying
fuck about the survivor,
but they will be lining up to
kiss my arse for that cure.
In politics, survival is timing,
and ours is running out.
We have 48 hours.
I need your best man on this, right away.
All right.
I know someone who might just fit the bill.
Get in the car, it's pissing down.
- How long have they known?
- Long enough.
- But that doesn't matter now.
- Matters to me.
There are survivors out there.
This is not some personal
quest I am sending you on.
- Focus on your mission.
- Who's behind it? Hatcher?
Hatcher's got the swagger and the smiles,
but it's Canaris who pulls the strings.
He's the power behind the throne. And he is
not someone you want to pick a fight with.
- Who, me?
- I am serious.
If the truth got out,
it would bring Hatcher, the government,
the whole fucking system down.
And there's no way Canaris
is ever going to let that happen.
Once you're over that wall,
there's no rules
- No back-up.
- Better that way.
Look after this for me, would you?
Don't suppose you got a cigarette?
There's no smoking on the helicopter,
and I don't smoke. Fair enough.
Dr. Marcus Kane,
he was leading the research into the
virus when the gates were closed.
He was trapped inside the hot zone.
His lab was located inside the
quarantine compound in Glasgow.
If anybody was capable of
developing a cure, it was him.
I suggest you start at the lab.
Pick up the trail from there.
You will rendezvous with the
rest of the team at the wall,
then you will proceed north
in 2 armored transports.
Why not fly in?
Scotland is still a no-fly zone.
Hatcher needs to keep this
as low profile as possible.
So if we don't make it out,
no one will know we went in.
You have got 46 hours.
If you don't make it back, the city of London
and everybody in it will be left to die.
If it's there, I will find it.
You will need this. It's a GPS locator beacon.
It will tell us exactly where you are.
We will have a gun ship standing
by to extract your team.
So much for low profile.
Once you have the cure, it won't matter.
What happens if I don't find anything up there?
Then you needn't bother coming back.
For your own safety, return to your homes.
East London is under martial law.
What the hell are we going to do, Canaris?
Just calm down and listen.
Even if, by some miracle,
Sinclair finds what she's looking
for and makes it back in time,
the fact remains, this is
our fault, we made it happen.
Too many people crammed into ghettos
so tight they can barely move.
We created the perfect breeding
ground for a virus to take place.
And the more we save now,
the more chance there is of the
same thing happening all over again.
Now, we have an opportunity
to buy ourselves breathing room.
- What exactly are you suggesting?
- We're at war, Prime Minister.
It's basic combat triage.
Leave the dying to die.
With the whole world watching?
With a lie this big, we can get
away with anything we want.
- Major Sinclair! Good flight? Fine.
- Sergeant Norton. Welcome to no-man's land.
Why call it that? There's not another living
soul for miles south of that wall, except us.
What about the sentries?
No, the whole system was fully
automated about 20 years ago.
Nowadays they only expend
their ammo on the local wildlife.
A team arrived 2 hours ago.
They're prepping their gear inside.
Ask them to get suited up, Sergeant.
We're against the clock on this one.
Yes, sir!
- Has the team been briefed?
- I have given them their assignments,
objectives and the file on Dr. Kane.
Major Sinclair. Chandler.
Armor division. I will be your driver today.
Yeah, they may be ugly, but
they move like shit off a shovel.
Twin V12 engines, 2-inch armor plate,
and they will take anything from
30mm rounds to chemical weapons.
Just the ticket for a night on the town.
Where'd they find these things?
They patrolled the hot
zone, just north of the wall.
When the system was automated,
most of them were sold off for scrap.
These are the last 2 in service.
Major, meet Corporal Read. Tank driver.
Major. Carry on, Corporal.
- Riflemen. Miller, Carpenter.
- Major. Major. What have we got here?
Bio suits. Combat model.
High impact flexi-polymer.
Gives us total freedom of
movement and 24-hour protection.
Just what a girl needs.
Prototype, silicon foam grenade.
- This is frontline equipment.
- A going-away present from Canaris.
Are we expecting trouble?
- Is there a problem?
- No. No problem at all, Major.
Good.
This is our cargo,
Doctors Talbot and Stirling.
You were part of the task
force set up to study the virus?
That's right.
How do you do, Major?
I took over in '24.
Stirling joined me in '31.
Until Hatcher, in his infinite wisdom,
decided to pull the plug on the
whole program 3 years ago.
Tried everything, of course.
Just couldn't crack it.
I do hope this trip of yours
is worth the risk, Major.
Apparently, someone thinks so.
All right, listen up!
I want everyone suited,
booted and strapped. Back here in 10.
Open the gate!
Sentry guns deactivated.
All right, Chandler. Take us in.
- Shit! Chandler, what was that?
- Chandler, why have you stopped?
- I think we hit something. Major. Say again?
- I think you'd better have a look at this.
All right, Miller. Suit up and check it out.
Chandler, send up a flare.
Hey, Chandler, what's black
and white and spread all over?
I can't see any damage to the APC,
but your cow is a complete write-off.
- Moo.
- All right, get back inside.
You know that Dr. Kane was
the best man in his field.
His papers on virus research were required
reading when I was in medical school.
Basically, he taught me everything I know
but I never actually met the man.
This file's been closed for 25 years.
The government tried to suppress any
information getting out of the hot zone.
Didn't want people to know how
bad things had got up there.
I don't think we can stay here much longer.
Morality has abandoned these people. The killing...
Seems he dug in with a bunch of stranded soldiers,
fortified the hospital as best they could,
kept up regular reports on the
army frequency using their coms set
till the power went out permanently.
The fires have spread,
the power supply is dwindling,
and our food and water
are running out fast.
At night we can hear
the distant cries of pain and anguish.
They have begun to feed off each other.
It's medieval out there.
Ammunition is low.
The barricades won't hold out much longer.
Our time has run out.
This is Dr. Marcus Kane signing off.
What do the numbers mean?
It's the number of people in
each house that needed saving.
They were told to stay in their homes,
that help would come.
Clear.
Stirling, what do you know about line of fire?
I am a lab hound, not a combat surgeon.
That's all we need.
Line of fire is the air between
the target and the weapon
through which the bullet
travels very fast.
It's also the last place you
want to be in a fire fight.
If anything happens, you get behind me quick.
Understood?
You wouldn't want me to blow your
brains out is what I understood.
Stand back.
All right, check your corners.
We're clear.
Read, Fresno, we're on the
fifth floor, we're going in.
Copy that, everything quiet here.
I think the TV's buggered.
- Talbot, Stirling.
- You're up.
How the hell are we supposed
to find anything in this mess?
Just keep looking. It would help
if we knew what we were looking for.
Some evidence of Kane's work.
I will know when I see it.
Thanks.
That helps a bunch.
Shut it, Carpenter.
Major! Major!
We got a live one!
Chandler, did not copy! Say again!
There's a fucking girl here!
Outside on the street!
Whatever you do, do not touch her!
Chandler, keep her in sight,
but do not approach her.
Repeat, do not approach her.
Chandler! What are you doing?
You heard Sinclair! Get back inside! Now!
She needs help, Read, look at her! Chandler, no!
Fresno, get your short,
hairy ass back in the vehicle. Fuck.
Hey, hey. It's okay.
It's going to be okay. Whoa!
- Chandler! Do you copy?
- Yeah, she's alive, Major, but only just.
Major, she must be isolated so we can examine her.
All right, let's get her inside.
- Major, this lab looks untouched.
- Take a look. We're right behind you.
- Talbot, get down now!
- Christ!
Shit!
- Read, emergency Evac! Now!
- Copy that!
I have reached Stirling. I need my torch!
I need my torch! Major! Checking the back door!
Shit!
Chandler get back in the fucking APC now!
Okay, I am moving!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
We're rolling!
We're not getting out that way!
Jesus Christ!
Burn, you fuckers!
Fuck....
- Chandler, you're on fire!
- Don't I fucking know it!
Major, we are under attack!
I repeat, we are under attack!
Bastards!
APC 1 is down!
Shit!
Repeat, APC 1 is down!
We have lost Chandler!
- Fuck!
- Get to the elevator, sub level 1.
- Get in there.
- It won't work, there's no power!
Get the fuck in! Move! Move!
Sergeant! Cover fire! Copy!
Miller, foam grenade.
Whatever this plan is... make it snappy! Shotgun!
Major, what are we doing in here?
Going down! Pull it now!
Major, you are completely insane!
- Fuck!
- Check your corners! Check your corners!
Move! Move! Move!
Miller, get that fucking hatch open!
Oh, shit!
Get in!
We have got to go now!
Move it, Read!
Go! Go! Go!
Is anybody injured? Is everybody okay?
I am okay. I am fine.
What the fuck happened back there?
Read's got multiple impact warnings.
- Read!
- Stop, stop the car!
- Look out!
- Stirling, you still with us? I am okay.
- I am okay. Well, I think I am not!
What about Read?
She's dead!
- Fuck this shit, man! Fuck it!
- All right, grab what you can and bail out!
- Miller, cover Norton!
- Covering fire!
- Wait, wait, wait, tourniquet.
- I am doing it! I am doing it!
- Norton, alleyway!
- Copy!
- Stirling, go with him! He needs my help!
- Get over here! Go! Move it!
- Miller! Get behind me!
- Get Talbot! Fuck! Major, go!
Major, fucking go!
Come on, then, you fuckers!
Fuck....
I am out!
- Get your hands off me!
- Talbot! We can't leave him.
Go! Go! Go!
Move it!
Savages!
This one's for Sol.
Shit, man.
I am sorry.
I am so sorry.
I got a bit carried away.
But if you keep going on like this...
- See?
- There I go again.
I am sorry.
I am so sorry.
But you are making me so fucking mad!
Just talk to me.
Who are you? What the fuck is the matter
with you, eh? Enjoy pain, is that it, eh?
Because you are fucking asking for it!
Norton to Sinclair,
Norton to Sinclair, do you copy? Over.
Norton to Sinclair, come in.
Sooner or later, you're going to have to
consider the possibility that they're dead.
I am sorry. I am sorry to be blunt, but...
We still have a job to do,
with or without Major Sinclair.
Yeah, and right now, my job is you.
If anything happens to you now,
Dr. Stirling, we're fucked.
Let's try again, eh. Who are you?
And where have you come from?
Now, I know that Kane
didn't send you, so who did?
Where'd you get all the fancy gear from, eh?
The tanks. The guns.
Talk to me!
Did you say Kane?
You need me to speak a little louder?
Is that it?
Well, how's this?
Fuck you!
We came over the wall.
I fucking knew it. I fucking knew it!
I knew he was fucking lying! Who was lying? Kane!
You see, the bastard told us
there was nothing out there.
No hope of salvation.
But I knew.
I knew that one day someone
would come and prove him wrong.
If Kane's alive, I need to find him.
Shh. Save your breath.
You're with us now.
And you're alive only
as long as we need you!
Well, you see, if you did come over that wall,
then you must have planned on getting back.
We have tried before and failed.
I have seen too many of my
friends rush those gates,
but before they could even get close,
they were turned to fire... and fell as ash.
But with you here to lead us through,
we are going to go all the way.
Oh, lady, I could eat you right up.
You should forget
about that bastard Kane!
He's history.
But you, you are our
passport to the promised land.
I think you're going to
be sorely disappointed.
I will be the judge of that.
Can you hear that?
The hounds are hungry!
It's feeding time at the fucking zoo!
We need this one alive.
Make sure she stays that way.
Nice watch.
Sol. I heard what you said.
I need to speak with you!
- You will get your turn! Sol!
- The wind of change is blowing a hurricane!
Give them hell!
- No, no!
- No, no! No, no!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Here he is, the head chef,
the big cheese,
the sunshine of your lives!
It's Sol....
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have a rare treat in store for you!
Medium fucking rare!
Kane thought he could tell us what to do,
and we told Kane,
"Fuck you!"
Fuck you!
This is our city!
Whoever they send here,
we're going to catch them!
We're going to cook them!
And we're going to eat them.....
Eat them, man!
Here we go.....
- No! No!
- No! No, no....
- Burn him!
- Please! Please!
- No! No!
Get off!
You bitch!
Yes!
If you're hungry,
why not try a piece of your friend?
Hey...
What do I have to do to get a drink?
Put the key in the lock,
and turn it very slowly.
That wasn't so painful, was it?
Wait!
Get me out of here, and I can help you.
You can help me? Why?
What are you offering?
I heard you speaking to Sol.
You said you came through the wall.
No, no, no. Please.
Don't leave me here! He will kill me.
You have to do better than that,
I am afraid. I can help you find Kane.
- You know where Kane is?
- I should. He's my father.
If I find out you're lying,
you will wish that I'd left you here.
Follow me, and you keep
your bloody voice down.
Look out!
You can let go now.
Move it!
Come in, Sergeant!
Sinclair, this is Norton. Where are you?
On the move!
Meet us at the station on Queen Street!
Station on Queen Street, copy.
Come on.
Find her....
Come on!
Joshua, it's okay!
- You can trust her.
- She looks dangerous. She is.
Norton, do you copy?
Come in.
It looks clear.
- Go!
- Go! Go!
When I grab you, I am going to rip your
fucking head off! Run, you little fucker!
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Leg it!
Come on!
This way!
Fucking move it!
- Fire up the engine!
- Norton, if you can hear me, platform 4!
Are you coming or not?
Come on!
- Come on!
- Move it!
- Get on!
- You fucker....
Come on, Stirling!
No!
Come on!
Stirling, get down!
Move it!
- Come on!
- Run, Major! Faster!
Come on!
No....
Where are you taking us?
Somewhere safe for the moment.
Sorry to piss in your chips,
but we haven't got time to play safe.
You said you'd take us to Kane,
and I need to see him now.
I said I would help you find him.
I can't take you to him. Why not?
Because he will kill me.
And if he finds out where
you're from, he will kill you too.
Ever since Sol left, he's become
suspicious of everyone, even me.
His people are too afraid to defy him,
and those who dare are tortured or killed.
You're living proof of a
world beyond that wall.
All our lives he told us
there was nothing out there.
You being here makes him a liar.
What were you doing in the city?
- I went to find my brother. Sol.
- That maniac is your brother?
- That is one fucked up family, man.
- They're at war.
And we're caught right in the middle.
What is this place?
- A shortcut through the mountain.
- We use it all the time.
Looks like an old military
facility or something.
Whatever it was, they left in a hurry.
Didn't even bother to lock the doors.
Jesus, what have they got
in here, the Lost Ark?
Don't know, mate, but those
blast doors are 12 inches thick.
Whatever it is, somebody
somewhere wanted it kept safe.
Somebody's coming.
Telamon.
Run.
- Wait, who or what is Telamon?
- He's Kane's executioner.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. You can go, I am staying.
Give me your sidearm, and get out of sight.
You really don't give a fuck, do you?
I think your plan's shit,
but I guess I will stand with you.
There's something you don't see everyday.
- No! No! Joshua!
- No! No! No!
Come on!
Come on! Move!
Sergeant, put down your weapon.
We need to get to Kane the quickest way possible,
and this is it. Yeah, all right. Fuck it.
I hope you know what you're doing.
Wayward daughter returns.
You brought some friends.
Came over the wall. We want to see Kane.
I knew they'd be watching the cities.
That's why we chose this place.
Out of sight, out of mind.
I suppose it was only a matter of time
before they sent someone
to answer to the question,
"Why are you alive
when you should be dead?"
- That's what you want to know, isn't it?
- Ow! Answer him!
Something along those lines.
Leave us.
The answer is easy. In the land of
the infected, the immune man is king.
So if this is just a power trip,
why stay hidden?
Why not show yourselves?
You think we chose to cast off the
apparel of our former existence?
No, no, no. We didn't choose anything.
We were delivered.
These walls around you,
they were built to last.
And so shall we. What we have built
here from the ashes is pure blood,
uninfected by the outside world...
...until now.
Have you found the cure?
Even now you still cling to hope, huh?
If I were you, I would
abandon any such thoughts.
- There's always hope.
- But there is no cure. There never was.
We had prevailed here,
not because of science,
but through natural selection.
Survival of the fittest.
We have earned the right to live here.
Purged of the likes of you.
Take them away.
Don't you even want to know why we're here?
That you're here at all is sin enough.
It's the Reaper virus. It's back.
And if he touches me one more time,
I will kill him where he stands, I swear.
How dare they send you
here to ask for my help?
They started this fire.
They can burn in it!
Place your right hand on the screen.
Now look into the retinal scanner.
We're losing our city.
I better get up there.
It's time to get you out, Prime Minister.
Sub level 6.
How the hell did this man...
Isolate him. Put him in his office, and do it now.
Move, sir. I don't understand how I...
- Keep your distance! Canaris, I...
- Canaris! Back away! Canaris!
Good shot.
I was trying to save him!
You brought impurity into our world.
You must be cleansed. Do it.
- Please, Father.
- Please.
- Father, please!
- No!
- Daddy....
- No... Daddy...
Daddy...
No....
You, turn around.
Tie her hands.
Sinclair, what did they call you
before they called you Major?
Eden. Well, Eden, I still
think this is a shit plan.
So, tell me.
What's it like out there now?
What do you care?
I am curious.
Same shit, different era.
So we did the right thing, then, eh,
by keeping ourselves to ourselves.
Don't you mean turning your back?
You used to be a doctor.
At what point did you stop caring?
I used to be an idealist, too.
That night that they closed the gates.
That night, I lost everything.
My wife, my family.
- You don't know the pain.
- You chose to stay hidden.
Your wife and family could still be out there.
You ever stop to think about their pain?
I haven't slept one night in 25 years
without reliving that moment.
Who the hell are you to talk to me about pain?
What do you know?
What did you ever lose?
Bollocks!
Daddy wants to see you.
Step away!
Don't fuck about, mate.
I am not in the mood.
Stirling, get the keys!
Back off.
Out of the way, you dozy twat!
In there.
Doctor, not now.
Grenades. Lovely. That will do nicely.
Come on, Doctor!
I will tell you what I have lost.
I have lost my bloody mind.
Execute the prisoners!
Now!
Man the defenses!
We're under attack!
That's it.
- Nice.
- Yeah? Cool. Come, come, come.
Where are they?
Fuckers!
- You, finish her off.
- Shit.
Cally!
Come on! We have no time!
Come on. Watch out.
Come on.
Get to the horses!
- Move it!
- Come on! Grab the torches! Here you go.
- Sergeant, jam the door. Go on!
Sergeant, check and see if
there's a backup generator.
We're going to need something, and fast.
Take your pick.
Let's try that box.
No! Well, what are you looking at?
Break that fucker down!
- Whoa.
- Nice color. I will take it.
- I will get those blasting doors open.
- Stirling, Cally, fill her up.
- Where you going?
- I am going to find a phone.
Help me with it.
Hurry up, you lazy twats!
Come on!
Perfect.
- Get in the back!
- What does it do?
I will show you what it does.
Nelson. We got the package.
We're on our way.
Well, you'd better get here quick.
Canaris is in charge now.
Hatcher's dead.
Put him on.
It's for you.
Yes?
You still want your prize?
Then follow this signal.
Trace the source. Send the coordinates
directly to me. Okay, that's it.
Let's go.
Hold the fort while I am away.
This is as far as you go.
We will handle it from here.
Un-bloody-believable!
Fuck, yeah! Put your foot down!
I am tired of running from these bastards. Hold on!
Yeah!
Step on it!
Fucker!
- Shit!
- Jesus....
Too fucking close.
You think?
Hold on, we're going for a ride.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
Fuck!
Here they come.
Come on!
No....
- No!
- No! No....
- No...
- No....
Please.
Please stop!
You will kill us.
Cally!
Get off of her, you bitch!
Okay.
- You like pain?
- Yeah. Have some of this!
Put your foot down!
No.
Cally!
Cally! Cally! Cally!
- No!
- Oh, shit. No! Stop!
You dirty fuckers!
Fuck!
Shit....
What the fuck's going on, Sinclair?
They want my cure.
Major Sinclair.
You had me worried for a while.
Do you have it?
I have got it.
Where's the medical team?
Let's not make this difficult.
You have done a good job.
We will take it from here.
Stirling, bring her out.
You have to forgive Stirling.
He's very involved with his work.
Okay. Let's go.
We understand the need for sacrifice.
The longer we leave it, the better
shape we will be in once the dust settles.
Once the virus has eaten away the
dead flesh, then we will make our move.
- Just a question of timing.
- Making you the hero of the hour.
You said you had the cure. Where is it?
She's the cure. The survivors are immune.
We can use her blood to make a vaccine.
- Hand her over.
- She's not going anywhere without me.
- Captain.
- Get behind me.
Hand her over now.
Go with them.
I don't trust him.
- There's no choice. So that's it?
- I have got nothing left to bargain with.
I have done my job.
Now it's your turn.
A lot of good people died for this!
Is that all it was to you?
A job?
That's right.
Now, take her and go.
- Rough ride?
- Rough enough.
Don't suppose
you have got a cigarette?
Come with me.
I will get you all the cigarettes you want.
Pity.
I could have used someone like you.
She's so beautiful.
You okay?
Never better.
How'd you find me?
I used to be a policeman once.
I don't need it anymore.
Really?
Did Canaris get what he wanted?
He did.
I have a feeling he will be
holding onto it for awhile. Shit.
Don't worry.
He gave me something in return.
All the evidence you will
need to bring Canaris down.
He will come after you.
Well, then he will know where to find me.
Come on.
- Just do me one favor.
- Drive careful.
Be lucky.
The longer we leave it, the better shape
we will be in once the dust settles.
Once the virus has eaten away the
dead flesh, then we will make our move.
Making you the hero of the hour.
If you're hungry,
try a piece of your friend.