Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
It's like to walk in the fictional country
joking is upside down!
Do you think so  then you feel?
Death is like breathing pure oxygen!
A life?
It's like looking for the output,
and you're trapped in the wrong house.
How do you know to be able to udahnnes ses air
again until you die?
Because I'll be outside my body.
Buoy and I wiill be free.
How do you know?
How do you know that it will not be worse?
I know it will be better than this.
You do not know it, Nancy!
What if death, as you say, is
leaving your body but not your soul?
What if you stay stuck in your soul?
What then?
Then I was free andd I will be free!
If you can release there,
why not get rid of here?
Liberating Nancy
Hello?
Baltimmore?
Hello!
You look different.
If you bring it?
- What? This?
You think you can not deal with that?
- I do not know! Can you?
Well saznajmo!
You know you have to Tailand
two types of dog food?
Is that!
- Yes.
One is if you just want to nahranis dog
the other is if you plan to eat it!
Have you heard this?
She wants too eat you!
Está bastante  Llena often
How you  doing?
Yes, the remains of  the house tonight.
5 is and will remain so. There will be nothing better!
The best would be  to go to sleep.
I do not want to talk ... no
I  do not want to talk about it!
Listen, I'll call you later! Valid?
Oh, shit!
What was your route by bus?
Prenatovvaren.
I was a little cold!
- Is blowing too?
No, it's perfect!
Are there any room?
- What?
Here somewhere!!
- CHILDREN?
Yes, with cameras and  a team of Document!
Well, I'll relax
in the next 45 minutes!
I'll be here, the player! Where will you be?
In an airport? In noisy
family gathering?
I will keep the baby? Sleeping next to someone
on the bench?
Or ... You will be here!
On your personal  site for golf!
Here we connect modern technology ...
With the elegancee of this sport.
There are eight such courts in
U.S. and Canada.
I wish you luck in the game!
Good luck!
I'm really wondering
Albert. Really impressed!
You must drink a minimum of two  drinks
price of pizza is $ 7!
The first drink is free.
That would be all over the country!
I am thrilled!
What can I say? Really
asm impressed!
Cheers, Albert!
- Cheers!
Well, we have too make serious.
For the dealers  will be great!
Yes!
What are your back?
I've got thrills in the legs.
I can not sleep at night!
- I always go to the gym?
Two times  a week.
If you want something serious, let me know.
I know someone who you can get
whatever you want!
Well, you tell him that
you get a new zaivot!
Where's Nancy?? I lost it!
Moved to digital entity?
Nancy was in Baltimmore with friends.
Tomorrow is  returned.
Who still has friends in Baltimore?
It is not the same.
Sometimes it's good to be
separate from each other, so you can ...
Restore the magic!
After the car wash,
I returned and got ... a message!
What kind of message?
- It has  decided to stay with friends.
Hello?
No, I told you
we will talk about it on Monday.
Yes!
Good. Hello!
It's good!
Do you need company?
- Shoot!
Is it zapocinjes every conversation?
No, with that, amp;quott;if you need company?
I think that just because I'm your man.
Do you need company?
- Yes, of course!
Well you see, you and you did my man!
Damnn!
How many others are there?
Too many to count,
a bunch of loser.
What?
- How do you know that I am not?
Women's intuition?
We will need something to
wear for my big finale!
Of course!
Your body and your mind are
sinhrinizovani golf shot.
Unified the ...
For the purpose, format and order!
Submit a gavitaciji ...
Direct effect ...
Feel the  moment!
Hold your view of the ball ...
And visualize its trajectory.
Be the ball!
-- Be the ball!
Ball is enerrgy!Refine
um!!
Be the ball!
-- Be the ball!
Be the  ball!
Do you think that you can not remember ...
acccurate feeling that you've gone through ...
Before you felt the need to hurt yourself?
Yes. Nothing.
What do you  feel now?
I feel with the smoke ...
Can you remember your thoughts
you went through your head?
Sometimes I think about my unclee,
sometimes on the Albert ...
Sometimes I'm angry!
- What  do you think of the uncle?
Oto how much he loved me!
-- Your uncle has hurt you!
It's me in that  way he liked.
You realize you love someone
povreedjivati does not mean it! Right?
Can we at least agree about that?
If I let you love me in
way that he wanted ...
I showed him  I love him.
Are you a feared?
- Wee played a lot, laugh!
A game and also caused the pain!
Yes!
Felt you were accepted while you are playing?
So ....
So the injury of themselvess or
injury by others ..
Makes you feel honored!
It seems to feel.
Have you ever injured Albert?
Can you describe how it looks
making love with Albert?
Yes!
The last time we did
masturbirao by me.
Do not write this.
What do you  think now?
Soy repulsiva
Albert ponasane has nothing to do with you.
We're not talking about you.
You are a beautiful woman
You are an intelligent woman, Nancy ...
No, I can not always be
what we want to be,
what we want when we can be!
Take  it?
Well, it's hard to believe that this
company exists for over 15 years!
15 years is a long time!
I know?
To create a long,
need rain, you need the sun.
At the end of the rainbow are something!
Pot of  gold!
I found this cup!
Yes, because the company,
Would not be leading in the state,
That no one man.
The man who gave me the money
Who has supported me  when I most needed.
I want to thank
the  man at the moment!
Thank you,, Albert!
Because it was a real good friend
after all these years!
And to continue this celebration!
My wife, my beautiful wife,
Jenny annd everyone else come to the podium,
To play a nice slow dance.
Let's  go!
I do not want too play?
- Yes!
When?
I have to go home!
- You have to go?
Yes, I do not feel good. I have to go.
You have to go so fast?
You need somee medicine?
Nancy, what are you doing? There in the fun!
What is it?
- Nothing,, I do not feel good.
I just want to go home.
- You can not relax?
To come out off this world?
It's not your party,
but rocks. This is his night!
Did not you can relax, at least tonight?
Good! You want to go home? Go home!
Here you go!
You know I do not like to drive at night.
I'll call a cab.
I do not know what you got until it ...
... Not lose!
We need a few hours to
come to the hotel and will ...
... Drop in to my
house to pick up some things.
If this is wrong?
¿Eso es una  margarita?
My gift for the tenth anniversary of Alberta.
Cuvam is close  to the heart.
Keeps memories?
-- Drained flower.
What is?
-- Souse.
What is it?
- Nothing.
It's all  right.
You can change your  mind to.
- What?
Nemas courage now?
I came here to do.
Sorry, I only recall that
able to think about your options.
There is no other option.
Really?
Maybe we should wonder
whether  this is really what you want!
I'm here.
I'll tell you what  you have to know.
This is your collection of video tapes?
You have a whole shelf.
What do you have in your bag?
- Excuse me?
-  Do not worry, I got your money!
Thirsty?
- What?
Will you something to drink?
- Yes! Whisky?
That's what I did last week.
Broken hours.
I stopped it, and not at all
remember how it happened.
Amnesia.
- Yeah, I think about it!
Amnesia!
Wity you are!
I do not know
Delujes not like that type!
No tienes que seeguir tecleando
Look at  this!
So here are all  actions occur?
Big mess!
Do it to me like you said.
Just as you  promised!
Oh, God. That's good!
Say it again!
- It's good!
I've got something special for you
what'll you wear.
Thank  God!
You have one message.
- Hello, This message is for Nancy.
Nancy, this  is Carol.
We have a meeting at 2 and
I  wondered whether jve wrong?
Stan? Yes, I am!
No, no ...
No, I entered the house and this is strange ...
Her clothes here.
She had scheduled a  meeting i. .. that
Yes, something iss strange here!
That's what you say. Two days passed,
and she has not appeared even once.
It does not look like her.
It would be  reported.
Yes!
Yes, I know. Hello!
911th Emergency slucaaajevi! How do I ...?
Hey!
What about  sweaters?
I want to  see you!
Turn around!
Watch  it!
On a good road that we're oduzmes breath!
You know? This is not me.
Who are you? A woman  from the Internet?
Part of me is.
- And what is the real you?
And who are you really?
This is true I am now!
And tomorrow?
- We  have no tomorrow!
We're just now.
Where are you?
- I'm here.
Good. Then we have  somewhere to go!
Are you ready? Yes?
Well, open your mouth.
More. Come on!
So, yes! Ready?  Here comes ...
Yes, I see  this ...
Yes?
Do not worry about fingers ...
Well I posissati them.
I feel with the piano.
-- Yes, you and you did.
That's right.
-- Where to go?
Just right. So!
That's right..
- Fun it!
Yes?
Feels good, right?
Take it easy,, let's go!
- That's good.
Again!
Come  on!
The good you are!
Continue,  come on!
Fun it!
- Well are you?
Resembling me of my uncle.
- Is it?
What was he? Blade Runner?
How many years have you
when you play like this?
- 7
- It's all explained.
You're so fuccking cute.
You're  good!
Yes, we could begin with our work.
En lugar de morir en vano
es mejor morir con dolor
Can I tell you something really funny?
You know what my mother did when
I told her that I will never have children?
No??
Kept me locked in a room for five days.
And called me  stupid slut.
I guess that is my uncle
helped by the decision.
Her brother?
- Yes.
It was  good.
He was a good one week
as it was programmed.
I thought I wanted children
In fact, and is wanted.
Maybe I would if I gave birth to a golf course ...
Albert managed to attract attention.
Do you sometimes ask why you born?
No, I do not wonder that.
But you know what I  am interested in?
I wonder how the name oof this place here ...
Do not!
- ... I  do not like it!
I love, what? Do not you love to be beautiful?
OK! What do you think that here we stop playing?
Do not leave me!
To continue with the plan!
Did I hear?
Hello!
I'm looking for .... Nancy Stuckwell
The service support, part
life insurance package.
Good.
Mrs Stuckwell applied for
two-year service to the protection of health ...
- As it is, protection against viruses ...
- No, not at home.
Do you know when you back?
- Actually I do not know.
You see, her contract expires, which means
which means that it will lose all its data ...
Good.
Well, someone hass her authority?
I am her husband.
Spouse meets our requirements for poverrljivocsu.
Or do I come back next week.
You know what?
In Stavri, we  will do it.
They asked me to send some Meili ...
Frankly, I do not know how to do it ...
Well, you can ... can you help me with that?
We'll see what we can  do.
- Rock and roll
Excellent!
And ....
... To see her system. Computer.
Yes, sorry. I'm a bit absentminded.
Shoes please.
Your wife??
- Yes!
You are a lucky man.
- Yes, I know.
Will it last long?
Let's hope that NESCOM.
You know? It is strange.
Usually the other way around.
Women are those who want to know
What do their husbands.
I do not want to know  what my wife is ...
Just want to send a Meile.
Do you know any passwords?
A little to facilitate things.
Some say that it means something ...
For example, her favorite color, flower ...
The name of the street where he grew up.
The name of the child.
We do not have  children ...
See, see ...
It seems that Nancy ...
- My wife?
Yes, yes ...
There is no password. No security password.
All odkljucano!
- Excellent!
So ... what do you want to send and to whom?
You know what? In fact I'm ...
Somehow worried.
Why?
Because my wife! You know,
she was not at home four days.
I thought I just want to send a post.
Yes, I said so, but ...
I'm trying to find some clue about it
when visiting, that I could not call.
I guess you do not know a single
your friend's wife!
I mean, it does not regard me ....
- No, you are not concerned.
Did you call 911 to see if is not
Department of Missing Persons?
No, I think that it occurred.
I thought:
# I'll give it another day.#
Yes, another day ...
Do you know a Farly her precious Farly-a,?
What is thhe name?
People use aliases.
- Yes,, but I know that name ...
What the hell it means #?
What are they?
- Her Meili.
There are hundreds, it seems that all
from the same person.
You want to show you how to open it??
- Yes! What is it with my name?
Albert, when you read this ...
- Let's see it ...
Sorry!
Albert, when you read this will be too late.
It's too late for your miserable
attempts to understand me or ...
... This crappy life that
should spend together.
It's good that I finally realized,
So I decided to go to you
I freed myself to this marriage.
I do not blame those that do not love me,
I feel nauseous when I think about the common bed.
Call it fear or whatever ...
But now I have the courage to do
what's good for me.
To the rest and start izpocetka.
Do not try to find me.
Goodbye,  Albert!
No, it's Nancy ...
It's not Nancy ...
she writes like this, this is not it.
You'd be surprised whaat all people can be.
And what do the people you know.
It can not be it.
I know, her entire life this thing.
Well, Albert. Maybe she met someone
because all of this message ...
Show that has been or is ...
in a  very intimate connection with ...
... Other men.
Well you, Albert?
- Yes!
I'm going to ... sipam own drinks. Will you?
Of course, I would like to
have a drink with you, Albert.
Hold me here,, everybody.
Odstampacu you this.
- Valid!
¿Qué improve?
I just thought that my life
be different, that's all.
What should be?
I do not know that we have twwo, maybe three children ...
Tipican happy marriage.
Do you and Albert once talked
on how to adopt a child?
Once, before
I was asked to udeam for him.
How did he  respond?
He said he wants  a Chinese baby.
It seems that Albert
very  difficult if you listen.
What happened then?
- Suddenly changed.
And then?
- Cao Chinese.
Are you still sometimes  talked on the subject?
Yess.
Hubble rico de lo quee el pollo preparaba
Sounds like the most important issue for Alberta.
Para Albert, Toquue no esa Tecla
Can you to the bathroom, please?
Of course!
I really have too go!
- Sorry!
I'll give you the key!
Thank you very much!
Are you  okay?
Nancy! Can you open the door?
Nancy, I know you think that  this is a
the only relief.
The only way to  get rid of ...
But I promise you that we will find
another way to relax.
Maybe take
but I know you'll be better.
Statistics gives us hope.
Nancy, I know ...
I know you feel like it
and nobody listened.
But I would like you to listen
and it would like to help you.
Nancy, please let me help you.
What happened, Carol?
Why all  this?
I had a feeling that you came
the stage when ...
- ... want to hurt myself ...
- So?
I'm fine, I just had to change my tampon.
And now I'm happyy. Happy, happy!
Yes, I  see!
I do not know what you thought that you'll  achieve
time that you come to my house.
This is my house, idiot!
My house!
Excuse me? You said something?
You will have to stay here a bit with me, okay?
Maybe take a while
read the entire November.
I think that I like to eat
one  of these virtual shit to you.
Let's see whether you like it.
Nucicu to filozofiram.
You're a degenerate.
By the way, as my wife? Is that right?
I want to answer me some questions!
Oh, shit! It's disgusting!
With all these thoughts in mind, i
continue to maintain concentration.
It's impresSive, Albert!
I'll give you the answers to what you want.
Ask a Question!
-  Where's my wife?
Are not you supposed to  be before they asked?
Fuck you! Answer  me a question.
They say that what you do not know
can not hurt you.
Do you think it is true Albert?
- Shut up!
What the devil did you have any with my wife?
What do not you  do it, Albert?
Well, well. Spusticu up to your secret  places
and I izpeci you right there.
Zavezacu your hands that you can not touch.
Y hasta te quemaré
abrirte agujeros Negros
And you'll continue to whisper #
You know, you're absolutely right. No I
it worked prokletoj my wife.
Have talked to.
- I bet it is.
And I know why.
Because I wanted to get rid of suffering, Albert!
You gave her leave, and I am free.
It's wanted.
- Not that she wanted.
I'm sure you did not want.
This is a wish from me.
Fuck you.
Sablaznjavao're my wife as a damn pedophile.
You wash her brain. It's obvious.
I did it again ... I bled for you
Who is this?
- Why did not you ask?
Really? Why did not you ask why
sitting alone in the corner ...
... And bleeding?
You've seen it every day. Right?
It's your nose in front,
You slept in the same bed.
You were not there  and said nothing.
Not that it touches not at all?
How could you? Why did not you just ask?
Ucutti!
Ucuti? It's the best you know?
Ucuti?
Ada try with something like Help?
Help!
Let me see if I can understand because if
I had a chance to go all this again
I could not do otherwise.
- Ucuti!
How can I do to help the person who I mean!
Where I had to vow!
- Will you umuknes?
A person who is with me  because
had a safety!
The person who we believed.
- Ucuti!
The person who came to you violated
and you is completely destroyed.
Ucuti, drkadjijo!
Do not you thought more
so talk to me
- Shit!
Drop Dead!
- It hurts, Albert.
- You are right that hurts.
Thank  you.
I think I feel closer to you now.
- Worn!
- It's exciting ...
Wear a lot of pain in you, Albert.
- Any more then each other?
- You ask me if ...?
Fuck you!
- Hit me!
I'll kill you!
Do you is fun, Albert?
How do you  feel now?
Can you add me so, please?
I will not to put this.
Nothing to me is not clear.
Did you entertain.
- No.
- Come on.
- Do not do it.
- Tucaj me.
Want me to tucas hard.
I want to.
Is that you want?
Is it good.
It's wanted!
What have you  of all this?
I'll tell you  what I have.
Pain.
- Fuck you.
- And you.
Where's my wife?
She has left you.. You remember?
I still can not find it if you want.
It is still outside, waiting to be found.
Is it good?
And what if it has died?
There lived while she was with you, and Now
when it is gone once you care?
Is it good?
's Safe.
Well, that's all II wanted to know.
You have beautiful skin.
I want to have sex with you,
when everything is finished. If you would like it?
Does it hurt?
- No.
- And this?
- You have a beautiful body, you know?
- No.
It's beautiful.
I want to  open it.
I thought that would  happen last night.
This will be a surprise, as you requested.
And this? I like it?
You like this, tiny?
I think I like him.
What do you think that will be?
Like a dream.
You're over your life
You have another vision of himself.
As one off them.
It's like you can dises under water.
- What do you think?
- Nothing.
Now you are here and there, and later
you swallow the dark.
And if you do it?
Not if the question is when.
This will be the end of  everything, you know?
That was our idea was.
Louis.
Nancy?
You want a service that we did?
It depends on how impudent.
Can you kiss me ...
... Gently?
You have one  more wish?
Yes, I have a  few wishes.
I want to be able to feel this.
And ....
I want to Albert can feel
complete solitude ...
You gave me sdusno
past 15 years of my life.
Every year we celebrated my absence.
I want to be able to feel this.
Maybe then he ...
Maybe you would understand,
we would have at least something in common.
Do you know what I mean?
Yes, I  know.
Why do you not like meat?
It does nott matter.
I remember a toy shop
annd I had to choose one.
It was a beautiful, beautiful.
It is still.
- And what happened?
- Hey ...
None of  that.
- It was not part dogovorao, remember it?
- I know, I know. I remember that.
But I know a lot about you,
and  in fact I do not know anything.
Do not worry,
I will not tell anyone to say.
I have two children, one four,
one seven years ago.
Really? Boys or girls?
Girl and boy has seven four ..
How come all at once interest
for my past?
Why not? No one will know,
except me, and I will live for a long ...
So it's not  important.
There is no more what to say.
Errors happen, as  I said earlier.
I??
Mistakes are made, people are injured
and continue on.
What mistakes?
How treat people
how they treat you.
Scars that leave each other.
Blame  her.
- Your mother?
- Mothers, fathers, women, everything is the same.
Q..
What makes you special?
Why do not prilozis document
sit in front of a court ...
And to stop it in
peaceful protest?
- Have I heard you well?
- Yes you did.
- Fuck you.
- Maybe, later.
No, fuck you!
Press'm hundreds of miles that I would be
found with you, not fuck with me!
That was the question.
These would have to wonder why, and this violates.
- I do not want to change.
- Do you want.
Want me to fuck in mind!
I've had enough  of this life.
Separation will not change any fucking thing.
Do you hear me? To get it?
Because I'd still be here
here and I do not want to be.
And if you can not accept tthat,
lost from my life!
What the hell you looking at?
I love that people talk about
personal matters, right?
Shit!
Let me, let me!
Nancy,  stop!
I know  you.
Please, Take me  to the hotel.
Good.
Here you have to make you better.
People like me do  not feel better.
Is it possible that our thoughts
make tracks and paths in our brain ...
And after repeated negative thoughts
become comitted to the path ...
That specific repeated stimuli.
And the negative feelings in
very difficult to redirect.
Are you finished?
It's all a bunch of nonsense.
You have no idea what a real pain.
You have no idea.
I think that you need this.
Maybe you're right.
Hi..
I can not refrain, when you start,
I do not know to stop.
Do not worry, I'll pick it all!
Sometimes I see the prostitutes.
Spend some time with them.
No chaos.
You think this is bad
to a dead marriage?
Worn, rubbish.
We could break it, ...
To stop the bye.
Maybe you do not know what to say
at the right time.
Communication.
This house is perfect, really perfect.
It's all crap.
But here I am  where I am.
I fuck it.
I have a proposal.
What?
If you do something for me,
I'll tell you where Nancy.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Are you finished?
It's all a bunch of nonsense.
Sedis there, pretend you're a very uvidjajna,
You make my stupid notes ...
Pretend that you have control.
- What is actually to your crap?
- Nancy, you are now very upset.
Yes, I am upset.
I am very, very angry.
What is  this?
We are a small therapist does not know what to do ...
Without their writings.
Why do you need all this when you  even
do not even know who I am?
All right,, Nancy.
Let's see what psychotherapist
has to say now about mad Nancy.
#The patient is now hostile moodamp #
No bullshit.
This is a very perceptive of you.
# The patient feels lonely and does not want #
Give it too Nancy.
Acute deterioration sense of self-consciousness.
From the book you pulled this definition?
Oh, here is a good.
# The patient feels unattractive #
There it is your feelings, Nancy,,
not about what actually did.
Let me ask you something, psychotherapist.
Where did you get your
fucking credibility?
Well, I think that'ss enough for today.
- Do not want to help me?
- Yes I would, Nancy, ...
But I can not help you if you
do not want to help myself.
Carol, and I never saw this.
Hello?
- Hi.
- Here it is.
You arrrived.
Hi, Albert.
I used a shower above,
help me for circulation.
Thanks for the shirt.
Albert told us
You were  that he did a service.
Yes, this is what fell upon?
As my mother?
- It's all right.
- Is that right?
- You want pizza?
- No, thanks.
- Cocktails?
No, thanks.
Yes.
Albert, can I tell you
something about this place?
You know that I have never been down  here,
I heard a little about him.
It's ... it's you.
In every sense off the fantastic.
I do not know how much work and passion
has been invested in this area.
This room is truly impressive.
I am impressed.
I deprived time for sure.
In order to turn out this good must be  spent
a lot of time down here I am.
Obviously not enough.
It's all in balance.
It's easy for you to say.
Albert has not reached your 7980th
Yes, you have to leave this, Albert.
Louis, do you have  family, children?
Girl of seven and  a boy of four years.
But I have not seen them for years.
Why?
My ex-wife will not let me.
They declared me unfit.
Okay.
Tell us where you  are you two met.
In fact, I met Nancy,,
on the Internet.
Really? Interesting.
Something related to the job?
No, no, not at all.
- We have common interests.
- Ah, well.
Is it back?
No..
- No?
- Where is she?
- I do not know.
- There's been days.
- Yes, I know.
- Have you called police?
- No, I did not.Why do not you
-?
- I do not know.
Do not you know?
Yes, I  know.
Where is she?
I was released, Albert.
So he wanted.
Hi mate.
You cried?
No..
- Safe are you?
- Am.
Why would otherwise cry?
That's my girl.
I want to make love last time
and I want it to be now.
I thought I do not want to know when it will be.
I changed my mind.
I want to do as you say,
as we agreed.
You heard me?
Yes, I heard you.
Wow.
Want  me?
I want  you.
Come and take me.
You're ...
Beautiful,, beauty.
Do you want to're taking me in love with this dress?
Very.
Do you want to kill me when I am in this dress?
No..
I do not want  to kill you.
- Coward!
- Listen.
- No, you're a coward!
- Stop.
Listen!
You came to me with this idea,
and to me it is no longer realistic.
- No.
- You're a moron.
- Asshole!
- I do that.
If you  want!
No..
You, you,  you ...
You promised me.
Over fucking computer?
This is the reality.
Look at me!
- No!
- Look at me!
- I love you.
- No, I do not love me.
- Yes.
- No, nobody likes me.
I hate you! You can not love me!
- Let me go!
- I know you.
I know  you.
Let me be your pain.
No, no, do not try that deceived me
your feelings.
You do not have no idea what a real pain.
- You know I know.
- No.
You think that we znacis something?
No znacis me nothing.
You're not  worth it.
Fucking stupid!
I do not want to go.
I can not give you anything.
I have nothing.
But I do not  want to go.
I have to go.
But I know you love me like I love you.
No, I do not like one, please.
Get up.
You want to die??
Want to die?
This is a fucking death!
News Now in the 9th
On this day a year ago
convicted murderer Louis D. Farley has been pronounced ...
Life in prison without
on parole.
Farley was in charge of
Nancy Stockwell comply ...
That was one thatt her own life.
Stockwell expressed her ...
How to want you?
I'm here.
You have everything you need?
- Yes.
- Good.
It is difficult, but you must endure.
Why?
How could  I know?
Not that I have not noticed.
It's here.
It was there in front of me.
- You did what you could.
- No, it's about what I did.
No..
Well  ...
Today I tried to
have sex with my wife.
I really do not understand why the  people
vencavajuci be harased.
It is better to leave the computer,
I started to feel bad.
Dreamer you tonight.
bye for now.
Nancy.
Inspired by true events
translation by heremony
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com