Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
GIRL: There used to be horses in that barn
At least that's what my grandfather says
We're probably the only horse farm
in Lexington Kentucky
that doesn 't have one horse
- Not one
- (Thunder rumbles)
MAN: It might rain.
Pat said it'd be a good day
for me to er... come down to the diner.
M A N Yeah, we
WOMAN: Just be breakfast and lunch
three days a week
MAN: If you 're working at the diner
she comes home from school to nobody or?
Well, Pop lives right next door.
I know you two don 't talk much,
but he and Cale get along real well.
- And er...
- And er... what?
You've been promising her for months
you would take her to work with you.
And I will. I will, Lil. But not today, honey.
I got a big race.
WOMAN: What do I tell her?
MAN: Tell her I was running late
and I didn 't have time to wait
- You tell her.
- Honey, I'm going to work.
(Engine starts)
All right, get in. I don 't wanna be late.
There you go
(Thunder rumbles)
- 58 and one.
- (Muffled reply from walkie-talkie)
All right, send Sonya. Don 't let her out.
I just wanna... I just wanna watch her action.
(Horse whinnies in distance)
I like him.
Her.
I like her, too.
(Chatter)
MAN: Can I get a bucket of multigrain
in stall number three please?
- Good morning sir
- Good morning.
Balon, you remember Cale?
Sure. She doesn 't come around any more.
Wow, honey, you've gotten so big.
Senorita, buenos dias.
Eddie let's take a look at Goliath 's Boy
- That means good morning.
- Good morning.
He's got legs like steel. Take him in.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
BALON: What have you got there? Candy?
Hey, Sonya. There you go, Sonya.
Ooh, yeah. That's Sonya. She likes candy.
- Sonya likes Twizzlers.
- Yeah?
Well... who's this?
Got a new jockey?
Manny, this is my daughter Cale.
Oh, hey.
Manolin Vallarta.
The greatest jockey in the world.
- Fattest jockey in the world.
- Fat?
Chacho, I'm too tall to race.
Look at you. Look at these clothes.
This is a barn, not a disco.
- Cambiate la ropa!
- Ooh!
He likes the way I dress. (Chuckles)
Now, yo u soo yo u r daddy?
You see how he's feeling the legs?
You see that?
Yeah well we just wanna make sure
the horse is sound and healthy
Your daddy always say you listen to a horse,
he'll tell you how he feels.
- OK. Thanks, Mark.
- (Horse whinnies)
(Tannoy announcement in background)
I don 't know, boy. I'll tell you, I don 't know.
The leg feels fine,
but she keeps... she keeps jumping at that.
She wants to get back in her stall.
Vamos, Sonya. Vamos.
Venga, venga!
She gonna race today?
Of course she's gonna race today.
Hello, Mr Palmer.
Nice to see you.
Wasn 't sure you were coming today.
I er... I don 't believe I've ever met...
Prince Tariq Abal.
PALMER:
Well, well, Sonya is just as pretty as she is fast.
Sir, I'll meet you at our box
after I talk with my staff.
- What's the story here?
- She's acting funny.
Some heat in that right front this morning
llm not sure if she wants to run today
I don 't feel any heat in that leg.
What did the vet say?
The vet and paddock judge
both passed her as fine, but...
Well, good. That's all that matters.
Sir, I'm just saying
I don 't... I don 't think she should go today.
Prince Tariq flew his personal Tr3Tr
8,000 miles...
for what?
I don 't know,
to win the Jansen Handicap, I guess.
To beat his brother Sadir.
Tariq only flies in if he can see one of his horses
run against one of his brother's horses.
We're messing with a champion two-year-old
who's won her first two races this year.
This'll make three.
She's a little star, no doubt about it.
She's a lot more than a star, Everett.
I'm listening to the horse.
She's telling me she could do better with rest.
You'd do better by listening to me.
Look, she's a nice horse.
But I've spent millions
developing a stable of horses for Prince Tariq
so he can beat his brother.
Now, I know you got big plans...
but just do your job.
OK?
Daily maintenance,
overseeing the workouts - your job.
Picking her races - my job
Are we good?
- Yeah, we're good.
- Good.
She's morning-line favourite.
(Claps) Let's go.
Have one of the Mexicans walk her round
to settle her.
OK, Mark.
You heard the boss. Let's go.
(Fanfare in background)
TANNO Y: Now the big race
the Jansen Handicap starting on the track
No 2 Ocean Blend
carrying two pounds over weight
You own a horse, sweetie?
This is just for owners.
Cale
Cale.
Huh.
BALON: Hey-hey.
- Hey.
See her, honey? Look at that. No.5, right there.
- That's our girl
CALE: Think she'll win?
- I got $10 that says she's gonna win.
- (Laughs)
TANNO Y: From the Wishman Stables
here's Rapid Cat
Dark Fire on one of the outside gates
(Horses whinnying)
Here we go, baby.
(Snorts and stamps hooves)
(Race bell rings)
TANNO Y: And away they go!
Easy. Nice and easy now.
(Shouts of encouragement)
MANNY:
She's fourth Come on sweetheart
- Yeah.
- Go on, Sonya!
M aypo t h s s yo u r day, h o h oy Co m o o h
(Excited shouts from crowd)
Bring it home, baby.
Come on, Sonya.
- Yeah!
- (Squeals)
(Whinnies)
(Shocked gasps)
(Crowd falls silent)
(Whinnies)
Oh, Manny.
- We gotta put her down, Ben.
- It's OK. I got it here.
Cannon bone.
- Look llm sorry Ben We gotta put her down
- She all right?
- Whoa!
- Hey, easy, girl. Easy.
Come on, it's OK.
Not here. Not here.
Take her back to her stall, but not here.
- Come on
- Attagirl
(Sonya whinnies)
(Heavy rain)
- Ben, I can 't put her down until you sign this.
- I want some X-rays taken.
Cale, come here. Come on.
Stay out of the way.
What's the point? She's finished.
B N do not be e ve th s
I told him.
- What? What'd you tell me?
- I warned you she wasn 't right.
- You put the saddle on her.
- What? Wait a minute!
Lunderstand, it's sad when these things happen.
- Sad?
- Yes, sad. This is an athlete.
Well, then, you just knowingly killed
a $ Tr50,000 athlete.
- We need to make a move here.
- Tell me
It's her cannon bone
You pushed her. She'd have run
in the Breeders' Cup. She was special.
Now s h o: S got a p roko h og a h d t: S ovo r
You don 't care about anybody, do you?
Horses or people.
Well, in fact, I do, Ben. That's why I'm giving you
the opportunity to find a new job.
- You firing me?
- And take your Mexicans with you.
They're men, Palmer. They got names.
(Sonya whinnies)
- You owe me money.
- You'll get your cheque, first of the month.
You pay me now
9000 for the last three months
Here's six.
Six. Take it or leave it.
I'll leave it. We agreed on nine.
You're three short.
- Wait for a cheque.
- I'm not waiting!
For God's sake, please put that horse down!
Dan, Dan, Dan, wait.
I'll take the 6,000 and the horse.
$6,000 and a dead horse
and I never have to hear from you again?
- That's right.
- Take the money
(Sonya whinnies)
Sedate her, Dan.
Put her down heavy for the night.
It'll cost you 400 just to dispose of her body.
Balon hook up a trailer
- You got a hard head, like your old man.
- Cale, go to the truck.
Living in that horse farm with no horses.
Balon, just...
Manny, take her out to the truck.
Delusional. It's a disease with you Cranes.
Get out before it rubs off on you.
BEN: Manny?
- Yeah?
Go get the old man.
Tell him it's an emergency.
Hi, Balon. I need the heavy winch,
the tow and easy sling to get her in this stall.
- OK where's that?
- It 's in the back stall there
- Oh OK I got it
LIL: Where have you been?
God, I've been so worried. Honey.
- What's going on?
- I had a horse go down.
Oh, my God.
- Anything else, boss?
- Give Balon a hand, will you?
- Manny?
- Hello.
MAN: What can you geniuses
be calling an emergency at night in the rain?
This about a horse?
Good night.
Inever ask you for anything.
That's right.
I haven 't heard from you in months.
That's why your business is so great.
I got a filly in there
with a broken cannon bone, Pop.
Thoroughbred?
Raco r?
Put her down.
You had a horse
with a shattered cannon bone once.
You harnessed it up somehow,
the leg healed and that horse was fine.
That was a long time ago.
You were just a little boy, Benjamin.
But I remember it. It worked.
He was an old lead pony.
Healed just enough to walk around for
a few more years before I finally put him down.
Which is what you'd do
if you had any sense at all.
Let's get her in the stall.
LIL: Cale.
- I'm going to need to help them, Mom.
Cale, I'm gonna spend the night with her.
You go on inside with Mom.
BEN: All right.
BALON: Right up there?
- Yeah.
- Right, Manny?
BEN: Can you get up to the big winch Manny?
Let's hook it up. Come on.
(Exhales)
- Was it a hard fall?
- Hard enough.
She didn 't get bumped or anything.
She... she just went down.
That's the one from the track
And my X -rays confirm it
It's a spiral fracture of the cannon bone.
BEN: But it is nondisplaced
- She'll never race again?
No, honey.
- But she might walk again
- There's a chance. It's up to her.
Try and keep her calm.
Stable rest.
That cast I put on her should hold.
We'll go really easy on her, Doc.
- Let's stay close on this
- You got it
All right, let's pull all the harness stuff.
Put the straps and the pulley in the tack room.
Ben, when Mr Palmer fired you,
us yesterday, well...
We all don 't have no jobs.
I'm sorry, guys. I forgot. Here.
There's a thousand each.
What's wrong?
Well, we train racehorses, right?
And... she's not going to race no more, so...
So why hang around to help you
get a broken racehorse to walk?
(Manny and Balon whisper)
You know who this horse was sired by?
Dreamcatcher.
You know who that was?
Pop, w h o was Droa m catc h o r?
Won the Dubai World Cup in '96.
Won seven of 11 graded stakes
and over $3,000,000.
We get her healed enough
to breed her to a decent stud,
sell that yearling for... I don 't know, maybe...
If it's a colt with good confirmation, maybe 300.
B N $300,000
You two be interested in a piece of $300,000?
(Bot h c h u ck o)
M A N N Y Yeah
How about it, Pop?
BALON: OK. Looks good to me.
We're all done.
BEN: Take it up.
Got it?
(Whinnies)
Good girl.
Good Sonya
Easy. Easy, girl. Easy, girl.
(Sonya whinnies)
One, two, three...
CHILD: Bye, Cale.
- Bye.
One, two, three.
OK, that's good. That's good.
She's doing great
- She OK?
- She's OK
(Whinnies)
- Whoa, whoa. You all right?
- Fine.
- You OK? She kick you?
BALON: Easy.
Come on. It's OK, honey.
- How is she?
- She's OK.
What were you doing?
She's... she's not a pet, Cale.
She's what I do for work now
so you 'll have to leave her be all right?
Llm sorry
- You sure you're all right?
- Fine.
(Slurps)
(Chomps)
(Sonya snorts)
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You make all that money
and eat as much pie as you want?
(Chuckles) Yeah, I can 't find a better job.
Manny's gonna take me
to watch him ride a racehorse.
And tonight I'm gonna muck out Sonya's stall.
- I'm thinking about painting it.
- Nice to have a horse, huh?
Especially after Dad said,
"There will never be another horse
in this farm as long as I live."
Did Pop tell you that?
Don 't you listen to everything Pop says.
There's two sides to every story.
Pop said Dad's the best horseman.
Says he has a gift.
Well, that's true.
We all know that's true.
- Hey.
- Hello.
Whoa, Zephyr. Whoa, boy.
Thanks, Mike.
- What'd you think about that?
- That was fast.
- Nice boots.
- Ah, Thank you.
Oxo rc so a co u p o o f h o rsos fo r a fow ow h o rs
- Pretty cool, huh?
- Yeah.
You ever ride in races?
Couple of times I did.
- But no more.
- Why?
Er...
I have bad dreams.
Three years ago I got my first real race.
I ran fifth.
What was the name of the horse?
Downtown Swing.
- It was amazing.
- Did you ever ride him again?
Yeah. In our second race,
I was flying into that first turn.
And then I looked under my arm
to see if I was clear on the rail.
When I looked back up,
there was a horse swerving into me.
My left foot came out of the iron,
I fell to the ground...
and I got run over by three horses.
Broke both shoulders, sternum...
four ribs
punctured a lung.
You never raced again.
(Sighs heavily)
You know, at night, when I fall asleep...
...I dream I'm in a big race on a very fast horse.
And I look to my left foot,
it slips out of the iron and I begin to fall.
But... before I hit the ground, I wake up.
- But you still exercise racehorses.
- Yeah.
Just...
It's just me and the horse alone on the track,
free.
No-one to bother us. It's much better that way.
- I'm sorry about your nightmares, Manny.
- It 's OK
It's God's way of telling me no more racing.
(Slurping)
Good night.
From Mom.
I'm good, honey. Just put it down there.
Cale?
Will you grab that roll of wire
underneath the fence?
Yeah.
You can just hang on to it there.
Pop said this farm used to be beautiful.
This farm was beautiful.
200 acres. One of the nicest in Versailles.
- See all that over there?
- Yeah.
Well, that was ours.
Pop: S ow h od so m o roa y h co raco m a ros
Big, beautiful female horses.
Waveland, Blue Jezebel and Miss Moffett.
That's right.
Pop said he built those stalls
and filled them with horses.
Yeah, he made a good living selling yearlings.
But you wanted to keep the yearlings
and race 'em, right?
Well, it got kind of hard,
watching horses born on this farm
go on to win big races for somebody else.
So you got Pop to keep some yearlings
so you could train 'em, race 'em.
You don 't just keep 'em, Cale. They're not free.
I'm going to brush down Sonya.
Cale Crane.
Yes, ma'am?
- Working on your creative writing assignment?
- Yes, ma'am.
What's your story about?
It's about a king...
...and his castle...
and a magic horse.
Bye.
She can stand on it.
Not for long. But she can stand on it.
I'll run a couple more tests but I don 't see
any reason she can 't breed. She looks good.
You helped her, Cale.
She's gonna have a baby. Yeah!
I'll see you Friday.
Well, I'm gonna call in a favour.
(Whispers) Go, Cale.
- Go.
So where are you going?
I'm gonna go see an old friend.
About a stud for Sonya?
Yeah.
About a stud.
You wanna come?
Yeah. I'll come.
Fusaichi Pegasus.
He won the Kentucky Derby.
Do you see him? That's Fusaichi.
Giant's Causeway.
Johannesburg.
He won the Breeders' Cup Juvenile.
You learn all that from Pop, too?
He's a beautiful horse.
Hey, Bill.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you.
- This is my daughter Cale.
CALE: Hi
- Nice to meet you, Cale.
- Nice to meet you, too.
So, you call two months ago telling me you got
a race mare needs to be covered, then nothing.
Well, it's been a pretty long road with that filly,
Bill, but she's ready to go now.
- So, you still going to be able to help me out?
- Right over here.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
are you ready for the world's greatest stud?
Come on, Todd. Bring him on out.
That's not...
- What is that?
BILL: This here is Thunder Pants
Honey, Thunder Pants is a teaser pony.
He's gonna help Sonya get ready
to go into the breeding shed with a stallion.
- Thanks, Bill.
- Hey, Cale,
want to meet the stallion I picked for you?
Cale, meet Grand Slam.
Grand Slam?
Unbelievable.
So, what do you think?
Well,
I think it's Grand Slam.
Everyone at Ashford
has a lot of respect for your family.
I explained your situation
and they want to do you the favour of a lifetime.
I just... I don 't know what to say.
- Say you'll have the filly here first week in May.
- You got it.
That week's the only shot you get.
He's booked till next year.
And you got to send me half of the 15,000
by the end of the week.
That's er... 15,000?
Well, Grand Slam's
normal stud fees are 200,000.
- We're waiving that.
- Yeah, I know.
The 15 doesn 't even cover
our costs in insurance.
No no Bill it 's an amazing offer I just didn 't
I'm wondering, though,
if maybe I couldn 't give you a share in the foal,
maypo to covo r a t h o oxpo h sos,
whatever they are
BILL: We just don 't do that
Not in a case like this
Are you saying you want to call it off?
No, Bill, I just...
Bill, I don 't have the money.
I am sorry, Ben.
- I didn 't fully know your situation
- That's OK Bill
Listen, I... I really appreciate the try.
I'm gonna call. All right? Thanks.
Let's go, honey.
POP: Llve never seen Grand Slam up close
CALE: He's got muscles everywhere
POP: What'd he say?
He's a horse.
I know. What'd he say?
"I am a great champion."
"When I ran, the ground shook.
The sky opened and mere mortals parted."
"The way to victory.
And I met my owner in the winner's circle."
"Where he put a blanket of flowers on my back."
You remembered that?
Sport of kings, you know that?
They call horse racing the sport of kings.
- So when you gonna take me to the races?
- I don 't go any more.
Haven 't been in years.
So I can take the Racing Form
and The Blood-Horse, right?
Your dad doesn 't want me
teaching you about horses.
So I should leave 'em?
You should stuff 'em under your shirt.
OK.
Cale, in that cabinet above the sink...
Yeah.
Is there a coffee can?
Mm-hm.
- Bring it to your dad, would you?
- Sure
- Good night.
- Good night
- Pop wanted me to give this to you.
- Thanks, hon.
- I'm gonna eat my dessert in the barn.
- All righty.
- What the hell is this?
- Coffee can
- You expect me to use it?
- Only flavour I got.
You're unbelievable.
There's almost $20,000 there.
You watched me sell this farm off bit by bit
till there was nothing left.
Why are you doing this?
Damned if I know.
Breed the horse, Ben.
Picking up that filly was the gutsiest thing
I've seen you do in years.
Guts?
I took the biggest swing I could and I struck out.
- And you gave up.
- I'm broke, Pop!
What do you expect me to do?
I expect you to take the money,
trust your instincts and breed the horse.
- You told me to put her down
- But you didn 't.
- Cos you're a horseman.
- Oh, don 't blow smoke...
Are you gonna spend your life
shovelling horse squat for sheiks
or are you gonna get back in the game?
Don 't think I don 't know
what's going on here with you and Cale.
It's in her blood, Ben.
Cale's a beautiful kid.
Stop filling her head with horse stories.
Horse stories are all I got.
Keep 'em to yourself.
I'll pay you back when the foal sells.
Any chance you'll keep the foal?
Race him or her?
No, we're going to sell the foal.
But we still have Sonador.
Sonador?
Yeah It 's her full name
Sonador.
(Whispers) Sonador.
I think it's Spanish.
Spanish for "Dreamer".
Good night, Dreamer.
- OK, I got it.
- I'm going to Pop's.
Lil, how many days they give you
down at the diner?
I got Monday, Wednesday and Friday.
But I could take more.
Palmer called around. Shut me out everywhere.
I can 't find any work
I'm gonna have to take down the sign.
The real estate sign?
It's all been sold.
The only land we got left to sell, we're sitting on.
Here's the first letter of foreclosure.
- Morning.
- Hello Cale
- Hey Doc
- Balon. Manny.
Sonya's gonna make us some money huh?
This horse,
she gonna make a special baby, huh?
- Is Ben around?
- Yeah. I'm right here.
All right. Just got off the phone with Bill.
We're back on.
Going to breed her to Grand Slam.
Ben, I've completed my tests
and I've got some bad news for you.
What?
She's infertile.
She's not gonna have a baby now?
No, h o h oy, s h o: S h ovo r go h h a h avo pap os
I'm sorry, guys.
I'm sorry, Sonya.
T: S O K
It's almost dawn.
You 've been up all night
What was I thinking, Lil?
Trying to breed that horse?
Cale loves that horse.
That's good, cos that little filly just ruined us.
That little filly is the best thing
that's ever happened around here.
Come on, Lil.
Since she's been in that barn,
we have a family.
For the first time in years.
Look, I'll work seven days a week at the diner
if it means you'll spend time with your daughter.
Can 't you see how much
she wants to be with you?
And I know that your dad disappointed you,
but that does not mean
that you have to disappoint her
This has nothing to do with my father.
- No, it has everything to do with him.
- You're wrong.
The truth is, if Cale hadn 't been with me
that night, I'd have left that horse on the track
and let 'em put the horse down -
and I'd still have my job.
Cale...
Cale?
Come on. Cale?
Honey, can I come in?
Come on, let's just give her some time.
Cale?
Come on honey Open the door
Please?
She'll come downstairs when she's ready.
We're going to run away.
We're going to run far away.
There you go.
We're going for a walk.
Cale...
(Door bangs)
Stop, Sonya!
Sonya, stop!
Hang on, Cale.
Cale!
Dad she won 't stop!
I can 't make her stop!
Cale, hang on!
Please...
Cale...
Cale!
Jump.
Jump!
I got you. I got you.
I got you.
Are you all right? You OK?
I got you sweetie
I got you.
- Is she OK?
- She's all right.
It's all right, baby.
T: S O K
- Are you OK, honey?
- Yeah.
- Huh?
- Yes, I'm OK.
Hey, Ben?
How's Cale doing?
- She's all right?
- She OK?
Yeah. She's fine.
OK.
- Could we talk to you for a minute, boss?
- All right. How's Sonya?
She was running back and forth
along the fence and...
- We were following her...
- Balon, did she break down?
How bad is she?
Well, in the truck it said that she's about,
I don 't know, a quarter mile.
And, well, she...
She was getting faster and faster.
Yeah
She's looking pretty strong sir
What are you?
Well...
You saying she should race?
You can load her up, Joe.
M a r a h: S Sto r m p roko h o r og
th o sa m o way as So h ya
Same fracture, same location.
Who's Mariah's Storm?
- She was a great racehorse.
- She sure was.
- Made a big comeback, too.
- Beat Serena's Song in the graded stakes.
When I saw Sonya's X-rays,
I thought I ought to show 'em to you.
- That bone is healed.
- Oh, yeah. That leg's good.
Now, getting her back into racing shape,
that's up to you.
Good luck.
Thanks a lot, Doc.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Well, she's not favouring that leg.
Ow: S s h o ook?
She looks big.
- Big as in strong?
- No, big as in fat.
That's mean. That's mean.
You shouldn 't say that.
She's been eating too many Popsicles.
- What?
You didn 't know I knew about that, did you?
(Laughs)
- 3Tr and two.
- 3Tr two.
36.
(Clicks stopwatch)
What do you think?
Well, in five weeks,
best she's done is three furlongs in 3Tr seconds.
Not fast enough to win much, is it?
Maybe a cheap claimer at Bluegrass Downs.
She was a graded stakes horse.
Now she's a claimer.
It might be a good idea to run her in one.
See if she perks up in a real race.
Yeah, I've been thinking about that.
You don 't think anybody would claim her,
do you?
Would you buy a horse that broke its leg?
You Know, she might win.
Could be easy money.
COMMENTATOR: And away they go.
Away to a beautiful start.
And Super from the extreme outside.
Coming from behind is Sonador.
- Her leg looks pretty good.
- Y eah.
COMMENTATOR: They make their way around
the first turn and head onto the back stretch.
- Come on, Sonador! Come on.
- Can you see her?
COMMENTATOR: Running in fourth is Sonador.
And Sonador's now on the move on the outside.
Then we have back in fifth. All For Nothing.
Come on, baby.
Come on, Mike, change your lead now.
COMMENTATOR:
They make their way around the far turn.
- Go!
- Come on, girl.
On the inside comes Obvious Favourite.
Come on, Sonya, only three furlongs to go now.
She's coming up!
Major Easy and Obvious Favourite...
Show her the stick.... now. Get her out of there.
Come on, girl!
(Neighing)
Third!
- Third.
- Yeah.
That's great.
A minute 1 3 seconds. A little slow.
but it's the beginning.
You Know, if Mike wouldn't have been boxed in,
I think.she would've won, sir.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org