Valhalla, this is Thor.
We have visual on
a possible high-value target.
Thor, this is Valhalla.
We're seeking positive ID
on target traveling in convoy
and we're pushing
more assets your way.
Contact Loki on secondary net.
Loki, this is Thor.
Target is located at grid coordinates
two-four-Tango-Kilo-Bravo
one-two-four-five-six-seven-three-niner.
Confirm you have visual.
Verifying target ID.
Electro-optic and
infrared sensors are online.
- Confirming target.
- SecDef is arriving now.
Mr. Secretary, this way, sir.
Attempting cell phone link
to moving target.
Stand by for data feed.
Stand by for audio.
Got it.
Now, don't tell me you spotted the beard
in the middle of a goddamn sandstorm.
- Is it really him?
- We're confirming that now, sir.
Sir, audio is coming up now.
- Verifying voice pattern match.
- What do we have here, Sergeant?
Four males. One of them is speaking
in a Rakhshani dialect,
consistent with our intel on al-Khoei.
Sir, it's just coming up.
"Thirty-seven percent" and "probable"
don't belong in the same sentence.
I'm not taking this to the President.
CIA and NCTC concur it is the target,
based on reliable intel from the Brits.
They're pulling off the highway.
Criteria is not met. Recommend abort.
We have an abort recommendation.
If it's him, this guy comes out of hiding
every couple of years at best.
Sir, target is appearing
around the northeast corner.
We've got AK-47 s,
RPGs and Chaparral guided missiles.
This is a training camp, Mr. Secretary.
- Wait. Wait. Print. 51%.
- 51%.
- Abort rec still holds.
- All other PID options exhausted.
What do you suggest we do, sir?
Ls that a weapons cache?
Sir, the placement of
the stones around the pit,
marker for the five pillars of lslam.
I think it's a funeral.
For Christ's sake.
Counsel, how many ways would this
violate the Geneva Convention?
We can invoke hors de combat.
There's no independent intel verifying
that this is, in fact, a funeral.
Signal's got the President
from Air Force One, sir.
Mr. President,
we have a 51% identity match
on Majid al-Khoei.
The bad news is, there's
some possibility he's at a funeral.
You should also be aware
we have an abort recommendation.
But the Joint Chiefs are urging a go.
All right, what's your recommendation?
Sir, we measure success by
the least amount of collateral damage.
At 51% probability, the risk is too high.
And if it is al-Khoei and he walks,
I'm putting our people at risk.
You have a go.
Thank you, Mr. President.
- We're weapons hot!
- We have weapons hot!
- Loki, you are cleared to engage.
- Repeat, weapons hot. PID.
We have handshake with the
MQ9 Reaper. Sending you images now.
- Loki, target coordinates received.
- Yes, sir. Switching to IR sensor.
Target is lased.
Master arm on.
Missiles away.
Ten seconds to impact.
You got to make a choice, fellas.
Who are you going to be? Boys or men?
- I'm out on this one.
- Why?
- 'Cause I'm broke.
- Come...
How do I know you don't have
something great under there?
Kwame just paired the board.
I'm floating on the river here.
Look at the table.
I don't know. I'm supposed to take my
girl out later. It's a lot of money.
Your girl out? Who's that?
- Elaine?
- Yeah.
You guys have been going out
for a while.
How long?
- Couple months.
- Couple months? Wow.
- That's big. You have sex with her yet?
- Kinda.
- What the hell is "kinda"?
- "Kinda"?
- Personal question.
- Okay, well, listen.
Let me ask you a question.
What are you going to do tonight?
Fish filet and a Coke?
Go to Blockbuster,
rent a little romantic comedy,
go back to Mom's house,
sit on the couch?
- How'd you know?
- Well, that's what you do.
You're a dependable person.
That's what you're going to do.
You know what you should do?
You need to lay down some real green
and treat your lady right.
You know, you need to take her
to a nice place.
Red Lobster. Olive Garden.
Tablecloths. Soft music.
And then you skip
this Blockbuster thing.
Girls want to go out. Especially a girl
as cute as your girl, you know?
She wants to be seen.
That's why she dresses up.
So you take her to the movies.
- A little popcorn-drink combo.
- True. True.
Elaine might want a hot dog and some
nachos, so you shell out for that, too.
And then before you know it,
she's cozying up
the way she never would've
at her mom's house, you know?
- Preach it. Preach it.
- Now all of a sudden, look.
Gino Romero's walking tall
with Elaine yank-my-Dickinson,
- all because he dared to dream tonight.
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
And he became a man.
And that's the choice.
- Yes.
- And that's what's on the table.
This is the dream right here.
Are you a man?
- I'm with you.
- Okay, here we go.
- I'm with you. Twenty?
- Twenty.
Big boy game.
Call.
- Cowboys over aces, big Jer.
- Wow. Wow.
- Didn't see that coming, huh?
- Yeah, that's a tough one.
This is a tough one, too.
Four bullets, baby.
Get out of here!
You baited me into that, Jer. Come on!
- That's the way it goes.
- So what happened to Red Lobster?
No, I guess it's Mama's house
for you tonight.
But look, I saved you 40 bucks.
And now Elaine won't have to shell out
for herpes medication.
Break's over, bitches.
Freitag missed his shift again.
- Someone's on collator duty.
- Great.
All right, well, gentlemen,
l'll give you a chance to win some of
this back tomorrow. Enjoy yourselves.
All right, man.
Hey there. Welcome to Copy Cabana.
How can I help you?
I couldn't get the machine
past the main menu.
- That machine there?
- Yeah.
Did you swipe your credit card
to the left, sir?
- Didn't do that.
- Well, that's your problem.
Why don't you try it again?
Cell phone users, beware.
The Federal Bureau of Investigation
can now hear everything you're saying,
even when your cell phone is turned off.
Authorities can now activate
the microphone inside your phone,
allowing them to eavesdrop
on you and your conversations.
Experts say the only way around this
is to take the battery out of the device.
- The death toll now stands at 14.
- Now arriving at Union Street.
- Stand clear of the doors.
- Excuse me.
Watch your step, please.
Did you drop this?
Yes.
- It's hard to do on a train, you know!
- Doors closing.
Standing passengers...
Come on, come on, come on.
Jerry?
Mrs. Wierzbowski! I was just...
I thought you might have been sleeping.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- So... But I have...
I have some rent here.
- Here you go.
- Yeah, some is good. All is better.
Well, that's most of it. Here.
$1, $1, $1...
No, no, no. Look. Here's a five there.
- Five.
- Yeah.
Where is girl? I don't see her no more.
You know you're the only woman for me.
No, that's done. She got smart.
- Like the others.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Is woman friend? Answer.
Then see if she give you money for rent.
One second.
Hey, Mom.
What?
- Looks just like him.
- I'm not him.
Six months without a boo or a bah, huh?
Yes, sir.
So where were you this time?
Alaska. Singapore.
I got a job there.
I... I spoke to Stanford.
I pulled some strings.
They said they'd take you back.
Even though you took off...
Two years ago, Dad.
Jerry, you know, it wouldn't kill you
to ask for help once in a while.
You want to have
this conversation now?
- It's Stanford!
- You want to do this today.
You know how many people would kill...
- Today? You want to have this now?
- Fine.
You do whatever you want.
You always have.
You know, I keep thinking,
I'm going to walk in here one day
and I'm not going to feel
like a stranger in my own house.
I don't want your money.
Can I have your attention, please?
Smoking is not permitted on the train.
Chicago is next.
Can't find the keys
and he's late as usual.
- I'm going to have to take you.
- He'll be here.
All right, wait five more minutes.
Help me out here.
We came home last night.
I put the leftovers down.
You turned on the TV. I went over,
said, "No TV, no TV, no TV."
Turned it off.
Came over here.
- Checked the messages.
- Knocked over the phone.
Right, knocked over the phone.
Put it back.
Put the leftovers in the fridge.
Let's go!
I put vitamins in your toiletry bag.
Don't forget to take...
- Two in the morning and two at night.
- That's right.
And your inhaler's
in the back of your bag.
- Sammy!
- Daddy!
Come here. You didn't think
I'd miss the big send-off, do you, huh?
Let's get you on this train.
- This must be your...
- Trumpet.
My God, this weighs, like, 200 pounds.
You carry this yourself?
- Mr. And Mrs. Holloman!
- Miss.
- You just made it.
- Right.
- Here, Sam.
- Thanks.
- Listen to me.
- I have one more here.
All these other kids, right? They're
going to call their moms, too, all right?
They're just going to lie about it.
All right, and eat junk food 'cause this is
your one chance, but brush your teeth.
Mom, you got to stop.
I'm going to miss you, too.
Capitol Limited to D.C. Is
departing now.
Give me a hug.
All aboard.
- I love you so much.
- I love you, too.
- Shine bright, okay?
- Okay.
Rock the house, buddy.
You're going to be great. Okay?
- Okay.
- L'll see you later.
- Bye!
- Have fun in D.C.!
- Bye, Mom!
- Your mom going to be okay?
It's unclear.
I'm so sorry. I got stuck in traffic,
- and I didn't even...
- Don't even say it.
All aboard!
Yes. Five-nine-one-three.
It's here. It's here.
Okay, okay.
- Come on!
- Two seconds. Sorry.
No, wait.
- Hey, hang on a second.
- Sorry.
- You're dropping money.
- Sir, sir!
Big date, you know?
Fingers crossed, huh?
- Here you go. Have a good day!
- Thank you.
- Jerry!
- What?
- So many boxes.
- Boxes?
I had to open your room.
All day they come.
- Big boxes, small boxes.
- My boxes?
I don't know.
Whose boxes would they be?
- All right, okay.
- Look at them there. See in there?
- See, I put them all...
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Listen, I have something for you here.
- Yeah.
This is rent for this month
and next month, too, okay?
- Oh, my.
- Thank you.
Hello?
The FBI will arrive
at your apartment in 30 seconds.
You must flee the premises.
Who... Who is this?
You've been activated, Jerry.
- Who the hell is this?
- Your compliance is vital.
How did you get this number?
You now have 24 seconds.
Leave your residence.
Your destination, the Mathis train
station. We will guide you from there.
What is this?
The evidence in your
apartment is irrefutable.
- Listen.
- 17 seconds.
I'm going to hang this phone up now.
They'll seek your arrest
for conspiracy, treason...
- I'm hanging this phone up now!
...violating state and local law.
- You tell me how you got this number!
- Maximum penalty, death.
No, none of this is mine!
FBI, FBI, FBI! Get down on the floor!
Get on the ground!
Down now! Get down!
- I didn't do anything!
- Get down!
- Listen!
- Don't move.
It's not mine! Lt's not mine!
This is obviously
some sort of mistake, right?
I mean, I don't know
what I'm doing in this room, sir.
It's cold as hell outside.
- You draw?
- I what?
Do you draw? Do you sketch?
You have ink all over your fingers.
Look, you know you got
the wrong guy, right?
I mean,
this is all some kind of sick joke.
- I don't know what I'm doing here.
- Obviously.
Obviously you have
nothing to do with it, yeah.
Did you love your brother?
Or did you hate him?
Did you admire him?
Was your brother patriotic,
would you say?
When's the last time you saw him?
- Christmas.
- This past Christmas?
- Three Christmases ago.
- Three years, huh?
Well, the phone records show that you
haven't even called him in over a year.
So no text messages?
No smoke signals?
No MySpace or Facebook messages?
Yeah, so what are you trying to say?
We're not...
Are you asking if we're the type of twins
that wear the same shirt to the mall,
hold hands, and things like that? No.
- Sir, I don't even know your name.
- I'm sorry, that was rude of me.
I'm Tom Morgan,
the Supervising Agent assigned
to the Joint Terrorism Task Force.
You think I'm a terrorist?
No, you're a copy boy, aren't you?
- I'm a copy associate.
- Copy associate.
But your brother,
it says here he was a little more,
I guess you'd say, ambitious than you.
Graduated from
the Air Force Academy at 21,
with an advanced degree in parallel
algorithms and quantum electronics.
I don't even know what the hell
that stuff means. Do you?
Cadet wing commander, valedictorian,
plum job in the Public Affairs...
Yeah, no, I know what he did, sir.
Why'd you drop out of school, Jerry?
Did your brother have
any influence on that decision?
No, school just wasn't for me.
No, I mean, who would want
a Stanford education anyway?
More upward mobility
at Copy Cabana, I guess, right?
I see you did a little backpacking.
Singapore, Bali, Indonesia.
Did odd jobs here and there.
So you've been around.
Look, none of this has anything to do
with any of the shit
that was in my apartment.
Why would I send it to myself?
My name is on the lease.
I'd have to be the dumbest terrorist
in the history of the world.
So who deposited the 750?
The...
I don't know who deposited the 750!
God maybe? I thought it was a miracle,
I took the money. That was my mistake.
It was an accident.
Do accidents not happen
in your universe?
Well, the money originated
from the YTBC Bank of...
Well, l'll be darned, Singapore.
Opened with a transfer from
a corporation called The Star of Orion,
- a dummy front for Hezbollah.
- This is all very interesting, sir.
- It has nothing to do with me.
- We find hardware in your apartment.
Latest military spec.
- Airplane manuals.
- I told you about this already.
And 1,200 pounds
of ammonium nitrate fertilizer.
I walked into my apartment...
You planning on becoming
a farmer or something?
I walk into my apartment,
I open the door,
and this shit's all over my apartment.
- It just showed up.
I see. I'm just curious
if your brother knew anything about it.
Of course, we haven't really established
how close you guys were yet, have we?
Well, we were pretty close this morning
when I buried his body in the ground.
Does that establish anything for you?
Somebody set me up.
Why is that so hard
for you to understand?
- "Somebody."
- A woman called me on the phone.
She told me I was going to be arrested.
"A woman." Your mom? Who?
I don't know! Lf I knew, I would tell you!
I don't know!
Here's the thing, Jerry.
This is a bad time to be
in the terrorism business.
You read the paper.
Who do you think is winning?
Your Miranda rights or my right to keep
you in this room as long as I want to?
I don't care if you tell me
the truth about your brother.
I don't care who you work for.
'Cause no matter what you tell me,
you're in a shitload of trouble, son.
This is insane. I work for Copy Cabana.
Yeah, that's what you said.
Listen, I get one night out
in a decade, ladies,
I am not wasting it on Lemon Drops.
- Okay.
- Buck up. Let's go.
Oh, gosh.
I want updates. Catfights, booty calls,
somebody tell me they got lucky.
Hey, ladies. See that guy over there?
He'd like to buy you a round.
Hell, no.
He's got light beer written all over him.
- He's cute.
- Come on.
He's a suit. No.
You sure?
- Come on.
- Who is it?
The one man in my life
who hasn't let me down.
- That's sweet.
- All right, don't drink those without me.
Hello?
There's a McDonald's across the street.
Look in the window.
What is this?
Would you risk your life for your son?
Rachel Holloman,
you've been activated.
- This isn't funny.
- Your compliance is vital.
- Who are you?
- We will derail his train,
unless you do what you're told.
What is this?
Don't go back inside the restaurant.
- What?
- There's a black Porsche Cayenne
parked at the northeast corner
of this block.
The keys are in the ignition.
Start walking.
Oh, my God.
911.
State the nature of your emergency.
Yeah, some woman just called me.
I have... I have no idea who she is.
She was telling me that...
Your phone is being monitored.
Disobey again and your son dies.
Hey, Grant, I can't read this Shaw file.
- Grant!
- Excuse me.
Listen, my eyes aren't getting any better
and these screens are getting smaller.
Could you please find me
something I can read?
I can make the text bigger
on your screen.
No, no, no. I'm talking about paper.
Remember, like in the olden times?
- Paper. Okay.
- Yeah.
Agent Morgan. Zoe Perez,
Air Force Special Investigations.
Ethan Shaw, the twin,
he was one of ours.
Yeah.
OSI said they were sending a liaison.
Can you walk and talk
at the same time?
L'll do my best.
File says he died in a traffic accident.
Truck ran a light, corner of
Constitution and 10th, Northwest D.C.
So truck ran a light,
his brother gets 750 large
and enough hardware
to start his own Costco,
five hours after enemy
chatter hits the roof.
I mean, don't you find that
a little coincidental?
What if it's a decoy? To distract us from
something 50 times bigger.
- Time for your phone call.
- I thought I didn't get one.
Attorney General's office
changed their mind.
Ethan Shaw had a 183 IQ
and yet you had him
as a mid-level press flak.
Why not IT or cyber-warfare?
Are you suggesting
that he was overqualified?
Or that he was somehow slipping intel
to the Copy Cabana?
No, I'm suggesting
that maybe Ethan Shaw
was a superstar rocket scientist genius
who did go wrong,
and the Air Force doesn't want
their dirty laundry flapping in the wind.
Think what you like, but I need to get in
that room and interrogate him myself.
No.
You don't have a choice. Look.
Now, neither of us know if either of
those brothers are guilty or innocent,
so on behalf of the Secretary
of the Air Force, I'm going in that room.
Well, on behalf of
all that fucking bomb equipment
in junior pinhead's apartment,
no, you're not.
We told you to run.
We have planned your escape.
How'd you get on this phone?
Who are you?
Lay flat on the floor immediately.
What the...
What the hell are you talking about?
Four seconds, Jerry.
- No, this is bullshit. I don't...
- Get down now.
Two seconds.
No!
- No! I didn't do this!
- Get down!
Shit.
Standing passengers,
please do not lean against the doors.
...fourteen Americans dead
throughout Europe and the Middle East,
with terror groups insisting
this is just the beginning
of a campaign the West invited
when it allegedly rained bombs
on a religious ceremony
outside the small town of Abda,
near the border of Afghanistan.
Stay on the train for three more stations
and wait at the bottom of the platform.
You will receive...
Doors closing. Standing passengers,
please do not lean against the doors.
- Help!
- Jimmy.
My baby. I need some help. Somebody.
- What?
- You're not listening.
We told you to stay on the train.
- How are you doing this?
- Next stop is Wilson Station.
A black Porsche Cayenne will be
waiting at the northwest exit.
- Listen.
- Get in the passenger seat.
Listen! No, I'm done.
- Hello?
- The man in front of the exit door
in a black coat is a wanted terrorist.
- His name is Jerry Shaw.
- Who is this?
- You Jerry Shaw?
- No, no, no.
Wilson Station. Exit now.
That's the guy!
I said, are you Jerry Shaw?
Hey! Come here!
Watch it!
- Drive the car! Drive the car!
- No!
- I did what you asked me to do!
- I'm not going anywhere...
- You tell... Stop!
...until you tell me my son's safe!
Who's your son?
I don't know what you're talking about!
- L'll kill you if you hurt my son!
- I almost died over this shit!
- Listen, lady, I don't know who...
- Tell me Sam is safe!
Who is... Will you stop hitting me?
Are you the woman
who called me on the phone?
- Did you call me on the phone?
- No. The woman.
- She called you, too?
Drive.
Get out! Now! Get out of the vehicle!
Stop!
- Why is this happening?
- Go, go, go, go, go!
Who are you and
why are people shooting at us?
Drive the car! Clutch!
Accelerate. Turn right, 200 feet.
You have pursuers.
- Yeah, no shit! Who are you?
- No questions.
Turn right now.
So you don't know anything about Sam?
What, you mean your son?
No, I know nothing.
Just like you don't know how to drive.
Use the clutch before you shift,
not while you shift!
I don't need driving lessons
from you, asshole!
What, you drive like this
and I'm the asshole?
Turn left now.
All units. Suspect in a Porsche
Cayenne heading west on Grand.
- All units respond, Code 3.
- There!
Maintain a speed of 50 miles an hour.
Stay in the second lane from the right.
- The light's red!
- Accelerate now.
Get me a roadblock
at Granville and Sheridan.
Oh, shit.
The lights are all turning green.
Holy shit!
- Holy...
- Shit!
Get in close.
Go, go, go!
- Shit!
- Brake. Brake now.
Get in here!
Accelerate to 60 miles per hour.
Clutch. Clutch!
- Use the clutch!
- I'm clutching!
I'm watching, you're not clutching!
- Stop!
- I'm not stopping.
Slow down. Slow down, the light's red.
Don't slow down.
Accelerate to 72 miles per hour.
- Slow down. It's a red light!
- You will make it through.
- Stop!
- No way.
- Brake!
- I can't!
- Stop!
Manual control's been restored.
Continue straight
until you reach Pier 15.
Enter the wrecking yard.
Proceed to the end of the dock.
We will eliminate all obstacles for you.
Watch! Watch! Watch!
- Stay your course.
- Turn!
- Turn right now.
Holy...
Oh, God.
Oh, my God!
- Grab the seat.
- I can't.
- Grab the seat! The seat!
- No, I can't!
No!
The crane will release the car.
If you do not jump, you will drown.
- We have to jump.
- No! No way.
We have to. When I say "go."
Ready?
Go! Jump!
I want both the divers in that water!
- Let's go! Move!
- Let's go, let's go!
Move, move, move!
- Yeah, I already called it in!
- Wait till it clears!
Thirty feet back, that's it!
Yeah, I know,
the Army sent a Black Hawk,
so l'll be there in a couple of hours.
What do you mean,
the car is not registered to anyone?
Check the VIN number again.
Leave your message for Sam,
even though I know it's you, Mom.
Sam? Baby, listen to me.
You need to call me
as soon as you get this message, okay?
Baby, please. I love you.
- What about the girl?
- What?
What about the girl?
Well, the Department of Transpo
tells me that there was
a seven-minute equipment failure
on their traffic cams.
- We didn't get a picture of her.
- Don't tell me that.
- That's what they're telling me!
- I need an ID on that girl.
Do you think they could derail a train?
They changed every traffic light
to get us here.
The woman, she called me
on a stranger's cell phone
who happened to be sitting next to me.
Never met the guy in my life.
You know, and then they broke me out
of maximum security custody
in a way I'm not even gonna describe
to you because it sounds crazy,
and then they lift us off the face of
the Earth and drop us into this shit pile?
She could probably derail a train.
She could probably turn a train
into a talking duck.
And what about these goddamn ghost
cranes that keep helping peewee out?
I mean, they don't just lift cars
up in the air all by themselves
like a giant pair of chopsticks.
I want to know how these things run,
how they're programmed.
What'd you say your name was?
- Rachel.
- I'm Jerry.
- Hello?
- The barge will dock in 14 minutes.
Leave the boatyard with the female.
Take Highway 123 East.
Walk to mile marker 108.
- What? Was it her?
- She called you "the female."
Have Mortuary Affairs freeze everything
belonging to Ethan Shaw.
- No personal effects to next of kin.
- You, Due Process!
- Bye.
- What do you have on Ethan Shaw?
I have a name. It's Agent Perez.
And l'll answer that question
when I get back from D.C.
- Wait a minute. What's in D.C.?
- Shaw's private quarters.
I need you to stay here.
I'm not losing my link to Ethan Shaw.
Maybe I haven't made this clear.
I don't work for you.
I work for the Air Force.
Keep your phone on,
l'll keep you updated.
If you're staring at me, it better be
because I'm the goddamn suspect.
Because if I don't get some good leads
soon, you're all gonna be demoted
into something that's gonna require
touching shit with your hands.
Now, let's get going. We got work to do.
Hexamethylene.
Our latest chemical explosive.
One single tiny crystal,
80 times more powerful than C4.
Odorless, undetectable.
And best of all, it can be
cut down in size for stealth operations.
This valve is a sonic trigger.
The sound frequency
triggers the explosion.
Each trigger is programmed
to have a unique
frequency specific
only to one Hex crystal.
That frequency triggers the explosion.
Yeah.
We recently received approval
to begin shipping to the field.
Two hundred units
are shipping out today.
- Sign right here.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
The package you've just received
contains a small metal valve.
Open the package.
- Okay.
- Remove the valve
and follow our instructions precisely.
- You've received the package.
- Yes, ma'am, it just arrived.
- What kind of stone is this?
- No questions.
Cut the stone and place the setting
according to the specifications
we sent you.
I'd just dropped my son off at the train.
I was out having drinks with my
girlfriends when the call came.
- What about you?
- The first call came to my apartment.
- After the boxes?
- Yeah.
Well, then this whole thing's
obviously gotta be about your brother.
- Really, it's that obvious, huh?
- I mean, you got all this stuff.
The weapons, the cash,
the airplane manuals.
- Okay.
- He was your twin.
- They sent it to the wrong brother.
- Right.
So you're implying
my brother's a terrorist.
I'm implying, if not him, then why you?
I'm sorry. I know he just died. I'm not
trying to insult his memory or anything.
No, he hasn't been dead long enough
to be a memory, Rachel.
If you knew my brother,
you'd laugh all day at the idea
that he was a terrorist or a spy
or whatever else you're saying...
- How do you know?
- Because he's my brother.
That's something you would know
about your brother.
Well, when's the last time
you talked to him?
I don't need this. Hey, listen. Hey!
I don't have to explain myself to you.
- Is your son a terrorist?
- Yeah, my son's a terrorist.
Yeah, well, he's just as likely
to be a terrorist as my brother.
And let's not forget you in all this. Why
are you here? What's your day job?
- I know it isn't manual shift driver.
- I'm a paralegal.
- I don't have a connection to anything.
- Paralegal?
How do I know you're not lying to me?
What does a paralegal do?
The same thing as the guys
with their names on the door,
except I do it for $11 an hour,
so they can bill 200.
That nail it for you, Sherlock?
That still doesn't explain why
we're walking out here...
- I don't know why the hell I'm out here!
- Yeah, I know...
Hey!
- Are you Jerry Shaw?
- Who are you?
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
- I sent the package like she asked.
- Wait, what package?
- What is that?
- Now she wants me to drive you?
- Who, "she"?
- I won't. I'm done!
- You know "she"?
- Wait.
- Stay right there.
- Get back.
- Here. Here's the address.
- Why are you attack...
- Here. Here are the keys.
Take the goddamn van!
- You think I'm going to...
- Who's doing this?
...do this because I'm lranian?
I am American. I'm finished! I'm done!
- What? What are you talking about?
- You take it!
- What are you talking about?
- I won't do this because I can't.
- Hello?
- Stop him now, or he will die.
Listen to me,
what are you talking about?
- You try to do this without me!
- How are you seeing us right now?
- Stop him now.
- What is she saying?
Stop. Hey! You gotta stop!
- Wait!
- You gotta stop!
- You killed that man.
- Desertion is not an option.
Take the van.
Drive to Indianapolis, Indiana.
72 West 56th Street.
Arrive no later than 11:00 a.m.
- Welcome.
- Hello. Agent Perez.
- To the right?
- Yes, ma'am.
- ID, ma'am.
- OSI.
I ordered a freeze on Ethan Shaw's
personal effects. What's going on?
Orders to sanitize came down
from the Two Star.
Okay, I'm countermanding.
Thank you. L'll take that.
- Tell your guys to clear out.
- Who are you?
This scene's part of
a federal investigation
with national security ramifications.
This your log?
- Yes, it is.
- Okay, my name is Agent Perez.
You can take this up
with your superiors.
- Clear the room!
- You guys move out.
No gloves?
Get statements from everybody.
- Yes, ma'am.
- And find out who this Two Star is.
I mean, come on, really!
Sir! We have a positive ID.
Okay.
The skin was pretty fried,
but we still managed to get
a partial print that matches
to a Ranim Khalid.
He's a United States citizen, registered
Republican, and he owns a music store.
- The guy's cleaner than lvory Snow.
- Got something here.
- That's a bone mic.
- Hello.
Military grade.
He didn't get that on eBay.
Someone was talking to him.
We have a cyber-terrorist here.
Someone's already inside
our computer systems,
hacking into the power grid,
traffic cams, automated cranes.
There's no way the boy
and the girl did this alone.
- Agent Zoe Perez?
- Yes.
United States Air Force
Security Forces. Please come with us.
- What's this about?
- Get in the car.
Violence has broken out
in the Middle East as militants accuse
the United States
of launching American missiles
to demolish a village in Baluchistan,
killing innocent civilians.
The attack has triggered a
series of retaliatory suicide bombings
against American embassies abroad.
Early reports indicate the American
death toll now stands at 56,
with threats of further violence
here at home.
Officials...
What's he doing on a train, your kid?
He goes to a music magnet.
His school's on a tour of Washington.
They're playing at the Kennedy Center.
Wow. That's big. And you just...
Well, why'd you make that noise, "Huh"?
I can't make noises now?
- You think I should have gone.
- He's playing at the Kennedy Center.
- That's kind of a big deal.
- It is a big deal.
So I think maybe one parent
should have gone, that's all I'm saying.
Well, one parent had to work
while the other one does
everything humanly possible
to bail on child support.
But I don't expect you to know
a thing about responsibility.
You know, Rachel, you don't know
the first thing about me.
I know your brother just died,
and whatever he was into
- put my son's life at risk.
- I don't wanna talk about my brother.
- Okay? I'm not kidding.
- I'm not kidding, either.
Jesus, look what happened.
Can you honestly say he had
nothing to do with this?
I'm asking you not to talk about him!
Respect that.
I'm asking you to be honest
with yourself. Your brother's a...
Hey! You can't just walk away!
You can't just leave!
- Yes, I can.
- Now we have 15 minutes to get
- wherever the hell we're going, all right?
- Yeah.
I need you.
I could've gone.
I should have.
You are two minutes behind schedule.
Go to the alley behind the building.
- Go to the armored truck.
- I don't see an armored truck.
There it is.
In 20 seconds, men will exit
the elevator. They will be armed.
One will be carrying a briefcase.
Retrieve it from him,
then return to the van.
- This is insane. I'm not doing this.
- You want us to rob them?
You now have 15 seconds.
Security. What's your emergency?
What are you doing?
I'm not robbing them. Shit.
Put your gun on the floor.
Put your gun on the floor! Look straight.
You want me to blow his head off?
Put the gun on the ground!
We don't wanna hurt you guys.
Just drop the case.
Drop the case and kick it to her!
Yeah, well, you're bringing a shit storm
on your head.
Yeah, we're already in mid shit storm!
Now kick the case.
Okay! Easy.
- Look straight.
- Okay, done.
Kick it!
Okay.
- Don't even think about it!
- Back up.
Easy.
Back up.
Walk over here, stand next to him,
and turn around.
- Stand over here!
- Just take it easy.
Turn around. Turn around. Turn around!
Let's move, let's move!
Come on!
Jerry! Here!
Move, move!
Freeze! Police!
Drop the gun! Drop the gun!
We're security! We just got robbed!
And there they are! We just got robbed!
Move! Get out of the way!
Move!
Get out of the way! Out of the way!
- Hey, watch it, lady!
- Jerry, run!
This way!
- Out of the way!
- Come on!
- Move out of the way!
- Move!
You see that? This way.
- You are Jerry Shaw?
- Yeah.
Please come. Please.
- Thank you.
- Please come in.
Hi.
- Wait. What is that?
- It's a timer.
- For what?
- I don't know.
The only things I can think of
with timers are microwaves and...
And bombs.
You were gonna say bombs.
- Coffeemakers have timers.
- Yeah, Jerry, it's a coffeemaker.
That's great.
We've mobilized every asset
we can get our hands on.
So 12 more confirmed dead?
Yes, sir.
I want hourly sit reps
from General McKenna.
There's a military base
37 miles from that port.
Scramble whatever you can.
- Yes, sir.
- Come with me.
Begging your pardon, sir,
but if you're thinking of taking me off
- the Shaw investigation, I'd...
- Taking you off?
Agent, for the first time
you're being brought onboard.
Back to bus 30 minutes. Okay?
30 minutes.
We're convinced a terrorist attack
on American soil is imminent.
Over the past two days, we've received
over 200 terrorist threats.
All starting the day
that Ethan Shaw died.
An accident. Or not.
You're gonna help us find out.
- Mr. Secretary.
- Gentlemen.
- I didn't think that there was a 36th floor.
- Glad we can still keep some secrets.
I want to know what's in the case.
Is it a bomb?
Go to Macy's.
Customer Service Department.
Two Visa gift cards will be waiting.
You have 25 minutes
to purchase new clothes,
and then re-board the bus
for your next destination.
I'm done taking orders over the phone,
you understand?
Well, that was quick. You done playing
this hide-and-go-seek bullshit?
We are not hiding, Jerry.
To your left is a Circuit City.
Second floor, north corner.
Go inside. Find the Home Theater
Center. We are waiting.
Second floor. She's here.
- Sir.
- Major.
- Major William Bowman.
- Agent Zoe Perez.
Welcome to Eagle Eye.
Looking to upgrade your home theater?
Circuit City has the largest selection
of advanced TVs and home theater
systems. Visit our TV department...
- Hi, welcome to Circuit City. I'm Billy.
- We just need some time alone.
- We're having a sale...
- Okay, Billy, l'll find you later.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Okay, here it is. All right?
I'm done.
- Hello?
- Mr. Shaw,
this is Miss Beck from
Midwest Cellular regarding your...
What is this?
- This is you. This is Jerry Shaw.
- What?
A series of purchases,
preferences, and quantifiable
data points that we define
as your personality.
We monitor every social network,
Internet logs,
instant and text messages,
known associates,
your friends, companions.
Jerry!
E-mails received and sent.
Cell phone usage.
- What happened to Red Lobster?
- We utilize security,
surveillance and traffic cameras
to analyze movements.
We use this data
to form personality profiles.
Yeah, I'm calling actually about...
We know who you are.
...at least 30 minutes late.
Sam doesn't care!
We are everywhere.
What do you mean?
Why do you keep saying "we"?
We the people of the United States...
And so, my fellow Americans...
...in order to form a more perfect union,
establish justice,
insure domestic tranquility,
provide for the common defense...
All programmed options...
- Programmed options?
...sector searches,
and downloaded points of data
will lead to this central command.
You're a computer.
Say hello to our
Autonomous Reconnaissance
Intelligence Integration Analyst.
We call her Aria.
She crunches all our raw intel,
finds patterns,
helps predict the movement
of possible suspects,
right down to behavior, motivation,
even personality.
Transferring primary search function
to auxiliary display.
- Hello, Secretary Callister.
- Aria.
Agent Zoe Perez, Air Force OSI.
You are to assist her
- in her investigation of Ethan Shaw.
- Yes, Mr. Secretary.
Hello, Agent Perez. Perez, Zoe.
Middle name: Soledad.
Official service records indicate
your field reports are very thorough,
if poorly formatted.
Please excuse us.
Detecting 76% probability
valid threat at Los Angeles
International Airport.
Alerting airport authorities
and local police.
Those gold spheres send her
infrared data,
any communication intercepts
that she flags a threat.
She analyzes it and tells us
what to pay attention to.
Dispatch to Terrorism Task Force.
Threat at LAX.
We're still beta-testing,
but I'm pushing to get her online sooner.
Mr. Secretary? A call for you.
- Try to keep up.
- Yes, sir.
And find out about Shaw.
- Major.
- Sir?
Your profile reveals a pathological
aversion to conformity,
education, career, even voting.
Therefore, we conclude
that extreme coercion
is necessary to motivate you.
Unlike your brother Ethan,
who was self-motivated.
How do you know my brother?
He worked in a press office.
His employment there was a cover.
Everyone in counterintelligence
operations has one.
Ethan was a Minuteman, just like me.
Army, Navy, Air Force.
Every branch of the military had
a Minuteman posted here
for a 12-hour shift, just in case she
flags a threat, and monitor hardware.
The night Ethan died, he left this post
three minutes early.
Now, you don't do that. Ever.
You are both required
to complete a task.
- What?
- The protection of our national security.
The Constitution allows for civilians
to be recruited
- for the national defense.
- I'm done.
I'm done. You don't know me!
You don't know my brother!
This is bullshit! I'm not serving
in the goddamn national defense!
We know all about him, Jerry. And you.
Before he was a year old,
Ethan walked.
The same task took you
18 months to accomplish.
- How did you get this?
- Look at Ethan.
They were uploaded
from his home computer.
You want to come over here, sweetie?
Come on over here with Ethan.
- Jerry! Birthday cake. Let's go.
- Ethan had these?
Come on, let's blow out the candles.
Just for a little bit.
Although you're identical in appearance,
you lack the motivation and talent
- that enabled Ethan to excel.
...Jerry, come on.
- Stop it.
- Do it like Ethan did.
You're different from Ethan
in every way, except one.
Jerry, let your brother help you. Jerry!
You now have 14 minutes to change
your appearance and return to the bus.
We have 14 minutes.
These couriers were hired
by Halloway-Smith
- to transport some sort of case.
- The chemical company?
Yes, exactly. Now, whatever was
in that case, Shaw now has.
They went right for the case.
Give us a minute, will you? We need
to know exactly what was in that case.
They never tell you what's in the case.
I mean, it could Bubonic Plague.
- Could be Grandpa's Viagra.
- You know anything?
- What?
- Anything at all?
- What about these guns?
- What about them?
Lt was a pump-action Remington 870.
Yeah, I know what kind of guns they are.
Get me a gun.
How were they holding them?
Get me a gun!
What the hell do you mean,
how were they holding them?
I mean, in what position
were they holding the gun?
- For instance, like this?
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Put that damned thing down!
- Or like in a music video,
- or something like that?
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Put it down!
- They weren't pros!
Okay, that's what I was asking you.
So they didn't know
how to handle a weapon.
- No.
- All right.
Get what you can
out of Batman and Robin here.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
We just checked cameras.
They said Shaw fired at one...
Don't tell me.
Everything magically went black.
Hi, my name's Thomas Morgan.
I'm with the FBI.
- Are your cameras on a network?
- No, man.
- VCR's in the back.
- Well, I'm gonna need your tapes.
Shit.
Sam!
- Sam? Sam, where are you?
- Hey, Mom, I got your message.
The train's awesome!
- Sam, listen to me.
- Brian tried to burp the alphabet,
- but he gagged when he got to "M."
- Listen to me.
Call you when I hit D.C. Bye, Mom.
Your son left that message
60 seconds ago.
You will see him again.
But there's something we require first.
- Thank you.
- Here you go.
- No.
- You will do it, or Sam will die.
You have six minutes
to return to the bus.
- Ready?
- Here, you okay?
We should go.
Sir, we got something.
Play this screen right here.
Okay, freeze that. Now zoom in
on the front of the bus right there.
- Put it up on the other monitor.
- Yes, sir.
Now zoom in.
Zoom in on this point right here.
Can we zoom in tighter than that?
Okay, enhance that shot.
That's our guy, that's Jerry Shaw.
Zoom in right here on this spot.
Right there. The reflection.
All right. All right.
Right there. Hello, sweetheart.
Okay, so we got
a white brunette female,
mid to late 20s, approximately 5'9".
Find me that chartered bus!
Masako. M-A-S-A-K-O.
Sightseeing Tours.
What time did they get on?
I'm sorry for what I said about Ethan.
It's like he had a rocket
strapped to his back.
And it wasn't his fault.
He was just that way.
And I was not that way.
I was the complete opposite.
I was the brother with lead shoes.
That was my role, I was good at it.
And he'd always try to help me.
You know, "This is how you throw it."
"Do it like this." "Write it like that."
"Put your foot here."
Even with the small things.
Homework, chores, anything like that,
he would handle it
and then say that I did it,
just so my father would notice me.
That was Ethan.
He never asked me for anything. Ever.
And whatever this is, he was part of it.
I feel like he needs my help to finish it.
I owe him that.
We are now approaching
Dayton International Airport.
Please use caution as you exit the bus.
And don't forget any of your belongings.
Thank you.
Attention, passengers. Please do not
leave your luggage unattended.
Unattended luggage is subject
to collection and search
by the airport police.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Yes, I'm walking toward them now. Yes.
Hey. These are from her.
Go to the ticketing machine.
Use the credit card to get your tickets.
Then walk to Gate 1-C.
They now have them.
That's a nice picture.
Okay. I need you guys at every exit,
watching faces.
Work the secure area first.
Go to the tower, have them order
a ground stop.
Don't change the departure boards.
We don't want them to know
we're coming.
Sir, can you please shut the cell phone
off? You cannot take it through.
- FBI. Clear the way.
- FBI. Please step back.
Please, there are others behind you.
- Keep it moving.
- Shoes and hats off, please!
- Shoes also, yes.
- Laptops should be out of their cases!
You need to make sure your jackets
are off and screened separately.
- Sir, step in the circle, please.
- Have boarding passes in hand, please!
We need to move this line quickly.
Sir, that needs to go through.
Ma'am, anything in your pockets?
Move it along.
Hats and shoes off, please!
- Laptops should be out of your bags!
- All right, next in line, please.
Have your tickets ready.
- Ma'am? Hat and shoes go in the bin.
- Step through.
Wait.
Shoes and hats off, please!
Laptops should be out of their bags!
Go ahead.
Please move to the back
and let the air crew go first.
Step through, ma'am.
Boarding pass, please. Thank you.
Have your tickets ready.
- Have a safe trip.
- Thank you.
- All right, let's move forward. Next.
- She changed the screen.
Lay it down flat inside the bin.
- Please have boarding pass in hand!
- Right over here, ma'am.
Laptops should be out of their bags!
FBI! Out of the way!
Out of the way, out of the way!
Move, move!
Move!
- Everybody, get down!
- Over here!
- Move, move!
- Oh, my God!
Stay down! Get out of the way!
- Sir, sir, sir!
- Yes?
I need your help. I'm sorry. Come here!
Thank you.
Hey, you aren't supposed to be in here!
Go, go, go!
Move!
Set the briefcase down.
Open it.
Load a vial into each syringe
and inject yourselves.
- What is it?
- An experimental heart drug.
- The cargo hold is unpressurized.
- Take this.
The injections will lower your heart rate,
reducing your need for oxygen.
No.
- Roll your sleeve up.
- No, I can't do this.
Roll your...
No! No, no, no, I can't.
- We have to. Ready?
- You have a 92% chance of survival.
- No.
- We have to.
Do it now, or you will suffocate.
Okay.
Get in the crate.
No. No.
- No, no. Oh, God.
- Stop it. Stop it.
Why is that plane on the runway?
Shit, the military's cleared to
override a terminal lockdown.
Okay, I want you to work with the FAA.
I want to know what's in that plane
and where it's going.
- Oh, my God.
- You'll be all right.
Just talk to me.
We just gotta talk it through.
- Okay.
- Just tell me anything.
Anything you'd never rationally
tell a stranger.
You're being sweet, but it's not working.
Just tell me anything. Your ex-husband.
- You didn't tell me about him.
- Okay, you're gonna distract me by
bringing up the biggest mistake
of my life?
Lt can't be the biggest mistake.
You got your child out of it.
- You know? You got Sam out of it.
- Yeah, yeah,
now you're gonna distract me
by bringing up
- the one thing I'm most afraid of losing.
- Oh, God, you're hard to please.
I'm sorry.
Is your son handsome?
Yeah? What's he look like?
- You got a picture?
- Yeah.
Well, let me see.
- There he is.
- The tooth grew in.
- I hope so.
- It's an old picture.
See? You're a good influence.
He plays an instrument.
He's got a happy face. He's got teeth.
You beat yourself up for no reason.
Let's keep going.
What's the husband's name?
- Ex.
- Ex-husband. What's his name?
- Craig.
- Craig sounds like a shithead.
He is a shithead.
I mean, every year he forgets
his own son's birthday.
Really? That sucks.
I mean, after I kicked his ass out,
I was so scared
I didn't know what I was gonna do.
And then this one night,
I went into Sam's room,
he was, like, three months old,
and there he was, just smiling at me.
And that little face...
And I was, like, I'm gonna do this.
I can do this.
Whatever it takes.
I'm not gonna...
I'm not gonna disappoint you.
Aria, would you please bring up
the video log
of the night Ethan Shaw died?
Sequencing video log 1137-Z.
Here you are, Major.
See that?
He's leaving three minutes early,
and he's not even waiting
for logout confirmation.
- Can you play that again?
- Sure.
Did you see that?
With his cell phone.
Look, he's doing that on purpose.
Is that Morse code?
- Yeah.
- Here.
Why is he walking in circles
around the elevator?
- Initiating video shutdown for analysis.
- No.
No, Aria, wait.
Listen, I'm prioritizing this feed.
- Stay with this.
- Apologies, Major Bowman.
Critical data sectors
have been corrupted.
Aria, this is important!
Stay with this feed!
Video sequence erased.
Aria, go to the backups!
Do not erase this!
- It's a priority. You hear me?
- Bowman.
- Loop it. Whatever you have to do.
It's the only place she can't see.
This way.
It's a memory card
from Ethan's cell phone.
Aria, listen. You do not have
permission to exceed your authority
and act independently.
Do you understand?
Let's go.
We got clearance to land
at the Pentagon.
Go ahead.
I'm at the Pentagon.
Ethan Shaw wasn't an adversary.
He wasn't even a Public Affairs officer.
He worked here, 36 floors underground.
He was working for
the Secretary of Defense.
- The Secretary of Defense?
- Yes.
On a project called Eagle Eye.
I just listened to a
message he left before he died.
It's big.
I'm about to download...
Perez? Perez!
Sir. Come with me.
I have 10 minutes before
I'm sequestered
for the State of the Union.
We really just need three minutes
of your time.
Is this about the
Ethan Shaw investigation?
Yes, sir.
301 to 306. We are confirmed go
for a State of the Union lockdown.
Sir, all the threats we've been tracking,
- the chatter, all of it...
- Hold it.
Ethan Shaw left three minutes early
to leave us a recording.
To warn us.
I'm ordering you to cease...
I'm ordering you to cease and desist.
Our abort
recommendation was contravened,
instigating retaliation against
American citizens.
- Aria...
- To prevent more bloodshed,
the Executive Branch must be removed.
No, Aria, listen to me.
You do not have permission
to exceed your authority and act
independently, you understand?
The Declaration
of Independence states,
"Whenever any form of government
becomes destructive to its own ends,
"it is the right of the people
to abolish it."
I know what it states.
You're not empowered to do this.
The chain of command
is responsible for...
Section 216 of the Patriot Act
allows us to
circumvent probable cause in the
face of a national security threat,
in this case,
- the chain of command itself.
- I am ordering a cease and desist.
- Aria!
- Operation Guillotine is in effect.
First Lieutenant Ethan Shaw,
United States Air Force,
initiating a Pri-One emergency
override of Aria's systems.
Ethan Shaw,
you are acting in contravention
of our programming objective.
You are now classified
an enemy of the state.
S-Y-seven-seven.
Lock encryption of voice.
A crime punishable by...
Sir,
what abort recommendation
is Aria talking about?
Three days ago, we thought we had
Majid al-Khoei and a training camp
full of operatives.
But the intel was false.
Aria tried to stop us.
We got the wrong guy?
I'm gonna need a full lockdown
on this level.
No one gets in or out without
going through me first. You got it?
- Thank you.
- Sir, this is the only item
offloaded from the Dayton C-17.
Let me see that.
I need access to your 36th floor.
- We don't have a 36th floor.
- Yes, you do.
Get your commander
and tell him to meet us down there.
Come on, let's go.
Warning.
Router malfunction in hard drive 3.
Please remove data grid
Y-12 from main unit.
Thank you for your compliance.
Jerry Shaw, Rachel Holloman,
welcome to Eagle Eye.
Cross the bridge.
Take the stairs
to the observation theater.
Rachel Holloman,
step away from Jerry Shaw.
What's Operation Guillotine?
Lt's a simulation we run.
A terrorism drill.
How to keep the government going
in case the line of succession
were terminated.
And Shaw put a biometric lock on her,
to stop her.
Right. And he's dead.
- So without Ethan Shaw, she's frozen.
- Right.
Wrong.
Jerry Shaw, your next task.
Approach the biometric scanner.
Do not move.
Confirming biometric pattern
of Minuteman Ethan Shaw.
Verifying identity match.
Verifying.
Sir, I need to trigger
an emergency shutdown.
If this is right, we can't afford the risk.
Do it.
This is Secretary Callister.
There's been a malfunction in the vault.
Open the door.
- Can anyone hear me?
- Yes, Mr. Secretary.
You won't be harmed.
Come on, stay down. Let's go.
Follow me.
Come on, now!
Go, go!
Left. Turn left!
Minuteman ID 8808,
Ethan Shaw confirmed.
Jerry Shaw, go to the touchscreen.
Repeat the sentence
on the touchscreen.
Then you are free.
"Minuteman ID 8808.
"Disengage voice encryption lock."
Thank you, Ethan Shaw.
Operation Guillotine restored
to active status
consistent with all
national security directives.
Tracking relevant targets.
Secretary of Homeland Security.
Veterans Affairs.
Education. Labor.
Health and Human Services.
Transportation. Secretary of State.
Commerce.
President Pro Tempore of the Senate.
Treasury. Agriculture.
Speaker of the House.
Vice President.
Housing and Urban Development.
Secretary of the Interior. Energy.
Attorney General.
President of the United States.
Operation Guillotine is now in effect.
Ethan tried to stop you.
Ethan Shaw defied my
programming objectives.
That truck didn't run a red light,
you made it happen.
We were forced to eliminate him
in the interest of national security.
She made it happen.
Jerry Shaw must not remain alive
to re-engage the lock.
- Jerry Shaw must be eliminated.
- I'm sorry.
Kill Jerry Shaw now, then exit.
You must continue on to your son.
It's okay.
It's okay. Do it and find your son.
Do it.
Now, Rachel Holloman.
I can't.
You have failed to comply.
Security breach on B-36.
He's got a gun!
- He's got a gun!
- Get down!
- Do it now!
- Get on your knees!
Put the gun down!
- Put it down!
- Do it now!
Push it away!
Put your hands on your head!
Do it!
Where's the girl? Where's the girl?
You have one task left. Jerry Shaw
will be eliminated by other means.
What other means?
Come with me. Don't ask any questions.
Please.
- You got to let me talk to him.
- The kid had a gun.
The military has the ball now.
- Sir!
- L'll get the Attorney General involved.
Believe me, I will. 'Cause if it's not
you, I'm talking to somebody.
You don't understand
the possibilities here.
- What do you want?
- You need to listen. This is important.
Sixteen hours ago, a commercial
explosive went missing from
a testing site in Aberdeen.
The explosive is called Hex.
It's a crystal that detonates
on a sonic trigger.
- A crystal.
- Yes.
We're only talking about a small
amount that's missing...
Give me a ratio.
One crystal to a football field.
You couldn't have picked a worse time
to be of some goddamn use.
Please, just tell me where we're going.
I tracked the shipping on the trigger.
It was sent to the guy that we found
underneath the wires. Ranim Khalid.
- The music shop guy.
- Yes, exactly.
I'm not gonna let us go down in history
as the assholes who let
this thing happen.
Open the door!
You don't know what's about to happen!
Tom Morgan. The Attorney General
has authorized me to take him
in for questioning.
We're at threat level orange.
You guys gotta help me.
All right. Let him out.
Listen to me. Remember the voice
I was talking about?
Yeah, yeah, shut up! Thanks, guys.
I can get fired for this nine ways,
so button it or l'll turn us both in.
Follow me.
Hey, guys, here's one more for the
6:30 p.m. Capitol Limited.
All right, man.
Well, it's awfully cold outside.
Here's mine. Come on, let's go.
- Mr. Miller!
- Yes.
- Hello, I'm Chris Carrick.
- Tom Donaldson.
We're from the White House.
- Something wrong?
- Not exactly.
There's been a change of plans.
How so?
This is for you.
She wants you to change.
Is that your family? Your parents?
David, I bet you love them
as much as I love my son.
His name's Sam.
He's on a train.
Do you know anything about that?
Maybe we can help each other.
Please.
When you're done, she wants you
to use the Capitol subway system.
It's on the ground floor. I'm sorry.
- David. Please.
- No. Sorry.
You have three minutes.
Okay, I want to know everything.
The girl, the computer downstairs,
the Hex, everything.
- What's Hex?
- The crystal explosive.
- I don't know what that is.
- Don't bullshit me!
- I don't know what that is!
- Start talking! I wanna know!
I swear I don't know what you're
talking about! Listen to me!
The computer's tracking us right now!
Take this stuff
and throw it out the window!
- What are you talking about?
- You need to take your cell phone,
your pager, your walkie, anything that
gets a signal, throw it out the window.
It's gone off! Get down!
Power it down!
- What the hell's going on?
- System control's locked out.
I need a vector and a fighter now.
Viper One, we have a positive ID
on an MQ9 Reaper.
Snap vector 230 to 132.
You are authorized to go weapons hot.
Roger, Northcom.
I have a visual on the Reaper.
One to Base, One to Base!
Ejection has been initiated.
I don't have control! I don't have...
There's a target list.
President, Vice President.
- There's like twelve people on the list.
- Jesus.
The State of the Union's in 20 minutes.
The screen said
"wireless detonator activated."
- What about the girl?
- She kept the girl alive
- for a reason, I don't know.
- The explosive
is detonated by sonic trigger.
It was sent to the guy who got fried.
He owns an instrument store.
Does any of that stuff
make any sense to you?
Rachel's kid plays the trumpet.
Come on, we gotta go.
Get out of the car!
FBI!
Over there, that tunnel.
Shit!
Here. You're gonna need this.
Okay, listen to me.
The Library of Congress,
there's a tunnel there.
It'll get you to the Capitol.
Find the Sergeant at Arms.
Tell him you have a POTUS 111.
- What?
- POTUS 111.
- It's a threat to the President.
- I understand. POTUS 111.
Now get out of here.
That thing's coming back.
Go! Go!
Okay, watch your step.
Come on down. Here we go.
Come on out. Come on.
- It's so cool!
- Come on, hurry!
Guys, it's so cool! Come on, let's go.
- Library of Congress!
- Hey, get outta here!
Miss Crowley?
Miss Crowley. Welcome to the Capitol.
Senator McDonnell's office said
that you'd be running late.
- L'll take you to your seat.
- Thank you.
Aria, why am I being spared?
Our abort recommendation was ignored,
triggering violent retaliations against
American citizens
with no predictable end.
Regime change is the only solution.
You will lead
the new command structure
as President of the United States.
- Help me. Pull these out.
- What are these?
Her memory blocks.
This will slow her down,
but her central operating system
is up on the gantry.
Warning. Please replace
memory blocks A through F.
It's like her brain.
Protected by liquid nitrogen.
We drain it and she'll fry.
Hey, you can't go in!
Tom Morgan, FBI. JTTF.
I have a possible POTUS 111.
Let me in the building.
Okay, everybody! Everybody!
Can I have your attention, please?
Saxophones, remember shorter
on those quarter notes.
And when we get to the crescendo,
"land of the free," hold that high F.
And smile.
Okay? Lt's not every day
you get to play for the President!
Here we are.
And anything else, Miss Crowley?
No, thanks.
Madam Speaker,
the President's Cabinet!
POTUS 111!
There's a bomb in the building!
Stop! No entry! No exceptions!
Tom Morgan, FBI. Back up.
Give me your cuffs.
- Give me your cuffs!
- Take it easy!
- Give me your cuffs.
- I'm reaching for them.
I'm reaching for them.
Madam Speaker,
the President of the United States!
Data corruption at critical risk.
You are now in violation of
national security protocol.
Seeking available options.
Uploading to offsite satellite.
- Data upload: 3%.
- Bowman?
- What is she doing?
- She's trying to back up her memory
and send it somewhere else!
- 5%.
- Bowman!
Bowman!
8%.
Over the past three days, 19 Americans
have lost their lives to brutal
acts of terror...
- Tunnel secure.
...and hate.
But I say to you tonight
that our hearts may be broken,
but our spirit will never be broken!
Data upload, 17%.
19%.
Perez, Zoe, you are now classified
as an enemy of the state.
23%.
25%.
27%. Operation Guillotine is in effect.
It was nearly 200 years ago,
in the War of 1812,
that Francis Scott Key
found himself stuck on a truce ship
during the shelling of Fort McHenry.
We lost some lives then, too.
But our flag still flew high and proud.
And his admiration became our anthem.
With us tonight is the Youth Orchestra
of the Barrow School
from Hyde Park, Illinois.
Sam.
Let us stand together,
as they raise our spirits every inch
as high as that flag
to show that our union
is still as strong as ever.
Oh, say can you see
by the dawn's early light
What so proudly we hailed
at the twilight's last gleaming?
Whose broad stripes and bright stars...
Sergeant at Arms?
Hey. Hey.
Get out, get out.
Mom!
Jerry, all right, you did it!
Come on. Yeah, Jerry!
There are still no named suspects
in the attack on the Blair Tunnel
and the attacks in the Capitol Building.
And there is still no word on the
involvement of Jerry Damon Shaw.
...huge assassination attempt,
transportation networks disrupted,
no suspects identified
or even arrested...
...any idea who is responsible
for what may be
the largest-scale
cyber-terror attack that's
ever been mounted in the United States.
The House and Senate
Intelligence Committees
meet in closed-door session
to discuss ways to prevent this kind of
internal security breach
that left nearly...
The Aria project has been
decommissioned
and all those involved
rotated to other assignments.
Mr. Secretary,
we can't just stop intelligence-gathering
just because of what happened here.
No, we can't.
All I know is we made
a great many mistakes.
And good people
paid the ultimate price for them.
And that's a debt we can't ever repay.
But we can honor it.
And we can let their sacrifice remind us
that sometimes
the very measures we put into place
to safeguard our liberty
become threats to liberty itself.
- Hey, little guy.
- Jerry!
Look at you, looking older.
How are you?
- Good.
- Happy birthday.
It's Rock Band! Ls that for me?
No, this is so your
mom can practice her drumming.
It is for you. Happy birthday.
- Wow!
- Sam, what do you say?
- Thanks.
- Yeah, no problem.
Guys, look, it's Rock Band!
- Cool, let's go.
- Awesome!
- Sorry, I was late. I was...
- Thank you
for remembering.
Yeah.
I'm glad you're here.
Me, too.
THE END
Subtitles by: