Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
- Happy Bayram!
- Thanks. Same to you.
- Shall I fill her up?
- Yes.
Happy Bayram.
- Happy Bayram.
- Same to you.
- Can you make me one with cheese?
- I'll hook you up.
- What's the music?
- It's Kazim Koyuncu.
- Don't you know him?
- No.
- His music is very popular down here.
- I've never heard of him.
He was from Artvin. Died of cancer
two years ago. He was young. Like you.
All because of Chernobyl.
It's only now that's becoming clear.
120, brother.
- And a toast?
- Yes.
That makes 130.
YETER'S DEATH
PROLETARIANS OF ALL COUNTRIES, UNITE!
- Hello.
It's 50 euros for half an hour.
- What's your name?
- Jessy.
- Jessy, do you do French?
- French, Italian, Greek.
- I'll do it international for you.
- Bravo. Bravo.
- The music is alright?
- Sure, why not.
- Have you got the 50 euros?
- Yes.
- Take your clothes off.
- Are you Turkish?
- Could be.
Now I'm ashamed.
- What is your real name?
- Yeter. That's enough.
"Yeter" means "that's enough".
I'm the youngest of seven sisters.
- What will you have to drink?
- Water. Water.
Where are you from?
Uncle, have you come
here to chat or to fuck?
- Don't call me uncle, please.
- What shall I call you, then?
"My divine lover?"
- Please call me Ali.
- Ali.
- Can you still get it up at your age?
- God willing.
Show me.
- Goodbye, my rose!
- Take care, brother Ali.
She was speaking Turkish.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will be
arriving in Bremen in ten minutes.
We would like to say goodbye and
wish you all a good onward journey.
- Hello, dad!
- Hello, Nejat.
Sit down.
I'm still frying the fish.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- And you?
- I've brought you a book.
- What is it about?
Just read it.
- Are you having some raki?
- Please. And you?
Of course.
I've got this Iranian friend, Mahmut.
He's given me a tip for the fourth race.
- Which horse?
- "Ofliff Sunsine".
- "Ofliff Sunsine"?
- Yes.
The fifth horse in the fourth race.
Do you mean "Sunshine of Life"?
- What does that mean?
- The sun of life.
It would be nice if the sun of life
would shine for us some day.
It's an outsider, dad.
We'll see.
The odds were at least 70 to 1!
100, 200, 300, 400, 500, 600, 700.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Come on, I'll treat you
to an ice cream, with chocolate.
Who are you screwing at the moment?
- A gentleman doesn't tell.
- I didn't know that.
It's impossible to talk to you
about anything, anyway.
Take care, dad!
- Read the book, okay?
- Yeah, yeah...
Goethe was opposed to revolution.
Not on ethical grounds.
Much because it seemed to him
to be too uncontrollable.
Two quotes illustrate this.
The first:
"Who wants to see a rose bloom
in the depths of winter"?
"Only a fool could want
this untimely intoxication."
Come now, old man!
- I'm not 14 any more. It takes time.
- Then I'll charge you extra.
I'll give you another 50.
Just talk, talk!
- Tell me to grab your ass!
- Grab my ass. Come, my lion!
I want to ask you something.
Are you happy with your job?
- I can't complain.
- Look. I live on my own.
I'm a pensioner, and a widower.
What's that saying?
- "Only God is entitled to solitude."
- Bravo.
I'm looking for a woman to live with.
I would pay as much as you earn here.
In return, you only sleep with me.
Agreed?
- Have you fallen for me, old man?
- You don't have to say anything now.
Here's my cell phone number.
Call me whenever you like.
- Peace be with you.
- I don't understand.
We heard you speak Turkish.
Are you ashamed of being a Turk?
You're both a Muslim and a Turk.
Understood?
- I'm not deaf.
- Don't try to be funny.
- You are on a false path. Repent!
- Repent!
- I repent.
- Don't let me catch you there again.
It would be a shame about you.
Peace be with you.
- Peace be with you.
- And peace be with you.
- He made his move too soon.
- Go on!
I'm glad that you came. Welcome.
- Will you treat me to a coke?
- Of course.
Are you hungry?
When you said you'd pay me
what I earn in the brothel...
- Were you being serious?
- How much do you earn?
I'm left with 3000 a month.
Do you have that much?
- I'll get it.
- How?
I get a pension and I have
some money on the bank.
I've got some land and
property back home.
And I have a son. He's a
professor at a German university.
He earns good money. If the worst
comes to the worst, he'll help us.
- Where are you from?
- Trabzon.
Listen, I won't make any demands.
All I want is for you to live with me,
and sleep with me.
- I am hungry after all.
- Okay, let's go.
- The soup is delicious.
- Please enjoy.
- Where did you learn to cook so well?
- I taught myself.
I raised the boy both
as a mother and a father.
I'll take care of it.
- You've brought him up well.
- Like a girl.
Here you are.
It's fish cakes.
You'll love them. Tuck in!
How old were you when your mom died?
- He was six months.
- Poor thing. Didn't you re-marry?
- I did. A widow with a daughter.
It didn't work out. They're long gone.
I'm a widow too.
My husband was shot in Maras in 1978.
- You're from Maras?
- Yes.
- More coke?
- I'll get it.
Sit yourself down. I'll fetch it.
- Are you really a professor?
- Yes.
- I'll fetch the dessert.
- I'll do it.
- No, because you're a guest.
- Lf I'm going to live here, I'll do it.
- Don't drink so much.
- I'm not drinking so much.
You got me drunk deliberately.
Keep your hands off her...
- Are you okay?
- Fuck off!
Yeter! Where are you, Yeter?
How did you two meet?
He came to me.
- Where?
- He didn't tell you?
I'm a lady of easy virtue.
What does that mean?
A whore. A hooker if you prefer.
Good night.
Nejat?
Dad...
Dad!
Hello. I'm Doctor Özada.
Your father had a heart attack.
His condition is critical.
He'll be in intensive care overnight.
We'll have to open up an artery.
Then we'll keep him for observation.
- Any questions?
- Can we see him now?
I'm afraid not. Excitement
isn't good for him right now.
Return tomorrow morning.
- Do you have any children?
- I have a daughter.
- How old is she?
- 27.
Does she know what you do?
She thinks I work in a shoe shop.
Occasionally I send her some shoes.
I would do anything for her.
I wanted her to study.
To become someone like you.
Getting old is awful.
There's no advantages.
Completely pointless!
You'll be released soon.
- Yeah, yeah.
Nejat, don't forget to
water the tomatoes.
Nejat, the tomatoes are ripe.
- Do you want one?
- Just to taste.
Let's bring him some.
Surely he'll be happy.
What's wrong?
I miss my daughter.
It's been so long since
I heard her voice.
I can't get ahold of her.
Nejat...
Did you fuck her?
I made some börek.
Would you like some?
Take it away. I don't
want any börek.
Don't look at me like that.
The doctor said "no pastry".
Fine, so eat shit.
You won't eat börek,
but you smoke. Seriously?
Don't get involved in my life.
You have yours and I have mine.
Are you leaving?
Wait!
Take this, for your trip.
Yeter
Make me a raki.
We'll shortly arrive in Hamburg.
Connection...
Did you fuck him?
I asked you a question.
- You're drunk.
- No I'm not.
Don't touch me!
Stop that!
I paid you,
and now I will fuck you.
- You don't own me.
- Yes, I do.
- Come on, give me a blowjob.
- Shove your money up your ass.
Where are you going?
- Where are you going?
- I'll go wherever I please.
- You're not going anywhere.
- I'll say it again.
I'll go wherever I want.
I know your type.
Yeter...
Yeter!
To your right again.
And stop.
Step inside here.
- It's so small.
- I'm afraid so.
Go on, enter.
You will be given your
personal items later.
We haven't seen Ayten for a long time.
She just dissapeared.
- Since when?
- A few months now.
That's her.
- Do you have a more recent photo?
- No, sorry. Have a look yourself.
Very cute.
- What was she studying?
- Economics...
- Medicine...
- No, sociology.
- Economics or medicine?
- To be honest I don't know.
Enough already.
- Can I have that photo?
- Yes, but that's her mother.
Take it.
- Where are you staying, cousin?
- In a hotel.
- Stay with me.
- It's okay.
- I'm serious.
- I'm fine on my own.
- How long will you stay?
- As long as it takes to find her.
With 20 million people in Istanbul,
you're bound to run in to her.
- Name?
- Ayten Öztürk.
- From?
- Either Maras or Istanbul.
Kahramanmaras...
One moment please.
- Name?
- Ayten Öztürk.
- I meant your name.
- Nejat. Nejat Aksu.
- Why are you looking for the girl?
- I want to finance her studies.
Why?
Because knowledge and education
are human rights.
Well said.
Listen, Nejat.
The streets and our case files
are full of kurdish children.
We deal with them every day.
They are illiterate
and turn to violence.
Wouldn't you rather
help one of them?
- What good will this do?
- Perhaps someone will get in touch.
FOR SALE
Shall we have a look inside?
I don't understand books. Especially
not those written in German.
I'm off to my workshop.
If you need me, give me a call.
See you soon! Bye.
Good afternoon.
And to you.
- Is this your bookshop?
- Yes.
- Do you like it?
- Yes, quite a lot.
- I'm glad. I'm Markus Obermüller.
- Nejat Aksu.
- Would you like some tea? Or coffee?
- Tea will do.
Çengiz, serve us some tea.
- Please have a seat.
How come you're selling?
- Well, you see...
I've been here for ten years.
All of a sudden I miss Germany.
Despite that I'm surrounded by
all this German litterature. It's like...
It's like a museum here.
Extinct. Like latin.
And I've been feeling... Homesick.
I understand. How much
do you want for the shop?
- What was your name again?
- Nejat Aksu.
- What is your occupation?
- Professor of german, in Germany.
- That would be funny, if... If a
turkish professor in germany-
would end up in a german bookshop
in Turkey. It fits!
Yes, maybe so.
So you're staying in Turkey
for the time being?
- Yes.
- And your work?
Perhaps teaching isn't really my call.
And your father?
A murderer is not my father.
LOTTE'S DEATH
Öcalan, we are with you!
Long live the partisan struggle!
The rights of the people
cannot be stopped!
A cop!
Pursuing person with gun.
Reinforcements to Dilek Café!
Fuck!
Who's been arrested?
Özlem, too?
Police!
Down on the floor!
Hey! You can't just...
Long live the resistance!
My name is Öznur.
Öznur Kulak.
My name is Gökce Tuna.
I am Nurhan Ertas!
- Hello.
- Welcome.
- What's the name in your passport?
- Gül Korkmaz.
Always use that name.
In subways and by bus, never ride black.
- What does that mean?
- You have to buy a ticket.
If you get stopped by the police
you don't know us.
Okay.
If you want to shower, go to the
bath house. The girls will show you.
The cheapest food is at the university.
You can eat for three euros.
This is where you sleep.
- Do you have money?
- About 20 euro.
- You could work for me.
You look like a waitress.
- Is Bremen far away from here?
- About an hour on by train.
Can you lend me some money?
I'll return them tomorrow.
- How much do you need?
- 100 will do.
Thanks.
1837, I'm Gabi.
- Hi, do you speak english?
- Yes.
- I need a phone number from Bremen.
- Where?
- From Bremen.
- Bremen, yes, and what?
- Name Yeter Öztürk.
- Öztürk is the surname?
Yes, name Yeter.
Y... e... t... e... r.
No, I only have with the Y
beginning with the name Jasmin.
Okay, I understand.
- Thanks.
- Bye, bye.
Foot...
Shoe...
SHOES
And now what? You owe me.
You need to work for me.
You call yourself a comrade?
Getting all uptight about £100!
- Do you even know who I am?
- How should I know?
- Toss her out!
- Get lost!
Fine, I'll go on my own.
- You can all go fuck yourselves.
"Who wants to see a rose bloom
in the depths of winter?"
"Only a fool could want
this untimely intoxication." Secondly:
"I oppose revolutions, for they destroy
as many old things as it creates new ones."
- Excuse me, can I ask something?
- Sure.
I forgot my money and I'm hungry.
Can you give me some money? Borrow!
- How much do you need?
- Three, I think. Three is okay.
- I don't have change, just £10.
- Okay, no problem.
No, no! I can change it inside.
- Give me your adress, I'll send you the money.
- You don't have to.
Yes, please.
- Next time you can invite me.
- Okay. Chicken please.
Aren't you hungry?
What are you studying?
- How do you say it in german?
- Sociology.
- And you?
- English and spanish.
- Where do you come from?
- I'm from Istanbul.
- And you came here to study?
- No.
- So, why are you here?
- Because it's cheap.
- Do you like it?
- I don't care because I'm hungry.
Where do you live?
Nowhere.
But where do you sleep?
Do you really want to know?
Yes.
This is the kitchen.
You can take anything, anytime.
I'll show you the guest room.
- Hello mom.
- This is my mother Suzanne.
This is Gül.
She's staying with us for a while.
- Hello.
- I hope the bed is not too small.
- No, it's perfect.
Want to see my room?
- Cute...
- Yeah. I used to live here during school.
I just came back from India.
I was three months in India.
- Oh I see.
- Do you have anything to wash?
I had to escape quick, that's
why I only have these clothes.
Do you want to try my things?
- Is it okay?
- Yes.
Yes...
- And this?
- Good.
- No, I don't like American brands.
- I guess you're right.
Thank you Charlotte.
Lotte. You can call me Lotte.
It's shorter.
No, I like Charlotte. It's better.
Very generous of you, letting a
stranger come and stay with us.
- We have to help her.
- You don't even know her.
That is so german, mom! She's here
illegally. She's persecuted back home.
- Then she should apply for asylum.
- Yes, and if she's not granted it?
You know that it's illegal.
Would you be kind enough
to make her bed?
Lebensmittel is something very german.
It started in the 1300's and...
I don't know how to say it in english
but it's something very german.
- When you're baking bread...
- Baking bread?
No, no, it's "backen".
I'll show you.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org