Good night, Carrie.
Have a good weekend.
Oh, Mr. Burke.
Your meeting on Monday with Mr. Harrington
has been pushed back to 1:15.
Have a nice weekend.
You are not where you belong.
- The girl broke the lamp.
- Which lamp?
The antique lamp.
- In my room?
- Yes.
That lamp cost over $220.
Well, maybe we can get it fixed.
We're never gonna get it fixed.
I think that's why she did it.
Yes. All right. I'm going.
- Will you bring me cigarettes?
- I'm not coming back.
- What?
- What do you mean?
- I'm not going to come back.
- You're not ever coming back?
- No.
Why not?
I don't want to
live this kind of life.
What does that mean?
That I can't live this life.
- You can't live this life?
- Yes.
- So you're leaving me?
Then what about me?
Don't you love me anymore?
- You don't?
- No.
- And why is that?
- I don't know.
- And when did you find this out?
- A long time ago.
- You did?
- Yes.
- How long ago?
- Years ago.
You've known for years
that you don't love me?
Then why do you decide
you're leaving me now?
- I've had enough.
- Yes, but why now?
Because you don't interest me,
spiritually or sexually.
Hadn't you known
this for some time?
Why do you think?
- I think that you did.
- Yes, I did.
Then why didn't you leave then,
you stupid shit?
All of these years you say you've
been living here? You idiot!
I've had enough! You idiot!
Passing judgment on me all this time!
- I never passed judgment...
- And then you tell me you're leaving!
- Yes.
- Go, then.
I'll call ya.
Please! And we'll talk. What should
we do with the house, cut it in half?
Go, get out of here, go!
- You think I'm fooling.
- I do not. Goodbye. Thank you.
Goodbye! Get out!
Get out of here! And don't you
ever come back, do you hear me?
- I'll tell you who's got it easy.
- Who?
The niggers.
Sometimes I wish I was a nigger.
Sometimes I wish I was too.
I'd rob a store.
I don't blame 'em, I swear to God.
Because I want to tell ya...
we're bred to do the
things that we do.
Northern race, one thing...
southern race... somethin' else.
They want to do is sit under the tree
and watch the elephant.
And I don't blame them one small bit.
Because there's too much pressure on us.
And that's no joke, and that's
not poetry. It's just too much.
It is. It absolutely is.
- A man has got to get out.
- What do you mean?
A man has got to
get away from himself.
That's true.
Because the pressure is too much.
- What do you do?
- What do you mean?
What do you do to get out?
- What do I do?
- Yeah.
What are the things to do?
What are the things anyone does?
Pussy? I don't know. Pussy.
Power. Money. Adventure.
I think that's it.
Self-destruction.
I think that that's it.
- Don't you?
- Yes.
Religion.
Um, I suppose that's it.
Release. Gratification.
You gotta get something that opens
your nose. Life is too short.
My wife and I are incompatible.
I'm sorry to hear that. In what way?
I don't find her attractive.
And she hates my guts.
It's a boring thing to talk about,
but that's what's on my mind.
I understand.
- You do?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Believe me, it's all right.
I know that we all need it,
we don't know where to find it...
and I know what it means
and I understand.
I... feel...
I know, like your balls
were cut off.
Yes. A long long time ago.
And I don't feel like a man.
- You know what you need?
- No.
- You need to get laid.
- I do. I know I do.
And that's why the
niggers have it easy.
I'll tell you why.
There are responsibilities
they never have accepted.
Try the Allegro.
THE PRIEST
What is that?
It's a club on 47th Street.
I want this to be on me.
I want you to remember...
there was someone who listened.
You'd do the same for me.
Want to buy me a drink?
Yes.
I'm putting myself at your mercy.
This is my first
time in a place like this.
I don't want to be taken
advantage of. You understand?
Buy me a drink, and
we'll go in the back.
- And do what?
- Whatever you want.
$50.
Buy me a drink.
- You... get a commission on the drinks?
- Yes.
- How much commission do you get?
- 50%.
That's $100.
- It's too much.
- What?
Too much. Thank you.
- 80.
- No, thank you.
- I'll give you 50.
I'll give you the 50 you'd get
if I gave her 100 for the drink.
But I'm not gonna give them 100.
- But you have to buy me a drink.
- No, I'm sorry.
- All right, give me 30.
- On top of the 50?
- Yeah, you give me 80.
- To you?
Yes.
- I should give the 80 to you?
- Yes.
- And then you give her the 50?
- Yes, I got to give her the 50.
No.
For the drink.
No, you don't have to pay
her for the drink... tea.
- It's not tea.
- It's not tea?
If it's not tea, what is it then?
I came in here to be straight!
Why do we go through this?
Get in or get out.
Don't mill around.
Seven. Go in seven.
Oh, no. Six... I mean, six.
Go in six.
Take your dick out.
Come on.
- I'm not a cop.
- I know you're not a cop.
Take your dick out.
I'm gonna give you a good time.
How do we get this barrier
to come down?
It doesn't come down.
Then how are you
gonna give me a good time?
Come here.
Give me 10 bucks.
Put it through the thing.
I... don't have 10 bucks.
Yes. Give me the 20.
And you're gonna make change?
Yes, just give me the 20.
Give it to me.
Good.
Now take your dick out.
Can... can I have my 10?
Give me my 10 back. Come on!
Give me my 10 bucks.
Let me hold the 10.
Give me my 10 back and I'll
give you a tip when you're done.
Thank you.
Now, take your dick out!
How do we get this thing
to come down?
It doesn't come down.
- It doesn't come down?
- No!
Well, then what the fuck am
I giving you 10 bucks for?
Look, you can touch me.
You can touch me.
I don't want to touch you.
I want you to touch me!
Come on! Honey, come on.
You're only cheating yourself.
The fellow over there? He's a shill.
Who is?
- You know how to beat the game?
- How?
You figure out which
card has got to win...
and bet the other one.
They're all shills.
They're all part of an act.
Red is also
gonna get you men in black.
20 gets you 40, 40 gets you 80.
Cops cops cops cops.
Yo, don't run, don't run.
Check it out, man, check it out.
Is this what you're
lookin' for, man?
Yo, I'm sayin', take it.
I'm tryin' to give you somethin'.
EVERYTHING
FOR THE GENTLEMAN
Now is that what
you're lookin' for or not?
- Is this true?
- Would I give it to you if it wasn't?
- Hello.
- Have you been here before?
- Uh, no.
How did you hear about us?
- Are you from out of town?
- Yes. What's the deal here?
- This is a health club.
- I know.
- And our rates are by the hour.
- Yes?
$68 for the first hour.
Sauna, free bar, showers.
The hour doesn't start until you
and the masseuse are in the room.
All right.
Whatever happens in the room,
of course, is between you.
I understand.
- You understand?
- Yes.
For two hours it's $150.
If you want two hostesses
that'll be $200 for one hour.
Whatever arrangements you choose
to make with them is between you.
Good.
- What would you like?
- One hour.
You pay that now.
How would you like to pay?
- How can I pay?
- Cash or credit.
The billing on your card will read,
"Atlantic Ski and Tennis."
I'll pay with cash. Thank you.
Not at all. Have a lovely evening.
- How are you?
- Fine.
I've never done this before.
- No?
- No. That feels good.
- You've got a good body.
- Thank you.
- Do you work out?
- I jog.
And I used to wrestle in high school.
- You've kept yourself in good shape.
- Thank you.
So what shall we do?
- I'd like to have intercourse with you.
- That sounds nice. I'd like that too.
You would?
How much would that be?
For a straight fuck, that'd be 250.
Th-that's too much.
You know I'm givin' you a break...
'cause it's your first time here.
No, it's too much on
top of the 68 at the door.
I know, I know, I know. But, you
know, I don't get to keep it all.
It's too much.
I split it with them.
Yeah, I mean, they
don't pay me, I pay them.
It's too much.
Okay, well,
how much do you have?
All I had was 100
for the whole thing.
- You mean 100 for it all?
- That only left me 30.
Honey, you couldn't
get a thing for that.
Well, how much do you want?
All right, for a straight fuck, 220.
I couldn't pay that.
Well, I'm sorry, then.
It would've been nice.
- I'll give you 100.
- No.
- 120.
- 200.
- Because this is your first time.
- I know.
- Because we split with them.
- I understand.
- All right, 200.
- Thank you.
I appreciate this.
Would it offend
you if I wore a rubber?
Not at all.
- Do you have one?
- Yes.
- Do you want to pay me now?
- Yes, certainly.
I need cash, honey.
- They said at the door...
- You have to pay me with cash.
I don't think I have it, but...
- Well, how much do you have?
- Well, I, um... only 60.
Oh! Jeez. I'm sorry,
honey, I can't do it.
Well... well, wait, wait.
Maybe you could... wait!
You know, why don't you
go get it and come back here?
Well, where could I get it?
Go to an ATM or a
restaurant and cash a check.
- I'll be here till 4:00.
- I'll... I'll...
- Yes, thank you.
- Not at all.
See?
Here you go. You can't
win if you don't play.
- You, sir?
- Me?
- You gonna try me again?
- "Again"?
I remember you beat me out that
50 that time with your girlfriend.
- When was this?
- On 14th Street.
You gonna try me one more time?
Play for that 50. 50 gets you 100.
We'll see who's fast as you was.
Pay on the red, pass to the
black.
Where's the queen? You
pick the queen, you win.
Where's the queen?
You put a 50, win 100.
Now, who saw the queen?
- I got her.
- How much?
Put your money up. How much?
- Uh, I bet 50 bucks.
- Put it up.
There.
My man, I'm just too
quick for you today.
We got two cards left.
Who saw the queen?
Pay on the red queen. Who saw her?
- I saw her.
- Aw, shit, man, he too fast for me.
For $50?
All right, all right. Put it up.
Will you pay me if I win?
Yes, I will. If you win.
But you got to win first.
- All I got to do is turn the queen?
- That's all you got to do.
I'll bet you $50.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
Put it up.
Now...
which one you like?
There.
WHEEL OF FORTUNE
I'm sorry, my man.
This time you lose.
Now we even. Take another shot.
You pick the queen, you win.
I'll bet you another 50.
Let me see those cards.
These cards is fine.
It's you that's slow.
- I want to see those cards.
- These cards are good. You lost.
You show me those cards.
You ain't seein' no motherfuckin'
cards. We're playin' a game here.
You lost, man. Get lost.
You let me see those cards, fella.
You wanna see these cards?
Here's your motherfuckin' cards!
Turn around!
He said... he said my cards...
Come on, let's get out of here.
I want a room.
$22.
I lost my wallet.
Go to the police.
You can call up American Express.
I don't want to hear about it.
You can call the credit card people.
I... I have insurance.
You can call them yourself.
Right across the hall.
I have no money.
I'm sure it's a free call.
- Does that phone require a coin?
- I'm sure I don't know.
You know if it needs a coin
or not to get a dial tone.
You know if it needs a coin,
for Christ's sake.
You want to live in that kind of world?
You want to live in a world like that?
I've been hurt. Are you blind?
Would you appreciate it
if I acted this way to you?
I ask you one simple thing:
Does it need a coin?
No. It doesn't need a coin.
You make your call and
then you go somewhere else!
Please deposit ¢75 for
the first three minutes.
What do you get for that?
What is that, 14 or 19?
14.
Yeah? Let me see that.
How much is that?
685.
Why is that? How old is that?
Is that old?
You know how much gold
you got in there? Feel that.
Where is it marked?
- Right there. You want the loupe?
- No, I can see it.
What?
- I want to pawn something.
- Talk to the man in back.
- What?
- My ring.
- Take it off.
- It's difficult to take it off.
- Spit on it.
I got it off.
What do you want to do with this?
You want to pawn it?
- Yes, how does that work?
- Is that what you want to do?
- Yes.
- Are there other things to do?
What you can do, no.
I mean, if you wanted it appraised...
or wanted to sell it,
or if you wanted it to pawn.
- I understand.
- All right?
- How much to get it appraised?
- $5.
- What would you give me?
- How much you want for it?
Whatever it's worth.
You pawn it, all you're gonna get...
you know how this works?
No.
What you get, a quarter of the value.
Approximately for one year,
you're paying 12%.
You can redeem your pledge with the year...
you pay the 12% to that time
plus the amount of the loan.
- What is my pledge?
- Well, that depends on what it is.
What do you mean?
- What it is. Do you understand?
- No.
Whatever the amount is,
that is your pledge.
- The amount of the loan?
- That's right.
I understand.
What are you looking for the ring?
What's it worth?
The most I can give you is 120 bucks.
- I'll take it.
- I'll be back. Give me the ring.
This is nice.
What are you asking for this?
43 bucks. 40 bucks.
40 bucks.
- Why's it so expensive?
- Why is it so expensive?
No, I'm gonna pass.
I'll catch ya later. Thanks.
Why is the knife so expensive?
This is survival knife.
GI issue. World War I.
And that is why.
- Survival knife.
- That is correct.
Is it a good knife?
Is the best knife money can buy.
SWORD
You want it?
What are you lookin' for?
What?
- What are you looking for?
- I'm not lookin' for nothing.
If you're lookin' for that
joint, it's closed.
- What joint?
- That joint you was lookin' for.
Thanks, no, I'm not lookin'
for that joint.
Well, you lookin' for somethin', and
I think I know what you lookin' for.
You do?
Yeah, you come with me.
I get you what you want.
What am I looking for?
I know. We'll get you some action.
We'll get you something sweet.
I know.
That's what I'm doin' here.
What are you saying?
I'm sayin' we gonna find
you somethin' nice.
You're saying you're
gonna find me a woman?
That's what I'm
doin' out here, friend.
- How much?
- Well, how much you want?
- I want somebody clean.
- That's right.
- I want a blowjob.
- All right.
- How much?
- 100 bucks.
That's too much.
Well, how much you wanna spend?
Say, $35.
- 60.
- No.
- 40?
- Yes.
- Is that all right?
- Give me the 40.
I'll give you the 40
when we see the girl.
I'm not gonna leave you. You comin'
with me. We goin' to see the girl.
Good.
I'll give it to you then.
You give it to me now, man, understand?
That's the transaction.
Unless you a cop, you give me the
money, then that's entrapment.
Yes. I'm not a cop.
All right.
You see what I'm sayin'?
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
Now, you come with me,
we'll walk here like we're talkin'.
- Is she going to be clean?
- Yes, she is. I understand you, man.
I understand what you want.
Believe me.
Is there any money in this?
Well, you know, there's some.
You get done piecin' off the police...
this man here, the medical,
the bills, you know.
- How much does the girl get?
- 60%. Oh, yeah.
Uh, it's right up here.
All right, motherfucker, now give
me all your money! All of it! Now!
All right.
Don't turn around.
Just hand me all you've got.
All right.
Don't you make
a motherfuckin' sound.
I'm gonna do everything you say.
You just hand me all you've got.
- You motherfucking nigger!
- Hold on!
Motherfucking shit!
Jungle bunny!
You coon! You cunt!
You cocksucker!
- Take me upstairs?
- Oh my God!
You fuck! You nigger!
You dumb cunt! You shit!
Shit! You fucking nigger!
Don't fuck with me, you coon!
I hope you're dead!
I want a cup of coffee.
No. A beer.
Irish whiskey.
- Irish whiskey?
- Yes. A double.
- Beer chaser.
- You're in a peppy mood today.
You're goddamn right I am.
And do you know why?
Because I am alive.
You know how much of our life
we're alive you and I? Nothing!
Two minutes out of the year.
When we meet someone new.
When we get married.
When... when...
when we're in difficulties.
In a car crash. And that's it.
You know, we're sheltered.
- Who is?
- You and I. White people.
All of us. The white race is doomed.
And do you know why?
- Sit down.
- I can't, I'm working.
You can do anything you want to do.
You don't sit 'cause you're working.
The reason you don't sit down
is you don't want to sit down...
because it's more
comfortable to accept a law...
than question it and live your life.
All of us. We've bred
the life out of ourselves!
We live in a fog. In a dream.
And we are dead.
- How old are you?
- 23.
I've lived in a fog 47 years.
Most of the life, it's gone.
I wasted it because I didn't know.
And you know what the answer is?
To live. That's it.
In one moment, for which
I thank God. To live!
I want to tell you something.
No one's going to know.
Just you. That's all.
No one's keeping score,
and no one cares.
- I want to go home with you tonight.
- Why?
Why do you think?
I want to fuck you.
It's as simple as that.
- What's your name?
- Glenna.
- You see this?
- Yes.
That fuckin' nigger comes up to me...
"Gimme all your money."
47 years fits me to sweat and say:
"He's underpaid. He can't get a job.
He's bigger than me. He's a killer.
He don't care about his life...
so he'd do anything".
That's what I'm fitted to do.
In a mess of intellectuality
to wet my pants...
while this coon
cuts my dick off, huh?
Because I'm taught to hate.
I want to tell you something.
Something spoke to me.
I got a shock.
I spoke back to him,
that motherfucker!
I came out there with my knife,
and I stuck it in his neck!
Up your ass, you coon!
You wanna fight? I'll fight you!
I'll cut your fuckin' heart out!
I don't give a fuck!
- Yes?
- I don't give a fuck.
I got some warlike blood
in my veins too, ya fuckin' spade!
The blood ran down his neck.
- With that?
- You bet your ass.
Did you kill him?
- Did I kill him?
- Yes.
- I don't care.
- That's wonderful.
And in that moment, when I spoke...
you understand, 'cause that was
more important than the knife...
I didn't fucking want to understand.
Let him understand me.
I wanted to kill him,
and in that moment...
47 years of prejudice
came out of me...
47 years of all those...
of all those cleaning ladies...
who might have broke the lamp.
So what?
I swear to God,
for the first time I saw...
they're people too!
- You know who I hate?
- No, who's that?
- Faggots.
- Yes, I hate them too.
- Do you know why?
- Why?
They suck cock. And that's
the truest thing you'll ever hear.
I hate them because they
don't like women.
- They hate women.
- I know that they do.
- It feels good to say it, doesn't it?
- Yes.
Then say it. Say it.
If it makes you feel whole,
always say it, always, for yourself.
- It's hard.
- Yes.
- Sometimes it's hard.
- You're goddamn right it's hard.
And there's a reason why it's hard.
Why?
So that we will stand up.
Glenna, there is no law.
There is no history.
There's only now.
And if there's a God,
he may love the weak, Glenna...
but he respects the strong.
And if you are a man, you should be feared.
You must know you command respect.
- That's why I love the theater.
- Yes.
Because what you must
ask respect for is yourself.
- What do you mean?
- When you're on stage.
Yes.
- For your feelings.
- Absolutely! Absolutely, yes!
- And not be someone else!
- Why should you?
That's why I'm so proud
to be in this profession.
I don't blame you.
- Because your aspirations...
- And I'll bet you're good at it.
They have no bounds.
There's nothing to
bound you but your soul!
I understand.
Do something for me.
Act something for me.
- Will you act something for me?
- Now?
- Sitting right here?
- Yes!
- Would you really like me to?
- You know I would.
You see me sitting here.
You know I would. I'd love you to!
- You want one?
- Nah.
What would you like me to do?
Whatever you'd like.
What plays have you done?
- Well, we've only done scenes.
- You've only done scenes?
I shouldn't say "only."
They contain the kernel of the play.
What plays have you done?
In college, I played Juliet.
In Shakespeare?
Yes, in Shakespeare.
What do you think?
Well, I just meant there's
plays named "Juliet."
- There are?
- Yes.
I don't think so.
Well, there are.
Don't... don't... don't be so limited
and don't assume I'm dumb
because I wear a suit and tie.
I don't assume that.
Because what we've done tonight,
since you met me...
it didn't make a difference then.
Forget it. All I meant...
- You say you're an actress.
- I am an actress.
That's what you say, so I say:
"What plays have you done?" That's all.
The work I've done,
I've done for my peers.
- What does that mean?
- In class.
- "In class"?
- In class or workshop.
- Not for a paying group?
- No, absolutely not.
Then you're not an actress.
Face it.
Let's start right, the two of us.
I'm not lying to you,
don't lie to me...
and don't lie to yourself.
You are a beautiful woman.
You have worlds before you.
I do too.
What I'm saying, start now,
start tonight, with me.
- Be what you are.
- I am what I am.
That is right and that's what I
loved when I saw you tonight.
What I loved. I use that word.
I loved a woman, standing there...
a working woman who brought
life to what she did...
who took a moment to joke with me!
God bless what you are!
Say it. "I am a waitress!"
What does it mean
if I say something?
- Say it with me!
- What?
I am a waitress!
I think that you'd better go.
If you want me to go, I'll go.
Say it with me... what you are.
And I'll say what I am.
Say what you are, and
I'll say what I am.
- What you are?
- I've made that discovery.
Now, I want you to change
your life with me! Right now!
For whatever that it can be! I don't
know what that is, you don't know.
- Speak with me, right now! Say it!
- I don't know what you're talking about!
Oh, but the Lord, yes you do.
Say it with me!
- What are those?
- Pills.
For what? Don't take them.
Go through it with me!
- I have this tendency to get anxious.
- Don't take them!
Go through it!
Go through it with me!
You're scaring me!
I am not! I know when I'm
scaring you, believe me.
- Get out!
- Glenna!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Leave me the fuck alone!
What did I do, pledge my life to you?
I let you fuck me! Go away!
Listen to me.
You know what madness is?
- I told you, go away!
- Listen to me.
Lis... I'm lonely too.
I know what it is too, believe me.
- You know what madness is?
- Suzy?
It's self-indulgence.
Suze, can you come over here?
Will you please put that down!
Do you know how rare this is?
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm talking to you!
Don't hurt me!
I... no, I can't deal with this.
- You're being ridiculous!
- I... no... no. Help! Help!
Would you shut the fuck up?
What are you trying to do?
Help!
- You wanna wake the neighbors?
- Will somebody help me?
- Shut up!
- Help! Will somebody help?
You get away from me! You are
the devil! I know who you are!
I know what you want me to do!
Get away from me!
I curse you!
- You shut the fuck up!
- You can't kill me! I'm good!
You stupid fucking bitch!
You're nuts! Are you insane?
Are you insane?
You fucking bitch!
You stupid fucking bitch!
You stupid fucking...
Now look what you've done.
Now look what
you've bloody fucking done.
My mother had a hat like that.
I'm not making conversation.
She wore it for years.
She wore it when I was a child.
I didn't just make it up.
It happened.
Excuse me.
Who the fuck do you think
you are? I'm talking to you!
What am I, a stone? Did I say,
"I want to lick your pussy"?
I said my mother had that same hat!
You cunt! What am I, a dog?
I'd like to slash your fucking face!
I'd like to slash your motherfucking
face apart!
Will somebody help me?
You don't know who I am!
Is everybody in this town insane?
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Fuck you! Fuck the lot of you!
I don't need you!
I worked all my life!
I worked all my life.
You say, "Oh, no, not me.
Not me, Lord, to whom
you hold out Your hand.
Not me to whom You
offer Your eternal grace.
Not me who can be saved."
But who but you, I ask?
Who but you?
You say you are a grievous sinner?
He knows that you are!
You say: "He does not
know the depth of my iniquity".
Believe me, friends, He does.
And still you say:
"He does not know".
You say this in your secret soul.
"He does not know the
terrible depth of my unbelief."
Believe me,
friends, He knows that too.
To all who say His grace is not
meant to one as black as you...
I say, "Who but you?"
To you alone.
Not to the blessed.
You think that
Christ died for the blessed?
That He died for the heavenly host?
That did not make Him God!
It does not need a God.
For you!
There is none so black
but that He died for you.
It's required of God
to sacrifice for man.
You hear me?
For you!
He died especially for you.
Upon my life
on the graves of my family...
and by the surety
I have of his eternal bliss.
He died for you, and you are saved!
Praise God, my friends!
Praise God and testify.
Who will come up and
testify with me, my friends?
Who will come up and testify?
Who will testify for Jesus?
Who will testify with me?
I will testify.
Who is that?
I will testify!
Sweet God, let that man come forth!
Who will come open up his soul?
Hallelujah, my friends!
Be with me!
That's the man! That's the man!
Get him now! That's him! Stop him!
Where is that man?
Let him come forth!
Just a minute, sir.
I... I'm on my way to church.
Sweet Jesus, let that man
come forth!
That's the man that
tried to rape me on the train!
What's this all about, sir?
- He had a knife!
- Must be some mistake.
He tried to rape me. That's the man
who tried to rape me on the train!
There's some mistake.
I'm on my way to church.
What's the trouble here?
No problem. I'm on my
way into this mission.
This man tried to
rape me on the train!
Obviously the woman is mad.
Can I see some identification,
please?
Please, officer, I... I haven't time.
It's been a long...
I don't have my wallet on me.
My name is Gregory Burke.
I live at 428, 22nd Street.
I own the building.
I have to... preach.
- You're gonna show me some ID.
- I don't have any, I told you.
Well, you're gonna have
to come with me.
Yes, but in one moment.
Not now. I have to preach.
- Come on.
- Please. You're making a mistake.
Let me go, and I'll...
I'll come with you afterwards.
I swear I will.
I swear it on my life.
There's been, uh, some
sort of a mistake.
I'm an elder in this church.
Come with me, if you will.
I have to speak.
Look... What's that?
Nothing.
It's a knife.
It's there for self-protection.
What was the knife for?
For protection.
- From whom?
- Everyone.
- You know that it's illegal?
- No.
It is.
I'm sorry.
Speaking to that woman in the way
you did is construed as assault.
I never spoke to her.
She identified you as the man
who accosted her last evening.
She is seriously mistaken.
If she presses charges,
you'll be arraigned for assault.
For speaking to her?
You admit that you
were speaking to her?
I want to ask you something.
All right.
Did you ever kick a dog?
Well, that's what I did.
Man to man, that's what I did.
I made a harmless comment to her.
She responded like a fucking bitch!
Did you try to pick her up?
Why would I try to pick her up?
- She was an attractive woman.
- She was not an attractive woman.
- You gay?
- What business is that of yours?
- Are you?
- No!
You married?
Yes, in fact.
I was going back to my wife.
- You were going back to your wife?
- I was... going home to her.
You said you were going back
to her. What did you mean?
I'd left my wife, all right?
- You left your wife?
- Yes.
Why?
I was bored.
Didn't that ever happen to you?
- And why did you lie to the officer?
- What officer?
Who picked you up.
There's no Gregory Burke
at the address you gave.
You didn't give him
your right name.
- I was embarrassed.
- Why?
- I didn't have my wallet.
- I'd left it at home.
- Why did that embarrass you?
I don't know! I have had no sleep!
I just want to go home!
I am a solid...
Look...
my name is Edmond Burke.
I live at 485, West 79th Street.
I work at Stearns & Harrington.
I had a tiff with my wife. I went out,
I've learned my lesson.
Believe me.
I just want to go home.
Whatever I've done, I'll make right.
All right?
These things happen,
and then they're done.
When you stopped me,
I was going to church.
I've been... unwell.
I confess to you, I've...
been confused, but...
I've learned my lesson,
I'm ready to go home.
Why'd you kill that girl?
What girl?
That girl you killed.
- How's everything?
- Fine.
- I'm all right too.
- Oh, good.
You wanna tell me you're
mad at me or something?
Did you kill that
girl in her apartment?
Yes.
But I want to tell you something.
I didn't mean to.
But you wanna hear something
funny? Now, don't laugh.
I think I just had too much coffee.
I'll tell you something else.
There are too many people in the world.
That's why we kill each other.
I suppose you're
mad at me for leaving you.
I don't suppose
you're, um, inclined...
or nor do I think you should be
to stand by me.
I understand that.
I'm sure there are marriages
where the wife would...
or the husband,
if it would go that way.
But, I know ours is
not one of that type.
I know you wished
at one point it would.
I wished that too, at one point.
I know...
I'm sure this is how you feel
when someone near you dies.
You never said the things
you wanted desperately to say.
It would have been so
simple to say them...
but you never did.
- You got the papers?
- Yes.
- Good.
- Oh, yes, I got them.
- Anything you need?
- Nope.
Can't think of a thing.
You take care now.
You know... you know... you know...
we can't distinguish between anxiety
and fear. You know what I mean?
I don't mean fear. I mean...
I do mean fear.
I don't mean anxiety.
When we fear something
I think we wish for it.
Death. Or burglars.
Don't you think?
I always knew I would end up here.
Every fear hides a wish.
I think I'm gonna like it here.
- You do?
- I do.
You know why? It's simple.
That's why I think I am.
You know, I always thought white
people should be in prison.
I know it's the black
race we keep there...
but I always thought white people
should be there.
- You know why?
- Why?
To be with the black people.
Does that sound too simple to you?
No.
Because we're lonely.
But what I know...
I think all this fear...
all this fucking fear
we feel must hide a wish.
'Cause I don't feel it since
I'm here. I don't.
I think for the
first time in my life.
I think we're like birds.
We suspect when
there's going to be an earthquake.
Birds know. They
leave three days earlier.
Birds leave when there's
gonna be an earthquake?
Yes. And I think,
in our soul, we feel...
we sense there's going to be...
a cataclysm.
But we cannot flee.
Something tells us, "Get outta here!"
White people feel that.
You feel that?
Well... but I don't
feel it since I'm here.
So... so... so...
I must be somewhere safe.
Isn't that funny?
No.
- You think that it's not?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- That's all right.
- You want a cigarette?
- No, thank you. Not just now.
That's all right.
- Maybe later.
- Sure.
- Now you know what?
- What?
I think you just get on my body.
I... yes.
What do you mean?
I think you get on my body. Now.
I don't know what that means.
It means you should suck my dick.
Now, don't you wanna do that?
No.
- Well, you just do it anyway.
- You're joking.
Not at all.
- I don't think I could do that.
- Well, you better try.
Or you're gonna die.
Let's just get this out the way.
Seriously, we're
gonna be here a long time.
I don't think we
want to start like this.
I'm not gonna repeat myself.
I'll scream.
If you scream,
you'll offend me...
you gonna die.
Look at my face. Say I'm foolin'.
I can't. I can't do...
The motherfuck you can't, missy!
Right now, missy!
Right now, Jim,
and you'd best be nice.
You don't have to talk.
I don't want to talk.
Are you accustomed to life in here?
- Do you know what happened to me?
- No.
I was sodomized.
- Did you report it?
- Yes.
- What did they say?
- "That happens".
- I'm sorry it happened to you.
- Thank you.
Are you lonely?
Yes. I feel so alone.
I'm so... empty.
Maybe you are ready to be filled.
That's bullshit.
It's bullshit. It's pious bullshit.
- Is it?
- Yes!
That you are ready to be filled?
Is it impossible?
Yes. Yes!
I don't know what's impossible.
Nothing's impossible.
Nothing is impossible, not to God.
Is that what you're saying?
Yes.
Then you're full of shit!
You understand that?
If nothing is impossible then let
Him let me walk out of here!
And be free!
Let Him cause a new day, in a
perfect land, full of life and air...
where people are kind
to each other!
And there's work to do!
Where we grow up
in love and in security.
We're wanted. Let Him do that.
Go on. Let Him do that...
you asshole, if nothing
is impossible to God.
I think that must be easy.
Not "Let me fly"
or "If there is a God...
make him to make the sun
come out at night". Go on.
Please.
Please! Please!
I'm begging you! I'm begging you!
If you're so smart, let him do that!
Please! Please!
I'm begging you!
Are you sorry that you
killed that girl?
- Edmond?
- Yes.
Are you sorry that you
killed that girl?
I'm sorry about everything.
- But are you sorry that you killed?
- Yes.
Yes, I am. Yes.
Why did you kill that girl?
I... don't...
I don't...
I don't think...
"Dear Mrs. Brown.
You don't remember me.
Perhaps you do.
Do you remember Eddie Burke,
who lived on Euclid?
Maybe you do.
I took Debbie to the prom.
I know that she never
found me attractive...
and I think she was coerced
in some way to go with me...
though I can't think in what way.
It also strikes me as I write...
that maybe she went
of her own free will...
and I found it important to think
that she went unwillingly.
I don't think this is true.
She was a lovely girl...
and I'm sure if you remember me...
you will recall how
taken I was with her then."
You have a visitor.
Please tell him I'm ill.
You can't control
what you make of your life.
Now, that's for damn sure.
There's a destiny that
shapes our ends.
- Rough hew them how we may.
- However the motherfuck we may.
- And that's the truth.
- You know that is the truth.
And people say it's hereditary
or it's environment but it's not.
What do you think it is?
I think it's something beyond that.
Beyond these things
that we can know.
I think maybe in dreams we see
what it is. What do you think?
I don't know.
I don't think we can know.
I think if we knew it, we'd be dead.
We'd be God.
We would be God.
That is absolutely right.
Or some genius.
No. I don't think even
genius can know what it is.
No, some great genius.
Or some philosopher.
I don't think even
genius can see what we are.
You don't think that...
I think that we can't perceive it.
Well, something's goin' on,
I'll tell you that.
And somewhere, some poor
sucker knows what's happenin'.
- Do you think?
- Shit, yeah.
Some whacked-out sucker
somewhere in the Ozarks.
Shit, yes.
Some guy.
Some inbred sucker
walks around all day, just...
- You think?
- Yeah.
Well, maybe not him,
but somewhere, some guy.
Some fuck locked up
has got time for reflection.
Or some fuckin'... I don't know...
some kid who's just been born.
Some kid that's just been born.
- He's got no preconceptions.
- Yes.
- All he's...
- Yes, absolutely right.
Yes. Maybe it's memory.
- That's what I'm sayin'. Maybe...
- It could be.
Or some knowledge.
Some intuition.
I don't even mean intuition.
Something... something...
- Or maybe some animal.
- Why not?
The whole time when they say
"We'll wait for the men from space."
- Maybe they're already here.
- Maybe they are.
- Maybe they're animals...
- Yes.
...that were left here.
- Eons ago.
- Long ago.
- And have been bred here.
Or maybe we're the animals.
Maybe we are.
You know how they...
they are supreme on their...
on their native world.
- But when you put them here...
- We call them dogs.
Or animals. And we scorn them.
We scorn them in our fear.
- But don't you think...
- It very well could be.
But on their native world
they are supreme.
I think that's very...
And what we have done is
to disgrace ourselves.
We have.
Because we did not treat
them with respect.
- Maybe we were the animals.
- That's what I'm saying.
Maybe they're here to watch over us.
Maybe that's why they're here.
Or to observe us.
Maybe we're here to be punished.
You think there's a hell?
I don't know.
You think we're there?
I don't know, man.
Think we go somewhere when we die?
I like to think so.
I do too.
I sure do like to think so.
Perhaps it's heaven.
I don't know, man.
I don't know either.
But perhaps it is.
I would like to think so.
I would too.
- Good night.