Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
Fucking idiot.
Send him off!
ELEVEN MEN OUT
Your dad's playing well.
Where were you in defence?
What do you mean?
Are you the one
from the magazine?
Do you have time?
Yes, let's do it in
the locker room.
She wasn't really into it
at first
so I just whipped it out.
Shit, man, didn't she faint?
Of course she did. It's so big!
Put that away before
you hurt yourself, lad.
This lady is with me, guys.
Hey, shit!
What's the
matter with you?
Why don't you join
us in the showers?
What did you think of the game?
It was okay,
wasn't it? You won.
Didn't you see the penalty?
I'm not into football.
Am I on the cover?
You're on the back page,
the last thing people read.
The back? What the hell
are you talking about?
Who do you think you are?
Some superstar?
I should be on
the fucking front page,
we're top of the league.
Football doesn't sell copies,
it's not sexy enough.
I'll give you a story
that sells.
Round up, there's
something I've got to tell you.
I don't really know
how to put this,
so I'll give it to you straight.
I've known this for some time.
I'm gay...
a homosexual.
You're on the cover now...
I want to say something too,
I understand you and I want you.
Hey, I'm not joking here.
- Stop talking crap, man.
What, are you serious?
Yes, I'm gay.
Could I have one photo
in the shower?
Dad, I don't want to talk about
this right now,
this is my decision.
How could you do this to me?
Are you on drugs?
Maggi, wait for me in the car.
Dad, I'm gay.
Don't say that again,
don't say that in front of the lads.
We'll fix this.
- What do you mean?
I'll get you a shrink.
There must be a cure for this.
Dad, don't start that crap.
What's up, Eiríkur?
Hear your son's a fairy.
Fuck off home, you got
practice tomorrow!
Shouldn't we collect
the balls first?
Shut up or I'll throw
you into reserves!
Jesus Christ.
Reserves? No way, man.
Boy is he mad.
Maggi told me everything.
What are you thinking of?
I don't want to discuss
this with you.
You sure
chose the right moment.
You think of no one but yourself.
He's in shock...
Cool it. Yeah, cool it. You're
the one who should cool it.
You're the queer around here,
aren't you?
Show me some respect for a
change. - That's a good one.
Where is he now? Who?
Where's our son now?
He's with someone.
It's none of your business
who's minding him,
do you think I'd just
dump him anywhere?
I can't talk to you
in this state,
you're just drunk
and boring.
Shut up, You're just
an asshole, know that?
You're pathetic.
Gugga, come and dance,
can I steal her for a moment?
Sure, go ahead.
A pint. What'll you have?
Just a beer.
Stop it.
Cut that out.
But you like it,
don't you?
Yeah, give us a kiss.
Joke! Fat chance.
Cut it out.
Are you crazy?
You're loving this. Come on.
Come on.
Why are you grabbing me?
Stop it.
How long is it since you
came out of the...
Jesus Christ, she's always
the same slut.
How is she taking it?
Terribly, they're total morons,
I've had enough of this.
A shot of "Hot and sweet"?
It's always the same,
year after year.
What's it going to be
like next year?
For the reunion.
No title.
Knocked out in the 5th
round of the cup.
Can't be any worse.
I wouldn't bet on it.
Are you doing any
playing yourself?
Me and the lads are
playing once a week,
want to take a look?
I can give you a lift?
Football is shit.
There are two guys
in the team who are kind of gay.
Kind of?
Well, they're actually gay.
You might like to meet them,
or something?
I can pop around.
They're great guys.
Gugga, what are you
doing? Get out of here.
Jesus, what's going on here?
I'm trying to take a leak.
Let me give you a
blow job then.
Jesus Christ.
What are you doing?
Jesus, I can't take this!
Lads, we've got to
fucking fix this.
By castrating him?
It's terrible for
our image to lose him like this...
You're a shrink,
Ási, can't you fix this?
The sex drive is...
He hasn't quit,
no-one says he's quit.
That's not on the cards.
It is, if he's going
behave like a queer.
He might contaminate
the younger lads.
It's not contagious.
Just think of our Olga.
She got caught up
in shit like this,
and where is she now?
The Westman Islands.
This is just a temporary
situation.
It'll all blow over.
Yeah yeah.
I'll fix this.
I'm not one for
spreading gossip,
but I've heard
disgusting stories.
Really disgusting.
Perverted.
Then he has the nerve to
turn up at the reunion.
Hang on, what did you hear?
What's so bad
about being gay?
Isn't everyone these days?
Are you gay?
That's a lie.
Look, I can assure
you my son is not...
Gay, go on, just say it.
I don't want no ass
bugger in my team.
We've got to bar him.
He's not playing with us if
he's a pervert.
What are you doing here?
Haven't you
spoken to your dad?
You're off the team
so you're not allowed.
Is this a joke?
Do you find this funny?
No.
- Aren't you gay?
We can't have gays
playing with the champions.
Go join some other team.
Go fuck yourself,
leave me alone,
I'm busy.
Go talk to your dad.
Ottar dear,
come in for a second.
What is she doing here?
Whisky, Ottar?
Where's Maggi?
He's at the
Counterstrike tournament.
Sit down and chat
with your brother and the girls.
Orri.
Yeah, sorry man.
So how's it going, pal?
Just fine.
We just wanted to have
a chat with you,
just the family.
Yeah, we're only here
to help you. Orri and I,
and Gugga of course.
I also have a friend...
- Shut up.
You know I still love you.
Shit, you're a mess. What
the fuck is she doing here?
Isn't this good, the family?
Just sitting down and
talking things over.
Yeah, we're just
talking things over here.
People need to talk,
all of us together. Always!
This is no small situation
that you've gotten us into.
Surely you realise that.
It's a shock for us...
the fact that you're...
Gay!
That you are Gay!
This gay shit of yours
is just bullshit.
I'll go see if
dinner's ready.
Cut it out, Orri,
I don't have to put
up with this shit.
Just listen to him.
Shut up! What are you
doing here anyway?
I've come to help you.
OK lads,
the meat's ready.
Where's mom?
Isn't she going to eat with us?
She went down to the club.
It's women's night at KR.
So did you cook for us?
Hey, bitch!
Not a word out of you.
I've had enough
of this crap.
Can't you see what
you're doing to me?
I'm just thinking things over.
Don't give me any
of that crap.
Dad!
Pull yourself together
and stop all this
gay nonsense!
Your mother and Gugga here...
Sit down, Ottar,
I'm talking to you, lad!
You can't talk to the dude.
You know that. Jesus!
He just needs some time.
- Shut up!
They're born into the world,
you bring them up...
...teach them how to fend
for themselves and this
is all the thanks you get.
Fuck.
Ragnheidur!
You can come in now.
Orri!
- Shut up!
He was so young
when he scored that goal
against those fucking Italians.
Only 15.
Dad. He's gay.
A faggot!
Lt'll be alright.
Mom...
...Did you make some
kind of pudding?
Orri!
I'm in a hurry, I've got to go
and open the video store.
Orri, we should leave.
You go and wash up
or something.
Try to do something
for a change.
Stop bugging me,
I'm talking to Mom.
Try to show your mom
some respect, lad.
Maybe I'll just
take it with me then.
I'll bring the bowl
back of course.
This isn't like the time
I took the soda-stream thing,
I'll bring it back. I Promise.
There's some cream
in the fridge.
OK mom.
See you, coach.
Shouldn't
we get going?
Yeah, Maggi, aren't
you coming with us?
No, I've got to
complete this mission.
Don't you want to
get dressed and...
Cool it.
What mission?
I'm killing these
mobsters...
These are great guys,
you know.
You know, we're pretty
easy-going around here.
Come on, lads,
put some sweat into it!
Here's Ottar.
Well then,
where are the gays?
You won't be disappointed.
Daniel, come over.
I want to introduce you
to our new striker.
Guys! This is our
new striker, Ottar Thor.
Weren't you on
the KR team?
Let's split into teams.
Ottar, don't you want
to go and change?
Right, lads, line up!
Into what?
Well, what do you think?
Great, good fun,
a lot better than I imagined.
You're just being polite.
I mean it.
Thanks for the game.
You too.
Matti, have you got
any hair conditioner?
Are you out of your mind?
I've got some,
what do you want?
Redkin or Aveda?
Just Redkin.
Ottar, have you had
a go at screwing Danny here?
I'm out of here.
Don't go.
You've got to try it sometime,
it's really good, man.
Isn't Matti here
next in line?
Hey, don't give me that.
Stop it!
Next meeting is on
Friday.
Stop it! God, you're a pain!
We've done quite well
in the amateur league.
But been stuck in third place
for most of the summer.
Just need one push
to the top of the league.
We need to tighten our
team work a bit, better attack.
What do you mean?
You're cute, honey,
just not aggressive enough.
I haven't stopped playing
for KR yet.
Your dad won't stand
for that.
No, he'll shove you straight back
into the closet, love.
Fancy sitting on the
bench all summer?
Can I give you
a lift somewhere?
Actually I have a car,
but yeah, why not?
Bye.
I've got to pop in
somewhere first.
Fancy a barbecue?
Sure.
The homies are on the
balcony, come in.
What's she doing here?
Sopranos, all in the family.
Have you given any thought to
women's football, Pétur?
Pálmi is doing great with
the women's team, man.
I saw them play those Italian
sluts, fucking great stuff, man.
He did a great
fucking job on them.
Once you've proven yourself
with the women,
the national mens team
could be next!
See what you've done?
I don't believe it,
they just scored!
So he kept on
sending me letters
and stuff,
and then when my wisdom
teeth were taken out,
he sent me a box of ice-pops!
I swear, don't you think
that's cute?
How long have you
guys been together?
Wow, that's been nearly...
Two months. Shit!
Dad can be a bit difficult, but
mom is softer than the old man.
I'm working on him.
Trying to ease him into
the homo vibe.
I rented him that
Philadelphia movie.
That AIDS movie.
The one with Tom Cruise?
Hanks.
Yeah, the one about the
brave queer who dies.
So how old were you
when you won the title?
Yeah, you made a
great Miss Iceland.
Yeah, you sure were.
You must have been in
really good shape back then.
I suppose so, yeah.
I'm just saying that when Peter
here was coaching Lilleström...
They lost every game
that season...
That's why he's just
coaching amateurs
and working
in the video store...
He's lost all credibility.
We managed a draw
against Rosenborg.
It's incredible how
unlucky
Lilleström has been with its
coaches.
What was the name of
that dude before you again?
You mean Stefán Oli?
He killed
himself, didn't he?
Shut up, Orri.
It wasn't because of that.
I'm just saying that a
draw is for losers.
Nothing personal.
A draw is when you don't lose,
but you don't win anything either.
Wasn't that before Ottar
came out?
You were still together then,
weren't you?
It was more on and off.
Yeah, and then you
had that accident, didn't you?
Hey, you were driving
drunk, weren't you?
I remember Orri saying that.
Big scandal.
It was in all the
gossip magazines.
I'm not saying that goal you
scored wasn't any good.
Against Arsenal.
It was fine.
I'm not trying to take
that away from you.
Want a hotdog?
Mustard, onion?
Got any mayonnaise?
Jesus, man,
what the fuck's that?
There's no mayonnaise here.
Mustard or ketchup
or we just forget about it.
It must have been
fun doing modelling
after you won the title.
All those fashion shows and
photo shoots?
People often say, I should
be a model.
Yeah, but still.
You're not pretty enough.
And you're also fat.
Oh... I thought...
No! It's just not like that.
Let's have another drink.
KR? The worst game of all time?
Screwed on their own turf!
The lines are open.
Hello, who's speaking?
First I'd like to thank you
for a great programme.
What's happened to Ottar Thor?
Has he changed sides?
Is there any truth
to these rumours?
That he's going to be
playing with girls?
You're referring to the
rumours regarding his sexuality?
Isn't he a queer bast...
It's your fault we lost.
I'm just the way I am.
I am what I am.
It's not my fault they
kicked me off KR.
Are mass-murderers just
meant to be themselves?
That's not
a fair comparison.
What's this asshole
doing here, anyway?
Take it easy.
We're just friends.
You think of no-one
but yourself!
They're going to give
me hell in school.
I can deny it all.
Then you're on the
magazine cover.
Well, hopefully.
You've just fucked everything
up, the way you always do!
Can't you two just be friends?
- Shut up.
He's just a spoilt brat.
Hallo. Mom?
Hey, who are we
playing against?
Hi Maggi, how are you?
Are we ready to party?
What, are you drunk?
Listen, pal, take a cold
shower before you get changed.
Are you Pétur?
I hear this is a gay team.
I'm gay.
This ain't no gay team.
Doesn't matter, I'm gay
and I'm playing.
I've had enough
of this fairy shit!
Pétur, go after him.
I heard you need a goalie.
- Yes, have you played?
Well, you know,
with lots of teams.
In the amateur league.
Welcome then. I'm Lára.
- I'm Brósi. Have you got a kit?
We're not queers!
Is it natural for footballers
to talk like this?
"Hey, he's cute"
and all that kind of shit.
Bullshit. Where did you
hear that?
I don't want to be
on the bench all summer.
Pétur, this isn't
going to work.
Why not?
The rumours about
our team.
They're saying this
is a faggot's team.
Who's saying that?
Everyone. I can't play
on this team anymore.
Why not?
Are you prejudiced?
I'm not.
I know lots of gays.
I'm just not
one myself.
I'm not gay either.
Yes you are.
What's that supposed
to mean?
What are you
talking about?
This is a gay team
and I'm not gay.
If you're not gay
then this isn't a gay team.
Exactly.
No, but that's what
everyone is saying.
I can't play on
this team anymore.
Come on, don't go!
Right, shall we get going?
We've got a situation here.
Delta Force forfeit the game.
- Why?
One of us is injured,
we're only ten.
That's okay,
one of ours just quit...
Let's not go crazy,
we have rules,
It's eleven in each team.
Okay...
We get three points then...
Let's shake on it.
What's going on?
They're giving us the game.
They don't want to play us.
You know that bloody well.
Homos 3 points,
Homophobia 0 points.
That's great, man.
Hey, they gave
the game away.
Really?
Yeah, we're top of the league.
Hey, Maggi is out front.
This one here has always been
one of my favourites.
It's Japanese, from Japan.
It's oriental.
Looks exotic.
This is just basic shit,
man.
Look at the dick
on that babe,
it doesn't get
any better than that.
That's incredible.
Come on,
you dirty old man.
Hi there, kid,
how's it going?
I'm picking up a tape for dad.
Your dad still
owes me.
That's just not
good enough.
This isn't charity.
I want to be paid so
you tell him that.
I don't want to have
to blacklist him.
Here's the tape,
get it back on time.
There are rules.
Leo is such a hunk.
Really sexy.
She's cute too,
nice boobs.
Leo put on weight after
he acted in that film the...
The Beach.
Yeah, I think it makes him sexier.
- Really?
Makes you want to bite into him.
Fucking gays, you turn it all
into some faggot bullshit.
Fucking perverts.
Maggi? Maggi!
Oh, just let him go.
Blow me.
Right now?
People don't want to
play us anymore.
That's pathetic,
this is a sick society.
People are
so insane.
Fuck it, this is a joke anyway.
This is no joke.
There are only five of us,
we need six to play.
Can't we just phone someone?
I could call Kári.
- Yeah, call him.
Who is he?
He came second
in that drag competition.
That's just what we need,
another drag queen.
How many more
do we need?
Six. - No, four.
This is Freddy and Percy.
They're going to stick with us.
They enjoyed it so
much yesterday.
They're both gay,
which does no harm.
Listen, if you don't know how to
tackle, just forget about it.
Fuck off.
Take it easy.
No! What are you doing?
We've never had cards
before.
About time.
This is ridiculous.
You did that on purpose, you
kicked me instead of the ball.
Stop squabbling,
you fucking queers!
Are you crazy, man?
Mouth to mouth.
Help him up.
Take the free kick.
Is mom home?
She called...
- Speak up.
She just called,
she's on the way home.
What's going on here?
What mess is this?
Grab your schoolbag,
come with me.
I'm in the middle
of a game.
I don't feel like coming.
Have you got money?
No.
Buy yourself a
pizza.
Tell your mom to call me
when she comes in.
See you.
"Cooking with Joey Fel"
Aren't you going to
help me?
I'm going to finish
watching Joey Fel
and then go to
the club with the lads.
Really?
I told you.
I thought we were going
to watch Moulin Rouge...
I've got red wine
and cheese.
It's a Nicole Kidman theme-night.
I'm just going to have
a beer with the lads.
Don't drink too much,
it's a big game tomorrow.
You sound
like my mother.
Will you be long?
Maybe.
I'm not responsible for you.
You look a lot better.
It's not too bad.
I hear they're going to
trash you.
They're not going
to give the game away...
After that screw-up
the other day.
It's going to be a hard game.
Great.
Otherwise you'll just
win the league.
I only mention this because
you've got to control your men.
You've got to control
those queers.
I don't want any fights.
This is just for the sake of
the league, you know?
For the whole concept
of fair play...
Just blow your fucking whistle!
Hey, guys, let's do
another song...
Dancing Queen
or Waterloo!
Oh, hi son.
Jesus Christ.
Fucking disgusting!
Eh, get out.
No, don't stop.
I've got to stop.
Hi, is Maggi here?
Just leave him be.
What happened?
What do you mean?
Nothing.
He comes back here in a
fucked-up state.
Spare me the sermon.
What were you doing
at my parent's place...
...Messing with me
and my affairs?
I don't know.
It was just bullshit.
Have you talked
to him?
No, he doesn't talk to
me about anything.
How's he doing at school?
Do you want to come in?
What do we do now?
I don't know.
Shouldn't I get going
before the kid wakes up?
I'm glad to see so many of
you could make it today.
I don't think the league has
ever been as popular as
it's been this year,
or as... diverse.
And now I'd like to invite
Iceland's best known coach
to draw this year's finalists.
A warm hand please
for Victor Ingi!
Is this the hat?
I'm sure you have something
snazzier in your division,
but this is good enough
for us amateurs.
The first team out of the hat...
Pride United, the faggots.
They'll be playing the
Fish Factory from Raufarhöfn.
Where the hell is Raufarhöfn?
Are you a moron?
In the east.
How am I
supposed to know?
Isn't that miles away?
Yeah, but they're
an easy team,
we've got a real chance
to make it to the final.
This is great, guys.
We're going into the
country to play football,
it'll be great fun.
Who cares if we know
nothing about Raufarhöfn?
Scoring goals is what matters.
It's all about scoring
more goals than the enemy.
I'd also like to tell you
that we've finally got
a website up at
www.amateurleague.is
with all the classifications
and everything.
Let's give the designer a hand.
Thanks, Goggi.
Are you sure
about this rehab?
Listen, about,
you know...
We don't have to talk about it.
We were drunk, that's all.
It's time I sorted myself out,
I must be hitting
rock bottom
if I'm sleeping
around with gay men.
Shit. This is a shock.
I was going to cook.
It's a theme-night,
I rented a Mexican movie,
I've got wine and...
Maybe the theme-nights
aren't working out.
Titanic wasn't my idea
of a great night.
Is that what's
bothering you?
They're meant to be
fun nights.
No, that's not it.
Isn't your wife still giving
you blow jobs?
Still? It happened once,
by accident,
I was drunk, you know what
I'm like then,
I'll do anyone.
You know what I'm like.
You know how I feel...
Just relax a minute, let go...
This isn't exactly what I'm
looking for right now.
I'll cook us a meal,
we'll have some wine.
Let's talk this over.
Come on.
We can still be friends.
Go clubbing
and meet at practice.
Don't be like this.
It's over.
Relax, just relax,
let me suck you off.
Ottar, come on!
You're just feeling horny.
Watch the movie and
jerk off.
Don't do this to me.
Don't walk out on me.
You know how I feel about you,
I'm fond of you.
Yeah, I know.
I'm fond of you too.
Yeah, but I love you or...
...or I'm really
fond of you.
We're over.
Let's just leave it at that.
What, bang bang, thanks
and it's over?
Sorry, don't take it so personally.
I'll see you at practice.
I'd like to start off by pointing
out some of the landscape.
Look at those
big blue mountains...
Enormous!
The game starts in an hour.
Where is the pitch?
The trawler won't be coming
in for two hours.
Two hours?
Half the team is
on that trawler.
We've got two hours to go.
- To what?
The game.
Jesus Christ! Celebrity corner.
Strike a pose.
Gay soccer star finally
comes out of the closet.
In-depth interview with Ottar
and loads of pictures.
Has that fucking rag come out?
Don't flash that
around here, pal.
"Still looking for Mr. Right."
Are you blind?
Says he likes Bruce Springsteen,
especially the early stuff.
Are you sure you're gay?
What pages are the photos on?
- Pages 20-24.
Now all hell's
going to break lose.
It's just one interview, come on.
Crappy weather.
It's been terrible all morning.
Bloody typical.
But they say it'll change later on,
wait and see...
How's the weather down south?
- Fine.
Isn't the trawler
coming in soon?
Yeah, everyone's really excited.
There's a car waiting for them
at the harbour.
Are your lads in good shape?
- Yeah.
I'll open up the centre.
You can get changed in there.
Come on, get a move on.
Take your shoes off,
there's a rack in there.
Has your dad been gay
for long then?
Dunno, not that long.
We've got a gay in the village.
He's cool and no-one ever
disses him.
Except when they're
telling gay jokes.
Do you want to fuck?
I'm not sure... Or...
There's not much else
to do around here.
Oh, really?
So tell me,
are you all queer?
This is the queer team
from Reykjavik.
Don't you know us?
So are you
a lesbian?
We're married.
We're just helping the lads.
They play the game,
we shout from the sidelines.
That's neat. We're pretty
liberal here in Raufarhöfn.
There's even a multi-cultural
community centre.
My wife is from Cambodia.
So she's "Cambodian"
but not "lesbian".
Good one.
And then of course there's Lárus,
the engineer. He's queer.
There's not much happening
for him and his gay life,
being the only gay in the village,
since that Pole
quit at the freezing plant.
He's going to be happy
to see you guys.
Hi guys, coffee is ready.
That's my woman.
What do you make of her?
Ok, that's enough, woman.
Stop that.
Where are you now?
Pulling into harbour?
No, I'm up at the centre.
Sigga's serving the
homosexuals coffee.
I see, could you drop Lárus off?
No, right you are.
The fishing's been
really great,
they decided to
keep on fishing.
Meaning what?
Can't we just call it a draw?
We're taking three points.
Those are the rules.
We get three points,
that's how it works.
You don't say.
Those are the rules.
So be it.
Shall we head down
to the pub? To Café Cambodia.
Is there a
cocktail bar here?
Come on, lads,
let's get plastered!
The wife runs a little café.
We even have an accordion
player on weekends...
...but he broke his arm recently,
poor thing.
Down to the pub, lads!
I want to hear about the
goal you scored against Arsenal.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Not now, man, later.
Don't be like this, talk to me.
Not now.
Haven't you got
a game to play?
It was called off.
So what's happening?
We're going down
to some bar or pub.
Café Cambodia.
- Yeah, my mom's place.
You go ahead
and we'll join you
once I've shown him
the sights.
Yeah, we'll see you
down there! Okay.
Maggi.
Why are you acting like this?
- What do you mean?
What's going on with you?
- Cool it, man!
I'm talking to him.
I'm just showing him the place.
- Where are you going?
To my bedroom, relax.
- To do what?
Just chill-out, man.
Will you be long?
No.
We've got to fix this
fucking mess.
Castrate him.
Shut up. I'm
doing the talking here.
Yeah, I've tried talking to
the lad. It's no use.
I even got Ási, the
shrink, involved.
Ási is a wimp.
What's the problem?
Does he want a raise?
Don't give me that.
We should have a non-gay
clause in all future contracts...
Something on paper
to confirm they have a wife.
Should we stick an asshole
clause into your contract too?
My contract?
What do you mean?
You know people talk
about you in the club.
Some girls in the junior
league have started to...
Now come on, guys!
We have to put a lid on this.
Remember the famous jockey
and his horse?
They managed to cover that up.
He makes us look like a bunch
of idiots.
Not necessarily. There's
no such thing as bad publicity.
Is your brain switched off? I want
him back on the fucking team!
Listen, is it alright if Maggi
stays with you for a few days?
Gugga got a place.
Is she going into rehab?
That's great.
Dad's out of the closet and
mom is in rehab, great parenting.
Can he stay here or not?
Yeah, the boy better
stay with his uncle for a while.
We can watch Barfly and even
Philadelphia when dad returns it.
Listen, thanks.
When are they releasing her
or whatever it's called?
In a few days, I think.
The kid needs a break
from all this gay shit.
I know
where he's coming from.
Maybe I'll even manage to nudge
him out of the closet.
Only joking!
You take care of
of the drunken bitch
and I'll take care of the
lad here. Case closed.
"He ain't heavy, he's my
brother." Strong words, I know...
...but I mean it.
Fucking jerk.
Listen, I owe you one.
I'll see you, okay?
Maggi, want a Coke?
What the fuck.
That'll cost 150kr.
A can of coke costs 150kr.
You know where the
kiddie movies are.
We have rules in here, boy.
Are you his dad?
We've managed to corner him.
He's wild, he's been
shouting about Raufarhöfn.
Is that where he was heading?
He doesn't have a
driving license, does he?
No, the dude is only thirteen.
Of course he can't drive.
He doesn't even have
any hair on his balls!
Do you own that jeep he's in?
- The Terrano Playstation?
Yeah, it's a fucking
pimped-up ride!
Take it for a spin
if the kid doesn't fuck it up.
Who gave him the alcohol?
- Was he drunk too?
Yes, I think so.
He couldn't have been drunk.
I gave him one or two beers
at the most.
It's better than the giant
nugget of hash he had.
I frisked the dude
and took it.
I confiscated it!
The hash?
Do you have it now?
Why, are you going to search
me with an anal-intruder?
I threw it away.
They've just
arrested the kid.
Jesus, what have you done?
Are you talking to me?
This is your fault!
- I didn't do this.
Sure you did!
You got him drunk and
lent him your car, you idiot.
That' s not true.
You said so.
Shut up. That's not true.
Look at the fucking jeep.
See what he's done!
Isn't it fucking insured?
You know what that
bitch is like.
The bloody whore
was going to do it.
They can never do anything
right, these cunts.
I don't even have
a driving license.
Hang on, you don't have
a license?
I can drive and stuff.
Those guys from the insurance
companies, they're insane!
Hey, what's your name?
- Who?
You. What's your name and
social security number?
Let's get going,
come on, Ottar.
Guys, what the hell were
you thinking out there?
The offence was in shambles.
Where was Ottar?
Though Ottar
didn't turn up, that's no excuse...
...you played like
a bunch of morons.
Where the hell was he?
- I don't know.
It's impossible without him.
I doesn't matter, I mean
you can't stop being a team
just because he doesn't show.
Guys, we're not in
junior league.
No, worse,
the amateur league.
Seriously, guys.
If you're going to play
in my team
you do what I say.
I'm sick and tired of all
you prima donnas.
There's only one
star in this team and that's me.
Shut up!
Why are you always
so nasty to me?
Relax! Brósi!
What are you doing?
I've had enough of this crap!
Maybe we should quit.
Don't say that.
I know we're all gay, but that was
never the point for me.
This isn't some kind of
a gay activist team.
I wanted to play football.
Let's not get bogged
down by politics,
this is about team spirit,
the team as a whole.
A man, a ball.
Yeah, I want
to play football.
Do you know
what makes us a team?
It's the fact that we're all gay.
No.
That's what unites us.
Fucking faggots.
Yeah, you fucking faggots.
I'm sorry.
Leave me alone!
Open the door, son.
Piss off!
Darling, open the door
and talk to us.
Fucking drunk!
Open the door now.
- Fucking fag!
Just leave him be for a bit.
Do you want some coffee?
This is for Maggi,
tell him it's from me.
Might cheer him up
in these dark ages.
Will do.
Do you think you
could pop over tonight?
What for?
For your mom's sake.
What about her?
She's dying.
Yeah, we didn't want
to say anything at first...
...she's had some tests.
She doesn't have much left.
I don't believe it.
She doesn't want to talk about it.
Your mother is a very
private person.
This is just between
you and me.
Understood?
What's wrong with her?
It's something...
...something incurable.
He didn't return the tape.
So last night I
knocked on his door...
Hi, there. Have a seat.
Nice article in the magazine.
- Shut up!
Let me do that, darling.
Sit down.
No need to strain yourself.
No thanks, not for me...
- Shut up, eat.
Son, maybe the issue
isn't so much that you're...
Gay, just say it.
Don't you think you should
forget all that nonsense?
I am your father,
they're laughing at me in KR.
Look at your mother,
see what it's doing to her.
What are you talking about?
- Nothing to do with you, woman.
This is between
Ottar and myself.
I'm only here for her. I haven't
come to listen to you.
Just relax.
- Shut up.
All of us here
care about you, Ottar.
Me, your brother Orri, Aµsi
the shrink here, your mother...
who, thanks to you,
has become the laughing stock
of the KR women.
Yet she's still here.
She loves you.
- Yes, as we all do.
Shut up, I do the talking
in my house.
I'm not here
because of you.
I'm here because
mom is sick.
What have you
told him?
I told him that...
That you were dying.
I only had a wart removed
from my foot.
It could
have gone badly.
Could I have a word with
you in the kitchen?
What madness is this?
Your dad is a bit eccentric,
he asked me to come here and...
Don't be talking shit about
my dad, okay?
Orri, take it easy.
I can't take any more of this,
I'm out of here.
Are you coming?
I'll hang around
here for a bit.
Finish eating,
make sure everything is okay.
Come and have a word with me.
Why are you always
so nasty?
Shut up.
Orri?
Jesus, domestic violence!
He's getting too cocky.
Does he expect us to play
against a team of faggots?
I was there and that
was the conclusion.
Yeah, on our pitch,
one game
and then he'll sign
the contract.
Over my dead body!
Look, this doesn't
have to be a problem.
And you say they suck?
Of course, they suck.
What is this shit?
If you go ahead with this I quit.
This could be good PR.
Picture the headline
KR supports repressed minority.
We're not going to
advertise this shit.
Guys, we'll make it
look like a practice game.
Are you serious?
Shut up.
It's my club, not yours.
August 16th, Pride United
versus KR on the KR pitch.
We're playing KR.
Hang on, where's the catch?
What do you mean?
Just think of what this game
can do for gay rights...
I'm not about to embark on some
bullshit crusade here!
We're going to play KR.
I've said this so often,
I'm no activist.
That's not what
this is about, guys.
Let's no get bogged down
by politics here.
Are we ready
to play a top team like KR?
This is about football!
Lt'll be fun, it'll be fun!
Here's to us, lads! Cheers!
To Ottar!
Gay United, wow!
Let us in, we want
to talk to the board...
...they're trying to change
KR into some kind of
gender-bender club.
I want to talk to him - now.
We'll get more seats in.
Call you back in five.
What's going on out there?
It's because of tomorrow's game,
people are upset by the gay
aspect of the game.
No, enough of this,
the game is cancelled!
It's not that simple.
- Why not?
The game is sold out.
They're going wild.
Stebbi says we've broken
all box-office records.
There are twenty or thirty
thousand gays on the march,
and they're all coming.
What march?
It's gay pride day
tomorrow, Björgvin.
Faggots and lesbians are
marching across town.
I'm putting
an end to this.
You can't do that,
the media will fuck us.
Is he ready?
He refuses to come out,
he's locked himself in.
Isn't he coming with me?
Maggi, are you OK?
He put a lock on his door,
I didn't want to interfere.
He's got a
girlfriend and stuff.
Maggi, don't do this to me.
I've got no time for this.
I thought we were all
supposed to tog out?
You've got to be in drag,
it's gay pride.
It's all about pride, baby.
I understand but we decided
to be a team.
Oh, don't be a square.
Give us a break.
That's what we decided.
Just walk out there, be proud,
be gay and have fun.
You'll be the
only one in a costume.
No, we're all in costumes.
Let's hope the weather holds.
They expect some precipitation
in the afternoon.
Some wetness.
- You mean rain?
That's what the
weatherman said...
Shut up, dad.
Are you coming on the march?
Downtown?
Of course
they're coming.
Are there gays
in Cambodia?
No, it's forbidden.
It isn't legal at any rate.
Get up, Eiríkur.
I'm not feeling too good.
Eiríkur Gudmundsson, get
out of that bed this minute!
You are going to watch your
son play football!
No-one has had to drag you to
a game before.
This is different.
He's playing with
a bunch of faggots.
What's wrong, son?
You're the one who's
driving everyone crazy.
There's been a lot going on.
I hardly even
know you anymore.
Don't give me that,
I'm your dad.
Yes, he is, he even
had a blood test.
Who's this?
That's his girlfriend.
- Mom!
That's your girlfriend.
Isn't her name Rósa?
Rósa from Raufarhöfn?
She's cute.
Yeah, cute Rósa.
I don't want to talk about it.
Are you still pissed
about that interview?
Of course I am.
You should hear
the slagging I get.
Everyone knows about it,
it was on the cover!
It's not that I hate gays,
I don't see why you
make such a big deal of it.
You went over the top.
I suppose I did,
I'll give you that.
Aren't kids more hip about
these things today?
Yeah, equal rights and all that?
I made a mess, but at least
your mom's still a Miss Iceland.
Your friends must think
that's cool.
No, well, maybe.
Raggi and the lads are
always talking about her.
That's not enough, you
can't solve it that easily.
And now you've
got a girlfriend too.
A girlfriend in secondary school,
that's cool,
no matter what people say.
She's just a friend.
I'd hold on to that girl,
she's a good girl.
How gay can you get?
Are we okay then?
Are you coming
with us? Yeah, ok.
Girls. Wait for me!
Has it started?
God, am I too late?
Hi, guys.
It's going to be strange
playing against you, man.
Why's that?
I'm usually in the
same team as you.
We've always been on
the same team.
What do you mean?
Hey, is there a
Gay Pride ball afterwards?
Down at the Gay Bar,
are you coming?
Yeah, guess so.
Why don't you just
come with us?
Yeah, why not.
- See you later.
We're not sitting here!
Come on, get up!
What do you mean?
You're coming with me or
I'm not talking to you anymore.
Have you spoken
to your dad?
He spoke to me earlier.
Now he knows I exist,
I'm not just anybody anymore.
Let's get the crowd going!
Well then, lads, here we are.
Don't worry if you are nervous.
The main thing is to
forget about the crowd,
and all the things people
want to read into this game.
How can I put it?
This is football, right?
I mean when I scored that goal
against Arsenal...
...it was a great goal,
and an unforgettable experience
to score in front
of 35 thousand people.
You'll never experience that, lads.
But you can believe in it.
Let's go for it, into
the game in that spirit.
I was just playing football!
Just a man and a ball,
a ball and a man,
and we're in this together and
we'll do our best, right?
And even better than
that if we need to.
Guys, it doesn't
matter who wins.
This is about who
scores more goals.
A man, a ball.
Let's do it! Together!
Faggots, faggots!
Fucking faggot football!
Come on then!
You're not going out
in that dress?
Put some pants on.
For a friend.
We didn't do too well, did we?
You didn't seriously think
we were going to win, did you?
No, maybe not, but...
That's football.
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com