There are over 700 slums in my city...
and most are ruled by drug dealers.
They carry AKs, Uzis, AR-15s...
you name iT.
Around the world
these guns are used for wars.
In Rio, they're in the hands of thugs.
Their bullets cut through cars like paper.
It's crazy to think that in a city like Rio,
cops just go into slums to enforce the law.
Cops have families.
They're afraid of dying too.
- Which way?
- Up here, let's go!
What happened here was inevitable.
The drug cartels and the police had
to work out ways to get along.
After all, nobody wants to die in vain.
Marcinho, here come the pigs!
I know. They're here for the payoff.
Fumaca, take them the money!
You two, cover him!
In Rio, peace depends
on a delicate balance...
between the thugs' ammo
and the cops' corruption.
Honesty isn't part of the game.
When honest cops go into slums...
bad shit generally happens.
- Are they getting out?
- Can you see Fabio?
- You won't need your gun.
- You're gonna leave me unarmed?
Get out! Get out!
- Can you see Fabio?
- Shut up, man.
Can you see him?
- What's going on?
- Calm down.
What's up Oliveira? Back again, huh?
Where's our money, punk?
Shit!
- What's going on?
- Hang on! Hang on!
- Shit!
- Is Fabio there?
- Shut up!
- What is it?
In Rio, every cop has to make a choice.
He either turns dirty,
keeps his mouth shut...
or he engages in war.
That night Neto and Matias
made the same choice...
I did ten years earlier: They chose war.
Who did you shoot?
- Who did you shoot, man?
- Let's go, dude! Move it!
- Shit! Who's shooting, bro?
- Two cops are up here!
Shit!
They're coming your way!
Shit, bro!
They think they can fuck with us?
Fuck!
Run!
- Shit!
- We're surrounded!
- Just keep shooting!
- We're gonna die, man!
Neto and Matias didn't
stand a chance of surviving.
Regular cops aren't trained for war.
I'm running out of ammo!
Just stay calm! Let's go in easy, guys.
There are a lot of people at the party.
We gotta go in carefully.
There may be cops down.
Me? I'm no regular cop.
I'm from BOPE, Rio's elite squad.
- Who knows this slum?
- I do.
- You're gonna take us in, then.
- Let's enter from the main road!
In theory we belong to the same force,
but actually, we're totally different.
Our symbol shows exactly
what we're all about,
and our uniform isn't blue, it's black.
Nobody goes in! None of you go in!
You all stay right here!
BOPE always steps in when
the regular force just can't cut it-
and in Rio, that happens every day.
They think we're dumb enough
to go in there?
My name is Captain Nascimento.
I was BOPE's Alpha Team Leader.
I'd been fighting this war for years
and I was getting sick of it.
ELITE SQUAD
SIX MONTHS EARLIER
Honey, I wanna be home with you,
but I'm working.
You can hear his heart beat? Let me hear.
Wow, it's strong... It beats so fast!
Honey, I gotta go back to work.
No, don't worry.
I'll put it in the microwave.
Love you too.
I'm not sure what bothered me most,
the dealers or the corrupt cops.
What's up, Pompeu?
- You bring the pieces?
- Yeah.
In my day the police had 30,000 men.
With that many guys they could
have ended the drug trade.
But they were badly trained
and made low wages.
They just didn't give a shit.
Fuck, man. I'd love to shoot those assholes!
Which ones, Captain? Just say the word.
Those fucking cops.
BOPE only had 100 men.
For every gun I took, 3 got sold back.
Number 14, let them make the drop.
We'll get 'em on the way out.
Sir, if I shoot the dealer,
I might hit the cop too.
- Both of them, huh?
- Absolutely, Captain.
Then squeeze the fucking trigger.
To me, those who helped dealers
were just as bad.
Man, I gotta admit it. I had a short temper.
And my life was getting
more and more complicated.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, honey.
- Let me just grab some...
- Sit down, I'll bring it to you.
No, honey, I gotta go.
I have to get to work early.
You just got home
and now you're going back?
- I hardly slept last night.
- How's the baby?
When I get nervous he feels it and he didn't
gain any weight last time.
What do you want me to do?
If I knew it would go on like this,
I wouldn't have gotten pregnant.
Bye.
Wait, at least take a sandwich... Beto!
With war, you always pay the price.
And when it gets too high it's time to baiI.
That's when I found Neto and Matias.
Captain Fabio: Maintenance Chief.
Captain Oliveira: 3rd Precinct Chief.
They started the same way I did,
as rookie officers at their precinct.
I was impressed on my first day too.
Welcome, Lieutenants.
From now on you are under my command.
You will be evaluated daily
by me and my men.
These officers,
which I am honoured to command...
in addition to being family,
are the best on the force.
Neto and Matias fell for the usual bullshit.
They were like angels.
But I needed someone like them.
Actually, I needed
a guy with the brains of one...
and the heart of the other.
It would have been easier
if I could've had both...
but who says life is easy?
This is where you're gonna work, Neto.
- This is the auto shop?
- Yeah. Is that a problem?
Can't you put me somewhere else?
I don't know shit about cars!
There are 46 cars and 12 motorcycles.
You need to get them all up and running.
- Hi, Captain.
- At ease.
These two are your assistants.
- Boss, car 249 will be fixed today.
- Finally, Tiao!
Yeah, but the parts aren't here yet,
so I took the clutch from this one.
But the car is brand new!
You're already taking it apart?
There's a lot of good stuff here.
I fixed two cars already this way.
Whatever, Tiao! This shit
isn't my problem any more...
It's the rookie's.
- Hello, Sir!
- Lieutenant.
- At ease.
- You can be at ease too.
- Have a sandwich, coffee, water...
- I'm not hungry.
Let's get to work,
I want this car back in shape today.
- But without parts?
- I don't care. Let's make it work.
Neto was impulsive,
he acted before thinking.
Matias thought way too much, before acting.
See that pile of paperwork? Each is
a crime that the cops didn't stop.
In Neto's hands they would turn to flames.
With Matias they would become statistics.
This is Lt. Matias. He's your new boss.
- Hi, boss.
- Lt., these are your assistants.
Corporal Bruno and Private Machado.
Your job is to fix the radios...
- and organise the reports. Got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Your desk is over there.
- Sorry, boss.
If you need anything, just let me know.
Carry on.
Neither of the two had my training...
But one of them
was gonna have to replace me.
Listen up, class...
Matias was dedicated and smart.
In BraziI a guy who is black and poor
doesn't get many opportunities.
But that didn't bother Matias.
He wanted to be a lawyer...
so he enrolled in Rio's best law school.
Get into groups of four, people!
Then choose one of these subjects.
Guys, I want to do the Foucault, okay?
There's only three of us.
We need someone else.
It's a privilege to have a cop like this
on the force.
Matias was very naive.
He thought studying the law had
everything to do with enforcing it.
To him, cops and lawyers
had the same mission.
I'm handing it in anyway.
The professor won't notice.
But to be part of my squad,
he would have to wake up to reality.
- Is this Sociology?
- Yeah. What's your name?
- Andre.
- Andre what?
- Andre Matias. Why?
- You're in our group, okay?
I'll explain in a second.
Foucault's Discipline and Punish.
Hi, I'm Maria. This is Dudu and Roberta.
To become a BOPE officer,
a guy needs to know his bearings.
You know the Pope is coming to Rio, right?
He wants to sleep at the Bishop's...
house next to the Turano slum.
And we need to guarantee
him a good night's sleep.
But Turano is a war zone!
I'll pay for a hotel room
in Copacabana myself!
I've already tried to convince the Governor,
but not even God
will change the Pope's plans.
He's sleeping there and that's it!
The Pope can't hear a shot, so we
have 3 months to clean up the area.
- We'll go in nightly.
- Commander, are you sure about this?
If we go in every night, they'll
know we're coming. We'll be shot at.
- People will die, Commander!
- Nascimento!
We start tomorrow. Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
- Dismissed.
The Pope had already been
to Rio twice before.
Didn't he know
how things worked around here?
No politician wants to see the Pope
take a bullet in his city.
If His Holiness wants
to sleep close to a slum,
what do you think
the Governor's gonna do?
Take that kind of risk?
Of course not. The Governor
would call on BOPE.
Neto, cut it out. I'm trying to study here.
Stop it for a while. Let's go for a ride.
Are you using your car tomorrow?
- What do you need it for?
- I'm going to the Prazeres slum.
Are you crazy?
Why are you going to a slum?
The guys at school run a NGO,
and our study group is meeting there.
They'll kill you there, man, you're a cop.
Neto, take it easy.
Nobody at school knows I'm a cop.
Be careful, man.
The Pope needed BOPE.
BOPE needed me...
and I needed a replacement.
It wasn't going to be easy.
I was gonna have to keep going
into slums just because of the Pope.
But I'd go in wearing black
and packing guns.
I didn't have a problem
with Matias studying.
The problem was he didn't realise
a cop isn't like any other student.
Hi Andre! I'm so glad you came.
This is Rose... and Elena.
He's much cuter than the other one.
You're frisky today, Rose!
Well, this is what I came for...
Boy, don't you stare now. Bye!
Sorry to make you come
all the way over here.
This is the office... and this is Rodrigues.
Rodrigues... Andre.
He represents the Senator who funds us
and he's a good friend of mine.
Do you have a candidate yet?
Well, now you do!
Senator Magalhaes. Number 4-5-1.
Take some to hand out.
5 minus 4 is 1. 4 plus 1 is 5. Don't forget!
It's hard to resist.
Who wouldn't want a pretty,
rich girI with good intentions?
Who wouldn't want to get in her crowd?
Hi, Romerito! This is Andre.
But a cop needs to know his limits.
- Maria, can we go to the arcade?
- Not today. I have work to do.
- Don't you have homework?
- Yeah, but I'll do it later.
But you promised you were going to study!
- I know.
- After rehearsal, go home. Ok?
- Okay.
- Now, go back to class.
- Is he having trouble in school?
- He's not doing so well.
- Do you know why?
- He doesn't like to study...
Maybe that's not it.
I don't know how Matias didn't see
the shit he was getting into.
I mean, you can't be a cop
and be part of the cooI crowd.
So... to Foucault,
the power structure shapes the law.
It's not under a social contract,
you know?
Power institutionalises mechanisms...
...to discipline and punish criminals...
...like in the jail systems of the past...
I'm so stoned, man.
...historically such institutions
are how the state enforces...
- Here, Andre.
- No thanks. I don't like it.
- Just a hit?
- No thanks.
Pass it over, Roberta.
- So, that's basically all I got.
- This is good shit!
You did a great job!
The project's due next week.
- Did you do your part, Dudu?
- Yeah, right.
Matias shouldn't have been there.
But since he was, he should have
busted those kids under law 6368.
He had just started law schooI and
already was looking the other way.
- Hey, guys!
- What's up?
- I think we did a good job.
- Romerito...
- weren't you going to study?
- Yeah...
- Look, he missed!
- Yeah, he can't even see the ball!
- Let me take you home.
- Just a second.
- Can I see your hand?
- What are you doing?
I think these kids are right.
Look the other way, kid. C'mon.
OK. Let's see if you're smart.
What letter is this?
- It's an "A"...
- Great. That's right.
- Now, what letter is this?
- I dunno... what is it?
- It's also an "A"...
- Really?
The kid needs glasses. Didn't you notice?
You think that's why he's doing badly?
I had the same problem when I was his age.
Let's go tell your mom.
- Come with us, Andre.
- Where? Up there?
To become a BOPE captain,
Matias had to learn to be unforgiving.
Just like the dealers.
They won't make fun of you
and you'll get good grades.
Hey Tinho, Bica... What's up?
- Hey, I took that test.
- Did you pass?
- Piece of cake.
- See? Studying makes a difference...
Don't worry about going up.
The guys here are socially conscious.
You can relax.
- Hey, wassup?
- Bye, Roberta!
- Glasses are for nerds.
- But look, Andre wears glasses too!
- Maria, I gotta go.
- Why, Andre? So soon?
I'll be late returning my friend's car.
That's too bad.
I'll take the kid to buy glasses
another day.
No, Andre, we'll take care of it.
Someone helped me when I was a kid
so I want to return the favour.
- Okay, cool. See you!
- Bye!
No one starts an NGO
without the drug lord's consent.
That socially conscious talk
is just bullshit.
To me, a dealer is a dealer.
- What's up, Baiano?
- Hey, bro.
I know how Baiano's story ends
and I bet I know how it began.
He must have had a fucked-up childhood.
It's not an excuse, but...
that's where most dealers come from.
- What's up, Goldilocks?
- Looks like it snowed up here...
- You got the cash, man?
- Here you go.
Xaveco, hand me two bricks.
What's really fucked up is when kids
with money end up dealing drugs.
There's no excuse for that.
Hey, man, what's goin' on?
- Nothin' much, just chillin...
- Bruno! What's up, bro?
- Hey, dude.
- Hey.
- How are you doing, man?
- Marcio... I got the goods.
- Cool, bro, come on in.
Hey Patty, how you doin'?
Just a minute. I'll be right back.
Here it is, bro...
- That's all you got?
- Fuck, man!
- It's hard to get this much weed.
- Well, bring more next time.
There's two grand here.
Get some more, dude, 'cause
people are smoking it like crazy.
I often ask myself how many kids
we lose to the drug business...
just so rich playboys can light up a joint.
Our goal is to seize all weapons.
We'll use channel 2.
Azevedo's team will go
by the Bishop's house.
- Renan's will go up Tamandare St.
- Yes, sir.
Nascimento, do you know 117th street?
Captain, do you?
I do, sir!
Well, 117 is next to the University
and is full of students.
I know, I told you this was a bad idea.
Nascimento, orders are orders.
We will reconvene at the centre of the slum.
- Understood?
- Skulls!
The strategy made sense...
but Operation Holiness
was just plain stupid.
But I couldn't be careless.
I was about to become a father.
And I didn't want to die for nothing.
- Stay down!
- Face the fucking ground!
- Hit the dirt!
- Stay down! Stay down!
Captain, are you okay?
- Where's the dealer?
- He's one of them, sir.
Line them up!
Move it!
I'm only going to ask this once!
Which one of you is the dealer?
Who is it?
- I'm just a student!
- You're what?
- A student!
- Just a student, huh?
Come over here, then. Look at your buddy.
Look real close. You see this hole?
Who killed him? Who?
- I dunno...
- You don't? I think you do!
Say it! Say it!
It was one of you!
One of us?
You're the one who killed him! You faggot!
You're the one who finances this shit!
You pothead piece of shit!
We come here to fix what you fuck up!
You're the ones who finance it!
You faggots!
Who's the dealer, goddammit?
0-7, bring the lookout.
Let's see...
Now let's see... Say it, kid!
Point him out! Who's the dealer?
Tell me right now!
This one, with the jacket?
Take him and the drugs to the station.
Captain, you OK? C'mon, let him go.
Now, get lost!
So, in closing, we believe
that Brazil's penal law...
...is a network of power and...
...unfortunately,
these micro power relations...
...end up exclusively protecting the rich...
...and consequentially, punishing the poor.
OK, good!
I think Maria and her group...
showed us that, with the abuse of power,
perverse institutions are created.
Can anyone give us an example
of such an institution?
- The police?
- The police. Good.
Tell us why.
We all know that when cops
go into the slums,
they just beat the shit out of people.
OK, Edu, so the police act perversely
against those who are poor
and compelled to commit crimes.
Professor? I hear what Edu is saying, but...
I don't think the police only act
perversely against the poor.
The middle and upper classes
are also victimised.
Maria and I were going to Buzios once
and they stopped us at a checkpoint.
The cops were really aggressive...
Did they hit you?
No, they pointed the guns at us!
Calm down, people!
- Go ahead.
- My father is a judge
and he said that the police go into slums
and just kill everybody,
like in the Candelaria Massacre.
Not only are they corrupt,
they're also cowards!
Calm down, folks!
Matias has his hand up.
Professor, everybody here has a very
superficial idea of what the reality is.
- Everyone is misinformed.
- Let him speak!
I'm sure there's corruption, but
most cops want to do honest work.
- Are you crazy?
- You're wrong, Andre!
Dudu's right. Who hasn't been
stopped at a checkpoint?
- It's routine here.
- No it's not!
They just want our money!
What I hear is that in the slums,
they shoot first and ask questions later.
It's not like that!
Let the guy finish, people!
I have a friend who's a cop,
and his best friend is also a cop
and they are honest guys!
I mean, sometimes
there has to be repression.
That's crazy, bro!
But you had weed on you, didn't you?
You have no idea how many kids die
because they start dealing weed or coke!
From your nice apartments,
you can't see that type of thing!
You're all misguided
by your stupid newspapers and TV...
That's it for today.
Mr Nascimento?
Were you in charge of the last operation?
Yes, I was.
Are you going to help me
find my son's body?
Ma'am, was your son in the drug trade?
Yes, sir. He was a lookout.
- We didn't kill your son.
- But you let him go, didn't you?
Did you think they'd forgive him?
Dealers kill lookouts who fuck up.
And... I knew it.
That mother made me feeI guilty,
and for a BOPE officer,
that's a dangerous feeling.
Was he your only son?
Yes, sir. He was.
It was time to find my replacement.
- Battery.
- OK, battery!
- And carburettor, boss!
- Hold on! Let him finish.
Brake disc, clutch, oil filter
and a cracked windshield.
Sir, this one needs a carburettor.
- Alright... carburettor...
- Yes, sir, that's right.
That car doesn't have a carburettor.
It's fuel injection!
- Does it have one or not?
- No, it doesn't.
- Listen to it! It has one!
- No, it does not!
- Are you fucking with me?
- No, of course not!
- It's got a fuckin' carburettor!
- It does not!
Look. Here's the carburettor, see?
He's right, sir, he's right.
It does have a carburettor!
But that's because
the original engine was replaced.
Look, everything's loose in here.
What do you mean?
Some cop sold the new engine
and put this old one in.
- Which cops did it?
- I don't know, sir.
Forget about it. It happens all the time.
The other day, someone stole a radio...
Are you guys insane?
Stealing gets you court-martialled!
- Yeah... right!
- Are you listening to me? Jesus!
If the cops had any brains,
they'd never let someone like Neto
be in charge of the auto shop.
Neto was just like me.
Once he got a mission,
he wouldn't give up on it.
What a bad call.
- I have a problem, sir...
- What is it? I'm in a hurry...
Some cop switched a new engine
with an old one, under our noses!
- You know who did it?
- No, but...
Ok, rookie. I'll ask the Commander
to open an investigation...
- ... and put you in charge.
- Me?
But I have to fix these cars
and I just need new parts...
Just make sure the Commander's
bike is running, ok?
- That's your priority!
- Yes, sir.
- Captain...
- What is it, rookie?
Here's a list of missing parts.
Jesus, that's a shitload of parts!
Why don't you ask Fabio for help?
- Sir, can't you help?
- Dismissed!
So what did the dirty cops do?
They told him to work the system.
Neto, I'll hook you up,
but don't forget my cut.
Captain, I just need to fix the cars.
I didn't join up to be a mechanic.
- Sir, where are we going?
- Just follow our usual fucking route!
The first time is always a good cause.
But once you steaI for the force
you'll also steaI for your family.
That's how the system works.
When a citizen wants a squad car
protecting his bakery,
or his bar, he's gotta pay.
I'm here for my protection fee.
Aren't you paying up today?
Yes, Captain. But I already settled today.
- You didn't pay me shit!
- I already paid Oliveira's guys.
Oliveira?
Sir, if I pay you too, I'm gonna go broke.
No, I'm the one who'll go broke.
I'm the one keeping you safe
and you pay Oliveira?
Deal with him, I mean,
you're on the same force, right?
Let's go, Neto.
- How much for this beer?
- It's on the house.
No, I'm paying. Here.
Cops ended up charging for everything-
For doing theirjobs,
and for looking the other way.
Hey! That guy's fining my customers.
I can't give you new parts
with this going on.
- Who gave the fucking order?
- But my parts! I need a new battery.
Look at him give out tickets!
Dude! Get over here!
- What's up, Captain?
- Get the fuck over here!
This area is mine.
Why are you fining everybody?!
- I'm just following orders.
- Whose orders?
- Bira's.
- Bira?
- Bira, get over here!
- I can't right now!
Here's an example...
The government was so broke,
it didn't have money to buy tow trucks.
So it decided to hire independent
contractors and pay per car towed.
Get over here!
Hold on!
Towing cars became so fucking profitable
that the system just ate it up.
You can't tow cars here!
This is my territory!
Captain, it's Oliveira's truck.
Here, work it out with him.
- What about my parts?
- Hold on.
Oliveira? It's Captain Fabio.
I came here to get some parts,
but I heard you've got this area now.
Commander, it's Fabio.
He's messing with our towing scheme.
Just clip his wings.
Fuck off, Fabio, it's my area now.
- Your area?!
- Yeah, deal with it.
Tell him about my parts!
Hello? That asshole hung up on me!
What about my parts?
Can't you at least get me a battery, man?!
- Isn't that the commander's bike?
- It's Friday, he's cashing in.
That's why his bike can never break down.
- Fuck, now I get it. Jesus!
- Yeah, we used to get our cut.
Now the Commander's keeping
it all for himself.
The system was so fucked up that
everybody stole from everybody else.
Sarge, my vacation is due next month.
- And my wife is taking off with me.
- How nice...!
I'd like to get the paperwork done,
so I can go.
I'm sorry but I can't do that.
I've got 40 cops ahead of you,
and our precinct needs you now.
Maybe I can talk to the boss
and see if he'll let you go.
- I'll have to do it by the book...
- But Sergeant,
I haven't taken a vacation in 4 years!
- You just need to do the paperwork.
- Maybe I can help you.
I want to help you,
but you need to help me help you.
Corporal Paulo, you wanna be happy?
You gotta make me happy first!
Am I right?
You gotta make me happy, man!
Understood, sir.
- Permission to leave, Sergeant.
- Granted.
That's a very serious accusation, rookie.
- I'm sure he tried to bribe him.
- Can you prove it?
If he can't prove it, it's just hearsay.
Rookie, just do your job and I'll do mine.
- Got it?
- Yes, sir.
Dismissed.
Neto just wanted to work for the police...
but he ended up like I did...
working against them.
Sweetheart, are you going up or not?
Honey? Are you okay? You feeling sick?
Beto!
Hi. Is everything okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
- You sure?
- Fuck! I can't breathe.
- Stay calm, honey.
- My arm is numb.
- It's not your heart.
It's just stress, trust me.
- Nascimento, your tests are all good.
- You sure?
I have a history
of heart disease in my family.
Your heart is in good shape.
Sometimes my ears start ringing,
my hands shake...
Your problem's not physical.
You're under a lot of stress.
I'm sending you to the psychiatrist.
- Psychiatrist?
- It's harmless.
When Matias defended the police,
he didn't know how fucked up they were.
For 2 months, he studied crime reports
and came up with a plan to position
the squad cars in strategic places.
But efficiency just didn't fly
at his precinct.
Sometimes it seemed like stopping crime
was the last thing
on the Commander's mind.
Shit, Estevao!
This report's gonna fuck me over!
Twelve homicides in a month?!
I can't report this!
Commander, I checked his report
and it looked fine to me.
- You trying to fuck me over, rookie?!
- No, sir.
Go get Fabio, then!
What about these four dead bodies, soldier?
The report is accurate, sir.
Didn't you see the map?
I don't give a fuck about numerology!
And now the piece of shit wants to
show me where to put my cars?
When a crime was committed in our
area, the Commander had to solve it.
But that took hard work.
- You asked to see me, sir?
- Yes.
- Is there a problem?
I want you to explain these four
bodies found in the Tabajara slum.
It's not my fault.
I did everything just like you said.
Dispatch, no bodies were found
in the 19th Precinct.
They're in Precinct 2, copy? Over.
It's easier to move the crime scene
than to actually find the criminaI.
There are lots of crooked commanders
that lower their statistics
by dumping bodies
into other people's districts.
But, some nights, it was
like musicaI fucking chairs.
Dispatch, the bodies are actually
in the 19th Precinct.
You copy that?
See, Commander? I took them out,
but they brought them back...
- I don't want to hear it.
- But Commander...
- Enough!
- Yes, sir.
Rookie, you are going to rewrite
this report.
Look at this. "Body found on the beach. "
A death on the beach is a drowning,
son, it's not our problem!
- But there was a bullet wound...
- Are you a coroner?
- No, sir.
- I want a new report by Monday,
because this one... never existed.
If you don't talk I won't be
able to help you.
It's just that...
It's not easy to open up.
And I don't know...
if you're gonna report the things
I tell you here to my supervisors.
If that's the case I'd rather talk
about a friend of mine...
who's going to be a father,
and is having serious problems.
Captain...
I can't help you unless you tell me
what your problem is.
And this isn't a confessional.
It's the Special Ops Psych ward.
And, off the record,
if I had to report everything,
there wouldn't be any cops left in Rio.
So... make up your mind.
You wanna talk or not?
Excuse me?
Captain, I will replace you when I can.
I need you for the Pope's mission.
I gave you a task, now get it done.
- Are we clear?
- Yes, sir.
Dismissed.
Call it fate, but...
the day I lost hope of leaving BOPE
was the day Neto came up with his plan.
- Hi, Neto.
- You got my car keys?
What are you doing, bro?
You're fucking up my map!
I figured out a way to fix the cars.
Come on, we just need to tell Fabio.
- What do you mean?
- Just follow me.
You're getting crazy!
I'm totally getting fucked by the commander.
What do you mean?
I'm broke. He's taking everything.
Oliveira's getting all my action...
You get a payoff from this club?
Yeah, so what? I'm not gonna raid the slums
and get shot at for
a lousy 500 bucks a month.
I can't believe this shit!
It used to be a straight deal, man.
It used to be an honest deal.
But the Commander's taking it all now.
- The dealers pay him off, too?
- You're so fuckin' naive...
Didn't you notice that his men
go into that slum every week?
They're going in there to get his cut!
How much do they get with the bookies?
At least 6 grand a week, maybe more.
Wow, that prick's
making some serious bank!
I know how we can get that money.
- And what's my cut?
- What do you mean?
You want all the money for yourselves?
No! We're gonna use the money
to fix the division's cars.
- Yeah, but what's my cut gonna be?
- You want to fuck the Commander over?
You kidding me?
You're the ones fucking me over!
- I'm gonna go take a piss.
- Wait a minute, Fabio, wait!
Andre, you better not bail on me, bro.
It was perfectly timed.
It took Matias 40 minutes
to get to the Commander's
biggest payoff spot.
That's when Neto stepped in.
- Try it again. See if it starts.
- Hurry up, man, I'm late!
- Okay, just try it again...
- I'm fucking late, man!
Think it's easy? You repair it.
- Now I think it'll work.
- Think so?
I'm really late, man.
Shit, it's gonna take some time to fix.
Hurry up and call Paulo. He'll fix it.
By the time the guy left, Matias
had already picked up the cash.
How are you, Santos, feeling better?
What do you mean?
Your buddy passed by
and said you were sick.
- Me, sick?
- Yeah, I even gave him the money.
You what?!
He said the Commander had sent him,
so I gave him the money.
Son of a bitch!
The plan was brilliant.
What could the Commander do,
call the cops?!
Neto worked the system perfectly.
But his plan was also very risky.
The Commander wasn't going to
take losing his money lightly.
At least Neto was fighting fire with fire.
Matias just kept on
making the same mistakes.
There's Andre. Let's go talk to him.
- No, I'm busy.
- I'm busy, too.
- Okay. See you, guys.
- Bye.
- Where have you been hiding?
- Hi, Maria.
- Check out who just walked in.
- Shit! He's gonna bust us.
What's up, guys?
- Mary!
- Maria!
- Everything cool?
- Where were you?
We just lost track of time.
- You look so pretty.
- So do you!
- Anyone want to dance?
- We are a little busy right now...
- Let's go dance.
- Alright. See you later.
Just because we have nice apartments!
Yo, I'm gonna go screw with him a bit.
Just don't end up screwing us over, man!
I guess someone's having fun with me.
But it's okay, I don't mind.
Let's keep dancing.
They tell you to obey,
they tell you to respond,
They tell you to cooperate,
and tell you to respect them!
Police for those who need it!
Police for those who need the police!
There's too much salt,
let's add some potatoes.
When the Commander
found out that 2 rookies
had stolen his money, he couldn't complain.
So, he took advantage of the situation.
Matias was sent to the cafeteria.
Neto was stuck back at the auto shop.
What are you doing here, Paulo?
They cancelled my vacation, to teach
me not to complain about the Sarge.
But what about the auto shop?
But now without his best mechanic.
Want some fresh guava jam?
Neto, I told you this shit was gonna go bad.
The Commander was sure
they were acting on orders
from someone higher up
who knew the system well.
Fabio!
- Yes, sir.
- Come here.
- You working tonight?
- Yes, sir.
I want you to check out
a funk party at the Babilonia slum.
- Me, sir?
- Yeah, you.
- Yes, sir.
- Tonight.
- Tonight?
- Okay. Excuse me, sir.
But the guy the Commander
would really punish,
was the one he thought
was screwing him behind his back.
Sweetheart, he's moving around!
He's the cutest little thing...
Too bad you're not here.
I want you to listen to his heartbeat.
Every time I thought about my son,
I remembered that kid's mother.
It must be fucked up to have
to bury your own son.
Let's suit up, men!
- Where are we going, Captain?
- We are going to the Turano slum.
We're gonna find that lookout's body.
The Colonel asked me to check out
a call about a funk party.
The slum's calm tonight, guys.
If we do things right
we might get some dough.
Don't tell the rookie though,
he'll rat us out.
Hey, rookie, what the fuck
are you doing with that rifle?
You think you're gonna go
into the slum with me?
- You're staying right here.
- OK. I got it, no problem.
Captain, this squad's going with Cabral.
- The Commander said to go with them.
- No, you're coming with me.
Rookie, put down that rifle and
go fix the Commander's motorcycle.
Let's go, Fabio, hurry up.
Neto, did you do that thing we talked about?
- Yeah, why?
- Captain, let's roll!
Okay, I'm coming.
'Cause I think they're gonna kill me, man.
- Matias.
- What's up?
- The shit's hit the fan...
- What happened?
They think Fabio did it!
- What do we do?
- Come with me. Let's go!
- Take over, Paulo.
- But Lieutenant...
Get down! Get down!
- Can you see Fabio?
- Relax, dude.
- What's going on?
- Calm down.
What's going on?
- You're not gonna need this.
- You're gonna leave me unarmed?
Get out! Get the fuck out!
- Where's Fabio?
- Relax. I'll find him.
- Can you see him?
- Shut up, dude!
What's up Oliveira? Back again, huh?
Punk, where's the money?
They weren't gonna kill Fabio
right there in front of everybody.
But Neto had an itchy trigger-finger,
and the way he saw it, that dealer
was reaching for a gun.
- Who did you shoot?
- Let's get outta here!
Shit!
What the fuck?
Shit, man! The pigs went crazy!
They're shooting at each other!
Fucking shoot! Cover me!
Do something.
I'm almost out of ammo.
I only have one more clip.
Shit, I got his machine.
- Leave a message!
- Shut up, asshole!
Now, if Cabral here gets promoted,
that's one more precinct
and that means more money.
- How much more?
- Excuse me.
Commander, help! We're surrounded!
- Call BOPE, Commander!
- What?
- Captain!
- What is it?
Cops are cornered at Babilonia.
I think one of them is hit.
There's no one available here.
Everybody's busy.
- What do I do?
- Jesus...
I am not in a hurry, son.
I can stay here all night.
- Where's the lookout?
- I don't know!
You deal here and you don't know?
I'm not a dealer, boss. I don't know!
We're gonna have to bag you again.
- He's out cold, Captain.
- Throw some water on his face.
Wake up, scumbag!
0-1, priority at Babilonia.
The cops are surrounded, sir.
Copy that, Carvalho. We're on our way.
Let's go clean up their mess.
We're going to Babilonia.
- What do I do with him?
- Put him on the Pope's tab.
Shoot them! Keep shooting!
We're gonna die, man!
- Shoot the motherfuckers!
- You guys are fucked!
They're shooting at us from down there!
From down there they can't hit us.
Just stay down, Matias.
Shoot, asshole!
- BOPE is here!
- Nobody goes in! Nobody goes in!
Everybody stay right there!
- We're gonna die, Neto!
- Shoot the fuckers! Shoot them!
- I'm out of ammo, dude!
- Then stay down.
Shoot 'em! Shoot 'em, Careca!
Fuck, bro!
Fuck!
They're coming at us!
- Lie down! Drop the weapon!
- I'm a cop! I'm a cop!
- We're cops, dammit!
- Drop your weapons!
- It's only you?
- Just the two of us.
Come here. Sit down.
Check the perimeter!
0-1, it's only the two of them.
Bocao, check out who we got.
- That's Marcinho, the drug lord.
- Let's take him.
- You guys OK?
- Yes, sir.
- Are either of you hurt?
- No, sir.
- Are either of you wounded?
Tonight you're gonna learn to carry corpses.
Yes, sir.
- What are you waiting for?
- Nothing, sir!
- Grab him.
- Pick him up.
Hold on. Hold on.
Hi, honey.
Your water broke?
Are you sure?
Stay calm. Remember what the doctor said?
No need to rush. I'm leaving
right now. I'll be right there.
-0-2...
- Sir?
You're in charge. Let's only take this
body down. My son's about to be born!
Congratulations, Captain!
Move it! Move it!
Jesus, this body is heavy as shit!
If you guys hadn't come,
they would've killed me.
- BOPE brought your weapon.
- Help us carry this corpse.
Let us through, man!
Get the fuck out of here with that shit!
- Sergeant?
- What is it, Lt.?
Excuse me. How do I get into your unit?
- You gotta be selected for it.
- How?
Check the Police newsletter.
Thank you, sir.
Keep an eye on this, Carvalho.
- Commander...
- At ease.
- Sorry for being late.
- No problem.
Just tell me... Is it a boy or a girl?
A boy... Rafael.
- What is that, Renan?
- It's pink eye.
- It's fuckin' ugly, man!
- Put your sunglasses on.
Now listen up. This is a gift...
but it's not for you. It's for the boy.
It's finally time to pick
your two replacements.
All right!
Commander, this is going to be
the best training camp in BOPE's history.
You can bet on it.
OK, let's get started. Number one here...
- Yes, that's Andre Pedrosa...
- He's on the bookies' payroll.
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
So he's fucked. He'll never make it.
Commander. I know this Olavo guy, too.
He's as dirty as they come.
Well, he's going down, too.
How about this Fabio guy?
I've heard of him.
He's a Captain, right?
- Fabio Barbosa.
- He's heavy duty.
He's been pimpin' chicks in Copacabana.
- I'll take care of him.
- Renan?
- Can you see OK over there?
- Yes, sir.
The guy looks like Batman.
Renan, what about the two rookies?
- The ones you rescued?
- I think they're ok.
- So let's see what they got.
- Listen up!
No busted eardrums this year, alright?
And no cut-off fingers.
Got it? Is that clear?
The thing with the guy's hand
was an accident.
He grabbed the blade
at the worst possible time.
- As for the eardrum... Carvalho...
- That was an accident, Commander.
An accident?
He was a major screw-up.
He deserved it, Commander.
A BOPE officer cannot date
a dealer's friend.
The truth is Matias was confused.
He wanted to be a cop but
he wanted to be a lawyer, too.
If Matias were a cop at heart,
he'd have told his girlfriend the truth.
But he made up a trip and let her go
looking for an internship for him.
He's been working with us
for almost a year.
He fucked up.
He's been great, a real problem solver.
Alright. But listen...
Can the interview be two weeks from now?
Great. Fantastic!
I was sure Matias was gonna give up...
halfway through training camp.
I just got Matias an internship!
You better get yourself a new boyfriend.
What happened?
Is everything alright, Baiano?
You tell me.
You know anybody in this picture?
Don't you recognise this piece of shit?
- This can't be him, Baiano.
- It can't be him!
He killed a friend of mine.
He killed one of our guys!
- What's it gonna be now?
- Cool down, man.
Look, Baiano, they have
nothing to do with this.
- I brought Matias here.
- Maria didn't know he was a cop.
- I just found out now.
- We didn't know!
Don't fuck with me!
Don't fuck with me, dammit!
Let me tell you something.
Pigs just can't come up here!
- Nobody knew...
- Shut up! I'm not done yet.
Who do you think keeps
the peace here? The police?
Give me a goddamn answer!
- The Red Command.
- That's right, bitch.
And I'm their front man!
To stay here, you need my blessing.
- We know.
- Who you with, playboy?
- Huh, playboy?
- With you!
- It's us!
- That's right, us!
It's us, Baiano.
I'll be watching, man.
- Go ahead...
- Shut up!
- Calm down, man!
- Xaveco, put some heat on him!
- What is this?
- Son of a bitch!
You've gotta be straight with me.
If not, it's gonna be a problem.
You can keep the newspaper.
Let's go.
Neto joined up 'cause he liked war.
Matias because he believed in the law.
And the dirty cop?
Fabio was just running away
from the Commander, man.
What he didn't know was, compared
to me, that Commander was a pussy.
JULY 1997 TWO MONTHS
BEFORE THE POPE'S VISIT
You have each come by your own means.
Nobody...
absolutely nobody invited you!
And you are not welcome here.
Prepare your souls...
because your bodies now belong to us.
I now declare open... BOPE Training Camp.
You will never survive!
Skulls... advance!
Assholes! You dirty bastards!
I know that to outsiders BOPE
seemed like some sort of a cult.
But that's just how it's supposed to be.
- Ask to leave! Beg me!
- No, sir!
We mould our men from pain
and humiliation.
To join BOPE, the guy has to prove
that he won't break under pressure.
- Go back to where you came from!
- No, sir!
- Go back to your precinct!
You think that no one here knows
that you're paid off by the cartel...
...that you're paid off by bookies?
Do you know why your number is 0-1?
Because you'll be the first to give up.
And I'm gonna make you do it!
- Ask me! Ask me to quit!
- No, sir! No, sir!
If you don't you're gonna be fucked!
- Beg, motherfucker!
- Okay, I give up! I give up!
-0-1 has given up!
- Skulls!
Out of every 100 cops who try,
five make the cut.
When I did it, only three of us made it.
Not even the Israeli army trained
men as tough as we did.
BOPE soldiers kill guerrillas
With knives in their teeth
they skin' em whole
We skin' em and then kill' em
with rifles by our side
BOPE soldiers defend Brazil's pride!
To join the war against the drug business,
you had to be able to take all kinds of shit.
The concept of strategy,
in Greek is "strategia".
In Latin...
In French...
- Are you taking notes?
- Yes, sir.
This will be on the test.
In English...
In German...
In Italian...
In Spanish...
Coordinator...
- What is it?
-0-5 fell asleep.
-0-5...
- Yes, sir!
Take this, please.
0-5, if you drop that grenade
you're gonna blow everyone up.
You're gonna blow up your comrades.
You're gonna blow up my assistants
and you're gonna fuckin' blow me up.
- Are you going to sleep?
- No, sir!
We all have faith in you, sir.
Now I will...
...start where I left off.
The concept of strategy,
in Greek is "strategia"...
In Latin...
In French...
- Team Leader!
- Yes, sir!
- Are you men ready for lunch?
- Yes, sir.
- How much time do you need?
- Ten minutes is good enough, sir!
You've gotta be shittin' me!
Team Leader, you're a joke.
You all have ten seconds to eat lunch.
Don't touch the food until I say so.
When you're done with your lunch,
I wanna see the ground clean.
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir!
- Now, go!
- Hurry up!
- Three seconds have passed.
-0-2 isn't eating!
- Your time is up.
- Time's up!
What is this food still doing here?
There wasn't enough time, sir.
Do you think it's fair,
in a country like Brazil,
where people are starving, 0-6,
for you to leave food on the ground
because you're disgusted?
- No, sir!
- And why didn't you eat, 0-2?
- I couldn't reach the food, sir.
- Can you reach the food now, 0-2?
Yes, sir.
Then kneel down and eat the food now!
I wanna see you eat all of it, 0-2!
- No bullshit!
- Yes, sir.
If you don't eat all of this food
the whole squad will spend the night...
out in the water, 0-2.
You feeling sick, 0-2?
0-2, if you throw up on your comrades' food
they're gonna have to eat your puke!
- Sir, I'm going to eat it, sir.
- Everybody eat! Now!
- Hurry up!
- Eat it!
It's all 0-2's fault!
I wanna see the ground clean!
Men in black, what do you do?
Take out the deviI that's wearing blue
Go up the slums and take out their crew!
Stop chanting!
Team Leader,
this is the worst squad
I've ever seen in my life!
Keep going, Team Leader.
Stop the chant, not the march!
I want you out of the water, now!
The first phase of the course was tough.
The idea was to weed out the weak,
and then punish the corrupt.
But me? I liked to punish first.
-14, lend him your ointment.
- I'm out.
-0-2! Wake up, bro.
- No, man, let me sleep!
- Take off those boots.
- I can't.
If I do I won't be able to get 'em back on.
- Take 'em off, dammit!
- You'll be fucked with wet feet.
Your foot is fucked, bro. Take 'em off.
Attention, 0-2!
- I've got news for you.
- Yes, sir!
You're the new Team Leader.
You have one minute to put this unit
in formation at the arena!
- Yes, sir!
- Move it! Move it!
Get in formation, you pieces of shit!
-23, get moving!
- That's 20 seconds, 0-2!
- Your time's running out!
- Yes, sir!
- Are they in formation?
Look behind you!
- Is that a formation?
- Squad in formation! Attention!
The squad's in formation, sir!
- That's a formation?
- Yes, sir!
- You sure?
What about your unlaced boots,
you animal?!
You piece of shit!
-0-2, follow me!
- Yes, sir.
Move it! Move it!
-0-2!
- Yes, sir.
- Do you see that raft over there?
You see it? Now that your boot is unlaced,
- why don't you bring over the raft?
- Yes, sir.
- You think you can do that?
0-2...
know why you won't be able
to do what I'm ordering you?
- Sir?
- It's not just because you're weak.
It's because to wear this skull, 0-2,
you have to have integrity.
Something you don't.
You belong with whores.
You belong with pimps.
You belong in abortion clinics.
We don't like corrupt cops, 0-2.
Corrupt cops don't make it in BOPE, 0-2.
- Are you gonna go get the raft?
- Yes, sir.
- Are you gonna bring it to me?
Well, let's see if you can do it.
Quit, 0-2. You're weak!
Ask to leave. You're not gonna make it.
Ask to quit, you piece of shit!
- I can't take it any more, Captain.
- I didn't hear you, 0-2!
I didn't catch that.
I can't take it any more, Captain.
I give up.
Louder!
So that everyone can hear that
you're a pussy. Say it loud!
- I give up!
- There you go, you piece of shit!
Attention, squad! At ease!
Face instructors!
- Skulls!
- You'll never be one of us.
Never!
Attention, 12!
Yes, sir!
You're the new team leader, 12.
Sir, I give up, sir!
You men are making us very happy.
Thank you, gentlemen!
Thank you very much!
Attention, 0-8!
Our farewell ceremony was humiliating,
but it sent out a beautifuI message:
Fuck the weak and fuck the corrupt.
When the first phase of training
was over, only eight men remained.
It was time to choose my replacement.
Matias surprised me.
He passed the first phase of training,
but he was dumb enough
to go back to schooI.
- You know who told me you're a cop?
- Hold it. What happened?
The head of the slum!
You don't know what's going on.
You know how long it took me
to set up the NGO?
How long it took me
to make it happen? Do you?
Calm down, Maria.
I won't! You had no right
to put my life at risk!
- Don't shout.
- I was threatened, Andre!
You don't get it. I was threatened!
- Can I speak?
- No! You've put me at risk...
and my friends' lives at risk!
- I couldn't tell you.
- I don't believe you!
You are a lying son of a bitch!
I couldn't tell you... Wait!
Maria!
Tell me if I do something wrong, okay?
- He's so quiet...
- Don't make it too loose.
Choosing a replacement
for a captain like me
isn't as easy as it may seem.
- Is there anyone good in boot camp?
- There's one guy who's really good.
- Really?
- Yeah, he's a maniac.
He was just like me when I went through it.
Choosing the best guy
in the group wouldn't do.
I couldn't leave my men
without being sure that
they'd be well taken care of.
That's great news.
I think I'll be out in a month or so.
Only 3 ranking officers
made it through phase 1...
and Azevedo chose his replacement first.
Move towards the target!
So, I had to choose
between Neto and Matias.
Fire!
Holster your weapon!
Good job, 0-6.
But, it's easy when
you're shooting with my weapon.
Skulls!
Let's see the other four...
-23, where's your strap?
- Loose, sir.
At this stage of the game,
you're not wearing the strap?
If your partner gets shot
what are you gonna do,
- throw your weapon on the ground?
- No, sir!
- You gonna stick it up your ass?
Then put the fucking strap on!
- Yes, sir.
- Jesus!
You should fucking know better.
The end of training is tacticaI.
We teach our men to raid the slums...
and surprise the dealers.
They can't know which way
we're coming from. It's an art.
And like any art, practise makes perfect.
We move in one alley at a time.
Nice and slow, 0-6. Move slowly.
Slowly. What do you do now?
Scan the area, then move on.
Well done, 0-6. Well done.
Scan and move.
Move forward, now. That's it!
Just stay calm. What do you do next? Wait.
Is your cover here? Yes.
Hell can break loose, but you stay calm.
- Eyes forward. You clear?
- Yes.
Then go. If you can move, do it.
That's it, 0-6. Alright!
The finaI exam was the reaI thing.
In a real slum, with real bullets.
And the only right answer
was not to get shot.
- Shit! The cops!
- Get inside! Get inside!
Captain!
- The lookout ran that way.
- Alone?
Yes, it was just him.
- I'm going in...
- Wait, dammit!
- I'm gone!
- Come back, dammit! Come back!
I could not tolerate errors.
Our men in black raid the slums to kill...
and never to be killed.
Whoever replaced me needed to know that.
- What's happening, Lieutenant?
- Move in!
Go for the roof, Renan! The roof!
Come back, God dammit!
Get your ass back here!
You don't deserve this uniform!
You're no Skull. You're a punk!
You hear me? You're a punk!
What are you taking?
It's no big deal.
- Let me see.
- Everybody takes these.
No problem.
Well, you won't have to take those any more.
You're getting out. Things will get better.
Out of what?
- What am I getting out of?
- You're leaving BOPE.
Aren't you?
What's the matter?
You're quitting, right? Everything is set.
What happened?
I picked the wrong kid.
- What does that mean?
- I chose the wrong kid. I fucked up.
Azevedo picked a good one
and I picked a crazy one.
- But you've got a son now!
- So? Azevedo has two kids!
Quiet! The baby is sleeping, dammit!
Only one thing drove me crazier
than making my own mistakes.
Don't write the guy off yet.
Give him another chance!
And that was Rosane telling me what to do.
When's graduation?
Come on, baby. It'll be okay...
The worst part was,
sometimes I took her advice.
- This is what I want, bro.
- This? You sure?
Take a look at the book here.
- There's a cool Indian...
- Indian my ass!
Gimme the knife and skull, bro!
Hands up, face the wall!
When the men graduated,
they hit the streets.
Neto was the hungriest for blood.
He dove right into "Operation Holiness".
He wanted to guarantee the Pope's
good night sleep.
And with him leading my squad,
he killed 30 thugs in the first week.
Even though we prepare our men for war,
you may think what we do is inhuman.
But as long as the dealers
have guns, we have no choice.
Every BOPE cop learns that.
Now, even Matias was getting it.
And you know what? It was about time
he confronted those potheads.
See you all later!
Come here, punk. Come here!
- Take it easy, man.
- I want to talk to you... Chill.
I'm not gonna arrest you... yet.
You don't scare me.
Get that smirk off your face.
- See these glasses?
- Yeah.
They're for Romerito. Hands off!
You don't deserve to help the kid,
so I'm gonna give these to him.
If you go to the slum, you're fucked.
I don't associate with addicts or scumbags.
So, here's what you're gonna do.
Tell the kid to meet me tomorrow
at noon at the arcade.
- No, man. Ask Maria to do it!
- Wait! Are you crazy?
If you don't do this shit for me,
I'll arrest you.
Got it, you piece of shit playboy?
You think I don't know you deal at school?
Tomorrow at noon.
I'm gonna get you a new nose,
'cause you're snorting so much coke, man!
It's us, dude.
Xaveco...
Here, Goldilocks.
I'm not taking anything today, Baiano.
- Things are whack at school now.
- What? Are you joking? Why?
That motherfucking cop!
He threatened to arrest me.
What cop?
- What cop, boss?
- Who?
- Tell me what's going on.
- Just some shit...
What kind of shit?
What kind of shit, you fuckin' asshole?
- Hey, Neto.
- What's up, Andre?
- I have a message for you.
- What is it?
They called from that lawyer's office.
I confirmed your interview.
Maria must have arranged it.
I don't need her favours any more.
Are you crazy, Andre? Don't be stupid.
You gotta get that job!
So what's up? Don't stutter, punk.
- Spit it out!
- Fine!
- There's a kid at the NGO.
- NGO my ass!
And the cop wants to help him.
I can't. I gotta go give Romerito
his glasses.
The kid was born blind.
Can't he wait another day?
So what's he gonna do? Tell me everything.
Okay, I'll tell you!
- He's gonna bring them up here?
- No, not here.
You know I gotta do this, right?
Where are you gonna meet him?
- At the arcade.
- What time?
- Spit it out, dammit!
- At noon! At noon!
Years later, Matias told me that
he wouldn't have gone to the
interview if Neto hadn't insisted.
Deep inside, he wanted to be a lawyer.
What are your plans
once you finish school?
I intend to specialise in Criminal Law.
I hadn't chosen the wrong replacement.
Man, you got another token?
You winning or losing?
- Losing.
- You gotta win, dude!
Ze, give him another token.
- Romerito!
- He's here! Let's go, boss!
Take it easy, bro.
We gotta kid here. Relax.
- Are you Romerito?
- Yes, sir!
I got a gift for you!
Now you'll be able to see better.
- Where's Andre?
- Working. Try 'em on.
- Wow, cool!
- Now you look like a man.
Quit joking.
Sir, I think you better go.
Get inside the bar!
Don't shoot! I'm gonna
finish off this son of a bitch!
What the hell is this? What the fuck?!
Shit!
The son of a bitch is BOPE!
Shit! Let's move!
Baiano knew that if Neto died,
he'd be good as dead, too.
If a BOPE officer gets killed,
we won't stop till we get the
guy who did it.
Baiano had warned those kids that
he didn't want cops in his slum.
But a BOPE cop?
That he would never forgive.
But those rich, college kids, man...
They just didn't get it.
What the hell...
You can't barge in like this!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Fuck!
Put that gun down, Tinho.
What's going on?
Can you tell me where I can find Matias?
He's over there.
He's gonna make it, Carvalho.
- But, Nascimento...
- He can pull through.
- He took two bullets in his back...
- Yeah, but he's gonna make it.
What do you want?
- Is your friend doing okay?
- No.
I went to the police station, they
said there's nothing they can do...
- And Romerito? How is he?
- He's fine. He's at my place.
But...
they took Roberta and Rodrigues.
Don't worry, Baiano is socially conscious.
Andre, I'm serious.
Rodrigues was bleeding...
Didn't you tell me you were an honest cop?
Now it's okay that I'm a cop?
Anyway, I'm sure
your friends are already dead.
Don't do this!
- For the love of God!
- I warned you, didn't I?
Burn the fuckin' piece of shit.
- Burn!
- Burn, motherfucker!
- No!
- Light him up.
Is everything okay?
Don't you ever talk about my job again!
What...?
No more talking about my job in this house!
You understand?
I give the orders in this house!
Not one word about
my team inside this house!
Am I clear? You got that?
I give the fucking orders!
Listen... go to your mother's,
and only come back when I tell you to.
But... where are you going?
Don't worry... I'm gonna stay around here.
Two bodies were found
in the Prazeres slum.
The bodies are believed to belong
to student Roberta Fontes,
the daughter of businessman Alceu Fontes,
and to sociaI worker Pedro Rodrigues.
Reporter Ana Luiza is interviewing
the Security Secretary,
who has just made a statement.
Does the body belong to Ms Fontes?
We need to wait for the report to
make sure the body is actually hers.
We are doing everything we can
to help victims' families.
- What's wrong, Auntie?
- You okay?
Fire!
For Matias, Neto's death was a tragedy.
They'd been friends since childhood.
But, I had to use his pain...
...in order to complete my mission.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm not here to argue.
I'm just asking what you're doing here.
I think I can help you.
How can you help me?
I know someone that can help you.
Who?
I'll tell if you promise
that she won't be harmed.
OK, sure. Who is it?
It's Rose.
Now this bitch is gonna talk.
Now you're gonna talk!
- Where's your fucking boyfriend?
- I don't know!
- Where the fuck is he?
Where is he?
- I don't know.
- Speak up!
Where is he, damn it?!
- You think I'm joking?
- Enough!
Ok! Tell me now!
Where? Where?
Give it up, punk!
Put your hands up... don't say a word!
Don't you do a damn thing!
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know...
- Damn it! Where's Baiano?
- Hurry up! Tell me!
Matias, you gotta insist
with these punks, got it?
Where the fuck is Baiano?
You son of a bitch!
Where's Baiano? Speak up!
- Where's Baiano?
- Where is he?
I didn't know the playboy was one of you...
What playboy?
Captain, I know who he's talking about.
In Rio, no one protests when a cop dies.
They only do it for rich people.
When I see those rich kids protesting,
I feeI like kicking their asses, too.
- You son of a bitch!
- Stop it!
- What are you doing?
- Let me go!
- Stop it!
- Son of a bitch!
- Get out of here!
- Get off of me!
- Stop it!
- He killed my friend, dammit!
- He killed my best friend!
- You let go of me!
- Stop it, Matias!
- Let him go!
You gonna hit a cop?
You gonna hit a cop, now?
You motherfuckers! You're just like him!
A bunch of rich assholes!
Get out of here, Andre! Just get lost!
What? You slut! You're just like him!
A bunch of fucking potheads!
Matias wasn't just out for revenge,
he was turning into a real BOPE officer.
- Open the fucking door!
- Take it easy! Put down that gun!
Where's the fuckin' pot?
Where is it, dammit! You son of a bitch!
Where's the fucking weed, man?
- Where's the fucking pot?
- Alright! Alright!
Go get it, you faggot, son of a bitch!
Hurry up!
Let's go, damn it!
My mission wasn't to secure the
Pope's good night sleep any more.
Neto had already taken care of that.
I had to get back to my family
and put someone worthy in my place.
But to do that I had to nail Baiano.
No matter what it took.
Up against the wall! Lift up your shirt!
I couldn't go in and search
innocent people's homes.
I know it sounds crazy,
but at that point I would do anything.
Nothing could stop me.
We gotta check out the perimeter, Andre.
Up there, at that entrance,
there aren't any dealers.
We're gonna have to go door to door.
Open up!
Police! Hands on the table!
Wake up, scumbag! Wake up! Wake up!
- Good morning, son!
- Good morning, sir!
- May I please search your room?
- Yes, sir.
- May I take a look around?
- Of course, sir.
0-4! Can you please search his closet?
Look what I found, 0-1.
These shoes cost more than what
we make in a month, sir!
- Where did you get these?
- I won them, sir!
Now you've lost them. Come on, let's go!
We'll be in deep shit, Captain.
The locals are watching.
- We're causing trouble.
- Renan, Renan. The guy killed Neto.
I came up here to catch him
and I'm gonna finish him off today!
- You wanna leave?
- We're messing with innocent people.
You wanna go? It's not a problem.
Take your team and these five kids.
If you feel so bad about it,
take all of 'em.
- Go ahead, Renan.
- Fine. Let's go.
Are you a student? Can you fly, punk?
Come over here. Get down and kneel.
I want you to know that
I don't want to hurt you.
- Got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know, sir.
- Speak up!
- You wanna play tough?
You wanna be bagged, son?!
Kneel him in front of me.
- Son, where's Baiano?
- I don't know.
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know!
- Where is he? Tell me!
- I don't know.
Bag him!
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know, sir.
Where is he, you son of a bitch?
- Give him up!
- You're gonna die anyway!
- I don't know, sir.
- Captain, he's not talking.
- Take off his pants.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, shit!
- Talk, son of a bitch!
What a pussy! Give me this shit!
Pull his pants down!
Are you gonna talk now?
- Alright, I'll talk!
- You gonna tell us?
- Yeah.
- Go on. Take him.
Fuck, Xaveco...
Something's wrong, man.
Take it easy, boss. Let's just stay put.
Something's wrong. It's too quiet, man.
- Everything's OK, boss.
- OK, my ass!
Go get some water, and take a look around.
All clear, Captain!
Listen, boss...
I can give you 30 grand,
just take me to the hospital!
It's over, you son of a bitch.
You're a goner, and now you're gonna die!
- Not in the face, though!
- What?
Because of the wake, man.
I already had Baiano.
0-7, give me the 12-gauge.
Let the kid go. Let him go.
Now I just needed to see Matias kill him.
Then my mission would be accomplished.
Then I could go back to my family
knowing I had been replaced
by someone worthy of the job.
Take him out. He's all yours.
Wait...