Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
So far, we've found
four of'em.
Jim...
Roger, Pete-
What about Ed?
The Quechuas told me that they found him
in the water at the edge of the beach.
By the time that we got there, the water
had come up and carried him away-
Marilou, I wanted so badly
to go get him.
- Then there's still a chance?
- No, ma'am.
The Quechuas positively
identified him.
They took his wristwatch
to prove it was him.
- And Nate?
- Well, we found Nate...
in the river right near
Palm Beach.
Nenkiwi lied about the foreigners.!
They did not try to kill us.
- Ask Maengamo.
- Why do you lie?
I saw their guns.
I flew in the wood bee.
You should be quiet, Gimade.
Don't spear me, Gikita.
Why should we kill you?
Nenkiwi's baby grows in me.
Mincaya-
Mincayani, let me stay here.
Don't kill me, Mincayani.
Let me live.
Spare the baby,
Mincayani.
Let the baby live,
He will demand his child.
Maybe he won't.
He won't if you're there.
When does this end?
- Where is Gimade?
- I am your true wife.
Put my son in the earth.
Go.
I'm not your friend anymore.
I'm not anybody's friend anymore.
It didn't work.
Don't judge that too quickly.
You know, hurting a dog won't help.
Come here.
No. This my family!
My family...
killed your family.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, no.
- Sorry.
- Dayumae was never the same...
- after that day.
- It's okay.
The cycle of violence
that her family had lived in...
had come around
to catch her again.
She began to talk about
returning to her tribe...
so that they would know
that not all foreigners kill.
It wasn't very long before her family
provided her the opportunity.
Her sister Gimade and mother Akawo
were still looking for her.
And now they were desperate enough to
take their chances with the foreigners...
just as she had done years before.
We won't let them hurt you.
We found spears!
So you want to shoot them?
Is that what you want?
These women are dead. Dead.
We'll take them back to their people.
If Gimade and Akawo
had not been women...
they would've been killed.
So Dayumae believed women going to
her family might be shown the same mercy.
Leave quickly!
You look like Dayumae.
But you don't fool me.
You're a spirit.
You look like a man.
But you don't fool me.
You're Mincayani.
She is Dayumae!
She knows our stories.
You hid me in the forest,
Mincayani.
When I ran to the foreigners...
they let me live.
She's a spirit.
I don't like this, Mommy.
It's just a game, honey,
to see who can touch the most.
When will the wood bee
family attack us?
They will never attack.
Until we are asleep.
I've lived with them.
Can't you see I am well?
The wood bee family
wanted to tell you...
Waengongi doesn't
want anyone to kill.
- Waengongi?
Waengongi doesn't
want anyone to kill.
How do they know
what Waengongi says?
Waengongi marked his trail
with carvings.
They say we shouldn't kill.
Where are these carvings?
Show them.
The wood bee family
can show you.
Will you let them
live with you?
Why would they live with us...
after we speared their family?
I want to live with the Aenomenani.
With my enemies.
I will see these carvings.
If these women cause trouble...
we'll just spear them.
I say spear them now.
Mincayani, they'rejust women.
I've seen their house!
Their house of blood!
I've touched it!
If she's truly Dayumae...
why not ask about Moipa?
Who speared your family?
Who killed your father, Caento?
And your baby sister Nemo?
Moipa.
Moipa and the Aenomenani.
Moipa is dead.
We killed him.
Just as you
will kill Aenomenani.
I will never...
Then you're not Dayumae.
Why didn't the wood bee men
shoot us?
They came to tell you...
Waengongi has a son.
He was speared...
but he didn't spear back.
So the people spearing him...
would one day live well.
Kimo has fallen under a spell.
Why would the foreigners
tell us not to kill?
They want us to be weak!
I say they're all spirits!
And Kimo better be careful.
Or else.!
The sting ray poisoned you.
Bring my spears.
Drink this, Mincayani.
Bring my spears!
You saw them, Mincayani.
Don't deny it.
I saw spirits.
You saw them.
Only spirits!
You saw!
Kimo shouldn't
help these women.
The Aenomenani will say...
"The foreigners have tamed them. "
Kimo's already tame.
After this, he'll build
a house for their God.
Then he'll die in it.
Just look at
Kimo's face!
Every day a spirit
possesses him more.
The women are also changing.
They say this house
will be your grave.
What do you say, Mincayani?
You no longer know your family.
You must be blind.
They're coming.! More foreigners.!
They're coming.!
Oh, my God!
Good to see you!
Hi!
Marj, Kathy and Stevie.
They are Rachel's family.
Oh, that's boiled
plantain mash and water.
Oh, I have so many stories...
about when I first came to visit
Aunt Rachel and the Waodani.
She is a girl with short hair.
No, he is a boy.
Let's just say there are
some things you never forget.
I will see for myself.
You're right. He's a boy.
According to Waodani tradition...
as my father's oldest son, I would be
responsible for avenging his death.
So Aunt Rachel warned me never to
appear too interested in the particulars.
She, herself,had no idea
who the actual killers were.
But, of course,
I couldn't help but wonder.
And that was
when I first saw Mincayani.
I remember feeling
like I irritated him.
Something's dead.
I'll come back for you.
Mingi.!
Aenomenani!
The Aenomenani
have speared Mingi.
We found their tracks.
I say we take spears...
and follow them.
We will not be weak!
We will kill.
Bring us drink.
I will not kill the Aenomenani.
Following Waengongi's carvings...
I will walk his trail.
- How many?
- Very many.
Why don't they attack?
Maybe they don't know
our warriors are gone.
They are my family.
If I talk to them, maybe we'll live.
I'll go with her.
If you go, Kimo,
they will spear.
Are we going to run?
No, Stevie boy.
We no kill.
Waengongi say, "No. "
You no kill.
Even spearing us, we no spear you.
Aenomenani very angry.
They say we make fever.
They die.
Ompodae say, "No. "
We live well.
Ompodae and Dawa pleaded
with their family for hours.
In the end, it was the Aenomenani's
sickness that helped turn the tide.
In the darkness,just before dawn,
they became too weak to attack.
Dayumae.
My family has fever.
Some are already dead.
More are dying.
Take them to the huts.
Bring them drink.
I'll get medicine.
Help us.
My family has fever.
Help us. They will die
if we do not help.
Shell, this is Tiwaeno.
We have an emergency. Over.
Tiwaeno, Tiwaeno, this is Shell.
What's wrong, Rachel? Over.
Kimo and Dawa have returned
with the Aenomenani. All of them.
They have polio.
They're dying. Over.
Roger. You'll have to
quarantine the village, Rachel.
You read?
We read you, Frank.
Tell everyone to pray.
Look at Kimo.
He used to be a great warrior.
No matter.
Kimo brings our enemies
to our spears.
What's he shouting?
- He's saying, "No food. Children will die. "
- Mincayani.!
The quarantine meant
we couldn't leave the village.
No one could walk
in with supplies.
I felt trapped in a place that wasn't my home.
Little did I know that Mincayani
felt trapped as well.
And this place was his home.
How are you bearing up, Rachel?
The monkeys and wild boar seem to
have abandoned this part of thejungle.
Thanks for the drop. Over.
This is all the medicine we have in Shell.
We're bringing more
down from Quito.
And we need more advice on
how to keep 'em breathing.
Maybe you could talk to Dr. Wally?
I did. You just got to
keep them moving on those teeter-totters.
But their lungs are still filling!
We'll keep you in food and medicine
until the quarantine is lifted.
Tell Marj
Marilou says little Phil is fine.
We're all praying for you.
Mincayani, if I don't rock
the boy dies.
Bibanka, when you sleep,
I'll tie many to you...
to carry you up to the clouds.
Don't listen.
He's a dreamer.
Kimo shocks me...
because he's keeping
those killers alive.
And Dayumae...
They no longer fear
the Great Boa.
Just call them termites.
Mincayani, we must
put her in the ground.
Can one so small
jump the Great Boa?
Or will she become a termite?
Do you know what
the ancient ones said?
To die is nothing.
To jump the Great Boa
is everything.
By spearing,
we become strong.
With enough strength,
we can all jump the Great Boa.
But now Kimo...
and Dayumae...
and the one they
call Waengongi...
are leading our family
to a place...
where we will all be termites...
forever!
But I will fight them...
to my last breath.!
If you kill again...
you will kill us all.
After eight weeks,
the quarantine was lifted.
My mother and sister
and I could finally go home.
The teeter-totters had stopped...
and with them, the endless cycle of revenge.
- The Waodani had found a reason
to live differently.
And in the end...
that seemed to be what
so many of them were waiting for.
I'll miss you so much.
You'll just miss the manioc.
I'd like to say good-bye
to Mincayani.
It's important to do
what's in your heart, Stevie.
I hope to return one day and see you.
If I don't see you in this place...
I hope to see you...
in Waengongi's place.
My father always hoped...
that we would be sincere friends.
After I left Mincayani...
I started a new life that would take me
to the United States.
Aunt Rachel and I kept in touch...
and occasionally
I'd visit in the summers.
She spent the rest ofher life
with the Waodani.
Waodani Territory
I was living
with my family in Florida...
when I got the news
that Aunt Rachel had died.
It didn't come as a surprise.
We had known about her cancer.
And though she came
from a large family in the states...
she wanted to be buried
with the Waodani...
who she considered
to be family as well.
So my wife Ginny and I traveled
to Ecuador to honor her request.
- What are you thinking?
- How do you...
weigh a life?
Faith?
Rachel wanted you to live with us.
She told us you would.
I live far, far away.
My wife and children...
have never lived in the jungle.
I will visit you often.
Your father's buried here.
Rachel's buried here.
Why not live where
your family is buried?
It isn't possible.
Our children must
understand outside ways...
and our family must show them.
Are you not our family?
Steve didn't hear Kimo's words.
He still needs to know.
All Mincayani said was
there was something I needed to see.
No other explanation was offered.
And so ourjourney
that had spanned two worlds...
bridged the Stone Age
and 21 st century...
finally led us here...
down the lonely Curraray River.
That's his plane!
Is this it?
Is this where-
Is this where it happened?
It happened here.
They didn't shoot us!
There's more you need to know.
I saw them.
Your father saw them also.
What?
What did he see?
Tell me!
Your father...
was a special man.
I saw him jump the Great Boa...
while he was still alive!
I speared your father!
What?
Do it!
No one...
took...
my father's life.
He gave it.
My father lost his life
at the end of the spear...
and it was at
the end of the spear...
that Mincayani and I found ours.
It's true that my dad
and his four friends...
were not given the privilege of watching
their children and grandchildren grow up.
But Mincayani is a grandfather.
It's the first time in Waodani history
they've ever had so many grandfathers.
He's not only a grandfather to his own
children, he's a grandfather to mine.
My dad would've liked that.
Through the years, people could
always identify with our loss.
But they could never imagine the way
that we would experience gain.
Mincaye got to come to the states,
and that has started these visits.
He said some of the foreigners are
so nice that even when you're driving...
you just stop by their houses
and you go to one of the-
one of the openings
in their walls...
and he said, "Theyjust open it for you,
and then they start giving you food. "
and it's already hot,
and it's already cooked and stuff.
He said, I see those foreigners
very, very well.
When Mincaye came back
from the states the first time...
he told the people that the foreigners
are really big and fat...
because even when they go walking,
they don't move their feet.
Theyjust get on the trail,
and the trail moves.
Well, Ompodae, his wife, said,
"Oh, you're talking wild. "
Mincayejust kept saying,
"That's why all the foreigners are fat. "
They don't walk. They don't climb.
They don't make gardens.
When they got to that one...
Ompodae, she just said,
"Well, how are they gonna live then?"
Mincaye said, "They have
these big food houses. "
And he said,
"There's just piles of food. "
First, there's
these young people...
and they're standing
at the place where you go out.
And you smile as big as you can...
and he said, "They pretend
like they're not seeing you. "
Then after a little while-
Then they look at you, and they smile.
And he said,
"When they smile, boom...
you can just go
and take all the food with you. "
I said, "Well, it's kind oflike that. "
So I took out my credit card and said...
"First you have to give them
something like this. "
Mincaye looked at them and smiled.
"They just give it right back to you. "
Ompodae started griping at me.
She said, "Babae, what do you mean
sending Mincaye back here?
He was so fat that
whenever I'd say...
'Mincaye, go out
and bring some meat back for me"...
She said, he wouldjust go out, and
he'd find a tree, and he'djust-
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com