>>>>>>>>>>>>Mr. -bu-1<<<<<<<<<<<<
Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
Cloe,
Why do we talk in such a way?
This is what you said
Me?
Everything is my fault
Why do you blame me when the
relationship faced with problems?
What are you saying? Wish? Yes
I don't want to wish
And you always hope
your wish comes true
Why can't you accept the fact
that we've broken up?
This way, everything is understood,
we'll know what to do
If I've not mistaken,
you always want to make things clear
Isn't that correct?
Answer me!
Can we go now?
Thank you, Nuccio
Sing
Why haven't we been here before?
Not enough curiosity
Yes
Do you still remember
the beautiful things?
What do you want to remember,
the sun, the moon?
Don't you tell me suddenly
you've become a romantic person
I do all these things because
I don't want to be trapped in the past
This is a must
What I do remember is not the day,
but clouds
The sad feelings emerged
when summer came to the end
I don't want to be sad, that's why
sometimes I smile without reason
So, smile
How are you?
- How are you?
Can I take 2 apples for the horse?
- Yes
How are you?
- How are you?
Do you know her?
Who?
The girl who went outjust now
The girl lives below the tower
Thank you
I like this location,
today I was sued
If you want personal space,
it's up to you
You're not allowed to talk in such a way,
who do you think you are?
You're silly
- Is that so?
Yes!
Tell me what do we do the whole day
besides fighting, nothing else
What do you wanna do? Sex?
- Yes, sex
But make me happy,
sex is not an illusion
You think too much
Walk quickly!
I hate this, but I get it everytime
Isn't that funny?
You are always searching for purity
You are a hated person
I can't do anything
I like this
You like it?
Let us be here
What are you finding inside?
Yes
I like old things
- But I am young
I like it even more
Is this an invitation?
Hopes you like it
What?
Generally
I seems to know you for a long time
No
You're the opposite type
Other types
Who?
A saxophone player
I saw 2 butterflies near the beach
They're always following me
I'm sure you've met one of them
No
But I believes one of them is with us
You want us to find it?
- No
No?
This is a message
- Message?
Might be a message related to 2 people
Maybe
I feel cold
Goodbye
Are you here?
If I throw it, what will happen?
I tell your name
My name is Linda
How are you?
- How are you?
Hello?
How are you?
- How are you?
Where are you?
- Beach
The horse has ran away,
I want to bring them back
I am looking at the snow
- Where?
Paris
- I can't hear you, where are you?
I am in Paris
Is it snowing there?
I hope it snows here too
Cleo, if you're saying this
You makes me want to go there
I hope to get close to you
But the way you analyse problems
Hello? I can't hear
I said the way you analyse problems
The way I analyse problems,
how do we change?
Forget it
This is about searching
Foundation to something
Now I can't think of anything
Snow makes me calm,
I'm nervous now
la might be your best friend today
Kiss you
- Me too
Let's go back!
I don't remember exactly
when it happened
It was 2 weeks ago
Yesterday,
that was the day that I lost my...
It was the day after we're told we'll
be pitching this Samson's account
The copy guy comes in
and he's wearing a...
What's the socially acceptable term
Somebody encountered this trap,
kill it
We're shocked,
our molecules are moving
And before we processed this betrayal,
Howard says calmly
He decides to do something
about his hair problem
And he'll appreciate it if we kindly
refrain from making it
A topic of comment or conversation.
This is my team
Good people.
They're great at what they do
It's like Jazz
We can't talk about this tragedy
of Hallet's hair
I mean you should see him,
faces like starving animals
Look at me
Do something!
It is an alarm clock
They want a new concept
for their shitty little alarm
You know the, Samson,
'coz time is important to us
We're polishing the vase
when the house falls down
- Do you've an alarm clock?
- I do. Yes.
- You happy with it?
- It does the job.
Right, but you need a new alarm clock,
Dr Pearl
And it's gotta be a Samson
A new colour, a new texture
You want softer kick
You wanna kick it off a night stand
every morning for a year, you can
Our mechanism is incredibly
You see what I'm saying?
The message is simple
The life is lacking something
Pearl
Yes, it's short for Dr Pearl
You're talking about alarm clocks
All around me, these other firms,
they can hit home-runs
Left
Right
Melt in your mouth, not your hand,
it's great!
Dollar for dollar
Any of 'ur patients famous?
- I can't discuss my patients
All right, no, I saw a sketch
about that one at a night club
Doctor patient,
patience, doctor
I remember that, I want to remember
the names, anything personal
Mr Penrox ain't
Do you remember Jack?
I really can't help you there
Oh my god,
their sales up to the roof
I have the data
Your sister mentioned something
about a recurring dream
The woman in the dream.
The woman in the dream,
why did you say it that way?
Cecelia says it like that
Is Cecelia is your wife?
- Yeah
And you tell her about the dream?
I make the mistake of
mentioning it once
Now it has become a ritual,
it's a ritual
Until yesterday
What happened yesterday?
Yesterday I came down to the kitchen,
I was telling her about the dream
The latest installment.
There was a woman in the dream
When I wake up, I don't remember who
it is, but in the dream, I know her
It's not a sex dream
Exactly
But we're there and I said,
'Boy, who is it? '
Because I was thinking about it, I felt
like the air in the room has change
I look over and there she was,
shoulder shaking, she's crying
Why is she crying?
I don't know
Did you asked her?
She won't say it
She is upset?
Yes
Have you given any
thought of sitting down?
I'm wondering if cavemen
sat around talking about their dreams
And having coded conversations
with their wives
Over cold venison.
Do you often imagine
that you're a caveman?
No
I am happy with 1955
Look at the advances
in medicine, polio, TB
That was a joke
So, how is it with Cecelia
since her crying in the kitchen?
It's great
She's like a nurse on the night
when I've my tonsils out
Civil and unavailable
And how long is it since
you've been having this dream?
That's the thing...
It was the night when Hallet show up
with a new on his head
They show the woman in the dream
I've to show Cecelia
that I know the answer
Or she's gonna be gone
You've to help me, if this woman is
pulling away, I don't know what I'll do
So, I need to know the answer now
Before I leave, I gotta know
Mr Penrose
Human beings is not a car brake, I mean
we'll talk, we'll see what happens
Everybody is different.
You're under a lot of stress.
You're anxious about the job,
the recurring dream, the situation...
With your wife, you're much
more anxious than usual.
Exactly.
There're various ways I can try
to help you reduce 'ur anxiety.
First, I'll have you lie down
on the couch over here.
This couch?
Yes, right here
Just put 'ur head up on one end and
slide your feet down the other end
This works for people, the couch?
I can tell you,
I've great success with this couch
Should I take my shoes off?
- Yes, whatever makes you comfortable
We want your mind completely clear
Should I close my eyes?
- I find that helps
'coz I see things in great details
Sometimes, I imagine myself
as a person with no responsibility
That's very interesting
Part of me knows I enjoy it
Now, I want you to tell me
about 'ur dream
Okay
But first, take a minute, go back
to the beginning of the dream
When you got there,
Just pause for a moment, and
hold the first image in your mind
We at the beginning?
- Yes.
Tell me the first thing
you see in the dream
A woman's face
Can you see the woman
in 'ur mind right now?
Yes.
Where are you? Are you very close
or are you far-away?
We've facing each other in bed.
It's right after
That's very close.
Think for a minute what it feels like
How do you feel?
Then what happens?
She looks at me with kinda funny smile
And goes off to the bathroom
Turns on the tub and lets it run
This is when I realised we've
been in this room before
Describe the room to me?
Feels like a hotel room
Doesn't feel like a place
where anybody live
The only person
belongs to us
So, when I hear the water running,
I think,
I love it, that
she's gonna take a bath and I,
Begin to imagine her getting ready.
Taking off her make-up,
putting her hair up
So excited thinking about it.
When I hear her turn the water off,
I'm gonna go right
in the tub with her.
That's when the phone starts ringing.
- Who do you think might be calling?
- I don't know.
Aren't you afraid of being discovered?
- No.
Not even a slightest feel guilty?
- Not the tiniest bit?
No, no guilt whatsoever.
Then what happened?
Got better things to do
than answering the phone
She takes her bath
She gets up and dry herself up
She climbs up on the sink
in front of the mirror like a cat
And puts on her make-up
She finishes and,
Back in the bedroom,
I watched her as she,
Get dressed.
In the bathroom for a minute,
close the doors
She comes back out in her living room
She puts her hand on my face
There is a glove on her hand.
She kisses me.
I just lay there for a minute.
Then the phone rings again, I got up
Answer it, but there's
no one at the other end
- Then what happens?
- I wake up.
- Should I stop?
- No, no, stay in the dream.
I feel so sad.
Yes, you wanna be with her.
Yes.
Stay there on the bed.
You're in the dream now.
And I want you to go back.
I want you to go back in the dream
when the woman is in the bathroom.
The bathroom door is close?
Yes.
And you're lying on the bed?
- Yes.
Raise your head slowly, slowly
Where are you?
- I am standing.
And where is the purse?
The purse?
Yes, you said that when she sat down
next to you, she picked up a purse
- You see it?
- Yes.
I want you to go to the purse.
I can't.
- Why?
You're in a very vulnerable
state right now,
It's crucial you do not feel
judged at this moment.
If you turn around,
any expression on my face,
No matter how sympathetic
or supportive
And I cannot allowed that,
I'll not allowed that.
Thank you.
Let's go back to your work
for a while.
You feel as if
you've run out of ideas?
I feel like I've run out
of good ideas.
Something is missing.
Yes.
What is your favourite part
of the dream?
When she standing at the door
while the phone rings
Why?
By standing at the door and
letting the phone rings,
She's keeping outside world
away for a minute.
That's where I screw up, I answer
the phone and the dream ends
Maybe if I didn't answer the phone,
she'll come back
So, the phone is an interruption
from the outside world.
Yes.
Like the alarm clock.
Maybe.
You hear the alarm clock
in the morning, what happens?
I turn it off.
- Yes, but what did you wanna do?
Go back to sleep.
- Why don't you?
- If I don't get up,
I'll fall back to sleep
and I will be late for work.
Yes, yes, but you just want a few
more moments of sleep, just a few.
You've to reset the entire alarm
And the setting mechanism
isn't that precise.
What'll solve the problem then?
You've to turn the alarm off, and then
turn it off again automatically
I actually think I would.
Samson,
the alarm clock of your dreams.
Sounds like one of those good ideas.
Can I get up now?
Absolutely.
Feeling better?
Yes.
I feel like we've accomplished
something today.
No need to thanked me.
The work is an honourable reward.
Breakthrough is exhausting.
I feel really tired all of a sudden.
Are you all right?
- I feel like I can lay down again
You've some time left on your hour.
Thank you.
Are you up?
You must have hit the alarm
about a half a dozen times.
It's become a ritual.
What?
Promise me you'll talk to Hall
about his hair today.
I gotta go.
We can't pitch this,
we can't present this.
We work very hard on this.
And I'll like to think we've
accomplished something.
Don't you feel like we've
accomplished something?
No, I don't.
Neither do I.
We're living in the shadow
of a freaking snooze alarm
Where do you go from there?
What?
How are you now?
Fine
Don't you ever come again,
epidemic illness
No
You don't have to
That person is gone
Look at my face
Can't wear it anymore
No
You will be fine
Do you want to try?
- No
I believes you've done it well
Do you remember
The first time we met?
Yes
Do you remember my hand?
Where is block 1 first floor?
To the left
- Here?
Yes
- Thank you
Who is it?
Is Miss Hua here?
- Who is looking for her?
I'm Master Jin's worker,
he asked me to come
Mr Zhao, wanna go?
- Yes
Miss, Master's Jin worker is here
Let him ini
You can come in
Miss Hua
You're Master Jin's worker?
- Yes
Name?
Xiaozhang
What's the matter?
Nothing
Stand nicely
Put down your arms
What happened to you?
Nothing
Take out your pants!
Take it out!
Do you want me to call your Master?
Underwear too
Nothing?
Come here
Give me your hand
Have you touched a woman before?
No, how can you become a tailor?
You'll touch many women
It becomes like this when you touched
Who wants to find you?
Am I good to you?
All right
You remembered
Your master is old
He said you will be successful
Maybe you'll become
a tailor after this
You have to remember
your feeling today
The dress made by you
is gonna be very beautiful
Miss Hua
We have yet to congratulate you
Some said you are married
How come we don't know
such wonderful news?
Xiaozhang? He went out
Yes, the festival is near
A bit busy nowadays
Why do you say such things?
You know Xiaozhang
He won't served other customers
He only makes your dress
All right, when Xiaozhang is back,
I asked him to come to your house
All right
Didn't I say not to come again?
If they see, what will happened?
You take care of me?
I take care of you
What can you do?
What do I eat later on?
Eat me
Irritating
Forget it
Don't be like that
Next time, you go back first,
I called you, ok?
I go back first
- Just go
Mr Zhao, are you going?
- There are things to do
Goodbye
Ying, if Mr Zhao come again,
tell him I'm not at home
Yes
Has Xiozhang came?
- Not yet
Call him, ask him to come quickly
What Adonis?
Him?
He is my cousin brother
You always hear rumours
Looks like Adonis
- Waiting for you
His hair is less than you
I have choosen the house
When you come tonight,
bring the cheque along
I want to give deposit
What?
- Miss Kofi
Has Xiaozhang came?
Yes
Give him this clothes, tell him Boss Chu
bought for me this clothes from France
Let him do it carefully
Give him a few dumplings, say
I'm the one who give him to eat
All right
Hello?
What did you say?
What do you scare?
Scare of your wife?
Scare of me?
Scare of me is all right
Don't come tonight
This dumplings is given by miss
She makes it herself
Thank you
- Okay
Goodbye
- Goodbye
See you again
Master Zhang, so early
Have miss woke up?
- Miss is talking with Mr Zhao
Any problem?
The dress is ready,
I want to let her try
Give it to me
Looks like they're
gonna discuss further
All right
If there's problem, call me
Okay
- I go first
There's no need for you
to say like this
How many times must I say
we're relatives
We don't have any relationship at all
I know, you're boring, right?
Wanna dumped me just like that?
It's not that easy
You listen carefully
If you don't do things that satisfy me
I won't let you go
Miss, Master Zhang
is waiting for you outside
How dare for him to come
I don't want.
I won't sew at there again
Xiaozhang has gone out,
who is talking?
Sis Ying, how are you?
I am Jin, he has gone out
What? Miss is looking for him?
If he comes back,
I ask him to go at once
You're welcome, okay
Hello Mr Shao?
Me
You can't recognise my voice?
Terrible
You didn't go out?
I am okay
Call you, nothing
These 2 days
I miss you
Who?
Him?
I didn't see him
I didn't see him for some time
Mr Shao
I want to work
Being at home is quite boring
Nothing to do
Mr Shao
When I am performing
You have to come and watch
You promised to come?
Yes
Are you
Busy later on?
I treat you to eat supper
Where?
Okay
So, you must come
See you later
Is it tight enough?
Am I fat?
A little
You're usually 23 inches
Now
24 inches, 2 inches more
Do like previously
I want to go to work
Will be thin
Don't you misunderstand
I don't want to force you
I heard that you're sick
I called to ask how are you
Yes
You're our old customer
Okay
You rest,
when you have time
I asked Xiaozhang to come
and collect it
Okay
See you again
Who do you think you're?
You're just a hooker
You're just like last time?
Without money
No need to say anything
You are back
- Yes
What did he say?
He is sick, ask me
to find him after a few days
It's more than half a year
He can't take it anymore
She didn't go to work
Everyday live in luxury
Her lifestyle is luxurious
Force her after 2 days
The festival is here soon
Look at all these clothes
All needs to be changed
Just sell it
You keep the money
I still owe you
Nevermind
Nothing
You keep all these clothes
A lot are still new
I can't wear that many,
I want to go other places
I don't want to bring so many things
Keeping it is not useful
Just bring it along
Where are you going
Can't bring so many clothes
I haven't thanked you
Take it
I know you like alcoholic drink
Come
Drink
Who are you looking for?
Is Miss Hua here?
She have moves out
Do you know where she moves to?
No
- Thank you
Who?
Look for who?
Miss Hua, she have moved
Hello?
Yes
Xiaozhang?
He have went out
Who is looking for him?
Miss Hua
You
Yes, I am Master Jin
Sorry, I can't recognise your voice
It's been a while since
we keep in touch
We miss you so much
You're back, where do you live now?
Can you leave your contact number?
Okay
When Xiaozhang is back,
I ask him to go at once
Okay
See you
Where is Miss Hua's room?
The room at the end uptairs
Thank you
Drink tea
So long no see
You're just like last time,
didn't change
You too
Thank you
You're getting better
How are you?
Have you married?
- Not yet
Why?
No one wants to marry me
You introduce one to me
Introduce myself
You won't mind, is it?
No
Promise?
Yes
You're good to me
Can you...
Sew a dress for me?
What type of dress?
Tell me
A beautiful dress
I have an old customer who
came back from America
He still remembers me, ask me out
I think this is my last chance
Help me
Okay
This is the money I've left,
you take it first
If I have extra, I'll pay again
You keep it first
I still keep your dress
There's more new one.
Just change a bit
Don't use use anymore money
You still keep it
I can't wear all those clothes
I have become thin
Want to measure for me again?
There's no need
I am used to your body
Measure with your hand is enough
Do you know where Miss Hua went?
- You try to find her at the beach
She is usually there at this time
What is she doing over there?
To work, what else?
It is raining heavily outside
Is it enough?
Who is she to you?
We are friend
Friend? Your friend is good
Pay rent for her
She is very ill, if you've time,
bring her to see doctor
How are you now?
- All right
Don't you come again,
epidemic illness
No
I've altered your dress
There's no need
That person have gone
Can't wear it anymore
No
You will be fine
Do you want to try?
No
I believe you did it very well
Do you remember
The first time we met?
Yes
Do you remember my hand?
Do you hate me that day?
No
I have to thanked you
If not because of your hand,
I've change my job
Forget about me
Find other girls
Come here
You're good to me
I can't repay you back
I don't think there's chance
I am fine
I still have something last time
Now nothing
Only this hand that is left
Do you mind?
Where do you go?
I want to find you
I have send Miss Hua
She past away?
Yes
So quick
Today, there're many people
on the street sending her
She is very happy
Dan beautiful too
2 years ago, I thought she is gone
Now there's chance she is back again
Unimaginable
Yes
Couldn't imagine it
Have Liu's dress finish?
What happened to you?
The End
>>>>>>>>>>>>Mr. -bu-1<<<<<<<<<<<<
>> Napisy pobrane z http://napisy.org <<
>>>>>>>> nowa wizja napisów <<<<<<<<
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com