movie info:
Eternal.2004.DVDRip-XViD-TWiST
Sync And Translation: Client @ 8.3.2005.
Hello?
Elizabeth?
Do you like it?
- I bought it in Venice
- Elizabeth?
"Wild Cat"?
My real name is Jessica.
I thought that I should tell you.
I prefer "Wild Cat".
Your photograph  doenst do you a least of justice
I´m nervous as hell.
- I´d never...
- Let me take this.
Come.
Let´s have a drink.
Have a seat, "Wild Cat".
- This is a very nice place
- I do enjoy the privacy.
And you live here alone?
You´ll love this wine.
I think I´ll need something stronger.
To eternity.
So where´d you tell your
husband and you were going?
My husband?
Weddingring is never quite gone.
I am sorry.
I didnt mean to...
I am just very nervous.
Does it make the difference?
Not to me.
Is this your first time?
- Yes.
- I doubt it very much.
- Is that so?
- Did you enjoy your first time?
Dont tell me, that you can read minds.
Who was she?
Cristal.
Cristal Williams.
She must´ve been something.
I was in college.
College.
I havent done it since.
But you never forgetted the feeling.
No.
Allow me.
I think you´ll feel beauty.
I´m sorry.
Am I disturbing you?
No.
Prepare my bath.
Fuck!
Should you get that?
Yeah?
Where?
Allright.
Give me 20 minutes.
- Gotta go.
- Sure.
Car has been here for two nights,
it´s illegally parked.
Parking patrol called and had it towed.
Punched in the platenumbers, so here we are.
Hey, I got it.
- When was the last time you saw her?
- About three days ago.
- Why didnt you say something?
- She has done it before.
- You and your wife are having problems?.
- Why the fuck would we?
You called around, to mom
or somebody?
- No.
- How many time has she done this before?
Fuck me. I dont know...
Two or three times.
Never without this.
- Hey Ray.
- Hey Lisa.
- So how was he?
- He was fine.
- That´s a very lovely bag.
- You like it?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Dad, come and see,
I build a giant card castle.
I´ll be in a minute.
Wait me inside.
- So, what do I own you?
- You can pay me later.
Hey, you guys wanna come over later
and watch a movie?
Sounds good.
Carefull.
- There´s just one problem.
- What?
- I think i´m gonna sneeze all over it.
- You cant!
You wanna piece of me?
I´m gonna drop you.
Holy smokes.
You´re getting strong.
You wanna be a pro wrestler,
when you grow up?
- No.
- What you wanna be?
- Ninja.
- Ninja!
Did you know, that ninjas used to
use toothbrushes as lethal weapons?
- No they didnt!
- They did.
For real.
Go brush your teeth,
practice being a ninja.
When is mommy coming back?
She didnt tell you?
For real, Nathan.
Did she tell you?
No she didnt tell me.
Nathan, If she told you,
You´ve to tell me, I´m your dad.
She didnt tell me.
- You promise?
- Yes.
Now, when is mommy coming back?
Is she mad at you again?
No, she´s not mad at me.
Go brush your teeth.
Sorry.
I forgot my books.
Hey, hook up the internet?
Vice cop, who cant use internet?
How do you survive at the office?
Because, there is a bunch of little nerds with glasses,
that do it for me at the office.
And here, well..you are my
little nerd with glasses.
- So, what do you want to see?
- This here.
chantsdemaldoror.com
- Hello..
- What are you into now?
- It´s not me, its my wife.
- Looks like romance novels,  female-erotica.
What about this here?
Wildcat: area 51 UFO.
It´s a chat room on the site.
Mayby we get lucky.
- So, She was like chatting with people..?
- Propably.
There is a message saved...
It´s from "ERSZEBET"
- Forty minutes ´till the next one.
- Great.
Should have been here twenty minutes ago.
Yep.
You should have.
I dont think that I´ve ever seen you before?
You are new?
Here.
Where are you going?
Nature calls..
You wanna come along?
I didnt think so.
Hey, you better finish,whatever you are doing,
so we can go.
Shit.
You know, fuck it.
I´m gonna leave your bag at top, ok?
Hey -
Are you allright?
Hey, are you okay?
- Are you Erszebet?
- Who the fuck are you?
- This is private property.
- Detective Raymond Pope.
Erszebet, is that you?
- Wait here.
- You know, I´ll wait inside.
- Can I offer you anything to drink?
- I´m on duty.
No you are not.
Irina, two glasses please.
So, whats with all the boxes here?
- Moving somewhere?
- Have a seat.
- I´m allright.
- Be polite.
- Erszebet.
- Erszebet? Where did you get that name?
- Got off from the chat room.
- Is that how you spend your freetime?
Irina, stay.
I need to ask you some guestions
about a woman, you´ve been talkin to -
The seat is taken.
Who is she?
I dont know you and
I certainly didnt call you.
I hope you have a good reason
for imposing.
This woman, that you´ve been
talking to in internet -
When was the last time
that you saw her?
Has anything happened to her?
- She disappeared.
- She propably runaway from her husband.
That is my wife.
So why dont you cut out your smart-ass replies
and just answer the question.
You are questing this house, detective.
I could ask you to leave.
And I could ask you to
join me downtown.
stay up till 2am, drinking
really shitty coffee.
You could watch me type of my report,
or you could just answer the question -
have you seen the woman in the picture?
-Yes
- When?
- Mayby four days ago.
She came in -
stayed awhile.
And left.
And what was she here for?
You are the detective, impress me.
What was she here for?
She wanted to have sex
with another woman.
No worry, detective.
its not an entitment
on your abilities.
I´m sure you are
very capable man.
Did you have sex with my wife?
If she wanted you to know, I´m sure
she would have told you
Dont fuck with me.
Did you have sex with my wife?
I doubt very much that information
is going to help you find her.
You know what?
Fuck it.
I´m gonna be seeing you real soon.
Detective!
I hope you find your wife.
I´d love to see her again.
- To wife off a cop.
- I didnt know.
- You know, what this means?
- You boofed with her.
- I warned you to be careful.
- Why do you care?
They are just human.
They cant do nothing to you.
I´ll never be haunted down again.
The estate is owned by private british
trust for 200 years. Well, you dont see much of that anymore.
Residence has been rebuild 1947.
And it was sold five years ago.
- To who?
- I dont have those records.
- Actually, noone is listed as living in that address.
- Is that all you got?
- I could get you the name of notar,
who managed the affairs of trust.
- Brenda, you are so good to me.
- My pleasure.
The trust was constituted for the single
purpose in mind.
To manage the properties that used
to belong to Batory family.
Batory family?
Ancient Polish royalty.
This particular estate was sold
for one dollar, I handled the transaction myself.
Sounds like a helluva deal.
Used to be a simple way
avoiding heritage taxes.
So who heritaged the place?
I´m affraid my duties bind me
the confidentiality.
Your duties?
I´m pretty sure, mister Renaud -
that I can have a search warrant and
forteen cops inside an hour.
And I can promise you -
that I will dig up every scrap of paper you
ever bothered to write a phone number.
We both know, that would
be highly illegal.
Yeah, it propably would be.
C´mon, your an intelligent man,
succesfull business -
beautifull office.
You´ve got lot of high profile clients.
I dont think they´d appreciate that kind of circus,
that I´m gonna bring to you.
Who owns the place?
Dont worry.
I´m not gonna tell anyone.
Elizabeth Kane.
- What do you know about her?
- Nothing.
I received precise instructions,
she showed out of the blue.
- She doesnt ever bother, who live there.
- She does now.
Elizabeth is back?
- Yes?
- I´m here to see Elizabeth Kane.
- She´s not here.
- Where is she?
Hello?
Who was that?
Um, noone, some kids.
You can go back to sleep now.
Irina -
It was that cop.
He knows your name.
- Evening
- Come on in.
- Cognac?
- Yeah.
Had the car dusted for prints.
Only two sets -
yours and hers.
- What about her picture?
Showed it to all security guard, janitor
and all the office buildings in the area.
Noone remember seing her.
- Chips, anyone?
- Thought you were only getting ice.
Thought I´d throw in
some steaks and stuff.
Hey, my dad got that for
us from Indonesia.
Hey Nancy.
I´m glad you came.
Any news on Jessice?
- Nothing.
- She´ll show up, I´m sure of it.
- Are you out of your mind?
- Main event just started -
12 rounds to go.
He aint going anywhere.
C´mon, not in this house.
It´s not cool, Nancy.
I love my husband.
That´s right.
And we both know, how
much you love your wife.
That´s right.
I love my wife.
We just do things for each
other, which they dont do.
That´s right.
Dont stop.
What are you doing?
That is what makes us so good -
all this love -
That´s good.
Do it faster.
Fuck, he is gonna love that.
This wont take long.
Nice wheels
Wanna go for a ride?
I cancelled my last appointment.
I´ll be there in 20 minutes.
Yeah.
It will not be the same thing
we will have something special this night.
Bye.
I was thinking -
Who else knows my
name in this town?
- Couldnt come up with anyone else.
- He threatened to have my office searched.
That is one scary threat.
Your lovely daughter.
Is she still a virgin?
I cant have police here.
Your bank accounts -
You are in deep convenient -
That is why you are still alive.
But there are many things that
I value more than money.
Your daughter is not one of them.
Do I know you?
This is something -
Did Ray put you up to this?
In a bizarre sort of way.
This is fresh.
You can come out now Ray.
She is cute.
Come here.
I can see how he
would take a liking to you .
Your head is filled with
many strange things -
screaming, to get out.
Where is he?
Is he watching?
Would you like that?
I dont know.
Ray is gonna own me,
bigtime.
You are special one.
I will remember you.
Am I invited for the dinner?
You are fucking trespassing
again!
-- Call the cops.
-- She is not here!
-- He is here.
-- I should kill you.
-- I am going to have to take some measures.
-- I apologize.
I am sure you
can understand my situation.
Perfectly.
Your wife had an affair, discovered
the whole new world of possibilities -
and left you. I dont think its
that difficult to grasp.
You were the last person
that has seen her.
And I will treasure that memory
forever.
-- Some wine?
-- What the hell.
Who is the woman on the portrait?
That's why you are here?
To talk about art?
I´m taking polite fucking interest, okay?
Humor me.
If you thought we´d be standing here, waiting for you
without anything better to do -
I´m sorry to shatter your vision.
What do you need to know?
I want to know if my wife
said that she would see you again.
She said that she was looking forward to it.
Any specific date?
I didnt say  that
i wanted to see her again.
Okay, miss
Elizabeth Kane.
I´ve serious reason to believe
that my wife did not runaway.
As far as I´m concern, you were
last person seen with her.
Which is enough for me to go get your
fucking warrant for this fucking mansion.
You can give a damn if
your wife is dead or alive.
What is dragging you off the wall is the fact
that she couldnt stand you and she left you -
And she might be having
a time of his life with somebody else.
Let it go, detective. I am sure that
you will find ways to enjoy -
your newly found freedom.
Have a good
night, little buddy.
I have done
something terrible to you.
I´m sorry.
I have decided to bring back
your wife.
-- Dad, I am going to be late.
-- Allright.
- You left the patio-door open again
- No I didnt.
Hello Lisa.
Car´s looking good.
-- What happened last night?
-- Who is your friend?
-- Connie.
-- Hello, Connie.
-- Is this your detective friend?
-- I hope you havent being saying bad things about me.
Nice wheels. Is this
replica or the real thing?
C´mon.
So, where were you
last night at 3:00 AM?
I was sucking pillow.
No, you were driving your car.
-- No, I was in bed like from 11 a.m..
-- No, I saw you drive by.
-- That must have been someone else.
-- How many times have I fixed your car?
-- I think that I would know when I saw it.
-- Why would I lie to you?
You think that I could get a ride
sometime?
Yes?
No, I wasnt
feeling very well.
Yes, what the fuck
is the urgency?
Hello? Hello?
-- Has  your wife come back yet?
-- Not yet.
Have you talk
with Erszebet yet?
-- Dont you have stuff to do?
-- Yes.
- Go do it!
- Okay!
Tiny.
-- Remember Angy Manning from homicide?
-- No, not really.
How did your mess with infernal affairs go?
Well, well. I bought ´59 Corvette
to celebrate, thank you for asking.
Have a seat, Ray.
-- We need your help with something.
-- What is going on, captain?
Your partners wifes body was
found early this morning.
Multiple stapwounds.
Nancy Cusack is dead?
Her body was dumped near highway  15.
Someone reported seen someone
to take a large plasticbag -
out of the trunk of the car -
and going to the woods
-- We have the description of the man.
And the licenseplate number.
Did you make an arrest?
Goods needs a permission to
search your new Corvette.
-- What?
-- It would save me a lot of paperwork.
What the fuck is it this?
Ray, where were you last night
about 2:00 AM?
Not dumping my partners wife in the fucking
woods, if that is  what you are asking!
-- Who made that call?
-- A concerned woman.
Aint that just dandy.
Look, you know as well as I do,
only two people could have made that phonecall.
The one who saw it
or the one who did it.
You could help me to eliminate one of
those two real fast -
just tell me where
were you last night.
I was fucking sleeping,
it was 2:00 AM, asshole.
Well, was there anybody ...that could confirm that?
At least for part of the evening.
Yes, two mistresses.
Yeah, tuesday is a treesome-night,
we like to go-out whole fucking night.
I was sleeping alone.
Captain, this is ridiculous. We´ve
known each other for how long?
Ok, that is enough for now.
Angie, you mind
giving us a minute?
Of course, captain.
15 years. Yes...
I´ve  known you for 15 years.
And I´ve known the Cusacks wife
close to five.
You have to find
whoever made that call.
There is a nice little hotel in old Montreal -
ideal for little escapes.
I recommended it to you,
you remember?
What you do on your own time and
who you do it with, is non of my business.
Even when I saw you come out the room with
Nancy Cusack -
I kept my mouth shut.
But I ... I hope
you broke it up.
You know.. your wife disappearing,
dead-found mistress -
-- I have seen worse shit.
-- Captain, I did not kill her.
I know, I´m  with you Ray,
but Angy wants a DNA sample.
Fuck Angy and his DNA!
Fuck it!
Please, do it for me.
Nancy scratched to
her aggressor.
The forensic  found
skin samples her fingernails.
So?
I´m so sorry, Dean.
-- Fuck. What are you doing?
-- I should shoot you right now.
Put the fucking gun away! For fucks sake you
gonna get yourself in shit!
Dean, I didn´t kill her.
I swear to God, I didn´t kill her.
Did you have fun fucking my wife?
I didn´t kill her.
You think that I could
do that to her?
Piece of shit.
I trusted you!
Are you going to do it?
you are going to do it!?
I´m going to blow your fucking brains out.
Do it,  do it!
-- Ray, Ray!  Nathan...
-- Daddy!
How could you?
I need to talk to you!
I want you to go back to chat rooms, I want
you to ensure we´ll have young blood.
Young, beautifull, innocent blood.
When will I get to bite?
-- When you are ready.
-- You´ve been saying that for two years!
I´m ready now!
I´ll decide when you are. Two years  is nothing
compared to eternity ahead of you.
-- But why dont you let me  kill girls?
-- It´s not about killing.
It is about seducing
your prey.
She must watch you -
desire you -
You cannot take unwilling
soul.
And the blood
must be pure.
Fine.
Tell me about
your first time.
I dont know what you think
you´re doing.
-- I´m helping Ray to find his wife.
-- Why?
Now he is totally available,
I think you should invite him over -
get him drunk and
see what happens.
C´mon, you are so
into the guy.
If you are worried, I could
give you some pointers.
Thanks.
-- She wrote back
-- Answer her.
My friend told me that you would be a fun
person to meet.
What do you do?
Okay.
Like she´s going to call.
Hello.
-- Firebird?
- Erszebet?
-- You wanted to talk?
-- Yes, how is it going?
-- How old are you?
-- 21.
So .. what did you
your friend tell about me?
She said that
we would get along.
What is your friends name?
- Why, does it matter?
-- Can I call you back?
-- Yeah, but hang on lit...
-- I call you back.
She is not going to call.
She´ll call.
-- You want some water?
-- No, I´m okay.
-- Hello.
-- Hey honey.
-- Hey mom.
- How is the house?
-- House? Fine, me too.
-- Great.
Look, we wont be back tomorrow, your
dad wants to stay one more day.
-- Ok, that´s fine.
- You still have food?
-- Food?
-- Yes, food.
-- No. I´ll probably be dead when you get back.
-- Joker.
Good, I´m on public phone
only wanted to tell you.
-- Okay.
-- Good night.
Good night mom.
-- Yes?
-- I said that I´d call you back.
-- Erszebet?
-- May I come in?
-- How did you get my address?
-- I thought we might have a drink.
No. My parents are uppstaris. I didnt
ask you here. You have to go.
-- After the drink.
-- No.
Connie?
Look what you made
me to do.
It could have been
so much nicer.
Liz? You know what album thing is
that goes in this one?
Fuck, Liz,
what did you spill?
Evening, Raymond.
Vanessa, come and sit down here baby
I haven´t seen you awhile. You have been
staying out of trouble?
I always get myself out of trouble,
you know that.
-- You look a little bit down.
-- No, life is good.
A one big bed
of colorful roses.
You would like to go back and
share some of that happiness?
-- I´ve got one room for spare.
-- Oh, yes, that sounds good.
Told you that you´d find
ways to enjoy yourself.
-- What are your doing here?
-- We seem to share same taste.
Clubs, women.
-- You following me?
-- I came to see a good friend.
And here you are.
Isn´t it something?
I´m coming after you.
When you catch your bone,
you just dont let it go, detective?.
I admire that in a man.
If you feel the need to
talk, I´ll be backstage.
Try not to topple anything on
your way.
Step inside, detective.
My friend has been under a lot of pressure.
I need some time alone with him.
I have seen you here before.
I know that you´ve seen me.
Any issue standing between us.
It´s a time to clear it up.
Well, just write it down
and sign it?
Your wife came to see me
looking for something she was missing.
Unfortunately
for her, she lied to me.
I dont touch married women, detective.
-- Neither should you.
-- What happened?
Nothing happened.
Your wife was a charming woman. We spoke,
I shared my thoughts. She understood.
We had a drink, she left.
No hard feelings.
Your wife didnt
cheat on you.
At least, not with me.
And why didnt you just...
tell me that before.
There is something passionate about you
when you get upset.
I enjoy seeing that.
I dont know why.
So now what?
There is nothing else.
I´ll be leaving soon.
You will never have to
see me again.
Where are you going?
Sometimes its good to return to meaningful
places in your life.
As a  sort of balcrament.
A therapy for the soul.
You must have places like that.
Bongiorno, inspector Thurzo.
Interpol. Roma´s station.
May I speak with you?
I have an informant on board
of cruise ship " The Batore ".
This informant
has been instructed -
to tell me each time a certain
passenger boards the ship.
This certain passenger
is a woman.
One month age she
disembark here in Montreal.
And you went to
visit her to her house.
-- Is she wanted?
-- No, under investigation.
-- For what?
-- Possible murder.
Possible murder?
What is that?
An Italian crime?
We have no victims.
Only missing women.
Arent you little out of your jurisdiction?
I take some time off.
You see, I´ve personal interest in this case
my granddaughter went missing 6 years ago.
You have been following this
woman for 6 years?
On and off.
But I came here to warn you. This is
unusually dangerous woman.
You must only approach her in
strictly professional manner.
Keep your distance.
And let your own people
do the work.
-- The way you you do it?
-- Precisely.
I know what I´m talking about.
-- You, you could end up dead.
-- What is that supposed to mean?
It means that I have
a plane to catch.
If there is something that I should
know, mayby you should tell me.
Pope, Pope.
It is a curious name.
Arrivederci, detective Pope.
Yes, they pulled her out of the water
about 15 minutes ago.
She´s not even 16 years old.
No, I handle it from here.
We are going to need
a rape-kit.
Oh Jesus, Pope.
She was your babysitter.
She was just a kid.
I´m going to ask you something.
I want you to think
real hard about it -
because ... I´d really love to hear
your answer.
Now mayby ... mayby
we could explain -
Nancy Cusack´s prints and
the blood all over your car.
And mayby, allthou
it might be difficult -
we could explain
your skin -
under the nails of
your partners wife.
Now, help me out on here, ´cos
I really would like to help you.
Is there any way possible? I mean
any way possible -
that you could explain, how
your semen got out of your dick -
and into your
babysitters body?
besides the obvious.
Relax. I´ll be right back.
What is it, captain?
The bites on the girls throat -
Forensics says its neither human
nor animal. Sounds familiar?
Looks like we got a another riddle
for you to solve, you sick fuck.
Elizabeth!
Here, I brought you the results
so you could see yourself.
-- Is there a match?
-- Yeah, you.
-- Who else?
-- That´s it. Just you.
It´s fucking impossible!
She handed me the glass!
Well, she´s neither a ghost or
she had her fingerprints removed.
What is going on here?
-- I have to get out of here.
-- Pope, listen to me, you have a kid.
Whatever you got yourself into,
you gotta get yourself out, now.
-- I gotta go.
-- Pope,  what you mean go, go where?
Pope?
Shut the fuck up! Do not move!
Your client was not in
the castle. Where is she?
-- She is not my client.
-- You handled her affairs!
I handled one transaction,
for God's sake.
I´ve got sixth sense,
when someone is lying to me.
You have no idea the evil
you are dealing with.
You wanna see evil?
I´m gonna show you evil.
She´ll take my daughter.
Fuck!
Looks like we got
the same problem, Renaud.
I can get rid of it
... allright?
I make it all go away.
C´mon.
Venice. She has
a place in Venice.
Excuse me.
You know where this is?
-- Why?
-- I have a friend -
Excuse me.
Fuck!
That is enough.
Get out of here.
-- Excuse me. Do you speak English?
-- Why should I?
I saw this book of yours
in the window.
A man with fine taste in
woman, there it is
-- What is the story of this one?
-- Elizabeth Bathory. Countess Drácula.
Why do you ask? Usually those interested
in this book arent interested in history.
I saw this portrait
in someones house.
-- A copy, ofcourse
-- I do not know. I guess so.
Why do you call it
Countess Drácula?
Countess Bathory, was one
of the cornerstones -
of the modern vampyre mythology.
-- I never hearded the novel.
-- What novel?
Dear sir,  she was
as real as you and I.
And one of the most evil
human being that ever lived.
Care for a a biscuit,
italian specialty.
Thank you.
She was born in 1560, off
true Hungarian nobility -
renounced as one of the most
beautiful women of her age -
And sadist of unparallel savagery.
From her early age, the lady took pleasure
in torturing and killing her servingmaids.
Dismembering them and even
freezing them alive.
One day, on her usual fits of rage-
she slapped one of the maids so hard, that some
of the poor girls blood-
spilled out and splattered
on the countesses hand.
At which point, on her eyes, a miracle has occurred.
Then there ... on the spot,
where the blood had stained -
the skin appeared
to rejuvenated itself -
the wrinkles,
they seemed to disappear.
Of course, after that, there were
no limits for madames lunacy.
Over the years, some 650 young women
were maimed and brutalized -
simply to satisfy her thirst of blood.
She would drink it,
she would bath in it!
In dellusional quest
for eternal youth.
Thats some fucking story.
I often wandered, if woman like that
could live today.
You know, some people
think that she never died.
Someone people believe in
Loch Ness monster.
Do you sell any of these?
Yes, I have an invitation.
Its here in somewhere.
Nice outfit.
This is a very exclusive party.
This is where all
the fun begins.
Good. Yeah.
Oh, by the way, there is
a strict dress code.
No exceptions.
You´ll love this wine.
Come.
Buena sera.
-- Oh sorry, I dont speak Italian.
-- Isnt that a relief?
-- Enjoying yourself?
-- Yes I am.
-- What is the occasion?
-- You dont know?
No, I came with a friend.
He didnt tell me much.
-- He didnt?
-- No.
I´ve had my share of sneaking
into parties myself.
You busted me.
Where is the owner?
The proprietress?
I´m affraid she died ,
my dear boy.
around 400 years ago.
Do you trust me?
Sweet girl.
Open.
Is it too tight?
Now...
Countess Elizabeth
Bathory of Hungary.
-- Are you shitting me?
-- Do you know her?
This house is hers?
One of many.
The original palace was
demolished a long time ago.
This was built on
whatever ruins were left.
What about the present owner?
Very few people have actually met our hostess.
She never stays around long enough.
Elizabeth Kane
is current houstess -
with very selected circle of friends.
Look at all these women. Batory herself
would´ve been exstatic.
-- I assume that you are alone.
-- Yeah, you know, i better go get my friend.
Excuse me.
You have done well tonight,
Irina. All is forgiven.
I thank you for your beauty.
-- Did you miss me?
-- Oh boy, detective-
Elizabeth gonna be
really uppset.
And better not let
her see you.
Oh, God -
What did you do?
Get away from her.
Get away from her!
It could kill each of them before
you could limb halfway cross this room.
-- Fuck you could!
-- I will make this quick.
You have no idea how much
I loved that dog.
Try to stay awake, detective.
I would´t want you to miss what happens next,
for anything in the world.
What am I going to do with you?
If you werent a decent familyman, one
might think you´re enjoying all this pain.
Enjoying the blood.
You look well.
I am glad.
I dont feel so well, after I bounced  in that car
for 5 hours.
You will be fine.
What kind of fucked up jail is this?
You must not swear
in this place.
There is a monk.
Formaly a great psychiatrist.
Who has helped us many times in
the past on most extraordinary cases.
You might not agree
with some of his methods.
But I can assure you,
he is quite effective.
-- A monk?
-- Yes.
I dont think that this has been
reported to proper authorities.
I can assure you that it has.
What is your story?
What are you?
Interpol?
Vatican intelligence?
I want to thank you for coming to Venice
as a fugitive of the law.
It allowed me to follow you. Also allowed
me to get search warrant to go inside the house.
to have you arrested. Otherwise, I had no
legitimate motives to go inside.
So how come I´m not arrested?
But you did not do anything,
we both knew that.
And I have good
news for you.
You  think you killed the girl, but you did not.
It was a dog.
No, no, no. I killed the dog also. But
I left the girl dead in the hallway.
- No, no, no girl.
-- What do you mean, no girl?
What about Elizabeth?
I threw a knife right thru her back.
I wish you had, but
you were not in condition to throw anything.
You hit her with the handle of the knife,
she has a small scar in the back of the neck.
Allright, listen, inspector
Thurzo, Father Thurzo -
whatever the fuck
your story is.
I want to know what is
going on with that woman.
There are many things you dont
understand about our prisoner.
But you asked me to see her and I allow it
because she asked to see you.
But if you swear one more time
in this place -
I make you walk all the way
back to Venice right now.
I want to see the prisoner.
Show him.
-- What are they doing?
-- They pray for her soul -
and the souls of the dead.
And you have 10 minutes.
Inspector Pope!
Do me one favor.
Do not accept anything she gives you.
Nice of you to travel all the way here.
Care for a glass of wine?
Why dont I place the glass here.
And I´ll go sit over here.
Feel safer?
Two girls
died in your house.
One is in critical condition.
We managed to save other four.
That...
really upsets you.
How long has this been going on?
For quite some time now.
Is my wife dead?
You should not have killed my dog.
I was very fond of  her.
But your wife is not dead.
She is very much alive inside
of me, like all the others.
How many have there been?
Why dont you step right up and ask
me what you truly came here to learn?
-- Who are you?
-- There.
Have some wine.
No.
Be polite.
Carefull.
To eternity.
I should have warned you.
Its not quite your taste.
-- Who gave that?
-- Settle down detective, nobody that you met.
I got it from the hospital.
They have to take care of me.
To have this
condition.
Who are you?
In three days, they will transfer me to one
small clinic on the Swiss border.
They will take me by truck
on mountain roads.
It will be a long ride.
Anything can go wrong.
They will never expect anyone
to intervene.
They will dissect me.
Your 10 minutes is up!
Detective -
people have done far stranger things
because of love.