Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
If you want to know
the truth about someone...
find their dream...
and work backwards.
We're all chasing something.
More money...
more love.
I don't know,
maybe just one more chance.
What we're looking for is...
more life.
Yes, sir.
More of this beautiful life.
But if you're not careful...
you might go looking for more...
and wind up with less.
Come on. Come on.
This time.
I know. I know.
I know.
We'll talk about it later.
- Half an hour, I'll be home.
- Good evening...
- basketball fans...
- Love you too. Bye.
And welcome
to basketball action.
One of the better games
you will see all season.
The Eagles of Saint Francis
taking on the Matadors of Loyola.
Here we go!
Matadors. Matadors.
What? What? What?
- What? What?
- All right.
Bring it on in here.
A match up featuring two
of the premier guards in the league...
Godfrey Snow and Darius Jackson.
- St. Francis on the breakaway.
- There you go!
Godfrey Snow!
- What a jump!
- Godfrey!
Darius Jackson...
manhandles through the lane.
No one can stop him.
Up for the lay-up.
It's good.
Godfrey Snow working
two defenders.
Come on, Godfrey.
Make it look easy.
Wide open in the corner.
For three.
It's good.
That's right.
That's my little brother.
Careful, it's hot.
It needs more salt.
- A little.
- Dad, I eat salt with everything.
- I know.
- Mom's finally home.
- You know, I never liked him anyway.
- Dad, you told me you did.
You're too good for him,
Nicole.
He told me he likes
this Rebecca Simons girl.
She's such a slut.
She's got pierced nipples.
What?
Why would someone do that
to herself?
Pain's pleasure.
Haven't you ever heard that, dad?
- No, I have not.
- Dad, do you think I'm pretty?
Tell the truth.
- Nicole Carver, you are beautiful.
- You have to say that.
I absolutely do not.
Hey, guys.
I'm sorry, I'm late.
Thanks for waiting.
I'm starving, mom.
I feel like an Ethiopian.
I know, baby. I know.
Please tell me you finished
the great American novel already.
Almost. Almost.
What are you doing?
It smells delicious.
It's African groundnut stew.
It's the recipe from the magazine
section. I'm the best, aren't I?
I'll say.
Mom...
do you want my advice?
What?
Put a lot of sex into it so that
people actually want to read it.
Not like the last one.
- Nicole.
- What?
Aren't we supposed to be honest
in this house all the time?
That's the rule, right?
Uh, that's the rule.
I'm just trying to help, mom.
And I love you for it.
You smell like smoke.
Oh, that's the coffee shop.
Hey, come on! Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Snow finding room behind
the three-point arc.
It's good.
No one can stop Darius Jackson
from getting to the hole.
- Do something with the ball.
- Back up.
- What?
Come on, do something.
What? What?
Whatcha got?
Snow, nice through the defense.
Another dunk. The Matadors down one.
Fifty-eight, fifty-seven.
Jackson, all the way to the basket.
Loyola takes the lead!
That's it.
You know they say big time players
make big time plays.
Who's going to make the play now?
All right. All right, G.
You are a rookie.
You heard me?
Look at me when
I'm talking to you.
Roberts on the inbound
over to Snow.
He can't find anything.
Gives it up.
Snow working up the baseline.
Off the corner for the three
and the win.
It's no good. It's no good.
Loyola wins it.
A heartbreaking loss
for St. Francis...
and more specifically
for Godfrey Snow.
That's a nice shot. Rookies always choke
under pressure, punk.
Too-da-Ioo.
Damn.
All right, Clyde
How could you have missed
that shot?
You've been doing that shot
a hundred times everyday.
This ain't no game.
You got scouts
looking at you.
That's what you've been working for.
What's going on?
I don't know, man.
You're going to hit
that shot next time, right?
I choked in there, Clyde.
I don't care about that game.
That game's over.
We can't get that back.
You're going to run against these boys
again in the next tournament.
And you know
what's going to happen?
It's going to be about you.
Ain't nobody in this world can stop
Godfrey Snow but Godfrey Snow.
Nobody.
And you got to own that.
Can I hear it? Let me hear it.
Let me hear it.
Where's Godfrey Snow?
I'm sorry, did anybody see Godfrey?
Godfrey!
Come on...
you see that boy Jackson?
He got pro scouts looking at him.
And you held your own.
What's that say about you?
You're going to have say something
or I'm gonna slap you upside your head.
- I own it.
- I'm sorry. I didn't hear that.
I own it!
- Can I just get a little bit of noise?
- I own it.
- One more time.
- I own it!
That's what I'm talking about.
You own it. You're Godfrey Snow.
You're Godfrey Snow. All right?
Cool. Cool. Here.
Why don't you...
go get yourself something to eat
with your friends.
I gotta roll because I got a call
about a busted pipe.
They got you working
overtime again?
I'm a black man.
I work all the time.
Clyde, you know there ain't going to be
no more working once I get to the NBA.
That's what I'm talking about.
There he is.
- I own it.
- You own it!
That's my man.
Yeah!
Godfrey Snow!
Hit him hard this time, Murph,
so he finally understands, huh?
You know what the fucking doctor said?
The doctor said I suffer from stress.
Stress.
I don't feel any stress.
I hate doctors.
Maybe I have stress
and I don't even know I have stress.
Is that even possible?
- Is he here?
- No.
This guy. We never should have taken
this guy's action, man.
He's a pain in my ass.
Oh, he's all right, man.
I know him from way back.
We're trying to run a business here,
Murph. Remember?
She's something, Aug.
I can't stop thinking
about her, man.
Murph, what did I say?
It's not going away.
I really love her, man. No shit.
It'll pass.
It always passes, Murph.
But this is different.
It's like...
- It's like in here, you know.
- In here you mean.
- Oh, fuck you!
- Fuck me.
You'll see, Murph.
It'll pass. It always does.
He's here.
We'll both hit him.
I told you I'll get you
the money, Murph!
I don't get it, Clyde.
I pay plumbers a lot of money.
So, what's the fucking problem?
Murph, what you hitting me for?
You're my boy!
- Oh, you're his boy?
- Shut up, Clyde.
What is this?
We got history!
I think what Murph
is trying to explain to you...
is that we are running
a fucking business here.
What do we look like the Red Cross?
You people.
- Fuck you. Fuck you! Fuck you!
- Enough!
Listen to me, Clyde...
just get the money.
You got 'til the first of the month.
Don't make things harder
on yourself, Clyde.
Is that the way
it's going to be?
this is going to be?
You're supposed to be my friend!
We go way back!
And you were supposed to be
my friend!
You already did that, baby.
No, this is something else.
I don't want to get wrinkles.
Wrinkles?
I don't see any wrinkles.
I just see a beautiful...
sexy woman.
Come here.
Tom?
I'm sorry.
It's just the book.
I can't think of anything else.
- Okay.
- I'm consumed by it.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Dr. Carver?
Can I talk to you
for a sec?
Sure, Jill.
Goodnight.
I can't fail your class,
Dr. Carver.
Will you promise me
that I won't fail?
Jill, I can't pass you
if you don't do the work.
You're not doing anything.
Look...
my parents will kill me if I fail.
Isn't there anything I can do?
Do the work.
That's all you could do.
Do your best and you'll be fine.
But you have to do something.
Isn't there anything else
I can do?
Jill...
just do the work.
That a boy.
There you go.
Double jabs.
Double jabs. Double jabs.
Nice.
Who wants my man?
He's ready.
Hey, babe, Brunner's here.
Murph, you better be careful.
You're going to hurt yourself.
He doesn't care. He's in love.
Congratulations.
You guys hear?
Wing Loh is dead.
Shit.
We didn't do it.
I know you didn't do it, Murph.
I'm just wondering.
A nothing bookie, dead.
How does that happen?
Maybe somebody owed him a lot of
money and wanted to clean the slate.
Yeah, maybe.
Any other ideas?
What about Ivan?
Is Ivan worried about a fellow
like Wing Loh? I don't think so.
Ivan's sitting someplace
nice and warm right now...
- counting his gold. Trust me.
- King fucking Ivan.
You should pay his boy, Victor,
a visit.
I might just do that.
Be in touch you hear anything,
okay?
And...
you guys watch yourselves,
okay?
You especially, Murph.
Being in love and all.
Try one, Sticks?
Pass.
Wing Loh is dead.
You hear anything, Victor?
When I stand outside alone at night
I hear voices.
But I think that's just the boys
in the harbor.
Are you accusing Ivan of involvement
in the death of Wing Loh?
Ivan's smart enough
not to bother.
Why you here then?
Just a hunch.
There's something for you
on the coffee table.
No, thanks.
Well, I want you to know
that's always there for you, my friend.
Give it to charity.
Why don't you give it to charity?
Why don't you give it to one
of those heartwarming organizations...
that support...
war heroes such as yourself?
I'm no hero.
This was...
friendly fire.
I think you killed Wing Loh.
You're a lousy detective, Sticks.
Ivan would never bother
with a nothing like Wing Loh.
Ivan wouldn't.
But...
you're not Ivan.
It's game time, Murph.
Let's make some money.
Murph.
You got it.
Barry G.,
one hundred on Utah...
minus three and a half.
One-ten wins one, Bar.
Later.
Murph.
Hey, Jimmy!
How the hell are you, man?
- No shit!
- Enough with the chit chat.
- What color?
- Murph, please, please...
who cares what color?
- Come on, get his money.
- What do ya got?
Three hundred on the Red Wings...
minus two goals.
That's three to win in three.
No juice, split line.
Later.
- Hey, Aug.
- What?
You know what she said to me
this morning?
Murph, come on. Not now.
She said I am the best
she's ever had.
What is she supposed to say?
You're still in the room.
The best.
The best, Aug.
You're the best.
Fuck me, please.
Do me the favor...
- after we're done making all this money.
- You're just jealous.
Murph.
What's the matter?
It's Victor.
He wants you.
Give me the twenty. Give me
the twenty, twenty dollars. Okay.
Here we go. Right?
Here's the magic marker.
Here's your twenty. I'm going to make
a nice, big "X" on that twenty.
Okay? I am starving.
Thank you, sir.
I have very expensive tastes.
Here we go.
Like that and...
thank you.
Hey, buddy.
I want that twenty back.
That was a loan?
Not funny.
You want it back?
M'am, could you please give the kind,
generous gentleman...
- his money back?
- Me?
In your purse.
Right there in your wallet.
That's it. Yeah.
There you go. There you go, sir.
Here's a five for you, sir.
Remember,
I have very expensive tastes.
All right, here's a ten.
Now get the heck out of here.
Thank you.
You're a good sport.
Appreciate it. All right.
There you go.
Thanks.
Detective...
what brings you to this glorious
part of the world?
Certainly not the cuisine.
Walter.
Well, I'm absolutely fantastic.
Thanks for asking.
I couldn't ask for anything more
out of this life.
You ever hear of a guy
named Wing Loh?
Never.
But I love Chinese food.
You hear any mention
of that name...
Wing Loh...
I want you to listen
real closely, okay?
For you, anything, detective.
Whoa, cowboy.
It's the best thing here...
the ice cream.
You got a little...
little schmutz right there.
Just a teeny...
- Did I get it?
- No, not yet.
It's...
up... to the...
- Now?
- Just missed. It's like...
do you mind if I...
Allow me to...
Oh, there's a lot of it.
Feel better?
That was cute.
That was really cute.
- My name's Walter.
- I'm married, Walter.
- What's the point?
- No point.
Oh, what do you think?
That I want to make love to you?
- You're not my type.
- Ditto.
I was just in the mood
for a little conversation.
I thought you might be in the mood
for a little entertainment.
But if you don't want it, I'm gone.
I'm out of here.
Invisible man, whoo!
You hear about the one where the horse
goes in the bar and the bartender says...
What's with the long face.
That's old.
And I'd really appreciate it
if you just leave me alone.
Two cannibals eating a clown.
One cannibal says
to the other one...
This taste funny to you?
I saw you at the slots.
You don't want to play the slots.
- No, I do. I have fun.
- Fun how?
It's just fun for me. I like it.
You got to get the human element
involved to win.
See, the more human element...
the more chance you got to win.
These are for you.
Looks like you need
a breath mint.
That's hilarious.
- Where you going?
- None of your business.
Hey, my name is Walter Markowitz.
I'm a magician.
Bye, Walter.
I can't eat while
you're looking at me like that.
I can't help it. I need to.
No, no, no. No. No. No.
Not again, please. I can't.
"Amigos", something nice and romantic
this time. "Cielito Lindo"?
Hey, Victor.
How are you doing, buddy?
You never give up, do you?
I want to talk to Ivan.
He owes me.
Come on, Victor.
Throw me a bone.
Just a little something to tie me over.
Times are tough.
I did his kid's birthday party
three years in a row.
Who was working with Ivan
when he was nothing?
I know all the guys on the take.
All those cops...
I give him that information.
I can help you guys.
Is that so?
I know there are people
trying to take Ivan down...
coming after Ivan.
Now that's important information,
Walter.
Take a seat.
No, no...
No, really. No, I won't bite.
Sit down.
This steak...
it's a wonderful piece of meat.
It's...
like eating butter.
See the marbling?
It's probably aged for six weeks.
And these fries.
They're perfect.
They're thin and...
they're crispy.
You know, I think I'm going to have
them put it in a doggy bag.
It's your lucky day, Walter.
They're all yours.
Fuck you, Victor.
It's...
a wonderful steak, Walter. It's just
the way it should be cooked.
It's medium rare.
Fuck you, Victor.
Hey, Walter.
Will you show me a magic trick?
Let me see a bunny wabbit.
Can you... can you make
a bunny wabbit appear?
Where's my wabbit?
Go to hell.
Wait a minute.
It is you.
Claudia.
Veronica Cruz. Oh, my God,
it's been a long time, girl.
Only twelve years.
- Oh, my God, you look exactly the same.
- And I have two kids.
So, tell me about you.
What's going on with you?
Still stuck on zero.
I just haven't found
the right guy yet.
Who's the guy
you're having dinner with?
He may be the right guy.
We're going on six months.
Got my fingers crossed.
I hate to tell you this but...
the guy's an asshole, Veronica.
He broke my husband's jaw
last year.
I'm sorry, I...
I'll see you around, okay?
Shit.
Baby,
he owed us a lot of money.
- It's sick.
- It had to be done.
That is bullshit.
Normal people don't beat people up
because they owe them money!
- They do. Where I'm from, yes they do.
- No they don't!
Yes, they do.
Listen, wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Listen.
I love you, Cruz.
I want to be with you forever.
Don't touch me!
Fuck!
Wait! Veronica, wait!
Wait!
- Carolyn.
- Jesus...
- you scared me.
- Carol, it's one o'clock in the morning.
Where were you?
The coffee shop.
- Coffee shops are open this late?
- No.
After it closed...
I wrote in the car.
- What?
- I don't know...
it's amazing.
I write really well in the car.
I was worried about you.
All you had to do was call me.
I'm sorry. I'm...
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to wake you.
- I promise next time.
- Just call.
Okay.
Hey, you.
Writing in the car.
Goodnight.
I promise.
Yeah? Let me hear it.
We got to add tennis courts.
Hey, we got to add a putting green
at the crib.
All that. Heliports.
- Swimming pool.
- What's up with the pool?
Olympic size one.
I'm going to put some fish in it.
- Can you put fish in a pool?
- Yeah, you could put fish in the pool.
How about a Jacuzzi?
I mean 'cause I'm not going to visit you
if you don't got a Jacuzzi.
That's what I do.
I'm a Jacuzzi swimmer.
What do you mean "visit"?
You going to be there all the time.
They going to put a Jacuzzi
in your room for you.
- We got to have our own chef.
- Now you're talking my language.
- A white guy, right?
- Hell, yeah.
- What? French?
- French? I don't know 'cause...
I don't know if French people
can make collard greens.
Come on. One more.
One more. Come on.
All right,
let's get out of here, man.
Western College...
- Thursday night. You feel it?
- Oh, yeah.
'Cause the line's
got you guys up by eight.
You boys getting
some respect now.
About damn time.
What if you win by less
than eight?
A win's a win, right?
Yeah, yeah.
That's what I'm saying.
What I'm saying Godfrey is...
what if you win by less
than eight?
A win's a win, right?
Clyde, man, don't tell me you got
money riding on the game.
You always accusing me of stuff.
Come on, man.
Don't worry about me.
You need to focus on the game.
- You need to concentrate.
- Clyde.
I believe in you, G.
Who else am I gonna bet on?
I got to bet on you.
You said you was done.
I thought you was supposed
to be clean.
I'm trying to get there.
That's what this is all about.
I'm not doing it.
You see this?
Do you see this?
I didn't get this from hitting
my head on some fucking pipe.
These guys,
they want their money.
And I'm in the hole.
I'm going to get hurt really bad
if I can't figure my way out of this.
Come on, Godfrey.
Come on.
Look, we'll borrow the money.
Who the fuck going to lend us
the money?
I don't know. Coach.
I'm down twelve thousand,
all right?
Twelve thousand dollars?
- How you down twelve thousand dollars?
- I don't know. I don't know, man.
I just got out of control.
I just got out of control, you know?
You said you was done.
I'm trying, all right? I'm trying.
You swore to me. I guess your word
don't mean shit, then. Huh?
You know what? Fuck it, Godfrey!
Fuck it! All right? Fuck it!
I'm not perfect! Look at me.
I'm not perfect!
Who is? Who's perfect?
You perfect?
You make every shot
you ever take?
Did you make that shot
against Loyola the other day?
No.
You didn't hit that shot.
You fucked up.
You lost the game.
You...
You're not perfect.
I'm not perfect either.
Got me all messed up, man.
This is all messed up. I'm sorry.
That's not right.
I shouldn't have said that.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. All right?
I'm sorry. I'm just...
I'm just trying to get straight.
I'm just trying not to get hurt.
That's it.
What you need me to do?
Forget it, all right?
Come on. Come on. Forget it.
No, no, no, let's go.
Let's go home.
Let's get out of here.
Clyde, man,
what you need me to do?
I just need you to win
by less than eight.
Move your feet. Move your feet.
Come on. Come on.
All right. It's all right.
It's all right.
Let's go. Let's go.
Oh, God damn it.
- What's the matter?
- I got this indigestion...
this acid reflux. It burns.
- It hurts like a son of a bitch.
- That's stress.
Yeah, I know. That's what all
the genius doctors keep telling me.
You know...
Augustine...
the reason I invited you here tonight
is because I think you're an astute guy.
And I like the way
you do business.
- I'm just trying to make a living.
- Well, I think we should work together.
Pull our resources, so to speak.
Wow, that's quite an offer Victor.
But, you know, Murph and I, you know,
we got a good thing going now.
Murph's a liability.
You work with me,
you'll retire before you're forty.
Did you offer anybody else
this deal?
What do you mean?
Wing Loh.
Now,
why would you ask me that?
If we're working together, I should know
about the operation. Don't you think?
Wing Loh was offering
better lines.
He was stealing from both of us.
I heard something about that.
But it didn't really bother me.
I figured there was enough action
for all of us. Didn't you?
What do you think of my offer?
I think Murph and I...
pretty happy as we are.
Well, I think
you should think about it.
I think you should think...
about where you want to be
in five years.
Have a good night, Augustine.
You too, Victor.
Thanks for the game.
How's my boy, Ivan, doing?
Would you like me to say
"hello" for you?
Actually I don't know him.
I never met him.
I didn't think you did.
You know what? I have a theory
about Ivan, Victor. Just hear me out.
There is no Ivan.
It's like the Wizard of Oz.
You're Ivan.
Good night, Augustine.
- Come on, come on!
- Yeah!
Walter the magician.
- They're pretty loud, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
Cute again.
- That's for you.
- Thank you.
- And you are?
- Carolyn.
Carolyn.
Do you play, Carolyn?
- No.
- Come on, sit down.
This is my game.
I'll teach you.
Blackjack!
- What are you gonna do?
- Yeah. More.
- You want more? Let it ride?
- Let it ride.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on! Come on! Come on!
Blackjack!
It's her first time playing.
It's her first time!
All right. What? What? What?
- Again.
- Enough? Again?
- Again?
Going again.
Okay. Okay.
Remember what I told you
about the odds.
Let the dealer bust.
- Let the dealer bust.
- I feel lucky.
- You got to play the odds.
- One more.
- You want a hit?
One more.
- She wants a hit.
- Hit it.
Oh! Oh! Medic!
- Hello?
- Hey, Nicole. Is your mom there?
She's not here.
All right. Well, I'll see you
in a little while, okay? Bye.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Hello?
Hey, baby. Where are you?
Hi, honey. The coffee shop.
- Are you going to be home soon?
- Yeah, soon.
Well, I miss you.
I miss you too. Bye.
- You're very good under pressure.
- Hey, lady luck, are you in or you out?
- Are you gonna play this game or what?
- No, I'm in. I'm, I'm in.
That was so fantastic.
Thank you so very much.
Come on.
Did I give you enough?
Oh, yeah. I'm a simple guy.
You sure you want to quit?
Because, you know,
when you're on a roll like that...
No, I really have to go home.
Home is where the heart is.
Okay, well, I'll be here,
Carolyn Carver, okay?
I'm here!
Hey, you.
Are you my lover?
Are you my angel man?
- Did you finish?
- Almost.
I'm just happy.
Can't I be happy?
Carolyn.
I decided on the way home from the game
to get a Starbucks.
You weren't at the Starbucks.
I don't always go to Starbucks.
Portfolio on Main?
Did you try there?
No.
I'm sorry.
I cannot work
at the same place everyday.
It would drive me crazy.
- Where did you think I was?
- I don't know.
It's just that we don't get to see
much of you around here these days.
I'm almost finished.
I really am.
We just miss you, baby.
That's all.
How about the other guy?
Does he miss me too?
Yeah? Does he?
- I don't know. Let me ask him.
- Oh, no, no.
Let me ask him.
How are you doing?
All right.
Let's finish strong. Finish strong.
Come on, finish strong.
Push it out. Push it out.
Yeah.
All right. All right.
Good work, men.
Good work. All right,
you all go and hit the showers.
- Get back to your dorms. Hit the books.
- Yeah, all right.
Fill your brains with knowledge...
and you will succeed
on this planet.
There he is!
Godfrey Snow!
Madison Square Garden...
one free throw
from the World Championship.
And the crowd screams.
And he shoots!
And it's in!
He hits it!
Godfrey Snow!
- The man!
- You know, I be doing my thing.
- Doing my thing.
I'm going to need a little more help
from you, all right?
Just a little bit, okay?
How much more?
I don't know, you know.
I can't...
get it all back at one time,
right?
I mean,
they be all over me for that, right?
You know that, right?
Come on.
Hit me.
Hit.
I'm out.
Hit me.
Fuck it.
Oh, God.
Mrs. Snyder,
doctor will be right with you.
Cruz, hey, I got you something.
I don't want it.
Hey, hey, how come you
didn't call me back last night?
- Excuse me.
- Let's not do this here, okay?
But how come
you didn't call me?
How come?
I want to slow things down.
Why?
Because...
because, Murph,
I need some time alone.
Look, what I got you.
Look.
This is going to look beautiful
on you. Look.
I can't.
- I don't want it.
- You love me, Veronica.
- You said so yourself.
- You're a bookie.
- You hurt people.
- I love you.
I don't want to be with a bookie
for the rest of my life you know.
- I want more.
- Oh, all right, I'll quit.
- You tell me to quit and I'll quit.
- Okay, then quit.
- Exactly.
- Wait, wait, wait.
I want to hear you say
that you don't love me.
I don't love you.
- Yes, you do.
- No, I don't.
Cover up, Murph.
Come on, Murph.
Stop dancing. Get out of there.
There you go.
Come on, bitch.
Let's go.
- Nice.
- Come on, huh? You want me, huh?
All right, easy. Let's be nice.
Murph, Murph, Murph,
Murph, Murph!
- Calm down, man.
- Break it off.
Over to Henson...
he goes behind his back...
Ray opens on the course...
It hurts like hell, Murph.
I've been there.
You'll be all right.
You'll get through it, man.
Pretty soon, you won't
even remember her name.
- I'll always remember.
- You'll see.
I want out.
I'm done with booking, Aug.
No, you don't.
And no, you're not.
I made a decision.
I don't want to do it anymore.
- That's Veronica Cruz talking.
- Fuck you.
- Fuck me?
- Yeah.
Fuck you, man.
You know what? This has gone on
long enough. This is crazy.
What are you going to do, Murph?
Join a band? Med school?
- I love her.
- She doesn't love you back.
- What? You got to say that?
- Yeah, I do have to say it, man.
This is getting crazy now.
I'm tired of it.
You're my best friend.
You're my business partner.
Look, man...
we got a really good thing
going here.
We're on the rise, man.
We're on the rise.
And it is only going to get better
and better and better. I promise.
It doesn't feel right anymore.
You love booking, Murph.
Tell me you don't.
It's not good what we do,
Aug.
I'm talking to
Veronica Cruz's puppet.
It's not good what we do, Aug.
How could you say that, man?
Look at what these other guys do.
These bigwig, these hotshot...
businessmen and politicians.
They screw people
over for billions of dollars.
And then they go run behind
their million dollar lawyers.
And you got the balls to tell me
that what we do...
that what we're doing is wrong?
Come on, Murph.
You...
fuck.
- You all right?
- Yeah, just...
Let me tell you something...
Motherfucker.
What we do is good.
Okay?
Following me?
It's good.
We provide a service.
People like to bet.
We let them bet.
It's good.
I'll tell you something else. Okay?
Ready for this?
Ivan's going down.
Ivan's never going down,
you told me.
No. Ivan told Victor
to kill Wing Loh.
That's conspiracy to commit murder.
Bye, bye, Ivan.
Wait, wait, wait.
- How do you know Ivan did it?
- 'Cause I know.
That's how I know because I know.
All right?
Now you envision a world
with me and you booking.
No Ivan. No Victor.
Wing Loh's already out.
Forget about it. Out of the park.
Nothing can stop us.
Undisputed heavyweight champions
of the world.
Put your hand up.
Put your hands up.
All right?
- Let me get in that robe, big boy.
- Get the fuck away from me.
- You're in a good mood, when I act gay?
- Yeah.
Here it is!
- That's great.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- Wonderful.
Thank... Oh, that's so generous.
Thank you very much.
That's very nice of you.
Thank you so much.
Have a good night.
Walter.
- Walter.
- Oh, Carolyn.
My lucky lady.
Are you hungry? I'm buying.
Walter.
I'm listening.
I lost everything we won
last night.
- I don't believe it.
- No, I did... I...
I should have stayed like you said,
when I was on a roll.
- You're only a beginner once.
- Over the last six months...
I lost my family savings.
- All of it?
- Almost.
- Don't worry. You'll get it back.
- No, I don't...
You'll get it back
if you believe you'll get it back.
It's so much money, Walter.
You want to make some
of that money back today?
No. No, Walter,
I don't feel lucky today.
You don't have to be lucky
for this.
This is guaranteed.
You like to step into my office?
I know it's not much,
but I call it home.
We're going to play a little game
of hanky poo.
One for me
and two for you.
Here's the game.
Watch the lady.
Find the Queen.
Okay, two black cards.
One red.
Okay? There she is.
Simple as that.
Easy game.
In? Who's in?
Anybody? No?
I'll tell you what, two for one.
Two for one?
What do you mean?
Madam, that means if you bet twenty,
you tell me where the Queen is...
I give you forty.
You bet forty, you get eighty.
Eighty, you get one-sixty.
And so on, and so forth.
You in or out?
Yes or no.
Anybody?
Play or go. I see green.
- Okay. The end.
- Here?
Put it down.
Okay, is that your choice?
That's it.
Any other takers?
No?
Congratulations, Madam.
I think I owe you forty dollars.
There you are.
- I think I've had enough. I think I...
- No, no, no.
No, I...
No, I know when to quit.
Come on.
All right.
Okay, one more time.
Here we go.
Keep your eye on the lady.
There she is.
Just keep your eyes on her.
All right?
Okay.
All right, make your bet.
Okay? Here?
All right? Fine.
All right. Everybody. Okay.
Do you miss mom?
She's your wife, you know.
Yeah, of course I miss her.
Your mother's an artist.
You know artists are inspired.
They must force
the rest of the world out of their lives.
The way I see it...
if Mom were so inspired
she'd be able to write at home.
There's too many distractions here.
Like us?
Yeah, like us.
I wouldn't want
to take it anywhere.
I wouldn't want to take it on the road
or anything like that.
It's kind of stable.
It stays in one spot.
It is a mobile home
but it doesn't move.
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
Home sweet home.
You...
were a natural.
You were great.
You were really something
out there, Carolyn. I mean it.
This is yours.
- No, no, no. No, I can't.
- You earned it.
- No, no, no, keep it, really.
- We were partners out there.
And I couldn't have done it
without you.
Come on, we were a team.
- Okay, thanks.
- The maid comes on Tuesday.
Oh, my gosh.
Walter, is that you?
The Amazing Abraham?
That's me in the Catskills
back in the day.
I did two shows a night,
seven nights a week.
I packed them in
with five hundred people in a show.
I came this close
to being a big star.
- What happened?
- Magic changed.
I'm a slight of hand guy.
Everybody wanted bigger.
They wanted elephants disappearing.
- I don't make elephants disappear.
- That's good!
Thank you.
- That's really good.
- Yeah, I don't think that's magic but...
the Amazing Abraham's day
will come again.
The amazing Abraham's time
will come.
It's hardware store,
you know.
That thing gave me a rash
last time.
Stay cool.
You start getting nervy...
just think of a beach in Hawaii
and a pretty brown woman.
I can do that.
You do this right Augie,
you're off the hook.
Why the sudden change of heart?
Well, I thought it over, Victor.
Retire in a few years,
that sounds awfully good, man.
Besides, Murph wants out,
so I'm going to play ball with you.
Well, that's wonderful news,
Augie.
I knew you'd come around.
You're a very smart man.
Victor, I need to know
what you have in mind.
I need details...
about what
I'm getting myself into here.
Of course.
Let's talk in the steam room.
It'll do wonders for your health.
Okay, guys.
This thing's about to get a bath.
You and I, we work together.
We carve out a business.
Ivan's not involved.
He'll kill us.
He never needs to know.
A year together, the two of us...
you'll be a millionaire.
That's an attractive offer.
Did you whack Wing Loh?
I'd understand if you did.
I mean, me and Murph
we couldn't stand the guy.
You did, right?
Somebody had to do it.
Got you, motherfucker.
- Okay, I'm ready. Say something.
- What?
Introduce me.
Introduce you.
What do you want me to say?
You're the writer.
Ladies and gentlemen...
let's give a warm welcome
to this next performer.
The one...
the only...
the mystical, the magical...
The Amazing...
Abraham!
Carolyn...
my captive audience.
Ready for a shower of cards?
Hearts for you.
A heart, yes.
There you are, my dear.
I love it!
Pan of fire.
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com