Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
(children yelling in distance)
(horn honking)
(boy) I got you, boy!
(boy) Ahh! Ahh?
Man, you ain't got shit!
What?
Ahh, ahh! Fine, fine, mercy!
Told you I had you, nigga.
Whatever, I'm going home.
(baby crying)
(dog barking)
May I please get a purple juice?
Thank you.
(siren blaring)
Hey, Babo, do you like my hair?
It looks like a poodle.
Does my hair look like a poodle?
# Yeah #
# All right #
# I see you working my melody #
# The way it should be, yeah #
# How they make it look #
# On TV #
# I see you working my melody #
# The way it should be, yeah #
# How they make it look #
# On TV #
# Yeah #
# I see you working my melody #
# The way it should be, yeah #
# How they make it look #
# On TV #
# Yeah #
# The way should be, yeah ##
(boy) So Peanut Chews
ain't got milk in 'em?
(boy) Nah, they're nondairy.
What other vegan shit you be eating?
Everything you eat, man.
Man, I don't know, I
had some soy cheese once
and it was nasty.
You gotta get the right brand.
What brand? Tofutti.
Tofutti?
Okay.
So you've noticed
that your body's gotten
more ripped, right?
Yeah, you can see it more.
Meat stays in your body a long time.
It takes like, um...
it takes about, uh,
three days to digest.
Really? Yeah, for sure.
Damn.
(panting)
(inhaling)
(cell phone vibrating)
Hello.
(boy) Hey, it's Jay, I'm out front.
Okay, I'll be right out.
Hi, I'm Sarah.
Hi.
And you remember Jen, right?
All right, so I got three kinds.
Um, this is blueberry, AK,
and I've got quarters and mids for 75.
This is blueberry? Mm-hmm.
Can I open it?
They're 50, right? Yep.
So what do you wanna get?
I don't care, you can just pick.
Well, we're getting two, right?
Yeah, I'm gonna give you ten,
'cause I just wanna
smoke a bowl before work.
Okay, so one of each?
Okay.
So one blueberry and one AK.
You wanna pick them out?
No, I better not.
Um, I'd say these are
gonna be really good.
Thank you.
You guys mind if I use your bathroom?
Oh, no, it's up the stairs to the right.
Thanks.
Voila.
(bong bubbling)
(coughing)
That smells nice.
Is that the blueberry?
No, it's the AK.
You want a hit?
Ah, no thanks.
(Sarah) Oh, my God, that got me so high.
I'm so high right now.
I have to work in like 15 minutes.
Where do you work?
15th and Arch, it's a law firm.
And I have to be there in 15 minutes,
and I'm so high.
Fuck.
Okay, water.
(woman) This is really good pot.
Yes, it is.
So, okay, I'm out of here.
Um... I'll call you.
And depending on what time,
I guess we'll either
get something to eat
or just I'll meet you at the party.
(woman) Okay, bye.
Oh, bye.
Bye. Bye.
So it's my friend's birthday
and she's having this huge house party.
You should totally come.
Cool, okay.
Okay.
(rock music blaring)
Hey.
I love your beard.
Happy birthday.
(rock music blaring)
Hey.
(man) Don't fall in love.
Love is not really love.
It's just wanting pussy.
Don't stay with just one girl
for too long, you'll go stale.
Live a big life.
Make that money.
You fuck as many girls as you can, okay?
Can we get some more ice?
Yeah, get me a lemon.
Let me get a lemon and blue raspberry.
You wanna kiss me tomorrow?
What?
I said, "Do you wanna kiss me tomorrow?"
(clearing throat)
It's $3.
Let me get a five?
I'll get your soda.
I'll get her soda.
Okay, $4.
You like fish?
Yeah.
20 fish.
$5.
It's all you.
(bells jingling)
So many people have died.
It's fucked up.
And young kids too,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
You know, my boy is out there.
He's a sergeant.
You gotta train through
all that chemical stuff.
You still talk to him?
No.
You look so hot right now.
Shut up.
(laughing)
Are you hungry?
A little bit.
Okay, I'll be right back.
I love these.
They're organic.
No, thanks.
That's a nice painting.
Thanks.
Did you paint it? Mm-hmm.
Do you know...
"Going on A Treasure Hunt"?
Yeah.
My mom used to do that
to me when I was little.
Do it to me.
Sure.
# Going on a treasure hunt #
# "X" marks the spot #
# Dash, dash, dash #
# And a dot, dot, dot... ##
(truck beeping)
Man, I don't think I'm
ever gonna get to 150.
30 pounds was pretty ambitious.
I know.
I wanna go away for like a month.
I know what you mean.
Like Costa Rica,
go to the top of the
volcano and shit like that.
Yeah.
When I get my biceps
a little bit bigger,
I'll finally be able to relax.
I just wanna relax, man.
I feel too much pressure.
Pressure to what?
Gotta hold shit down.
My dad wants me to work in his store.
If he can open one.
That could be cool.
I know, but I don't wanna work.
I want to go to New Zealand
for the World's Strong Man competition
and win that whole shit.
You could do it.
And I could be your trainer.
Yeah.
(boy) What size you wear?
(Babo) Huh?
You heard me.
What size do you wear?
Four.
Four?
You a little girl?
No.
Wrong answer.
What's up?
Sorry I'm late.
How much candy did
you have to eat today?
None.
No. None?
All I had was one soda.
Look, I don't care if
you had one soda, man,
just stop acting like
you don't know what's up.
Sorry.
Look, man, I know you think
I'm going to hard on you,
but if you wanna make
it like you tell me,
it takes discipline, man.
All the time.
Not some of the time, Heslin.
And what did we say that discipline
starts with your what? My body.
That's right, your body.
Wash some of those greens off, man.
Make yourself a smoothie.
'Cause if you learned anything,
you know your body's mad
acidic right now from that soda.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Quit with that sorry shit, too, man.
Just get on your game.
All right.
Where's the greens?
Bottom right.
I don't see 'em.
Hey, sweetie.
Hey, Mom.
Hey, babe, you... have
you seen the greens?
Yeah, I ate them.
Great.
I made a salad when you
were in the basement.
Have one of those coconuts.
I'll cut it for you... this time.
Hey, you.
Hey, sweetie.
Stop it.
Emotionally right now, I feel crazy.
It's like I don't wanna do anything,
but I wanna do everything.
My mind goes nonstop and I just...
Uh-huh. I just shut down.
I'm trying to stay present,
you know what I mean?
Like just here, right
now, in this moment.
And not obsessing about the future,
"is it gonna happen,
is it not gonna happen?"
I hear that.
It's hard with Heslin.
And the crazy thing is, I know.
I see that he's thinking
about and dealing with girls.
And in our space, you know,
he doesn't have much privacy.
We don't have any privacy.
How's business?
It's all right, you know.
Kaleef is working hard.
You know how it is.
All right, so business is all right
and you live with an adolescent.
Yeah, in a nutshell.
(laughing)
Well, you're the nut.
Yes, I am the nut.
Speaking of nuts, Brian's crazy.
He wants to be a producer
all of the sudden.
Girl, he's making beats
and I gotta tell you,
they are atrocious.
Oh, no.
I'm lying my ass off all the time.
Telling him that I like them, you know?
'Cause I don't wanna hurt his feelings.
But the thing is, now he's
playing them all the time.
Kaleef started doing this weird thing
where he wants us to sleep
with our butts touching.
Wait a minute, Kaleef?
Your butts touching?
Yes!
Okay, now I've heard it all.
Now...
Deep breath.
(exhaling)
I love you.
(woman) Hey, Bo.
Mmm...
I love these, oh.
Hey, Mom, question.
What?
You got like $100 I can borrow?
No.
Neither do I.
Tough guy, wise guy.
What do you think I am, huh?
What you think this is made out of, huh?
Let me see, put those
dukes up, all right?
$100 prize.
$100 prize!
(bell dinging)
I'll do anything.
There must be some work you need done.
(man) Come in.
(dogs barking)
(girl) Babo!
What are you doing?
Shopping.
You smell that?
Nah.
Anyway, I'm gonna invite
you to my birthday party
tonight at Angel Hall.
Lots of people are coming.
It's gonna be fun.
Oh, okay, that's cool.
Just make sure you take a shower.
(bells jingling)
(TV blaring)
(siren blaring)
Hey, Ma, what's up?
What?
I said, what's up?
What's up?
You smell that?
That you?
Nah.
I was wondering if you
wanna kick it later?
Listen, do you wanna hang later?
I'm busy.
You're busy?
Yeah, I'm busy.
Look, I like smart boys.
You're saying I ain't smart?
I'm smart.
(woman) Hi, come to
our march, October 7th.
Come to the march.
October 7th, come to our march.
Take this please, thank you!
Hi, show this to your mom.
Come to our march.
(rock music blaring)
Hey...
I wanna get married
and have babies.
I wanna marry you.
I wanna cook... our house.
I wanna cook in our house.
I wanna get you a studio
so you can follow your dreams.
I want you to follow your dreams
and paint.
...and trees.
I saw it, I saw it.
I saw it.
Our future.
It's so good.
It just is so good.
I know, baby.
Fuck you.
Fuck me.
Fuck me... fuck you.
How can you treat me like this?
I'm gonna leave.
(man) Hello, good evening.
What would you two like?
I'll have the aloo gobi, please.
No ghee, please.
Um, I'll have the
saag paneer, thank you.
Anything to drink?
I'll have a Coke.
I'll have the house red.
I'm sorry, no alcohol.
(laughing)
Um... I'll have a ginger ale.
Okay.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
I thought you were leaving?
Fuck you!
(doorbell ringing)
Hola.
Come.
Come, come in.
Can I get you anything to drink?
Nah, I'm good.
Are you sure?
I got some really good red wine.
Okay, I'll have one glass.
Okay.
I'll be right back.
(woman) Here we are.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Cheers. Cheers.
(laughing)
Oh... okay.
Fuck, this is weird.
It's not weird.
This is what I do.
I deal with this on a daily basis.
So... and...
I covered all the instructions here,
so it's not like we
have to get anything now.
No, it's just embarrassing, you know?
What's so embarrassing?
I mean, everybody poops, Kelly.
Oh, oh, mmm, let me see this.
"Kaleef's Colon Cleanse."
Well, that's catchy.
I wonder how you came up with that one.
Ha-ha-ha.
And here's that, uh,
business proposal I
was talking you about.
That was quick.
That's how I operate.
Grab it, grab it.
(clanking)
(huffing)
Yo, man, you okay?
Yeah, I'm all right.
You want a protein shake?
Okay.
Fuck.
(laughing)
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
So your daddy's gonna give
you a "G," just like that?
Yeah, I ask.
I receive.
What's mommy do?
She's dead.
Mine too.
Oh...
(laughing)
No, it's not funny.
It's not funny.
Sorry.
How'd she die?
Cancer.
Me too.
Ovarian?
Cervical.
Oh...
(reggae playing)
Ahh!
I'm telling you, I'm real!
Then climb up that wall.
No!
Not right now.
You ain't real.
You must believe, son.
Now I must go.
# Try and change #
# Your perspective #
# And you might find #
# You're perfected #
# Just try and change #
# Your perspective #
# And you might find #
# You're perfected #
# Perfected #
# Perfected ##
(Babo) You shouldn't smoke.
Yes, you are right.
But see...
at this current moment,
getting a little closer
to death is a good thing.
You're depressed?
You want a piece of gum instead?
Sure.
Thanks.
I'm depressed too.
Oh, yeah?
What have you got to be depressed about?
The world.
I was reading this thing earlier
and it talked about all the poor people
in this country.
And it got me thinking
how poor my family is
and I got depressed.
Yeah, that's depressing.
You an actor?
Yeah, how'd you know?
'Cause you were playing a ninja.
Well...
yeah, but I just do this to...
for the money.
You wanna be making movies?
Yeah, yeah, and doing plays.
That's cool.
So what's your deal?
I'm just here 'cause a girl invited me.
Uh-huh.
You like her?
She's all right.
How old are you?
Seven.
You play chess?
I played like once.
You remember how to move the pieces?
Yeah, kind of.
Wanna play right now?
Sure.
White goes first, right?
Yep.
You wanna be white?
No, I'll be black instead.
Heslin?
Yeah, Mom?
Come here, I wanna talk
to you for a second.
Is there any way you
could come over here?
'Cause I'm about to
finish this final level.
Young man, you better just pause it.
Mom, please.
Okay.
Pause it.
Now, you know you can talk
to me about anything, right?
Uh-huh.
So... anything you wanna say to me?
No.
Hmm.
Well...
I know you've been through my stuff.
Oh.
Yeah.
So...
do you smoke weed?
Or does dad?
I do.
Sweetie, this is a complex issue.
It opens me up and it...
it helps me creatively.
It helps me...
connect to my high powers,
part of my spiritual practice.
But that doesn't mean you
can experiment right now.
You're too young.
You need to learn how to be creative
and how to find your higher power
and how to be yourself on your own.
With nothing.
I don't get high all the time.
And, well, for me...
it's like going to church.
Mom, I ain't trying to smoke weed.
So don't worry.
Good.
No, no, no, no, no.
We're not done yet.
So you having sex yet?
It's okay if you have or you haven't.
It's fine.
I know.
Actually, umm...
it's none of your business.
Okay, all right.
No, you're right, it's personal.
But as your mother, I have to tell you.
No matter what, Heslin,
always wear a condom, okay?
Mom, I know.
Please.
Oh, you're a good boy.
You must have great parents.
(video game blaring)
Yep. You all set?
Morning.
You wear glasses?
Oh, usually I just wear my contacts.
What books you reading?
Oh, "Flowers From the
Storm" by Laura Kinsale.
What's it about?
Oh, actually, I just started reading it.
Do you have a lot of No. Homework?
Well, if you ever need a
study buddy, I'm around.
(Kaleef) It's a movie.
Five words. Five words.
(laughing)
I don't know.
What is she doing?
I got it, it's "Willow."
(laughing)
What?
What's "Willow"? Come on, guys.
It's "Charlie and the
Chocolate Factory."
I'm like an Oompa-Loompa.
(man) Pops, I love you.
I think about you every day.
I miss you.
I need you.
I need your energy.
I need to be blessed.
Now things are hard.
I'm not where I'm supposed to be.
I'm 25 now.
And...
I feel like I should be holding it down.
Acting's tough.
Y'know, it's wearing on me.
It's... my thinking.
I'm getting nervous that it's slipping.
All the time.
And... I don't know what to do.
I mean, she's a'ight.
Her face is a little chubby, though.
Can I talk to you for a second?
You wanna talk to me?
Yeah.
I told the guy at the
store what I thought
your height and weight was.
And he guessed you were a nine.
So that's what I got.
But you can return them.
You got these for me?
Yeah.
Nine's my size.
Well, there you go.
(no sound)
(buzzer ringing)
Sit down.
Or I blow your head to smithereens.
Fuck.
Give me your bag.
Empty your pockets.
(moaning)
(gun cocking)
(trigger clicking)
(grunting)
(woman) And now to close practice,
please join me in a deep-cleansing om.
(all) Om...
Namaste.
(all) Namaste.
And now lay back on your
mats and rest in Savasana.
What?
(whispering) I got the
money for the store.
It's all yours.
Are you serious?
Thank you!
Thank you, thank you, thank
you, thank you, thank you!
(gagging)
Ahh!
Ahh! Ahh!
Rocco takes the rook!
And now you're shook.
Gonna try to book away
because I'm one check away.
(laughing)
Don't need to spaz out.
I mean, it was a pretty
sick freestyle, but...
(wheezing)
Whoa, hey, Babo, you okay?
Oh, my God.
Babo, you having an asthma attack?
Hey, somebody help!
Somebody!
Hey, Babo, just breathe
for me, buddy, just breathe.
I'm gonna get you some help.
Hey, somebody help, please!
Please, somebody help
me! Call an ambulance!
Hey, hey, Babo, just
breathe, buddy, okay?
I'm gonna get us an ambulance, okay,
and then I'm gonna call your mom
and we're gonna get
your mom out here, okay?
And we're gonna get her over here
and we're gonna get some help.
Okay, I'm going to put you down, okay?
Now I just need you to breathe for me.
Hello, hello?
Can I get an ambulance, please,
to 23rd and Pine Street?!
Yeah, I've got a
seven-year-old kid here
who's having an asthma attack.
Hey, Babo, buddy, just
breathe for me, okay?
Just breathe... hey, look at
me, look at me, look at me.
Hey, just breathe, okay,
we're gonna get your mom here
and she's gonna take care of everything.
Yes, please hurry.
There used to be an
old brewery over there.
Me and my boys would
go there all the time.
It was crazy.
Saw a ghost in there once, too.
For real?
Yeah.
You believe in ghosts?
I saw my grandma's
ghost at my dad's house.
Really?
What'd you see?
Well...
I was laying on the
couch in the living room,
watching TV,
and out of the corner of my eye,
I saw something moving
real slow down the steps.
So... I mute the TV
and turn and look.
It's my grandma.
And I just... freeze up.
She smiles at me and then disappears.
Were you scared?
It was too quick,
but after... yeah.
I didn't know what to do.
No one believes me.
I believe you.
(woman on PA) Dr.
Forest, dial 118, please.
Dr. Forest,
please dial 1-1-8.
Just don't let me fall asleep.
(laughing)
No, he's fine, he's fine.
Thank God.
Gentrification's what it's called.
Basically means they kick
out all the poor people,
tear down their homes, build
million-dollar buildings
so that they can get rich
people to live in them.
Then they make millions.
That's why this place is so fancy.
That's messed up.
Yeah.
I hate yuppies.
Then why did you bring us here?
It's good pizza.
Well, I think you shouldn't hate anyone,
no matter what they do.
Yeah, I agree.
You're funny.
What?
The way you talk.
Do you have insurance?
No.
It's going to be $52.67 then.
$52?
Yes, ma'am.
That's insane.
Look...
Iook, I don't have that kind
of money on me right now.
Is there anyway that I
could get the medicine
for what it would be if I had insurance?
And then, I swear to God,
tomorrow I will pay you the rest.
Look, ma'am, if it were up to me,
I would, but I just can't do that.
It's against the policy.
You can.
Look, my son just got
out of the emergency room.
He really needs his medicine tonight.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
Like I said, there's nothing I can do.
This is fucking crazy.
I'm sorry, can I just talk
to your manager, please?
I am the manager.
Look, ma'am, could you step aside
so I can help this customer?
This is bullshit!
Okay, customer?
Yeah, 'cause that's what we
are, we're customers, right?
We're not sick people, we're customers.
Look, ma'am, you're
gonna have to calm down.
You know what, you need
to stop calling me "ma'am,"
first of all like you fucking give
a shit. Escorted out. Ave to have you
And don't tell me to calm down.
Mommy, let's just go home, okay?
Okay, come on.
Let's go.
I promise you, I'm fine.
I'm sorry.
Okay, I'll take you home, okay.
That's a good boy.
Excuse me.
So what'd you tell them?
That I fell off my bike.
This is depressing.
Yeah.
But it's good for us as artists.
(laughing)
Yeah. So you wanna stop?
For how long?
Don't make me laugh.
For as long as possible.
I know.
Let's do it.
No nothing.
Promise?
I promise.
Pinkie swear?
Ooh...
(woman) Rah!
(Kaleef) You scared the
shit out of me, girl.
Good.
What's all this?
You know, I just made
a little dinner for us.
Where's Heslin?
At Tony's house.
Okay.
What's going on?
You just sit your ass down.
Yes, ma'am.
Okay, what is going on?
We got the money for the store.
What?
We got the money for the store, baby.
(laughing)
(woman) You're a lifesaver.
Okay, see you in the morning.
Bye.
Thank you.
How's your book?
It's good, but kinda sad so far.
Oh.
You really should eat something, honey.
So Rocco says he's gonna
come by tomorrow and hang out.
Yeah. Really?
I got to get up really
early in the morning
and handle a few things.
You know I'm going to
make you a million dollars
by the time I'm 15, right?
Yeah, I know.
Eat.
I'm gonna go to sleep.
Okay.
Good night, my angel.
Good night.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I should go.
It's getting late and
I'm gonna get in trouble.
Okay, I'll take the "L" with you.
(dog barking)
Okay, let's go.
Okay.
You're a really good kisser.
You could finish painting me blue.
(humming)
Babo.
Babo!
Come on, baby.
Come on, baby, breathe.
Why aren't you breathing?
Babo, Babo, Babo, okay, don't...
(sobbing)
I don't like this game!
Oh, my God, oh, my God!
Babo, Babo, Babo...
My baby.
My baby!
No!
(woman sobbing)
I wanna go home, I wanna go home...
I wanna take my baby home.
(crying)
Oh, my God!
(sobbing)
(boy) It's weird how one
minute we can be here,
and the next second... gone.
It's like a dream.
A bad dream.
It makes me wanna be
more careful in life.
Focus even more.
Pay attention to the details.
He was a good kid.
(bell dinging)
(boy) So what are you doing tomorrow?
(girl) Nothing really.
I have to do laundry with
my dad in the afternoon,
but that's it.
Well, do you still
wanna keep hanging out?
You mean tomorrow?
Nah, I mean...
for a while.
You wanna be my boyfriend?
I want you to be my girlfriend.
Okay.
Good.
He was so young.
Yeah.
You know... I hope we see his ghost.
Yeah, me too.
Would you...
rather be cremated or buried?
I think I would rather be...
buried, be in the earth.
See, I would be cremated
and sprinkled over the ocean.
Be with the earth that way, too.
She's gonna keep his ashes.
Yeah.
Do you wanna sit for a little bit?
So hot out.
You two just get married?
Yes.
(laughing)
Hey, you guys want me
to take your picture?
Sure.
All right.
This is nice.
Big smile.
(camera clicking)
There you go.
Thank you.
You're very welcome.
You two have a wonderful day!
You too.
It's nice.
Honeymoon?
Shut up.
Congratulations on the store, man.
Thanks a lot, Chris.
Produce for the people
and all that, y'know.
So what's next?
About three weeks of renovations.
That's it?
Yeah, yeah, well, the
place is already in
pretty good condition, so...
Cool.
I got big news, too.
Really? What?
The mother of that boy who died...
she's coming.
You're not gonna believe this,
but apparently her son who died
gave her a flier he'd gotten
just a few days beforehand.
Yeah.
Yo.
Let's do this, gentlemen.
I miss you.
I hope wherever you are, you're okay.
Thanks for coming to my party.
God bless you.
Amen.
(woman) No wait, don't come in.
I won't look.
Okay, fine.
Oh, shit, it's today.
What's today?
This.
We should go.
It would be good to get out
of our heads for a second.
Okay.
What time is it again?
It's 4:00.
Okay.
I'm done.
Can I look now?
Hold on.
Stand.
(man) They say cutback!
We say fight back!
They say cutback!
What do we want? Health care!
When do we want it? Now!
They say cutback!
We say fight back!
What do we want? Health care!
When do we want it? Now!
They say cutback!
We say fight back!
(all) Hey, hey! Ho, ho!
Poverty has got to go!
Hey, hey! Ho, ho!
# Try and change #
# Your perspective #
# And you might find #
# You're perfected #
# Just try and change #
# Your perspective #
# And you might find #
# You're perfected #
# Perfected #
# Perfected... #
(man) I'd just like to, uh...
end this...
with a moment of silence...
for our dear friend, Babo.
He passed away...
because he didn't have health care...
A moment of silence...
# Try and change #
# Your perspective #
# And you might find #
# You're perfected #
# Just try and change #
# Your perspective #
# And you might find #
# You're perfected #
# Perfected #
# You might find #
# You're perfected #
# Perfected #
# You might find #
# You're perfected #
# Perfected #
# Perfected ##
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com