Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Sometimes, loneliness can stalk a person
like a ghost, always reminding us
of what we had,
and what we lost and what
we can never have again.
It can take a person's hope,
hide it away somewhere,
where it can never be found.
That's... that's what loneliness can do.
Great.
Alyssa.
Yeah.
I'm going out tonight.
Order whatever you want, fries, sushi,
vampire blood.
Pizza boy's hot.
Not on the menu.
So who's the lucky guy tonight?
Buff Bill, Slim Jim?
Neither one.
Have fun, Grandma.
Do not call me that!
Do you smell that?
- Yeah.
- Again.
Alyssa, that's crazy.
So?
So, if you get caught
again, you're done.
Come on.
We've only got like, 30 seconds.
It's OK.
You guys go.
It's your funeral.
So, uh, Alyssa, you scored
in the 95th percentile
on the CAT 6, Science, and in
the 93rd percentile in English.
You are an excellent student when you're
actually attending classes.
But you know, until you make
up your mind to apply yourself,
you're really wasting everybody's time,
including your own.
Please, she's been through a lot.
Her mother passed away
less than a year ago.
She's never met her father.
Well, you know, the first time when
I heard all that, I was moved.
Uh, the second time, less moved.
Third time, I don't really care anymore.
So, anyway, there is a
packet here with a lot
of information in it.
And that's going to explain
your options to you.
It's only a suspension
until the expulsion hearing.
Maybe by then, Alyssa will
have, uh, decided to uh,
she's, uh... anyway, that's
really all I can do until then.
What?
You're really starting to creep me out.
How much did your mother
tell you about your father?
He was some guy she met
down in the Florida Keys.
You know, he's dead.
End of story.
That's him?
You mean, she had a picture
of him this entire time.
They were together for three years.
These letters are all from him.
She never opened them.
They came periodically, over the years.
- You mean he's not dead?
- Not technically.
You gotta be freaking kidding me.
Your mother was young and in love.
She wanted marriage and
children, and he didn't.
She never told him about you.
She thought it was better
to lie than to have
you wondering about a
father who wasn't there.
Alyssa, she's your mother, my daughter.
She did the best she could.
Why are you sticking up for her?
You knew the whole time too.
It wasn't my decision to make.
It was hers.
You know, uh, I think it's... it's time
you two were introduced.
Are you insane?
I can't do this alone anymore.
It's not fair to either one of us.
Not fair?
I just found out that I
have a father, and a mother
who lied to me my entire life.
Alyssa!
He studies dolphins in the Bahamas.
How bad can that be?
I hate dolphins.
Hey.
Hey!
Decker!
What are you doing here, Decker?
Get out!
Take your tourists with you.
Take it easy, man.
See how much fun they're having?
(INAUDIBLE) You don't own
these dolphins, you know.
Hey!
Has he told you what kind
of dolphins those are?
What?
Did he tell you those dolphins
are wild shark dolphins, ma'am?
- There's no such thing.
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah, you're completely safe.
Right.
Right. Don't
listen to him, yeah?
He just joking, man.
You know why they call
them shark dolphins?
Because they swim with the sharks.
Stop your crazy foolishness, man!
You can't see you're
scaring the tourists, man?
Hawk!
You son of a...
You just scared 10 tourists
off the island, nine of whom
called the Ministry of
Tourism to complain about you.
Yeah.
Well, that idiot Decker
was feeding wild dolphins.
He was letting tourists swim with them.
That screws with the
dolphins' heads, Coakley.
But you never said a thing
about cornering the market
on wild dolphins, James.
You have two dolphins.
Study them!
- Leave the tourists be.
- Yeah.
But mine are captive dolphins, Coakley.
Look, I've got to
study the wild dolphins
so I can compare their sonic
imaging data to the data
of the captive dolphins.
That way, when I put the two together,
I'm starting to get a clearer
picture of how they communicate
for the first time, right?
Look, Coakley, when I am done here,
I am going to put you and
your little island on the map.
There are three partners involved
in this venture, Hawker.
You, me, and the town
committee of Smith's Point.
- Two of the three aren't happy.
- Come on.
That's not fair.
You came here promising
jobs, media attention,
world-class scientists living here.
Now, three years later, all we've got
is you, your two dolphins,
and a set of financials data.
- Pathetic!
- Oh, come on.
Coakley, those are long-term goals.
Six months, man.
I just need six months.
I can give you 24 hours.
You're kidding, right?
Tomorrow, 3:00 PM.
The board will be there.
And you can make your case.
And it had better be brilliant.
It will be.
Trust me.
No.
This one?
All right, all right.
That one.
You win again.
Hawk!
How come I can beat you,
but I can't beat Bogie?
- That's cause I let you win.
- You're crazy.
You don't let me win.
You don't let anybody win.
Yeah, especially that Coakley.
OK.
Here we go.
This is set.
Come on.
You've got to do this before
your taxi shift starts.
OK.
You sure?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You sure it's recording?
Man, relax.
I have it, right?
- I'm relaxed.
- OK.
Spread out!
OK?
Ok.
October 22, echolocation
communication protocol cc 1-2.
I've placed the target
object in the box here.
Neither dolphin has seen
the contents of the box.
Bacall is isolated in
the far pen, pen two.
And Bogie is in the near
pen, the pen with the box.
Bogie is going to come across and check
out the target object.
Bacall is in pen two.
Here is Bogie.
Bogie is checking out with his
echolocation what's in the box.
I'll communicate to
Bacall, who is in pen two.
And Bacall has selected a match.
Now, let's see what's in the box.
Perfect!
All right!
Oh!
Think that will be enough?
Yeah.
It demonstrates the principle, and it's
got a pretty girl in it.
They're gonna love it.
What do you think?
Good work, guys.
All that because of
Hurricane Jean last month.
Boy, she was mean.
You know, people say God is angry at us.
But let me tell you, God
don't put nothing more
on you than you can bear.
How much farther is it to Smith's Point?
Oh, just about 20 minutes
up the road, ma'am.
But it's going to be busy.
Tonight's Fish Fry Night.
Fish Fry Night?
What's that?
Well, it started as a
fundraiser after the hurricane.
Every Wednesday, the (INAUDIBLE)
has this Fish Fry Night.
They're gonna spin the potato.
We fry it, toast it.
Ever had corn fritters, child?
No.
Well, you don't know
what you've been missing.
Um, do you happen to
know a James Harker?
James Harker, I do not know.
But Hawk Hawker... well,
that's another story.
Everybody knows him.
Sure to be at a fish fry tonight.
Everybody goes to fish... everybody
- comes to the fish fry.
- Oh.
All right.
Uh, let us out here.
All right, ma'am.
Thank you very much.
Yes, sir.
God, let's just find a
hotel, hop in a jacuzzi,
and just grab a couple of mai tais.
Wait here.
Ok.
I'll bring all the bags.
And then I'm going to go
and get myself some fish.
Ha, ha, ha.
You should try it, you know.
It's nice.
Cornelia!
(INAUDIBLE) here, please.
Thank you.
All for one and none for me.
Let's hear it for the turistos!
So glad they could make it
to our little island, huh?
He's just giving off some steam.
Nothing to worry about, OK?
Hey, guys.
How are you?
Ok?
Good.
Having a good time?
- Having a good time?
- Yeah.
Cornelia, how do I look?
Eh, Cornelia?
Sayonara, guys.
Sayonara.
Take care.
James?
Lucy?
It's been quite a long time.
Yeah.
Th... there's someone
I'd like you to meet.
I'd like to introduce you
to my granddaughter, Alyssa.
Hi, Alyssa.
You two really look quite a bit alike.
The... the truth...
Are you saying that I have a
dau... well, how'd that happen?
It's called sex, dad.
Excuse me a second.
Well, that went well.
You really are his daughter.
Is it too late to deny it?
I'm Tamika.
You should stay with us tonight.
We can talk about this tomorrow
when he's more presentable.
Thank you.
We should go.
It's a start.
Tami.
Tami, Tami.
I had the craziest dream last night.
I dreamt I had a daughter.
OK Come on.
Come on.
You're OK.
Come on, guys
Let's go.
Come on.
What were you doing in here?
I was just changing
the music on my iPod,
and one of the dolphins just
jumped up and grabbed it.
They're trained to
react to hand movements.
Yeah, well, how the heck
am I supposed to know that?
And where's my iPod?
Ok.
So, uh, your little jukebox here is DOA.
Moron, naked moron.
Oh, god.
Definitely not a dream.
No, definitely not.
Yeah, well, we're fresh out of soy.
Black OK?
Black's fine, James.
Thank you.
I saw Alyssa outside.
What happened?
Yeah, well, before we'd,
uh, discuss the young lady,
there's something I would
like to talk to you about.
By all means.
Ok.
For the record, I did not
walk out on your daughter.
And I did not know about any kid.
Ok?
She left me.
I just want that on the
table, just to start, OK?
She died, actually,
in a boating accident,
off all things.
She drowned.
Alyssa was there, saw the whole thing.
Oh, I... I didn't know.
I, uh, uh, I'm sorry, Lucy.
I... I really am.
...Alyssa's been
suspended from school.
She has a lot of problems.
I came here hoping that
maybe you could help her.
How could I help?
She's your daughter.
You... you would need to
find her a good school.
Whoa, Lucy.
You can't just sail in
here after all these years
and dump some screwed-up,
14-year-old girl
on my doorstep.
I've done all that I can.
She needs a parent.
She's an amazing girl, James,
when you get to know her.
Yeah.
Great.
Hello, Missy.
How are you doing?
You don't seem to be having
much of a day, do you?
No.
How's my breakfast?
I want to show you something.
You just sit there and wait awhile.
Look at this.
See?
Just... just... hold it.
It's coming out!
Yeah, it's all right.
It's OK.
Hold it.
Just blow on it hard
enough to tickle him.
If you blow too hard, you're
gonna scare him (INAUDIBLE).
Now, you see, he's singing to you.
Listen.
Listen to him.
He's singing to you.
Yes.
All right.
Put it... put it to your ear.
He wants to sing to you.
Good morning.
Oh, my god!
- Sorry, I'm sorry.
- Oh!
- Oh, my god!
- No, no, no.
It's OK.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Ow!
Ah.
I'm sorry.
I see you've met my father.
I'm sorry, love.
You're gonna put some uh,
some spray (INAUDIBLE), OK?
So see you... see you in a minute.
You want me to look at that for you?
It's fine.
I'm not going to touch it!
I just want to look!
We need some alcohol
before this gets infected.
Yeah, yeah.
You know.
Here you go.
It's only a scratch.
She's gonna be fine.
Thank you.
- I can do this.
- OK.
You know, so far, this
place has been a real riot.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry about the dolphins
stealing your little jukebox.
It's called an iPod.
You know, if it was me, I
would've thought it was funny.
Yeah, well, you didn't have
to babysit for a whole year
to get one.
So, I hear you're my daughter.
I'm sorry.
Let's try that again.
Let's not.
Good idea.
Are we going to have
to call an ambulance?
Oh, no.
She's going to be fine.
I believe you two have met.
Yeah.
Tammi's, um...
Tammi's my...
Roommate with benefits?
Something like that.
What?
So, are you sure?
About what?
About Alyssa, that she's the only one?
Oh, very funny, very funny.
Look, Tammi...
No matter how many times
you said you didn't want any,
I always wondered if
one day, we'd have kids.
I just didn't realize if we
did, she'd be half my age.
Tammi, this is not something
I planned or expected.
All I'm saying is, now that she's here,
you're always going to
have another day to work,
but you've only got one
daughter and one me.
Just think about that.
- So, how do I look?
- Great.
That good, huh?
OK, let's go get em!
Ugh.
Fish heads?
You mean, you actually cook
those things with their heads
on?
How you going to cook
fish without a head?
Hmm?
Come on, darling.
Have a bite.
- Come on.
- Oh, no thanks.
Hey.
Why don't you and Missy go
and get an old man a conch
for supper tonight, hmm?
I heard they're just laying
there, waiting to be taken.
Well, that's what I heard.
You remember what your mother said?
Follow your heart.
Mmm?
Alyssa.
Yeah.
I'm going for a walk.
You wanna come?
Uh, no, I'm good.
I'll see you in a while then.
Hi.
Hey.
I'm going conching
up at William's Point.
Want to come?
What's conching?
How about I show you?
We can stay, finish
that cigarette first.
My mother used to bring
me here when I was little.
She loved it here.
She liked to watch the tide
coming in over the (INAUDIBLE).
Here.
Hold this.
Ew.
What is it, like a giant snail?
Exactly.
I saw another one out there.
Got it!
Come in.
The water's nice.
I didn't pack a swim suit.
You came to the Bahamas, and
you didn't pack a swimsuit?
- You know who to swim, don't you?
- Yeah.
I mean, I can swim, but...
That's OK.
I'll do the swimming.
You be the conch sitter.
A dolphin!
I just saw a dolphin!
It just jumped out of
the water right there.
I've never known a dolphin
to come this far in before.
Well, I didn't make it up.
He just jumped out of the
water and looked at me.
Well, maybe they're just
checking out the new girl.
We should go.
We've got a stop to
make on the way home.
The experiment establishes
that dolphins can communicate
complex, three-dimensional images
to each other via their sonar.
90% of the sounds they
make are at frequencies
that we can't even hear.
Think about the implications of this.
It's as if I could email you
a digital image of this cup
without the use of a computer.
Think about it.
We've been looking for words.
Dolphin words?
Forget about words.
Who needs words when you can
paint images with sounds.
It's a totally alternative
way of communication,
just as complex, maybe even
more complex than our own system
of language.
It's a theory, unproven.
Well, if it were proven, we wouldn't
need to test it, right?
Well, for starters, this isn't
even a double-blind trial.
You knew what was in that box.
Now how do we know that you didn't
unconsciously cue the animal?
You remember Clever
Hans, the counting horse?
I mean, you have heard of Clever Hans.
Yeah, yeah, I remember him.
I did not cue the dolphin.
Who the hell is she?
I'm sure you've heard
of Elizabeth Glinton.
She's worked in senior position...
Oh, yes.
I know who she is.
"The dolphin's brain more
closely resembles that
of a hedgehog than a human."
That's a direct quote, I believe.
It's from one of her articles.
You got something against hedgehogs?
I have something against
the comparison, and you.
Oh, my.
What's she doing here anyway?
I'm here as a consultant.
Consulting about what?
The feasibility of expanding
your little facility here
to something more economically viable,
to attract, to entertain.
Tourists?
You can't do that!
That's going to ruin my research!
Well, James, there's always been
an economic imperative here.
I don't think Coakley has
kept that a secret from you.
So why don't you work with me?
I'm sure we can come up with
a way to generate some income
and produce those jobs that
you promised and haven't
been able to deliver.
Will you excuse me?
Here you go, kid.
Maybe your mom can show
you how to use this thing.
Hey, Hawker!
What?
I just wanted to let you know that um,
I'm willing to play nice if you are.
What in the hell does that mean?
It means I won't trash
your research if you don't
trash what I'm trying to do.
No, thanks.
Oh, come on now.
You've had your shot.
Let me have mine.
The hell I will.
Come on, lady.
- I'll give you a hand.
- Thank you.
Need directions to the airport?
No, actually.
Looks like I'm gonna be here for awhile.
Sayonara.
Thank you.
Ooh.
It's a biggie.
No thanks.
You take it.
This is called (INAUDIBLE).
They say (INAUDIBLE).
All the days of your life, you know.
And this does keep an old
mind young and strong,
imagine what it'll do for
me. Mmm, mmm, mmm.
Hmm, I saw this young
lady at the fish fry.
Uh, this is Alyssa, Hawk's daughter.
I wasn't aware our man
Hawk had a daughter.
Yeah, well, neither was he.
Hmm.
Yeah, well, child, you is special.
Because you know, it ain't right
for a man his age to be running
around without any children, especially
when he have a young lady like
Tami here to keep his bed warm.
You is a blessing.
I see you've been talking to my daddy.
Child, you know us too well.
You?
Well, what you waiting for?
All right.
Now she's a real conchy Joe!
What's a conchy Joe?
It's a white person who is from here
or has been here a long
time, like your dad.
Even if you're a girl?
Well, in your case, we
could make you a conchy Jane.
Jane?
Come on.
Eat up.
I want to introduce you to someone.
Be careful.
Yummy!
Are all these from the
hurricane last month?
Last month and the one before.
Seems crazy to live here.
Does it?
Well, you guys have earthquakes
and three-way shootings.
I reckon every place has got something.
Come on.
I want to show you the
town where I grew up.
Hey.
Hey, dear.
Hi.
So, um, this is Smith's Point.
I grew up here.
Hey, (INAUDIBLE).
- There we are.
- Thanks.
All right then, lady.
Hey, mama.
Brought you some fresh flowers.
Just been to our favorite place.
Sure was nice there.
Water was clear and warm,
just like it used to be.
Oh, and let me introduce you to someone.
This is Alyssa.
I think you'd like her even
if she is a little pale.
Has she been gone a long time?
Since I was 10.
My dad sent me to live in England.
I came back.
I missed home.
My mom was a swimmer.
I mean, every day, ever since
I could remember, she'd swim.
In the pool, in the ocean.
I used to go with her.
Said I swim like a fish.
How could someone like that drown?
I don't know.
They know that they aren't
the only children now,
making them nervous.
They want to be wanted.
They're fine.
Yeah.
What about you, hmm?
I'm fine.
All right, honey.
What?
I just wanted to see
what you do down here.
Yeah, well, I work.
I work.
- Well, that's it?
- Yeah.
I listen.
I listen, and they talk.
- How?
- OK.
Wow.
- That's really cool.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it's cool.
OK, that's it.
You don't want me here, do you?
Yeah, well, I'm kinda busy right now.
There's lots going on.
No.
I mean, you don't want me here with you.
Look.
Can... can we talk about this later?
No.
We can't.
Well, what do you want me to say?
I'm getting used to it, OK?
Actually, actually, it's not bad.
Ok.
I read the letters you wrote to mom.
Those letters weren't yours to read.
Do you have any idea
what a crappy father
you're turning out to be?
Just give it a little time.
Just give it some attention.
I am giving it attention.
Not half as much as your work.
You seem to think this is easy.
It's not!
Yeah, well most fathers figure it out.
Yeah, well, I am not most fathers!
OK?
I'm not.
Look, I cannot be
someone else in 48 hours.
Cause you at least have
had a little practice
at being a daughter!
You know, losing Mom was bad enough.
Finding out my consolation
prize is you is proof
positive that God hates me.
Wait.
What are you looking at?
Hey?
Alyssa!
She's gone.
Come on.
It's all right.
Come here.
Fine.
Go ahead and leave me
like everybody else!
Alyssa!
Is that you, girl?
Alyssa?
Oh, man.
You got her?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, my god.
Look at this kid, Danny.
Here.
Hold this.
OK, honey.
Easy now.
Easy.
Come on, baby.
Take it easy.
Yeah.
- Easy there, kid.
- Watch her head.
- You got her?
- I got her.
Yeah, I got her.
Thanks, Danny.
Well, I'd say you look
about as bad as I feel.
But I'm not sure whether
that would make you any more
- receptive to an apology.
- Go away.
Look, I, uh... the thing is
I... fact is, you're right.
I'm rude.
I'm stubborn.
- ...and selfish.
- That too.
Alyssa, I'm sorry.
I really am.
Look, your mother was
smart enough to realize
what a lousy dad I'd be.
And maybe she was right.
But I loved her, Alyssa.
I loved her a lot.
And, uh, I want to love you too.
I just don't know how to yet.
Do you have any idea how
big of a jerk you are?
Huh.
Yeah.
Good.
Here.
Put one of those on.
It's about time you start
earning your keep around here.
Come in.
You're going to help
me walk the dolphins.
Walk the dolphins?
Come on, guys.
That's as far as we go.
Why don't they just swim away?
Well, this is home.
They're used to living with us.
They're not wild anymore.
We're their family now.
They're really smart, aren't they?
Right.
And I would contest that
these animals are at least
as smart as any other human
on the planet... Coakley,
for example.
Principal McGowan.
Elizabeth Glinton.
Trevor Mason.
Who's Trevor Mason?
Nobody important.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, I get it.
You pretend to hate him,
but you really like him.
That's how women work, isn't it?
No.
Oh yes, it is.
Hey, guys.
Come on. Come on.
Let me show you something.
Hi, Dan-o.
Hey.
Here we go.
- Coakley called.
- Yeah?
Said he wants to see right away.
Well, isn't that sweet of him?
He must miss me.
Well, you can tell him
he can take a hike.
I'm hanging with my daughter.
He said if you don't
come, he's giving you 72
hours to vacate the premises.
What?
That's without Bogey and Bacall.
But he can't do that.
I think you better call your attorney.
No, no, no, no.
We don't need an attorney here.
I can do this myself.
Let me do it.
I'll be back in 20 minutes.
- Well, can I come?
- No, honey.
I don't think this is a place for kids.
What.
You don't think I'll understand?
OK, point taken.
You can come.
OK, I'll go get dressed.
Yup.
You go.
- I'll bring her.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
10 minutes, yeah?
10 minutes.
What's going on?
I'm getting our things
together so we can leave.
You can't do that to me.
We just got here.
It's the same old thing, Alyssa.
Last night, you were
passed out on the beach.
I was mad.
It was stupid, OK?
Please?
It was your idea.
It was a good idea.
You don't have to stay
if you don't want to.
Just give it a month.
If it doesn't work, I'll know.
I'll come home.
I love you, you know.
I love you, too.
Ok.
As you can see, we've
added more pens which
means we'll be bringing in more dolphins
once the facility is up and running.
And we've already purchased six more.
Um, we'll be adding
bleachers, a small cafe,
and enough parking for two
tour buses at the same time.
How am I supposed to do my
research in a place like this?
It's impossible.
James, what you're doing
here is junk science.
Junk science?
Perhaps I was being too diplomatic.
I should've said
third-rate junk science.
And you're dreaming if you think
it's going to have any impact.
I am on the verge of
something huge here.
Research here in this
situation is not a luxury
this island can afford.
It's just not on the menu, James.
Who is she?
This is my daughter.
Elizabeth will be taking over
day-to-day operation effective
immediately.
I will consider your resignation,
should you choose to submit it.
...What about...
I'm not a damned employee.
I'm... I'm a partner.
Yes, you are a partner.
And Coakley is a partner.
And the town committee is a partner.
You're a minority partner.
You are not going to do this.
Come on, Alyssa.
Dad, wait up.
Dad, Coakley can't speak for
the town of Smith's Point.
Coakley is an elected official.
The town of Smith's Point
has a voice in this, right?
Coakley does what he wants.
There has to be a vote.
Tell him you want a vote.
Yeah, you're right.
You're absolutely right.
There has to be a vote.
Let's go back in there.
Now, these pens will be made
of concrete as opposed to wood.
Will that affect the Dolphins' sonar?
No, not at all.
They'll be fine.
Coakley, I want a vote.
Oh, come on, Hawk.
No, no, no.
You're a third.
I'm a third.
The town's a third.
You say you got the town's
committee on your side.
Prove it.
I want a vote.
Fine, Hawker I'll call a town committee
meeting tomorrow at 3:00 PM.
Good.
I think you're
underestimating this town.
I think you overestimate yourself.
Come on, Alyssa.
I heard you and your
dad had quite a day.
Come on, child.
Come and sit with me.
Come.
So how do the fish see the bait?
With their nose.
He's out there somewhere.
Who?
Your friend.
You know, years ago,
everyone around here
was a fisherman, their nets
right along this shore.
Then the fish... the dolphin
drove the fish into the nets.
When they were finished,
the people shared
the catch with the dolphins.
Was that a legend or something?
Uh-huh.
It's happening like that
right now around the village.
There's a village in
Brazil, place in Mozambique,
and Africa, and other places as well.
But they don't fish like
that around here no more.
Do you think that the
dolphins can really talk?
I mean, really talk?
What do you think?
I think they can.
We just don't know how to listen well.
There we go.
I want to show you something.
Have a look at that.
It's an eye.
It's a dolphin's eye.
My grandfather made it.
He was one of the
fishermen I told you about.
It's beautiful.
He believed that dolphins
can see in ways that we can't,
and that they'll help you if you just
open up your heart to them.
You're here!
Come here.
You must be a girl.
A boy would never play so hard to get.
What's your name?
Can I call you Rasca?
Rasca, it is.
Good girl.
Oh.
You're so beautiful.
Look at you.
Oh, little show-off.
You're so pretty.
All right, Hawk.
Have something to eat.
Yeah, yeah.
Later, later.
Boy, worry don't nourish nobody.
Man, have something to eat.
All God's children got to eat.
Where's my daughter?
I saw her up at William's Point.
Who's she with?
A friend.
A friend?
Yeah.
Girl?
No.
A boy?
Ok.
I'm going up there.
Hawk!
Good girl.
Yeah.
Oh!
Come on.
Go on!
Yeah.
Good girl.
Come on.
Come on!
Alyssa!
Get out of the water!
It's OK, Dad.
She's my friend.
It's a wild dolphin, Alyssa.
Get out!
Get out of the water.
Rasca!
Alyssa!
Alyssa, wild dolphins who leave
their pod and seek out humans
are psychologically unstable.
They become attached
to their human friends.
They don't want them to leave the water.
They don't want to be alone.
Then they become aggressive,
and somebody gets hurt.
You don't know that!
Yes, I do.
This behavior's been
documented 21 times.
Look.
Here's a... I wrote this.
Look, read it.
It's bad for the dolphin, Alyssa.
I don't want to read
your stupid articles.
She doesn't have anybody but me!
Yeah, And that's not right.
Look, out there, somewhere in the ocean,
right, there's a pod
of dolphins that she
is going to connect with.
But how is she going to do
that if you don't let her go?
Why can't she just come
live with Bogie and Bacall?
Well, that's just not possible.
Bogie and Bacall...
They're happy here.
How would your friend feel
about living in a pen?
Why don't you understand?
We talk to each other.
We understand each other.
You're the one who researches it.
But you just don't understand it?
Alyssa, you're going
to have to trust me.
Wild dolphins have to stay that way.
I forbid you from having any
more contact with that dolphin!
You what?
Look, I know this is hard
for you to understand.
But believe me, I promise you,
someday you will understand it.
No!
I will never understand you!
Damn.
I don't think I can do this.
We can.
What do you want?
I, uh, wanted to give you this.
And so, imagine just
down the street, a magnet
that will draw perhaps
over 1,000 people a week.
1,000 people that would be
free to roam in the town,
and buy a nice, cold beer right
here in this establishment.
Or perhaps one of your delicious
Cobb salad, eh, Cornelia?
Oh they'd be welcome.
I'd even sell them some of
my famous peas and grits.
Precisely!
Your turn, Mr. Hawker.
So, now we all think that
our kind of intelligence
is the only kind of
intelligence that exists.
But is it?
Just because we can
manipulate the environment,
build things... cars, buildings, ships,
planes... doesn't mean that
that's the only intelligence
that exists, right?
Now, imagine if we were totally
suited to our environment,
like dolphins, don't
you think it's possible,
I mean, just possible
that our intelligence
would have evolved differently?
It would have revealed
itself in a different way?
I mean, they don't need to
build cars or drive them.
And it's not their lack of intelligence
that's blocking us.
It's our lack of imagination
that's stopping us
from understanding these creatures who
are as intelligent as
us, if not more so,
judging by what's going on
in this room here today, huh?
You want to know what
the bottom line is?
You don't have to go
to the moon to find ET.
He's right here living in
the oceans of the earth.
And I am this far away from proving it.
But you would destroy all of
that for a tourist attraction?
Yeah, yeah, Hawk, but a tourist
show that make real money, man.
You see, that's real money.
I make all of this today.
No, man.
Yes, all of this from
the tourists who want
swim with the dolphins.
- Now you're talking!
- You understand?
I mean, if they want a dolphin show,
you give them a dolphin show.
If they want a dolphin
show, that means we can
fix the potholes in my roads.
Right, Mr. (INAUDIBLE)?
Now you're talking.
Hey, and you tell me your
truck broke down the other day
when you fell in the pothole.
All the time, man, all the time.
Huh?
I tell you, man.
And we could buy homes.
I mean, we could live good!
Huh?
Live good!
You don't know what you'd be losing.
You're right, Hawk.
We don't know what we'd be losing.
But, you know what?
We know what we'll be gaining!
Money!
(INAUDIBLE)
That's right!
Money!
We'll be gaining money!
All those in favor of
approval of the dolphin park,
- say "aye!".
- Hey, wait a minute!
- Wait a minute!
- Yeah!
Yeah!
Aye, aye, aye.
Come on, let's go.
Yeah, drinks on me!
Come on.
Let's go!
Who wants some drinks?
Drinks are on the house, everybody.
Look.
I'd give them everything except
the dolphins and the boat.
Ok?
According to this, the
dolphins belong to the venture,
not to you.
That's bullshit.
They're mine.
I own them.
There may be a way.
Yeah?
Upon dissolution of the partnership,
you can get the dolphins back,
but only if all debts are paid.
Are all debts paid?
Nope.
$92,415.
Do you have that kind of money?
No.
How about assets?
Your house?
- Belongs to the partnership.
- Anything.
Come on, Decker.
She's your (INAUDIBLE).
I don't know, Hawk man.
I mean, how much do you
still owe the bank on this?
About $100 grand, more or less.
But she's worth $250.
Boy, I'll tell you what I'd do for you.
I'll give you $130.
What?
That's ridiculous.
I need 90 clear.
That's only 30 after
I've paid back the loan.
Man, is it really worth all this
for a couple of lousy dolphins?
Yes, Decker, it is.
Well, sorry, man.
I can't help you.
What was he doing here?
I asked him to buy the boat.
What?
- Why?
- Look.
I don't want Bogie and
Bacall to be in some circus.
I just won't have it, OK?
So you're selling the boat.
I'm buying the dolphins!
Where will we take them?
Where will we live?
Let's worry about that
when it happens, OK?
And Alyssa?
You're trying to sell
off her inheritance?
Right.
I never looked at it like that.
Well, you might want to start
looking at it like that.
Hi, Dad.
Hi.
Here's your letters.
Hey, you didn't open them.
What can I say?
You really pissed me off.
You know, I asked Mom once about you.
You know what she said?
She said you were a dreamer
of catastrophic proportions.
What are you thinking now you've
met the great catastrophe?
I know how much you care about them.
Tami cares about them too, and so do I.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- What was that?
- I don't know.
Let's check it out.
What are they doing here?
Did Coakley send you, huh?
Tell him he's too late.
I don't think so, Hawker.
Hold it right there, Coakley.
You have no right.
Well, as a matter of
fact, James, he does.
This is an article of transfer signed
by a judge in Port Lucaya.
And it assigns all assets
of the partnership,
including the dolphins,
to the majority partner.
And that would be Mr. Coakley here.
As much as it pains me to say it,
you are hereby evicted, Hawker.
I got to get my lawyer
to take a look at this.
Call him.
We'll wait.
Man!
Goodness!
It's Alyssa.
Wow!
I'm sorry, Hawker.
There's nothing I can do.
Come on, Coakley.
You can't do this.
Those dolphins are...
Gone.
What the hell are you up to, Hawker?
He let them go!
No, he didn't.
I did.
Alyssa, what have you done?
You know they can't survive in the wild.
Dad, yes they can.
Rasca will help them.
Don't worry, Dad.
I can bring them back whenever I want.
But some things are
going to have to change.
I love you, Dad!
I don't believe it.
Oh, nice. (INAUDIBLE)
Wait. Here we go.
Dad, they don't need that.
They're fine.
And so it is my idea that we
expand the research facility
and make it a place where
people come... not to watch
the dolphins perform, but to study them
and interact with them in
a protected environment.
Because I know now that we
can all learn from them,
not just intellectually,
but spiritually.
And if we open ourselves to them,
they can reach our hearts,
as well as our minds.
And that people would come from
all over for a chance, not just
to touch the dolphins,
but to be touched by them
and to experience a
communication that goes deeper
than just science can measure.
Hey, hey, hey.
I say we give Conchy Jane a chance, eh?
What'd you say?
All right?
All right.
Hey!
Hold up, hold up!
Guess what?
- Drinks on Hawk this time.
- Hey!
You guys can touch him.
(INAUDIBLE).
There you go.
Gently.
Alyssa made good on her plans,
with Rasca's help, of course.
Look at me.
Look.
Hawk still works as hard as ever,
chasing his dream.
And he's getting closer every day.
But along the way, he found
an unexpected treasure.
And now, she's his best friend.
And they've healed each other
and made each whole in a way
that, well, only we fathers and
our daughters can understand.
And as for the other
members of our family,
well, they're doing fine.
I think they're just waiting
for us to learn to listen right.
And who knows?
Maybe someday we will.
We just have to keep our hearts
open to them and to each other.
Started today.
Good day.
First day she ever smoked.
She's now a smoker.
(INAUDIBLE)
We're gonna practice one
real fast on rehearsal, right?
Wow, man.
Like this... hold it like this.
Hold it away from you.
Notice she doesn't bring it to her lips.
She's just, um, playing with it.
And the drinking scene was water,
in case anyone's curious.
OK.
So now we gotta go (INAUDIBLE).
(INAUDIBLE) take one, (INAUDIBLE).
It's one
cigarette. (INAUDIBLE).
No, not now.
There it is.
(INAUDIBLE)
Ok?
Ok.
These are real conchs.
Check it out!
There's like a little creature inside.
And he wraps himself around in there.
Can you see?
And they're kind of like squishy.
Ugh, kinda gross.
It's like snail of the sea.
Would you like some conch?
Don't... (INAUDIBLE)
so they're still connected,
right?
(INAUDIBLE).
That is (INAUDIBLE).
Oh, my god.
Actually, it was not bad, you now.
My first time, and I already ate three.
Conch's (INAUDIBLE).
I loved it.
It's crunchy, one of the
nicest things I've ever eaten.
Hey, we're finally
done shooting the movie.
And it's really sad and everything.
We finished yesterday,
and I'm back here to uh,
feed the dolphins.
Want some?
(INAUDIBLE).
Altogether it's like
20 people. (INAUDIBLE).
These are all the bad fish.
If they have a break in
their skin, a popped eye,
anything like that, you
gotta throw them out.
Look at him now.
(INAUDIBLE).
This is Cocoon.
This is (INAUDIBLE) mommy.
(INAUDIBLE)
Good boy.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org