Born on the day in the city.
I spell,
in my old Lisbon.
another life.
And with a knot of nostalgia.
in the throat.
I hear that a fado tunes.
in the farewell.
And with a knot of nostalgia.
in the throat.
I hear that a fado tunes.
in the farewell.
It was in the taverns
the Alfama,
in a sad moment,
this song where he was born,
his regret,
in memory of those who are
like the wind,
in the eyes of someone who loves
and not give up.
In memory of those who are
like the wind,
in the eyes of someone who loves
and not give up.
Glows when the old flame
feeling
I hear this sea that roars
while singing.
And from a Madragoa Bica,
at a time,
always returns this anxiety
at the time of departure.
Production
Script and direction
Which only lives in the past,
without goal
is a prisoner of fate
it invades ...
beginning of the busy
nineteenth century with the arrival in Lisbon
for work of thousands
people in rural areas,
but the colonies
Africa and Brazil,
fado  arises in courtyards,
brothels and taverns.
This type of music has survived
until today
in its original form,
But two centuries later
is an inspiration
Portuguese  latitudes
saw it.
As a water source
My hand is transparent
in the eyes of my grandmother.
Between land and sky
my grandmother knew black
those things of fate.
I see the sea leads
in the rivers of desire
who was born to sing.
The Zambezi
becomes the Tagus
chanted many times
to envy
Lisbon to live.
I see a hair braiding
the warm and singing fado
in a shawl of tirabuzones.
Like a fairy tale
African drums
become guitars
and coconut in sunflowers.
My grandmother knew black
how to read things in the destination
in the palm of each eye.
Life does not want or like,
God told the witch
I was born to sing.
Girl, what's the matter,
you're angry with me?
Is it because your black
was not inclined
at your feet?
Is it because your black
has not been inclined to your feet?
Let's make peace, my love,
I got here, to its knees.
here I got on his knees.
Here I am.
Girl, what's the matter?
Why are you crying, do you?
But if I cry why
're angry with me.
Cry if I am right,
Let's make peace, my love,
I got here, to its knees.
Here I am.
Do not tell me what is the cause
that I do not talk
when I entered.
Do not tell me what is the cause
that I do not talk
when I entered.
It will be because your love
I was already over.
I was not over.
It will be because your love
I already finished
Let's make peace, my love,
I got here, to its knees.
Here I am.
The wind blows
too hard
so you can relax.
The wind blows
too hard
so you can relax.
There are in my thoughts
something that is going to stop.
Perhaps the thing of the soul
who believe that life is real.
Maybe this thing quiet
that makes my soul alive.
Wind blows over,
I am afraid to think.
My mystery myself Avivo
if I lost in meditation.
Passing wind and forgets,
Dust rises and falls.
Alas for me if I could
know what is inside me.
Oh, me if I could
Weep, weep fado,
a fado died.
Today, exactly a year ago
Severa who died.
The Count of Vimioso
suffered a hard blow
when they went to say:
"Your Severe perished."
Run to your grave
and still get to see his body.
"Goodbye, my Severa,
God give you good luck. "
In that heavenly kingdom,
with your guitar in hand,
become fado
the angels,
his world upside down again.
Until the San Pedro
sitting at the gate of heaven
andalusia come to see Severa
was to give palms
and to sing a fado.
Weep, fado, crying,
Severa who perished.
The flavor was fado
it was completed.
Oh, street Capelâo
rushes of rosemary.
Oh, Capelâo Street,
If my love reaches prontito
besaré stone floor
she stepped on to the
while passing.
If my love
prontito arrives
besare stone floor
she stepped on to the
while passing.
I have the destination marking
soon
I saw you on.
I have the destination marking
soon
I saw you on.
Oh, my beloved gypsy,
andalusia embraced live fado,
hugging you die.
Oh, my beloved gypsy,
andalusia embraced live fado,
hugging you die.
Oh, my beloved gypsy,
andalusia embraced live fado,
hugging you die.
A nightingale told me,
viejito of Choupal,
the most beautiful fish
one died days
for having repudiated
His love fatal,
a young troubadour
which is love.
Also came to sing
their serenades
on the banks of the Montego
the genteel troubadour
no matter ever
gratae in their songs,
the poor who die
delivered to his love.
They say that since then
an echo murmurante
responding in Choupal
the band Estudiantina
is the voice of Tricana
he believes is the lover
until today there is still singing
its sad fate.
Tribute to Marceneiro Alfredo,
poet of the street.
A lifelong carpenter
to sing fado
until death.
Sad fado,
sad fado.
Carpenter.
Carpenter all his life.
Sad fado,
sad fado.
I was not born with a hammer
or follow the footsteps of my father.
No one wanted to be vague,
but wondered whether
what I wanted to be
I preferred to flee in a balloon.
Looking for my profession,
my way, in my training,
I found a notebook with no stripes,
Loose letters lost
a hatch.
I looked for a hammer
joined the words
and began to build.
First idea: A Window
to pass the truth
that is not in the novels.
A dark, lit a candle,
I felt the smell of sawdust
and I wanted to make the sequel.
Suddenly came to my mind
a door
to exit that cell.
I am
> carpenter to death.
> My blood flows and flows.
My love,
This also helps fado,
The day also consumed.
Soy
Carpenter's death.
My blood flows and flows.
Question
flavors and pains
which is my parents,
present and future.
Do not forget the crying
that is revealed in their faces.
I can not extinguish the flame.
The need another nail bed.
My body is delivered, exhausted.
Embrace my Karma,
which was accepted
and I need to return.
Need
sandpaper in one hand.
Limo imperfections.
Not trying to be perfect,
but the time I gently
maturing in each piece.
It is my goal.
I got letters all over the workshop.
No reward
while there is no money.
My mind just thinks
to have an idea.
Is the life of a carpenter.
Soy
Carpenter's death.
My blood flows and flows.
My love,
This also helps fado,
The day also consumed.
Soy
Carpenter's death.
My blood flows and flows.
Was given the gift
of construction
but with one condition:
Do not let
using the heart,
with conviction.
A mission that does not control,
the task of sculpting,
a feeling
or a simple scene.
Not in vain
always believe that I belong.
More
is to describe an emotion.
Let your mind wander, do not be afraid
make what you feel
in employment.
Write your vision,
do not be blind.
Use the hammer, no nails.
Breathe, stop, think.
Take off that tension.
Cree with inner strength
and forget what others think.
The flame should not be turned off.
It should not be shut down
the flame.
Caught the morning
like a child.
A rosebush interwoven,
a strain of hope.
As the body
the city
that early in the morning
dance rehearsal
of those,
force of will,
never tire of working.
Walk the street with the moon
in my Tajo
lights early.
Vago for Lisbon
tide naked
which empties into the Rossio.
I'm a man of the city
that early in the morning
wakes up and sings,
and love for freedom
the city stands.
I go down the street
dazzled
by the full moon in Lisbon
until the moon in love
grows in the sailing of the canoe.
I am the seagull that defeat
any weather
at sea
I am the man who carries
the tide of people scared.
And when caught the morning,
capture the morning like a flower
at the edge of the penalty deflowered.
A blue margarita,
daisy of freedom
I want as anybody.
Daisy in this city
I want,
I want to.
In my hands, the morning
also opened the flower April.
Flower without fear, perfumed
with the aroma of the sea.
Flor de Lisboa, well loved,
I do not want
but now I want.
It was in the Travessa da Palha
where my lover, a scoundrel,
made my heart bleed.
Bringing to another lover,
came contours, petulant,
with an air of provocation.
Bringing to another lover,
came contours, petulant,
with an air of provocation.
In the tavern Friagem,
between a bunch of Fados,
I came to them without rancor.
Because the woman who brought
certainly not worth
or shade
my love.
Because the woman who brought
certainly not worth
nor the shadow of my love.
It was in the Travessa da Palha
where my lover, a scoundrel,
made my heart bleed
bringing another lover.
Came contours, petulant,
with an air of provocation.
Bringing to another lover,
came contours, petulant,
with an air of provocation.
In the tavern Friagem,
between a bunch of Fados,
I came to them without rancor.
Because the woman who brought
certainly not worth
or shade
my love.
Because the woman who brought
certainly not worth
nor the shadow of my love.
To see who had more verve
sing a challenge
this one and me.
I left it up to the bitumen,
showing more fado,
proving to be more women.
I left it up to the bitumen,
showing more fado,
proving to be more women.
It was one of those scenes,
among many others in my life,
of which are never forgotten.
I only know that at dawn
when everything was finished,
we both went home.
I only know that at dawn
when everything was finished,
we both went home.
We both went home.
Return, life lived,
to enable it to see again.
so you can see again
one life lost
I never knew that life.
One life lost
I would not do again
those times.
What nostalgia.
I would not do again
those times.
What nostalgia.
Spring always returns,
the only thing that does not return
is youth.
Spring always returns
the only thing that does not return
is youth.
Time passes
and we were deceived.
and we were deceived,
Now laughing,
Now crying.
Now crying,
Now laughing.
Now laughing,
Now crying.
Now crying,
Now laughing.
"My God, how time passes,"
say from time to time.
In the end,
is the time that remains,
and people going past.
In the end, is the time
that is,
and people going past.
Have known
they were going to die young
I would never have loved
anybody in this world.
Have known
they were going to die young
I would never have loved
anybody in this world.
This dance
is the dream of my hope
it has taught me
your love was false
flower.
This dance
is the dream of my hope
it has taught me
your love was false
flower.
At the farewell
cry a lot.
That hurt
and I cried too.
This dance
is the dream of my hope
it has taught me
faso was your love,
flower.
At the farewell
cry a lot.
That hurt
and I cried too.
This dance
is the dream of my hope
it has taught me
your love was false
my flower.
Love, when shown,
it is not known to display.
He knows how to look
but not knowing how to talk.
Who wants to say what he feels
do not know what to say.
If he speaks, it seems that lying.
If shut, it seems to forget.
Oh, if she guessed,
if I could hear the eyes ...
And if you look enough
to know
that are loving ...
But I feel much, shut up.
Who wants to say
what you feel
remains without a soul,
speechless,
and totally alone.
It was in the dry
wild leaves.
Who put you that name.
Soledad,
loneliness.
He knows what words are
before they put the sun.
As a dream of agony ...
These eyes of mine.
Soledad,
Little India.
Is it so fast? Do not stop?
Little Indian.
In ash soil
abandoned.
What do you think?
Do not think anything.
Soledad,
loneliness.
Life is totally secret
as the stars
like the stars
in these ashes.
As the stars
like the stars
in these ashes.
Before they let the sun ...
Soledad.
- This is wrong here?
- Not very well.
Well
only he would explain
who serves your destination
without penalty and without joy.
Your heart is so big ...
very nice too ...
It is by God's will
I live in anxiety,
cries are all mine,
and all my nostalgia.
It is by God's will.
What a strange way of life
have this heart of mine.
Lives lost in life,
Who would you give this gift?
What a strange way of life.
Celebrities independent
heart that does not control,
lives lost among the people
stubbornly bleeding,
heart independent.
I do not already over,
order to stop beating,
if you do not know
where to go,
Why insist on running?
I do not already over.
Grândola, brown village,
land of brotherhood.
The village is in charge
inside you, oh city.
Inside you, oh city.
The village is in charge,
land of brotherhood.
Grândola, brown village.
Oh, my muse fado,
oh, my gracious mother.
I leave you, shocked,
the first of April.
Do not be so ungrateful,
do not forget who I love you
and who in your dense jungle
lost and found.
This land still
will meet his ideal,
will become yet
in a vast Portugal.
You know?
Basically I am a sentimental.
All the inherited blood
Lusitanian a good dose of lyricism.
In addition to syphilis, of course.
Although my hands are busy
torturing, drowning, degollando,
close your eyes my heart
and sincerely mourned.
With Culantrillo in the scrub,
rosemary in the reedbed,
liquors in the Moringa,
came a tropical
and the beautiful mulata
fits with the Alentejo
to which a bravata
stole a kiss.
This land still
will meet his ideal,
will become yet
in a vast Portugal.
My heart is calm
by nature
hit my hand
Hard and fast.
So,
when everything is done,
lost,
I question myself.
If you take your hands
off my chest
is that distance
between intention and gesture.
And if you close with my hands
my heart
I am surprised the sudden
sense of incest.
In the heat of battle
boasts a sharp grip
but my chest is opened.
And if the ruling
announces brutal,
quickly
Blind runs his hand,
because if not,
forgiving heart.
Guitars and zanfona,
jasmine,
coconut trees and fountains,
sardines, cassava,
in a smooth tile.
And the Amazon River
traveled Trás-os-Montes
and a large wave
flows into the Tagus.
This land still
will meet his ideal,
will become yet
in a vast Portugal.
This land still
will meet his ideal,
will become yet
in a vast Portugal.
Me, I just miss me,
Lady of my life,
I say that's my dream
and I
by birth.
I bring a fado song
in my soul
well-kept.
Come inside my surprise
looking
My fado.
My fate, my fate.
A friendship lost
can never return.
It was a feigned friendship
to go and play again.
Nobody gives anything
without a change
a reward.
Nobody gives anything
without a change
a reward.
Only a friend can
love without giving.
My mother, I sing at night
because the day I was punished.
And in the silence of things
I find the voice friend.
My mother, I cry at night
this love
in which I sink.
Because words
of life
and no other world.
So I am this song
my mother, as a wound
that seen at night in my body
no destination, but with fado.
That seen at night in my body
Fado but with no destination.
Maybe I read fado
what I mean nobody.
And we pursue,
to hear him.
And we Pursuing
My love has sung
under heaven so superior.
Because I gave
each fado
as if it were the first.
Perhaps I did not ask fado
everything that I,
therefore, even if I forget,
he does not forget who I am.
So even if I forget,
Not to see you cry
and see you cry now.
For wanting stronger,
want to see you at all times.
Flying over time
when you talk and I listen.
But the hours of our life
each have one minute.
Permítete be at my side
and not ever go again,
for my heart,
poor,
living in a life time.
For my heart,
poor,
living in a life time.
I am not afraid to fame,
Alfama with bad reputation.
Fame sometimes defamed
Good people, honest people.
Fado, come with me,
fado hear this from the street.
And sing desafiándoos
in a typical old town.
Come on, as I said,
you have to do at dawn
how good was that the evening
in the old Alfama district.
I am not afraid to fame
Alfama with the bad reputation.
I know that the world was talking,
and true evil.
So it was not always true
what they were.
Many people there wore
a very quiet life
a form of evil
was dotted with mud.
Fame
sometimes defamed
Good people, honest people.
Fame sometimes defamed
Fado this is mine and yours,
a destiny that bind us
while it is denied
the strings of a guitar.
Whenever you hear the wail
a guitar playing
we feel lost
who want to mourn.
Oh, people of my land,
Now I come to realize
I feel sad that this
The received from you.
And it would seem tenderness
if I leave Acuña.
It would be more bitterness,
I sing less sad.
Oh, people of my land,
Now I come to realize
sadness that I feel
The received from you.
BY RIPEADOS
--
- P
BY RIPEADOS
- PA
- PAC
BY RIPEADOS
- PACO
BY RIPIADOS
- PACOS
BY RIPEADOS
- PACOSS
- PACOSS.