Typical of Victor Von Doom...
to build a 30-foot statue
of himself.
Well, it's obviously aimed at first-time visitors
to create feelings of smallness...
inadequacy.
Good thing
it ain't workin'.
Reed, what are we doing here?
This guy's fast-food, strip-mall science.
This wasn't our first stop,
in case you forgot.
Besides, Victor's not that bad.
He's just a little... larger than life.
- Hi, Reed Richards and Ben Grimm-
- Executive elevator. Top floor.
What's it take to get
a smile around this joint?
Von Doom Industries, at the forefront...
of aerospace technology
and biomedical engineering-
The unparalleled leader
in government defense systems.
My research suggests...
that exposure to
a high-energy cosmic storm...
borne
on solar winds...
might have triggered the evolution
of early planetary life.
In six weeks
another cloud...
In six weeks another cloud...
with the same elemental profile...
will pass Earth's orbit.
A study, conducted in space...
could fundamentally advance
our knowledge...
about the structure
of the human genome...
cure countless diseases,
extend human life...
give kids a chance to live longer,
stronger, healthier-
Turn it off. Please.
- I don't think I've explained my proposal fully.
- No, I think you have.
Same old Reed- always stretching,
reaching for the stars...
with the weight of the world
on his back.
But dreams don't pay the bills,
do they?
You remember,
when we were in school...
we talked about working together.
Well, that's what
I was about to explain.
The storm is deadly...
but the shields
on your station's control room...
are designed to protect
any occupants inside.
So, it's not just my money you want.
It's my toys.
Tell me, if NASA doesn't trust you,
then why should I?
That's my job-
to stay a step ahead...
to know what other men don't.
- I can't take this.
- Ben, this is business. Just work.
He's right, Ben-
It is just business.
I think you both know
my director of genetic research...
Susan Storm.
One more thing he's got.
- Hey, Susie.
- Hey.
Oh, it's so nice to see you.
How's Debbie?
- Great.
- Uh, how have you been?
- Never better.
- This isn't gonna be a problem, is it?
- Oh, not at all.
- No, I-
- Good.
Then you are just in time...
to hear the great Reed Richards...
ask me for help.
You made a lot of folks at M.I.T.
feel like a junior high science fair...
so you'll excuse me
if I savor the moment.
You back this mission...
and I'll sign over a fair percentage
of any applications-
The number is 75,
and its applications and patents.
- What about his firstborn?
- Ben.
Come on.
Twenty-five percent of a billion is enough
to keep the lights on a while, isn't it?
Maybe even pay off your fourth mortgage
on the Baxter Building.
Deal?
Well, then, to our future.
Together.
It's funny how things turn out,
isn't it?
Hilarious.
He knew about NASA.
Maybe he made the call to shut us down.
Ben, think about all the people
we can help if this works. Huh?
Look, we got what we wanted.
That's enough.
A few days in space. It'll be great.
What's the worst that can happen?
If Reed's right, this little trip
could double our stock offerings.
And if he's not?
Reed's always right.
Good thing he doesn't always know
what he's got.
Reed, you should know those solar winds
have been picking up speed.
- I factored them into my coordinates.
- Right.
Of course you did.
In theory.
- It's a little different once you're out there.
- I can assure you-
When are we leaving?
I'll be scheduling the launch.
You can call me in the morning
for resources and crew.
- I think I remember the number.
- It's been changed.
I was hoping Ben
could pilot the mission.
We already have a pilot
on our payroll.
But you're welcome to ride shotgun.
Remember my brotherJohnny?
Can't do it. Cannot do it.
External S.R.B.'s,
orbital system engines.
- It's just like the shuttle you flew-
- No!
- I cannot take orders from the underwear model.
- Oh, come on, now.
That wingnut washed out of NASA for
sneaking two Victoria's Secret wannabes...
into a flight simulator.
- Youthful high spirits.
- They crashed it into a wall.
A flight simulator.
When have I ever asked you to do something
you absolutely said you could not do?
Five times.
- I had it at four.
- Well, this makes five.
Attention, all personnel.
Commencing launch sequence
in six hours.
I miss you already, Debs.
Captain on the bridge.!
Digital camera- $254.
Memory stick- $59.
The look on your hard-ass
former C.O.'s face...
when he finds out he's
your junior officer- priceless.
Thank you. That's so sweet.
I can handle this ship.
I can even handle
Mr. Blond Ambition.
But I don't know if I should be flying
or doing Swan Lake in these suits.
Who the hell came up with these?
Victor did.
The synthetics act as a second skin,
adapting to your body's individual needs.
See, now that means it keeps
the hot stuffhot and the cool stuff cool.
Wow. Fantastic.
Material made from self-regulating,
unstable molecules.
I've been working on
a formula for this.
Great minds think alike.
- Here you go, Ben.
- Thanks, sweetie.
Reed.
E. T.A. until cosmic event, nine hours.
If you're good, maybe next time
Daddy'll let you drive.
You keep talkin',
and there won't be a next time.
Long way
from the projection booth...
at the Hayden Planetarium,
isn't it?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
We can monitor the cloud's approach
and observe the tests from here.
Is it safe?
The shields on the station
should protect us.
- "Should"?
- What's the matter, Ben?
Getting paranoid in your old age?
Let's start loading those samples.
Get your suit ready, Ben.
So I see you're still doing
all the heavy lifting.
Maybe you should have stayed in the lab.
Fieldwork never suited you.
He does the talkin'.
I do the walkin'. Got it?
So, take a walk, Ben.
Actually, if you'll all excuse me,
I need to borrow Susan...
for a moment.
Sure.
Please tell me your guy's not trying
to rekindle things with my sister again.
Of course not.
It's strictly business.
Yes, well, his eyes
say differently, don't they?
Hey. Two hearts
got busted last time.
Maybe she's not over it either.
Wow, Dr. Phil, that's deep.
Let's think about that.
You got Victor-
more money than God, stud of the year-
and you got Reed,
world's dumbest smart guy...
worth less than a postage stamp.
That's a real toss-up.
Don't trouble your tiny little mind.
Don't wander off now, boy.
Securing air lock chamber.
Surprised I agreed to Reed's proposal?
I understand the business reasons.
Well, when you're
looking at your future...
it doesn't hurt
to find closure about the past.
Susan, every man dreams he'll meet
a woman he can give the world to.
In my case,
it's not just a metaphor.
Opening viewing station shield.
That can't be right.
Event threshold
in T-minus nine minutes, 47 seconds.
That's impossible.
It should be seven hours.
We've been together
two years now.
It's been a good two years, Victor.
The company's accomplished so much.
Right. Of course. The company.
But I've come to realize...
that all the accomplishments in the world mean
nothing without someone to share them with.
- Um-
- I've lived my life unafraid of taking big steps.
- Now it's time to take the biggest step of all.
- Victor-
If it helps,
think of this as a... promotion.
Victor, I-
I have four words.
Four little words that can change
our lives forever.
The cloud is accelerating.!
We've got minutes until it hits,
not hours.
- Victor, that storm is deadly. We need to abort.
- Get a grip, Reed.
We didn't come all this way to lose our nerve
at the first glitch. Just close the shields.
- Ben is still out there.
- So reel him in.
We came here to do a job,
so let's do it. Quickly.
Victor, Reed's right.
We have less than six minutes.
- Ben, get inside now!
- What's going on?
I ain't done arrangin'
your flowers yet, egghead.
Ben, turn around.
- Guys, I'm not gonna make it.
- You gotta jump!
It's the only way.!
- What are you doing?
- Closing the shields.
- You can't just leave them out there.
- Watch me.
You can't help them
any more than I can!
I can try.
Come on, Ben! You got this!
Johnny, get ready to close the portal.
- You okay?
- Oh. Yeah.
Ben! Ben!
Ben!
Wake up. Ben.
Hey, rise and shine, big boy.
How you feeling?
- Where am I?
- Back on Earth.
We're in quarantine.
Victor's medical facility.
Reed? Sue?
Oh, they're fine.
Everybody else is fine.
What's wrong with me?
I swear to you, Ben, they've done
everything humanly possible.
The best plastic surgeons in the world
are here, Ben. You had the best.
- Give me that mirror.
- I don't know if that's a good idea.
- They said the shock alone-
- I said, give me that goddamn mirror.!
Okay, Ben.
Just be strong.
Unfortunately, the doctors just
couldn't do anything to fix your face.
Hey. Nice do.
Likin' the grandpa look.
What?
Reporter ] You've been charged
with moving science a little too fast.
By whom, my competitors?
Danger is always part of this.
- How's she doing?
- Stable.
And her vitals are strong.
Blood panels show no irradiation.
Good.
- You'll step up this protocol-
- Every four hours, yes.
We know what we're doing.
Another day of observation, and you're all clear.
She's allergic to orchids.
Put the sunflowers by her bed.
They're her favorites.
Well, Victor...
the bank would like
to congratulate you...
on the fastest free-fall
since the Depression.
- We can't even give your stock away.
- Ned, I can turn this around.
You're going to have to, Victor,
or we pull out.
- You have a week.
- You're enjoying this, aren't you, Ned?
One week.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where do we think we're going?
I don't know if we've noticed, but the sickest
runs this side of the Alps are right outside.
Yeah, I've noticed. But there are rules here.
You can't leave until we-
Until we've finished the tests. I know.
I've never been good with rules.
You let me know
how those come out.
- Do you wanna help me with the zipper?
- This is not a ski resort.
Not yet.
Luckily, Grandma still sends care packages.
It's amazing.
- For an 80-year-old woman, you'd be surpri-
- You are trouble.
Mmm. "Trouble"is my middle name.
- Oh, you're hot.
- Why, thank you. So are you.
- And I'm not afraid to cry.
- No, I mean you feel a little feverish.
I've never felt better in my life.
My God, you smell good.
- When do you get off work?
- 4:00, but I-
Tell you what. You meet me at 4:01
at the top of the mountain.
That'll give you
a minute to freshen up.
This is yours. That's mine.
Nurses!
How long was I out?
Hey. Three days.
I was worried about you.
How are you feeling?
Solid.
Uh, it was a close one, though, huh?
What was that about?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
I've been going over the figures again and again,
and they all add up.
I just don't understand.
Maybe I should've aborted-
Reed, it was a freak of nature.
You couldn't have possibly predicted it.
Let it go.
You know, you live through
something like this...
it really makes you appreciate
having the right woman in your life.
- Yeah, you and Debbie are perfect.
- I'm not talking about Debbie.
What? Come on.
She's got a good thing with Victor.
- He's smart, he's powerful, he's successful-
- Maybe you should date him then.
Ben, she ended up
with the right guy.
Things worked out for the best.
Do I have to do everything myself?
You should stay to the right.
The left might give you trouble.
- I think we should drop, like, 10 more feet.
- Good.
Last one down
springs for room service!
Whoo-hoo!
My future wife!
Whoo!
You're losing!
All right, no more kid stuff.
Check this out!
- You're on fire!
- Thanks! You're pretty good too!
No! You're on fire.! Look!
- Whoa!
Whoa-ohh!
Care to join me?
I can only stay for one drink.
I have to meet Victor.
Oh. Wouldn't want
to keep Vic waiting.
Reed, what are you doing here?
I thought-
Great.!
Uh, maybe you can join us.
- How's the I.P.O. now?
- It's fallen.
We're looking at low 20s.
It's a good number, considering the fallout from-
From Reed's disaster?
Get me on the a. m. shows,
Larry King, cover of the Journal.
Gonna have to do something
about this scar.
Make sure they only shoot me
from my left side.
Actually, uh, the scar's tracking well.
People seem to think
it humanizes you.
And that's a good thing?
Maybe you should get some rest.
Later.
First I have some unfinished business.
A deal that needs closing.
Sir, I have always wondered-
Why Sue?
You could have any other woman
in the world.
That's why. Because I could
have any other woman.
No, let me tell the story! Let me tell the story!
Oh-
Wow.
You all right?
Bad shrimp.
I think I'd better go lie down.
Excuse me.
Oh, God.
So, are you feeling better?
Yes. Thank you.
Good.
That's, uh, good.
You always had a way with words.
Uh-Wow.
I should be going, 'cause, uh...
I have to meet Victor.
I'm really happy for you and Victor.
You're really happy
for me and Victor?
I can tell you guys are enjoying
what was the best part of our relationship.
- Which was?
- Passion.
For science.
You are such a dork, Reed.
You never got it,
and you never will.
- What did I say?
- Unless it's explained to you in quantum physics.
I just wanted
to let you know that I was-
It's been two years, and all you can say
is you're happy for me and some other guy?
Victor may be a lot of things...
but at least he's not afraid
to fight for what he wants.
It's nice to be wanted
sometimes, Reed...
to be seen and heard.
Look at me.
I can't.
- What do you mean, you can't? Look at me!
- Sue, look at your hands.
Hey! You guys-
Hey. You are never gonna believe
what just happened to me.
What?
Oh. Well, I can explain this.
It has to be the cloud.
It's fundamentally altered our D.N.A.
Let's not jump to conclusions.
We need a massive amount of evidence
before making that leap.
Whoa.! Guys, look.
Now, picture that, but everywhere.!
It was everywhere.!
What?
The cloud has fundamentally
altered our D.N.A.
Cool!
- And you know what, guys? I think I was flying.
- We need to find Ben.
I said cut it out,Johnny.
- Still getting the hang of it.
- Hey, Ben! It's Reed!
- Stop.
- All right.
- All right?
- Yes!
- God! What's wrong with you?
- God! What?
Sue, do you know the code?
Hey, Ben! Open up!
- You all right, Ben?
- Hey, does somebody have keys to these doors?
Anybody?
Just break the glass.
It can't be that thick.
That's gross.
Ben?
Look! Look, look, look, look!
What is that thing?
What's going on?
What happened in here?
- Are you feeling all right?
- I'm fine. Just a few scrapes, that's all.
Ben did this. He's had some kind of
reaction to exposure from the cloud.
We all have, um, different symptoms.
Symptoms?
- Victor, um, I should have-
- Just find him.
Anybody got any ideas
where the big guy's going?
He's going home.
Oh, you gotta be kiddin' me.
Little buttons! Hello, Operator?
- Hello?
- Debs? It's me.
Ben? Are you all right?
You sound a little different.
- Uh, listen, I need you to come out front.
- Out front?
You're home, baby?
Yeah.
I got a surprise for you.
Yeah, I got a little one for you too.
Ben?
Where are you?
I'm over here.
Don't come any closer for a sec, okay?
It's gonna-
It's gonna be a bit of a shock.
Honey, what's going on?
Debs...
remember w-when we used to say...
together forever,
no matter what?
Yeah?
Baby, you're scaring me.
- Oh, my God.
- Deb.
It's me. It's still me.
It was the accident.
- Let me explain.
- No! Don't touch me!
Debs!
What are you doin', lady?
Hey.! I'm callin'the police.!
Everybody all right?
I saw him.! It's that guy over there.!
What the hell's going on out there?
Oh, yeah, Ben.
A few days in space. It'll be great.
What's the worst that could happen?
Hey, little guy.
You're not afraid of me, are ya?
Perfect.
Thanks.
Hey!
- You think you got problems?
You take a good look, pal.
Huh. How bad could it be, right?
I don't think you-
Okay, pal, take it easy.
No, no, no. Don't go out there.
I said stop, you fruitcake!
No, no, no. Come closer.
That's further! Come closer!
I said stop! No, no, no!
Whoa!
Feet.!
Come here!
All right.
Calm down.
You wanna be scared?
Fine!
- Give me a couple tow trucks.
- Get back! Get back!
Get back in your vehicles.!
We'll tell you when you can go.!
- What are we gonna do now?
- We're not gonna get past these guys.
But you could.
Sorry about the truck, pal.
Come on.
A little help here.
You wanna hit the button, sir?
Stuck.
Sue, your clothes. Lose them.
Oh. Right.
This is so wrong.
What?
Oh!
- Wow. You've been working out.
- Shut up!
All right.
All right, freeze!
Now,just, uh-
just put the man
in the seat down!
Do it!
Any more great ideas? Why don't you strip
down and have 100 people stare at you?
- Sue.
- What?
Oh. Hmph!
I'm gonna need therapy.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Right now, uh,
just back away from him.
And, uh, I want you...
to put your hands
on your head right-
954 approaching scene.
- I still can't believe you made me do that.
- We got through, didn't we?
Just find Ben.
Stay back of the bridge.!
Ben! Ben!
Mom.! Mom?
Whoa!
Stay here, okay?
Coming.! Hold on.!
No, you-
don't.
No!
Hang on!
- Huh?
- I got ya.
This is the police.!
Get down on the ground.!
Don't shoot.! He's a hero.!
Get down on the ground now.!
Ben!
Whoo-hoo!
I swear to you...
I will do everything in my power...
until there is not a breath left in me-
You're gonna be Ben again.
- How 'bout this guy?
- I don't know.
I tell you what-
I never seen nothin'like him before.
I told you I felt fine.
Where are your ears?
- There are some folks outside that want to talk to you.
- We're not going public.
- We're scientists, not celebrities.
- It's too late, son.
Look.
- When a New York Fire Department ladder truck...
- See that?
became part of the tragedy.
But the rescue itself is not the story.
One of the four stretched
to an amazing length-
That's what they're calling you-
the Fantastic Four.
- Cool!
- No, wait! Where are you going?
- I'm gonna go talk to 'em.
- No!
- We should think this through.
- That's great. Brainstorm.
Where is it? Left?
Get back here right now!Johnny!
Settle down!
Do you believe this?
- Which one of you is the leader?
- That would be me.
No, seriously.
Okay, son, you're on.
Uh...
during our recent mission
to the Von Doom space station...
we were exposed to
as-yet unidentified radioactive energy.
- What happened on the bridge?
- How can you stretch?
- Is it true you can fly?
- Yeah, I'm working on it. It's actually difficult-
No, actually, we do not know
much more than you do at this point.
Uh, sir, Larry King just canceled.
Apparently there's a bigger story.
NASDAQ was up 9.9-
Bravest-
Actually, here they come now.
You had to see it
to believe it, folks. The man-
named the Fantastic Four-
We will be going directly to our lab
to diagnose our symptoms.
Symptoms? Is this some kind of disease?
No! No, no, no.
It's not a disease.
Symptoms? If having special powers
is a disease, then, yeah, we got it bad.
Excuse me.
That thing doesn't look so fantastic.
Ben Grimm is a genuine American hero.
What he means is,
every team needs a mascot.
A new day is dawning.
The day of the Fantastic Four.!
Look- Look, we went up to space
to find a way to understand D.N.A...
cure disease, save lives.
Well, now it's our D.N.A.,
our "disease," our lives on the line.
Thank you.
No more questions.
This is how you turn things around?
These freaks on the front page...
your company's in the obituaries?
- I was planning to use the publicity-
- The board's in agreement.
- The bank's lost enough already.
- Wait a minute.
It's too late, Victor.
Do you know how much money
I've invested in this company?
Victor, stop.
This isn't a negotiation.
It's a notification.
We're pulling out.
Is all that for you, Dr. Richards?
I'm afraid so.
Come on, Ben. Smile.
They wanna like you, bud. Say hi.
Uh, don't do drugs!
Welcome back to the Baxter,
Dr. Richards.
I've got the usual for you.
- Good to have you back, sir.
- Thanks, Willie.
We had a tough year.
Yeah, like, nine straight.
Either we're moving
really fast or not at all.
I'll take the stairs.
How come Ben can't turn it
on and off like we can?
That's what we're here to find out.
- If it happened to him- - What? You mean,
like, we won't be able to turn it off either?
- That would save time. Ha!
- You wanna walk around on fire the rest of your life?
- Is that a trick question?
- Grow up.
Come on. Am I the only guy
who thinks this is cool?
We should stay here until we can
define the extent of our changes...
and figure out how to reverse them.
Whoa.
Believe it or not, he lives here.
But I have to warn you,
it's gonna be a little crowded in some areas.
So, what do you think?
I don't know, Reed.
I think you might be bringing
your work home with you.
Come on. Let me show
you guys where you'll be staying.
Busy guy.
- Hi, everybody.
- Mr. Von Doom!
Would you like to comment
on the recent failure of your I.P.O.?
What about the rumors of a takeover?
God, I was so worried about you.
Victor.
- I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to call.
- Please.
No apologies.
I've arranged for your things
to be moved to one of my condos.
- You'll have round-the-clock care.
- Thank you.
That's very generous of you, but I think
I should stay here with my brother...
until we get a handle on things.
Susan, I think you should
let my doctors have a look at you.
Victor.
What are you doing here?
I'm starting to wonder
the same thing.
- How much do you know about what happened to you?
- Not much.
- We need to run tests to see the extent of the damage.
- You let me know what I can do.
We're all in this together now.
Victor, wait.
I just wanted to say I'm sorry
the mission didn't go as planned.
Didn't go as planned?
It was a catastrophe.
You ruined the lives of four people.
With all due respect, we're both to blame.
I told you to abort.
Abort?
I put my company, my name,
billions of dollars on the line.
- I will not let you make me look like a fool.
- If we could understand-
I don't want to understand it!
This isn't one of your science projects!
I just want to fix it, fast!
Is there a problem?
No.
No problem, Ben.
Just pay your damn electric bill
and get to work on finding a cure.
Whoa!
Wow!
He's heating up from his core.
And his vitals are completely normal.
If we're going to identify
the source of the mutation...
we need to isolate
your recombinant D.N.A...
so we can activate
positional genomes.
- Huh?
- We have to do a physical to see what got zapped.
Oh. Why didn't you just say so?
His internal organs are completely solid.
How bad is it?
You know, I used to smoke.
It's not invisibility per se.
You should be able to bend light
around other objects, even people...
if you could control
your emotional state better.
- Excuse me? - If you had more
self-control, you could locate the trigger.
Can you remember
your exact emotions on the bridge?
Anger.
Rage. Frustration.
Okay, is there any way to duplicate
that feeling? Some memory or-
I'm sure I can
come up with something.
- You feel anything?
- Nope.
Okay.
It's hotter than I anticipated.
- Johnny, back it down.
- I can go hotter!
Johnny,just back it down.!
Johnny, back it down right now!
Johnny!
Ohh!
Buzz-kill.!
You guys are crampin'my style.!
Johnny, you were at 4,000 Kelvin.
- Any hotter, and you're approaching supernova.
- Sweet!
No, not sweet.
That's the temperature of the sun.
Not only could you kill yourself...
but you could set fire to Earth's atmosphere
and destroy all human life.
Got it.
Supernova- bad.
How's that coming?
Oh, I'm so sorry.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. Fine.
- You sure?
- Yep.
I, um-
You probably thought that was
some form of latent hostility.
What in the world
would give me that idea?
I mean, you broke up with me, right?
- Are you kidding?
- No.
I distinctly remember
you walked out my door, ergo-
I was ready for the next step.
You weren't. Ergo, I walked.
It was a little more complicated
than that.
I just wanted
to share an apartment.
What was so complicated about that?
- There were a lot of variables to consider.
- No, there weren't.
There was you and me.
No variables, no math.
It was actually the simplest thing in the world.
- But like always, Reed, your head got in the way.
- No, it didn't.
Then what was it?
Did you feel anything when I left?
Do you feel anything right now?
Hey, guys.!
I think we have a serious problem.
Thank you.
- How are you feeling?
- Fine. I'm good.
Thank you for
coming out to see me.
- You said it was urgent, so-
- It is.
There's, uh, something
we need to talk about.
Something I need
to ask you.
Victor, wait a second. Um, I appreciate
everything you've done for me...
- but I think it's a bad idea for us to get involved.
- Just listen.
What are you doing?
I didn't bring you here...
to talk about us.
Please, this is business.
I need to know, how close is Reed
to finding a cure?
He's been working
'round the clock.
- The data needs to be tested and
analyzed before- - Same old Reed.
All analysis, no action.
Wasn't that the problem
with you two?
If the molecules aren't stable, it could
make us worse- maybe even kill us.
Then why is Reed
dragging his feet?
Maybe he likes having
his prize specimen under a glass.
It's ironic,
isn't it?
You're finally the perfect woman for him
because you're his science project.
- Please don't make this a personal matter.
- I think you already have.
Victor, we can't do anything
until the research is ready.
"We"?
Don't forget who
you work for, Susan.
So get to work
and do your job.
I wish my wife
would disappear.
So, what's the prognosis?
Your tissue,your organs,your entire
biophysical structure is changing.
Every system is still
functioning somehow.
And it's changing into?
I don't really know.
Some kind of organic metallic alloy.
Stronger than titanium
or carbon steel.
Harder than diamonds.
Like the shields
Reed said would protect us.
How long?
At this rate, the infection could be
complete in two, maybe three weeks.
What do you mean, complete?
I wish I could tell you.
I can't pretend to know
what we're dealing with here.
- I'll have to notify the C.D.C.
- What?
- The Center for Disease Control.
- I know what it is.
If this thing is contagious,
we may have a big problem on our hands.
I'm talking about an epidemic here.
Look at me.
I have a life. I'm the... face
of a billion-dollar company.
We need to keep this confidential.
Victor, this disease is progressive,
degenerative. I have to notify someone.
That's terrible news.
I think I'll get a second opinion.
Our uniforms were exposed
to the storm, like us...
so they can transform like us...
becoming invisible, changing size on demand
or remaining impervious to flame.
You guys look like an '80s rock band.
You know, Ben,
this material stretches.
I'm sure I can figure out a way to make it fit.
I wouldn't be caught dead
wearing that.
I love these costumes! They're missing
something, though. Needs, like, spice-
- They're not costumes.
- You can't use your powers in public,Johnny.
You guys are worse than NASA.
Johnny-
Maybe it's missing a utility belt.
If we can build a machine to recreate
the storm, we can reverse the polarity.
- And reverse the mutations.
- Curing countless diseases, not just ours.
But we're the focus,
right, Reed?
- Reed?
- Yeah, of course. Of course.
And you're sure you can
control this thing?
- Because last time it didn't work out so well.
- With the right amount...
of energy we can stabilize
the storm.
Maybe tie in
to the city grid.
You know, you really
need a janitor.
I bet this is what it looks like
inside your head.
- Oh!
- Sue!
That's okay.
- My fault.
- No problem.
- Hi.
- Did it just get really hot in here?
- Yeah. It-Yeah.
It's weird.
Yeah, it's-Whoo.
Whoo!
- Is this your floor?
- No. I was gonna- It's broken or somethin'.
- You guys goin' up?
- Is it hot in here?
Yes.
Listen, I'll call you
about that drink, okay?
- Good-bye.
- Bye-bye.
I'll talk to you later.
Bye.
It's like a sauna in here.
It's been like this
all day.
There you go.
There's your change.
Can I help you, buddy?
- Oh, my-
- It's Sue Storm.!
- It's the Invisible Woman!
- Hey,you're right.!
Sue Storm.! It is you.!
Listen, my kid loves you.!
I can't believe
I'm doing this again!
All right, I'm here. Let's make this quick.
I got places to go today.
Oh, wait. I don't go anywhere.
Johnny, it's imperative that we
stay inside for the foreseeable future.
I know, I know, Reed, but when you
said that last time my brain hurt a week.
Johnny, it's too dangerous
for you to be in public.
You've been saying that for years.
What worries me
is that our powers are evolving.
I know. I know!
I am so close to flying, guys, I can taste it.
- You can't fly.
- Yet.
- Johnny, can you put that napkin out?
- Oh,Jesus.
What's going on?
How you gonna cure us?
I'm gonna build a machine
to re-create the storm.
The cosmic rays will travel
from this generator to this chamber.
What, no pop-ups?
If I can reverse the wave signal-
It'll return us back to normal.
- Huh.
- Right. But what are the risks?
Even a small miscalculation could
increase our symptoms exponentially.
Or perhaps even kill us.
Now, dying- that's bad, right?
I say wejust let sleeping dogs lie, guys.
- So, how long till this contraption's up and runnin'?
- It's hard to say.
- How long, Reed?
- I don't know-
You don't know?
- You don't want this to get worse.
- Worse than that?
Guys, look, we're gonna
be stuck here for a while.
So let's just try and get along.
- Ohh!
- You could knock!
Sorry!
Johnny!
Reporter ] More bad news
for Von Doom Industries today...
as Ned Cecil announced
that his group of investors...
would seek to gain control of Victor
Von Doom's numerous technology companies.
Earlier, the I.P.O.
was pulled from the market...
after the steady decline
of its projected opening price.
Von Doom Industries was never able
to overcome the negative publicity-
Interesting.
Oh, you've gotta be kidding.
Hello?
Victor?
What's with these lights? Huh?
About the I.P.O.-
no hard feelings, right?
Nothing personal.
You know, you could always
move back to Latveria...
and start fresh.
Maybe that's where you belong-
the old country.
Nothing personal, Ned...
but I'm not going anywhere.
Surprise!
Are you surprised?
I'm surprised the fire
department didn't shut this thing down.
All right. Make a wish.
God.
I was good-lookin'.
- What did you wish for?
- I already got it.
- Everything I wished for.
- Okay, everybody!
How's it hanging, Ben?
Announcer ] Assassinating
competitions everywhere this season.
Truly unbelievable.
The crowd is going nuts here at the arena.
- If there's anybody out there
who can do what these guys do...
we dare you
to come on down here.
Look at this- spread-eagle, no arm,
back of the seat motobike grab.
I gotta get outta here.
Incredible performance,
vaulting him into first place.
Virtually impossible to pull off.
Hey, pretty boy.
Let's see what you got.
Where's your hot sister
and the monster?
Let's go!
Whoo!
All right! All right!
I want you all to make a lot of noise now
for a very special guest!
Mr. Johnny Storm
from the Fantastic Four.!
Whoa.! Look at that lift.!
That was fantastic.!
Hey,Johnny.!
Come on.! That's old school.!
Show us somethin'new.!
Something new.
You got it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! No!
Come on,Johnny! Come on!
- Is he flying?
- Wait- No!
That... is dangerous.
I'm okay. I'm all right.
I'm good.
He's okay! He's all right!
Johnny Storm,
ladies and gentlemen.!
I have to give you props,Johnny.
You were on fire.!
That's new.
Reed!
Reed! Have you read
any of these?
They're from all over.
People wanting us to fight crimes...
save their kids,
solve their problems.
Reed.
We can't even
solve our own.
No.! No freakin'way.!
Ben? Ben, what's going on?
What's wrong?
Cheering ]
- He didn't.
Oh, yes, he did!
Flame boy never listens!
What did he do to his uniform?
Woman ]
You've made history in Moto-X.
- I've gotta ask you about this outfit.
- It's Armani meets astronaut.
- So, what are your superhero names?
- They call me the Human Torch.
Ladies call me Torch.
- What about the rest of the team?
- That's the Invisible Girl.
- "Girl"?
- Reed Richards? I hear you call him Mr. Fantastic.
- Could have been worse.
- I guess.
Is it true what they say, that he
can expand any part ofhis anatomy?
Whoo!
I've always found him to be a little limp.
What is that?
What do you call that thing?
That's it. The Thing.
You think this is bad?
You should have seen him before.
Okay, now I'm gonna go kill him.
- Sweet,Johnny!
- I love you,Johnny.
There he is.
- Johnny-
- Look, can we talk about this later, guys?
No, we can't.
What are you thinking?
Where's my ride?
You think that's funny, Pebbles?
Johnny! You gave us names?
You don't think!
So now you're the face
of the Fantastic Four?
A face that's about to be broken!
This isn't permanent. We need to
be careful until we're normal again.
What if I don't want to be normal?
I didn't turn into a monster!
Johnny, say you're sorry.
Huh? Did you just-
- That's it, Tinker Bell! You wanna fly? Then fly!
- No, Ben.
Wait a minute, guys.
- Ben, don't do this.
- Let's see if we can get blood from a stone.
Let's see. Bring it, Burnout!
You two need a time-out!
- Talk to Blockhead. He started it!
- I don't care!
Damn it,Johnny!
Ben, wait!
What?
You need to control yourself
and think before you act.
Yeah, but that's your problem-
you always think, you never act.
What if we got these powers for a reason?
What if it's like some higher calling?
- Higher calling? Like getting girls and making money?
- Is there any higher?
You know what, Reed?
This is who we are.
Accept it.
Or better yet...
enjoy it.
- Wait, Ben! Slow down!
- Hey, check it out.!
He didn't mean it.
- You know Johnny. He's always been a hothead.
- It ain't him.
It's them.!
I can't live like this.
Just give Reed a little more time.
You know how he works.
Analyzing every little step
before he takes one.
- It's easy for you to be patient.
- No, it's not!
I thought I was done
waiting for Reed, but I-
We're all in this together, Ben.
Together?
Susie, look at me.
You got no idea what I'd-
what I'd give to be invisible.
Thank you, gentlemen.
I'm just going to pick up a few things...
for some friends.
Perfect.
That's not funny.
This is Ben Grimm here...
the first mook from Brooklyn to go
into outer space, so pay him some respect.
- Just give me the usual, and I'm out.
- All right.
Make it a double.
Make it a triple.
Put it on my tab, Ernie.
- You got it, sweetheart.
- Appreciate it.
No problem.
It's okay, Ben.
If there's a God, He hates me.
She... is not so into hate.
If you could see me,
you wouldn't be saying that.
Then let me see you. Can I?
It's okay.
Whoa.
Wow.
Huh.
So sad.
Hey, now, being different
isn't always a bad thing.
Trust me.
This ain't one of them times.
Not if you don't want it to be.
All right, Ernie,
I'm outta here.
- I'll take you.
- See you later, Benny.
I'm Alicia, by the way.
Thanks, Ernie.
Reed got what he wanted...
and everything he wanted...
he took from me.
Now it's time...
to take it back.
But first I need to get rid
ofhis... bodyguard.
This seat taken?
What are you doin' here?
I was worried about you.
You were worried about me? That's sweet.
Come on. Let me buy you
something to eat.
Looks like you could
use the company.
Reed?
I was just resting my eyes.
So I see.
The new readouts
look very promising.
Not promising enough.
When are the next tests?
I've run out of plants.
So I was thinking maybe...
there's always me.
No. It's too soon.
- Reed.
- I should get back to work.
You need a break.
- Sue, not now. Please.
- Come on. Let's go.
Remember our first date here?
God, I was nervous.
You know, I bribed the projectionist
ten bucks to keep the place open late.
- Really? I gave him 20.
- Mm.
- No. No way.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- I didn't want that night to end.
- Oh, Sue.
You were right.
It wasn't complicated.
I just wasn't ready to-
You always talked about
how you liked the kind of man...
who could approach you,
speak his mind.
One who wasn't afraid to tell you
exactly what he wanted.
I did... but I wanted you
to be that man.
Why didn't you
say something?
Reed, I'm saying it now.
That's my nose, genius.
Remember this place?
Of course. This is where
I first asked you out.
I think it was me
that asked you.
Oh. Right.
Well, you can be a little intimidating.
A girl can grow old waiting around
for you to take charge.
- Well, we can't all be as bold as-
- As who? Victor?
You know,
there is no me and Victor.
Never was.
Well, I guess that's what I thought
you always wanted.
A stronger man.
I did, Reed.
But I wanted you to be that man.
Well, why didn't you say so?
I guess it kind of would have
defeated the purpose.
But I'm saying it now.
So take charge.
That's not fair.
Excuse me.
I know it's not easy.
Life hasn't changed that much
for Reed, Sue orJohnny.
At least they can still go out in public.
But for you-
If you're tryin' to cheer me up, you're doin'
a hell of a job. Know what I mean, Scarface?
I'm just saying I know what it's like
to lose something that you love...
to see it slip away
and know it's never coming back.
Look, Reed is gonna
fix me up. Okay?
For your sake,
I hope you're right.
Look, he's a brilliant man. We should all
trust that he's working as hard as he can.
You're his best friend.
So what possible reason could he have
for taking his time?
I mean, other than
spending more time with Sue.
I figured the only way
for me to get you in here...
was to put that
in the window.
How'd you know
it was me?
'Cause I'm blind,
not deaf.
So, what do you think?
Eyebrows are a little big.
Please.
You have to come in.
Whoa! I'm not up
for a party.
- I'm not dressed.
- Relax. It's casual.
Well, what I mean is,
I'm a little... dusty.
I can take care of that.
Come on.
Those your puppets too?
Those are my stepdad's.
I try to stick to more
mature work-
the kind that brings
big, strong men into the door.
You could've just put out an ad
in the personals.
Oh, yeah. "Sensual blind chick...
seeks deep, spiritual connection
with a two-ton, rock-hard he-man. "
Hey! This ain't permanent.
My friend Reed's
lookin' for a cure.
I hope.
You feel okay
to me, Benny.
Oh, you don't know what it's like
to be out there, walkin' around...
like some kind of circus freak,
people starin' at ya...
- whisperin'.
- Yeah. I wouldn't know anything about that.
- I-I- - How many astronauts did
you know growing up in Brooklyn?
- Uh-
- None. Right?
But you dared to be different.
You didn't care what
anybody else did or said...
or thought.
So why start now?
You gonna let me finish?
Yeah. Why not?
Good...
'cause we got
a party to get to.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Hi, guys.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Hey, guys, I'm sorry. I gotta take a rain check.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Need a ride?
- I hope you don't mind.
- No, no.
Gotta take care
of the fans, right?
Look, I built my business
knowing what people want.
- Right now, people want you.
- Thank you, Victor. I'm flattered.
- We don't wanna let the people down.
- No, we don't.
Which is why we need to strike
while the iron's hot.
I'm talking video games,
action figures.
- Sponsors.
- Action figures?
- Really? -
Hmm. - Mm-hmm.
You talk to Reed
and Sue about this?
Johnny, let's
be honest here.
Reed, Sue, Ben-
Good people, all...
but stars?
I don't wanna break up the band,
but you're the one that people want.
- That's right, baby. It's all about you.
- Mm.
Don't you think
it's time to go solo?
Take the car for a spin.
Think about it.
Is this the life you want?
Or would you rather live in Reed's lab?
Hi. So this is it.
You okay?
- I guess so.
- Good.
Come on in.
Check it out.
I'm gonna get us some
beers or wine or somethin'.
They always let the blind girl
to the head of the line.
Oh, hi!
Thanks.
I don't know about this one.
It lacks a certain realism.
She's always had a thing for runaways
and strays, but this is ridiculous.
I know. Does she really think
these sculptures are gonna sell?
Who would want this thing in their house?
The girl's a one-woman charity.
Mm.
Benny?
It's true.
Yeah.
I have that effect
on people.
- Ben.
- Oh.!
So you remember my name
now, do ya?
Well, do you also remember what you swore
to do with every breath in your body?
We're working
as hard as we can.
Yeah, I can tell.
- Victor was right.
- Victor?
I don't know if this thing will change us back
or make us worse.
I need you to be patient
for a little while longer.
- Reed, look at me!
- I am looking! That's why I can't make a mistake!
I've gotta get it right,
and it's not right yet!
I spent my whole life protecting you,
and for what?
So you could play Twister with your girlfriend
while I'm the Freak of the Week?
- Ben, stop it!
- You stay out of this, Susie.
Stop it, or I will.
Get off me, Rubber Boy!
You guys, quit it.!
Ben.!
Calm down!
Good thing you're flexible enough
to watch your own back...
'cause I ain't doin' it no more.
You two are on your own.
Hey, look what
the marketing guys gave me.
Check it out. Listen.
You'll love this.
It's clobberin' time!
It's catchy. Right?
Isn't that great?
It's clobberin't-
That was the prototype!
Ben!
- Johnny, have you seen Ben?
- Yeah. Sunshine just left.
Look, Sue, I'm sorry.
I can't stay in this freak show.
I gotta get back to the real world.
You're calling that the real world?
You're not Mom.
Don't talk to me like I'm a little boy.
Maybe I would if you stopped
acting like one.
Do you even hear yourself?
Who do you think you are?
Why is everyone on my ass? If you guys
are jealous, fine. I didn't expect it from you.
You really think those people out there
care about you?
You're just a fad to them,Johnny.
Let's try something new.
You live your life, I'll live mine.
Sound good?
Oh, andjust for the record-
They love me!
Oh, God.
Reed.
Oh, my God, Reed.
What did you do?
- I can make it work.
- No!
I need more power
to control the storm.
- More power?
- You need a doctor.
- Come with me.
- Sue-
- One more try.
- You need rest.
Leonard? Bring Ben Grimm
to the Baxter Building.
Mr. Grimm?
They need you
back at the Baxter Building.
It's Reed.
Thank you. Want another one?
You want one more?
All right!
Thank you.
Hey. Johnny Storm.
Human Torch.
Listen, you wanna
get outta here?
- Is this your boyfriend?
- Is that all you do?
Bar tricks, stealing chicks.
What are you doin'?
You could've burned somebody.
You know, if I had your powers,
I'd be doin' somethin' with it...
not wastin' my time
doin' cheap tricks in bars.
Ben. Come in.
What is this?
Where's Reed?
Where do you think?
With Sue.
I'll take it from here,
Leonard.
Uh, yes, sir.
What do you want, Vic?
To help you.
The machine is ready.
- But Reed said it wouldn't be-
- He also said we'd avoid that storm in space.
But we all know
how that turned out.
He couldn't generate enough power
for the machine to reach critical mass.
Yet another mistake for Mr. Fantastic.
- And you can?
- Yes.
Tell me...
do you want to be Ben Grimm again?
Oh, thank you!
Vic?
Vic!
Vic, it worked!
Vic?
Everyone thought I was safe
behind those shields.
Oh, my God.
- The machine worked for me. It can work for you too.
- Oh, it did.
It worked perfectly.
You planned this.
I've always wanted power.
Now I have an unlimited supply.
And no Thing to stand in your way.
Take a good look, Ben.
This is what a man looks like
who embraces his destiny.
One down, three to go.
Vic?
Right on cue.
Ben?
- What did you do?
- Exactly what I said I would.
I built a better, stronger being...
and outsmarted
the great Reed Richards.
If you've exposed yourself to the storm,
you're endangering your life.
- You need help.
- You always know best.
So tell me...
what happens
when you super-heat rubber?
Mr. Von Doom. Are you okay?
Never better,Jimmy.
Why the long face?
Let's talk in my office.
Ben! Ben!
- Sue.!
- Johnny! The machine worked!
Give me a hand.!
- Come on.
- Ben!
Get his arm.
You all right, Ben?
Put him on the step.
What happened, big guy?
I leave you for five minutes-
The machine.
Vic used it on himself.
He was affected
by the cloud like us.
- Where's Reed?
- Vic must have taken him.
Dr. Richards,
allow me to begin your lesson-
Chemistry 101.
What happens to rubber...
when it's super-cooled?
Hmm? Give up?
That's not like you, Reed.
After all, we're both doctors.
Painful?
You don't know
the meaning of the word.
Just a little something
from our defense contracts.
Let's check in on the rest
of the family, shall we?
Oh, no.
- We gotta get out ofhere.
- I got an idea.
- Don't even think about it.
- Never do.
What are you doing?
Johnny, no.!
Come on! Come on, come on!
Flame on!
Whoo-hoo!
- We have to help Reed.
- It's too dangerous for you now. You have to stay here.
What did I do?
Whoa!
Come on! Think!
Two down, two to go.
- Sue.
- Shh.
What has he done to you?
How romantic.
Victor, please.
Call me Doom.
The machine works.
It worked on Ben. It can work on you.
We can turn you back.
Do you really think fate turned us into gods
so we could refuse these gifts?
Victor, you always thought
you were a god. Now back off.
Susan, let's not fight.
No, let's.
Susan, you're fired!
To think I was about
to share my life with you.
Marco.
Polo.
Marc-
Did you say good-bye
to your brotherJohnny?
It's time to end this.
No, Vic. It's clobberin'time.!
Damn, I been waitin' to do that.
Susie. You okay?
Victor ain't that bad, huh? Hmph.
He's just a little
larger than life, right?
Maybe next time
you'll listen to me before-
Ben!
Sorry, ladies.
- Stop the car! Stop the car!
- Pull over?
The brakes!
This is the police.!
Put your hands up
and step down from the vehicle.!
Take him out.!
Ladies, I'm gonna need
to borrow your car.
- The transmission sticks.
- Not gonna be a problem!
Good-bye, Ben.
I can't let you do that.
Reed?
I'll be right with you.
Hello, Susan.
You three are pathetic.
You missed me.
Had a little relapse, huh?
Welcome back.
This is gonna be fun.
I can't hold it.!
Johnny! Supernova!
- I thought we agreed that was bad!
- Now!
- Ben!
- Gotcha!
Sue! Think you can contain it?
Flame on, kid.
Is that the best you can do? A little heat?
Time for your lesson- Chem 101.
What happens when you
rapidly cool hot metal?
Ben.!
Whoa.
You done good, kid.
Come on.
Sue, are you okay?
Yeah.
Man, I love this job.
Job, huh?
Well, we do have the suits.
Group Singing ]
- Ladies, your drinks.
- I don't think we need another.
- Just one more.
- Thank you so much.
Cheers.
Oh. Oh! I need names and shots.
Bartender!
Custom-made-
36-quadruple "E."
Look, I've been crunching
the numbers on the machine...
and if I could rework the power-
Forget about it, egghead.
I'm good as is.
Better than good, baby.
You just need to work on your touch.
Mmm, I like the sound of that.
- Can I talk to you for a second?
- Sure.
Thanks.
I found a broken gasket
from space.
A gasket? Reed, come on.
We're at a party.
And if one of us were to wear it-
No more thinking.
No more variables.
Sue Storm...
will you marry me?
Sue, you kinda need to...
say something.
Oh! Yes. Yes.
That's my nose, genius.
These are my lips.
Aww. She's kissin'him.
They're so cute.!
- Congratulations.!
- About time,you guys.
Hey, no more wisecracks
about the way I look.
Hey, call me Mr. Sensitivity.
Okay, wide load coming through!
Everybody move! He's huge!
- Come here, Mr. Sensitive.
- Flame on!
Show-off!
How long will it be?
Should be about 12 days.
Aw, come on.
What's wrong with this thing?
Ready.