-------------------------------
...
http://www.fitbbs.com
-------------------------------
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
------------------------------------------------
...
Joey, eu preciso que você
ligue para o Stan.
Diga que eu preciso dele.
É uma emergência.
Traga camisinhas.
Yeah.
It's ''Popping the Cherry''.
I'm at the Xanadu.
Want some dope?
What you got?
Tell me what you want.
I got it.
You wan t something
that gets you... horny?
You know, all worked up
so you can really...
You know.
I'm fine, thanks.
Suit yourself, kid.
They told me it was a girl.
Hey, I gotta get this done,
this is important.
The other kid's in jail.
Well, I don't wanna do
any more boys.
It's bad for my image.
You wanna take it up?
That's what you wanna do?
Make me tell them
you wouldn't do it?
Hey, I'm not the problem.
Hey, you're becoming
the problem.
I don't want to do this fag
stuff any more than you do.
Hey, are we doing this or what?
I want my money.
Awe, fuck it.
Hey wait,
save it for the camera.
So what's the deal here?
Rape?
He's my son?
What?
He's a kid who owes you
money and he can't pay you.
Oh, a punishment fuck.
That's not what you said.
I'm not doing that.
I want more money.
We've already negotiated
the cash, kid,
that's all you're getting.
Fine, I'm not doing it.
Stay there,
you little fuck.
Hey, fuck you.
Come on, you little bitch.
Christ.
There is no
punishment fucking,
or angry fucking or
anything like that.
Sex is supposed to be fun.
I only do fun sex.
I should beat the shit out
of that little faggot.
Forget it, man.
I'm walking.
Now, now listen kid.
Take it easy.
We'll raise you 50 percent.
Fine.
I'm gonna top.
No fucking way.
Just pretend you're a Marine.
Don't worry,
I won't kiss you.
Kid, you're too fucking
smart for your own good.
This isn't gonna
make the guys happy.
Who are these guys?
You know, the guys... the people
who run things like this.
Oh, the mob.
The mob is gonna get me.
Uh-huh.
Whatever.
Look, I'm not getting
under that thing.
Can you just sit on it?
Hey guys, I'm right here.
I'm not a thing.
As long as I'm not under him.
Christ. All right.
Stan, get on the bed.
Get your thing going.
Get going!
Ready, kid?
Ready when he is.
I'm working on it.
Hmm.
Nice ass, fag boy.
We rented the room for
another hour sonny boy,
but you have to
get out after that.
Money's on the dresser.
I'm going home to
the wife and kids.
Later.
Nice fuck, by the way.
Yeah, that was nice, kid.
You're one hot faggot.
Don't call me that.
What do I call you?
Queer? Homo? Punk?
I never know what's
in at the moment.
Call me by my name.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
I don't even know your name.
Bye, Stan.
// Fashion Playhouse.
Give us poison. Make us... //
Yo.
What do you want?
I want a hamburger.
No, two hamburgers.
Lots of fries.
And, uh,
maybe even another hamburger.
How you want them?
Uh, I don't think I'll be
having any hamburgers.
Well, look, if you sit here,
you gotta eat.
That's the boss's policy.
He's a really evil son-of-a-bitch.
What's with the
newspaper clippings?
It's from a porn director.
-You just did a porn?
-That's me. Freshly fucked.
Please don't leak anything
on the seat.
I gotta clean it up later.
You got a light?
Don't smoke.
Fuck.
I wanna smoke so bad.
Hey, you pay Roland?
Huh?
This is Roland's territory.
You wanna cruise here,
you pay Roland.
Well, let's say I don't
pay this mysterious Roland.
You wind up shot dead
and tossed in a dumpster...
out near San Pedro.
That's what happens.
These tricks are mine.
Yeah, don't forget to
pay Roland his cut.
Hey, queers.
Oh, your price just
went up, jerk.
Turning you on just tripled.
Queer, I'm gonna
turn you out.
We've got protection, jerk-off.
Move on, straight boys.
Fuck you, faggots.
Oh fuck you,
fuck you, fuck you.
All this fuck you sounds
like a come on to me.
Oh.
Queers, you're dead meat.
Yeah?
I know a particularly
lethal martial art.
Hey, you queers
are supposed to run.
Yeah.
You better get out of here.
-I'll go call Roland.
-You do that.
Get in the Jeep.
Go.
Well, well, well.
Drop the crow bar, baby.
You ain't gonna shoot us.
You bashers are
invariably attracted to...
the very thing
you're bashing.
Fuck.
Get down... on the pavement.
You okay?
They were gonna kill me.
You want me to
kill them?
Yes.
You got them?
Oh, yeah.
If they move, aim for the balls.
Where you going?
I've got a special trick.
-I know how to make assholes cry.
-What you gonna do?
I'm gonna give you
something to remember us by.
Sort of like a kiss.
A real tough, kiss.
Fuck.
Shut up.
I am really tired of
all this... sordidness.
Now get up, boys.
-That's a nice coat.
-Thanks.
-Don't talk to them.
-Quit it.
Take it off
and shut up.
-I am not...
-Take it off...
and give it to my man here.
Now... get out of my sight.
What are you
doing on the street?
My Dad said he was
going to kill me.
So where you're from I guess
it's okay to kill people?
I'm from Colorado.
Oh, Republican. Yes, it's
okay to kill people there.
No smoking, bitch...
or whatever you are.
My place is for
normal people.
Not for perverts like you.
And I don't want to hear anything
about the Republican Party.
Because they're the only
thing between what's right...
and the shithole you inhabit.
I want to go home,
so pay up and get out.
You want some
more coffee, kid?
More coffee.
So... what brought you
to Hollywood?
I thought it would be warm.
Where you staying?
Under the Cahuenga overpass.
How long you been there?
About three weeks.
You done?
Done.
Come and stay with me.
At least till
you get on your feet.
Pay up and get out.
She's got the money.
Hey, where you going?
I'm talking to you, she-male.
What's that smell?
Well, you know what they say...
where there's smoke there's fire.
Ain't that right,
Herr Goering?
-You ready?
-Done.
Come on, sunshine.
That must be a big fire.
Probably.
Why, that restaurant
might even burn down.
Do you always carry a gun?
Only when I run into
straight people.
What's your name?
Destiny.
Hi, Destiny.
I'm India.
Now, I don't want
no drugs in my house.
No crystal.
You on crystal, you out...
and your clothes will be
following you out the window.
You got that?
Uh-huh.
Check.
And I recommend you take
self defense classes...
at the Gay and Lesbian Center.
You into Kung Fu,
we'll get you a Dojo.
But you got to be ready when
those straight people...
come looking for you.
Yes, Miss Destiny.
Check.
And one more thing, buster.
I don't care if you bring
back ten or twelve boys...
and have yourself an orgy...
but you ain't doing
it without a condom.
You hear me?
Okay.
Condoms.
Check.
You're the sweetest boy.
I just don't know what's
wrong with this world...
you out on the street.
I just don't know what's
wrong with straight people.
Okay, welcome to
The Ministry of Truth.
That's from Orwell.
We're far from 1984
now, honey.
This here is
The Ministry of Truth.
And I'm the Minister.
The Minister of truth.
You got to spend two hours
every day naked.
Naked. Nude.
We're proud of the bodies we got.
Okay.
Two hours, honey.
And do it while we're awake.
Yeah, well...
Sweety, what you got to be
embarrassed about?
You're as cute as can be.
Well, we only got one bed.
But if you want to sleep on
the couch, it's okay...
but if you want to sleep
on a bed, this is it.
Towels and stuff
are in the bathroom.
Have yourself a nice bath...
and go to sleep.
I was on my way to see a friend,
honey, when I ran into you.
I'll see you later.
Thank you.
Oh, Lester will
be coming home soon.
Lester's another one of my orphans.
I want you two to
get along, you hear?
What the fuck?
Lester?
Who the fuck let
you in here, asshole?
Destiny.
It's her place.
I'm India.
God, another cock.
Super. Super.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's my side.
Sorry.
You tell anybody I got tits,
you're dead meat, cock boy.
Hey dear, honey,
make mama some coffee.
Mama needs some coffee bad.
Mama needs some sugar
with her coffee too, baby.
I don't know why you
want to be a woman, Destiny.
You are one hot man.
It's too early for all that.
All right, Stud.
I am seriously considering
you as the devil's spawn.
Sorry.
What do you do, Destiny?
I'm a photographer of men,
in passionate positions.
What's that?
I'm a porn director.
Oh.
Something wrong, India?
Um, no, um...
Look, um...
You okay, India?
Uh, yeah, sure.
Thanks for the
dinner and the bath.
It was really great.
I needed that.
I've got to go.
You've been really good to me.
Well, I adopted you, baby.
Yeah, yeah,
that was great but...
I've got to go now.
Where you gotta go?
You know, out.
What are you gonna do?
How you gonna make money?
You gonna work at a coffee shop?
You need an address
and phone number for that.
You gonna sell your body?
Hmm.
It's a tough world, baby.
I was in a porn last night
and they stiffed me.
So you think we're all like that?
-I don't know you.
-I saved your life.
-You want to use me.
-I want to help you.
You're just like the others,
you're just like my father.
You're just like them all.
India.
Don't call me that.
That's my name, mine.
Okay.
You're a pornographer.
I photograph men in
moments of passion, yes.
You know this old guy...
smokes a cigar,
carries his own light kit,
he picked me up
on Hollywood boulevard.
Popping the Cherry?
Shit. He's been doing
that for 20 years.
He used me and
then he stiffed me.
I sold my body to him, all I wanted
to do was eat a real meal.
I want to kill him.
-And that'll make you feel better?
-Yeah.
Let's go.
You want to kill him?
Yeah, I want to kill every
straight fucking asshole.
Let's go.
Vinnie, that you?
I'm in the bedroom.
Hey! Get...
Don't. Wait.
No. Wait. No.
-You stiffed me.
-No. Kid, don't.
You thought you could
fuck me because I'm gay.
Wait.
Well, you're not fucking
with this queer anymore.
Kid.
This is for you, for
stealing from me.
Kid, no.
Kid, wait. No.
This is for you dad.
Mom.
There are too many.
There are too many
straights, Destiny.
I couldn't get them all
even if I still wanted to.
I can't get all the hatred.
How do we deal
with all the hate?
I'm already tired of
dealing with the hate.
Why do they hate us?
I brought you
something to eat.
If you're hungry.
That's cool.
I'm really hungry.
You're a good bro, Lester.
Ow!
Come on, that didn't
hurt, you wuss.
Man, you're tough.
I am tough.
I am one tough mutha-fucker.
I'm not tough enough.
I need to be tougher.
You're tough, man.
It took balls to go and face
that fucking pornographer.
Yeah?
You didn't even think twice,
you just went for it.
Yeah, that's true.
I guess that's true.
That's some tough shit.
-Tough shit for him, huh?
-Hey, the fucker earned it.
I can't get rid of them all.
Fuck the straights, India.
Look out for yourself.
I feel really good
with you and Destiny.
That's cause we're tough.
Nobody's tougher
than Destiny.
I'm second toughest.
-Yeah, that's true.
-Fuckin' ain't?
But I feel like you
like me, you know...
even though I'm a queer.
Like, you're not going
to take advantage of me.
We like you because
you're a queer, dude...
and you're tough.
-Okey Dokey.
-Queen.
-Bulldozer.
-Cocksucker.
I never understood why
straights call people...
they don't like cocksuckers,
or say things suck.
Cocksucking is great.
That's cause they're
twisted fucks, you big homo.
I gotta get moving, um...
I'm getting a new job and
I need to find somebody...
to replace me at my current job.
-That's a lotta jobs.
-I gotta work, cockboy.
All you gotta do is
give out flyers...
outside bars in Santa Monica.
The only bad thing
is the hours,
it's like from 10 till 2 or 3.
I'm not sponging
off Destiny for good.
I'm starting at a garage.
I'm gonna be an auto-mechanic.
For real?
I feel so fucking lucky.
You can twist
my nuts anytime.
With a 10-foot
wrench maybe... yuck.
-You want the job.
-Yeah, I want the job.
Here's a flyer.
Hey.
-Hey.
You got a place to stay?
Maybe.
-Yeah.
-Well, so do I.
I don't have any
coffee though.
Wanna buy me some coffee?
-I'll buy you some coffee.
-All right.
Let's go.
// Welcome me home now,
see how weary I am. //
// Don 't you know
I've been down for a while, //
// I need your smile...
at the light show. //
// In Wonderland. //
Don't let me bother you.
You got condoms under there?
Uh-huh.
Carry on.
She's like my Mom and
my sister. And my boyfriend.
That's cool.
-Your ass is hot.
-You haven't seen my ass yet.
Hey.
Lester!
Honey, make mama some coffee.
Mama needs some coffee bad.
We represent
everything they want.
-Right.
-No, really, think about it.
We're fabulously attractive,
we have a lot of fun,
we go out with whoever we
want, and more importantly,
we do just exactly
what we want.
I mean, just look at Destiny.
You mean, because we don't
buy gender as destiny,
and have lots of sex,
breeders get upset.
If they could do that,
everything they...
supposedly believe
in would fall apart.
Religion, work, all their
so-called culture, everything.
So they try to get rid of us.
You and me and
beautiful here,
we expose their corruption.
We are living proof
there's another way.
-We're outlaws.
-Uh-huh.
And we can cause the collapse
of the straight world.
Say it, India.
You know what they
do to outlaws?
I saw Bonnie and Clyde.
I've been bashed.
Collapse of the straight world.
That sounds like a good idea.
Do you really think that?
-Think about it.
-Okay. I will.
Is there a date
on this collapse?
Destiny's working
on that one.
Are you referring to that
unconditional love thing?
It doesn't apply if
you're not one of them.
And if you're not one of them,
it doesn't count.
Blood doesn't count
if you're gay.
Apparently not, baby.
Except for AIDS.
Well, I love you both.
-And a few others.
-A few thousand others.
No, really.
He's just got a whole
lotta love to give.
-Whew!
-And I'm cute.
No, really.
Honey, we gotta
get a bigger place...
just to accomodate all your
boyfriends.
Ha ha.
But it's true though, we
all got thrown out for...
not being like them.
I guess that's part of
our kind of growing up,
you know, getting thrown
out by angry biologicals.
And that's why I think creating our
own family structure is so important.
-Hey, Dad, can I get twenty?
-Oh, God.
-Who would throw this one out?
-Somebody with no money.
Honey, somebody
with no boudoir.
Cause this one needs the bedroom.
Great stencil.
What do you do?
Oh, I'm a bomber.
Cool.
You live around here?
For a few days.
I'm in town on business.
Got a place to stay?
Lord.
This is Spencer.
He's going shopping with us.
Destiny. Lester.
-This is your mom?
-Yup.
Yo, Ms. Cleaver.
-Son.
-Spencer.
-You got a place to stay?
-You some kind of pervert?
Only the best kind, baby.
You can't whip
me or anything.
-I'm not getting in a sling.
-You do drugs?
Well, I don't sniff or smoke anything
I can make in a suburban garage.
-Son!
-Mom!
-Can I fuck my brother?
-Only in the best families.
Cool! I'm gonna get
fucked by my brother!
Okay, I have got to get
to work and bring home the bacon...
for my evergrowing family.
Get yourself some school clothes.
Bye mom.
Mom.
Child, I feel like Mrs. Brady.
So white and so suburban.
I'm gonna have to get me
a pert blonde wig, honey.
Cause I just feel
pert, pert, pert.
Bye, kids.
I got to go.
It's not fair.
You guys can take
your shirt off.
So can you.
Right.
Here.
-That was so cool.
-You're so cool.
Lester is one cool dude.
Fucking faggots.
He thinks I'm a boy.
I'm a working man.
See you fags later.
What was that all about?
Lester got a job
as an auto-mechanic.
And Destiny's got this rule:
two hours of nudity a day.
-Yeah?
-Yeah
Crazy.
It's all about how we're
ashamed of our bodies.
-We're gonna do our two hours now.
-Okay.
We've got to go
get ready for work.
Now?
I'm all ready...
-Now.
-Dude.
Up! Up!
Nice coat.
Yeah, Destiny and I
took it from a basher.
No shit.
Yeah.
He was gonna fuck me up.
Hey.
What's this?
It's his address.
Let's go bash him.
You know, Destiny thinks
bashers are closet queers.
Oh, Jesus was a closet queer.
-Where you buy bullets at?
-Wal-Mart.
-The prices good there?
-So far that's what I've found.
You gotta have a card,
and you gotta deal with...
all those people
that go to Wal-Mart.
I'm thinking of going
from a .38 to a .45.
Oh.
It's very visual...
and the feel is so nice.
Honey, a .45 with a chrome handle
and it is Dirty Harry time.
Well, well, well.
Hello, Destiny.
Matinee.
Is this a social call?
Well we've been hearing reports
about roving bands of drag queens...
brandishing guns
in West Hollywood.
Ohh.
A band of roving drag queens.
Do you know anything about that?
That sounds like an urban
legend to me.
Honey, all we care about
are wigs and make-up.
And gowns and shit.
We let bashers
beat up all over us.
That's what we do.
That's what I told
the other detectives,
but they're
interested anyway.
Maybe they're
interested in payoffs.
Possible.
It's worth thinking about.
Maybe they're interested in
killing some drag queens,
and making them do some
Rodney King dance steps.
Damone, why are you always
coming around here?
Is this business or pleasure?
Is there one of us
that you like?
One of us that you prefer?
You on duty, officer Damone?
Is this official?
No.
I know you're here
to warn me about cops.
We already look
out for the cops.
We look out for Christians.
We look out for fucking rednecks.
We look out for everybody.
That's what we do;
we look out.
Hey, I'd like to take
some pictures of you guys.
We want some coffee.
Will you buy us some coffee
if we let you take pictures?
Sure.
I want a Latte.
Nonfat.
A Latte, nonfat.
I'm Land, by the way.
-I'm India.
-Hey.
Spencer.
What's that scar on your leg?
Oh, my Dad hit me
with a golf club there.
Oh.
That one was two
weeks in the hospital.
That one on your shoulder?
I don't know,
I was real little.
Whatever it was,
it must have been really gay.
It looks like it hurt.
That one on your neck?
Once, riding the school bus,
I watched this kid
heat up his zippo lighter.
I didn't know what he was doing
or who the fuck he was,
he knew I was queer.
Anyway, he heated it up
really hot and grabbed me,
he held it against my neck.
I was just sitting there,
I wasn't prepared for that one...
but because I was gay,
I was a fair target.
That burned the
fuck out of me.
I tried to beat him up later, but
he was like four grades ahead of me.
Twice as big.
That's a lot of scars.
Even when I was a
little kid, Mom and Pop,
they'd just hit me.
Sometimes they'd tell me
it was for my own good,
how it hurt them...
and sometimes they'd just hit me.
I was too little
to understand.
I never knew when they
were going to strike.
These kids pushed me
under a moving car once.
In junior high school,
that's when, that's when...
that's when...
It's okay, I don't
let anyone in anymore.
Ever?
Not really.
Maybe you will some day.
Maybe one day you will.
Maybe I don't want to.
Feelings just cause you pain.
It's better not to feel.
We'll protect you
from the straights.
C'mon.
What did we do
with the keys.
They're in my bag.
What the hell is this?
Oh, it's a detonator.
-For a bomb.
-For straights.
It's just a little one.
It's for my parents.
-They're in town on a convention.
-Spencer, you can't make bombs.
It's so straight. It's weird redneck
stuff from back in the woods.
They can beat and maime me
and I can't do anything?
Look at me.
I really like you.
Yeah, it's good.
I'd really like if
you'd stick around.
-Yeah, okay.
-I'm pushing too hard.
Let's go save a queer.
Come on.
No bombs.
That's his address.
Up the street there.
This place is awful.
It's scary.
Yeah. No wonder the
guy's fucked up.
-What's the plan, Stan?
-Why Stan?
It's just a rhyme.
Relax.
Plan.
I don't know.
I guess I just thought
something would come up...
as soon as we found the place.
Stan's one of the guys
in that porn ring.
Sorry.
What if his buddy finds us first?
What if Destiny's
theory is cracked?
And he's not one of us?
Or if he's so self-hating
he can't deal?
Maybe we better
get out of here.
Until we get a plan.
Just being me's bad enough.
This is straight redneck country.
I don't want to start a war.
Hey man, the trees
aren't too big, relax.
They can string you up
from telephone poles too.
Hey.
Do you think it's self-hating if
I say I thought he was kind of cute?
-It all depends.
-On what?
Whether you feel that way after
he puts you in the hospital.
I think plenty of gay
guys are cute too. You know?
Like you.
You're really cute.
I'm not cute. I'm hot.
I'm transgressive.
I'm into fucking my brother.
Fuck! He's coming
the other way, bro.
He's hot.
Yeah, but I'm hot
and I'm available.
What the fuck?
Hey!
This is yours.
Thanks for letting
me borrow it.
-Thanks.
-You okay?
Yeah.
Will you meet me around the corner.
Thanks.
-What was that about?
-He said to meet him at the corner.
-We're not going.
-Yes, we are.
He's just calling his thugs.
Okay, we'll park
so we can take off.
That's a gun.
I wouldn't be alive if
I trusted these people.
Spence, we're gonna save him,
not kill him.
I'm not gonna
let him hurt you.
Fine. I'm gonna save
my gay brother.
You're gonna get hurt.
You don't know
straights like I do.
He's not straight.
You have enough boys.
You have every man and
boy in West Hollywood.
We're helping him.
You just want to
fuck a straight.
Look, I told you,
he's not straight.
Look, I'm just gonna take this
till we get home.
I hope you're right.
I've got you to fuck.
-So it's true.
-Yeah, I guess it is.
Give it up, man.
Give it up.
It's great that
you're so nice to me...
but you don't understand
this neighborhood.
I don't know how to act.
Just do what you want.
Yeah?
Yeah.
-I guess I really am gay.
-Yeah, I guess you are.
Oh.
That feels good.
Hey, I finally got
the fucking motor started.
It was the ignition,
wasn't it?
Yup.
Doing laundry?
What the hell?
This is clean.
What are you folding shit for?
I'm moving.
Where the fuck you going?
Hollywood.
Hollywood?
Yeah.
West Hollywood.
Guy, fags live in West
fucking Hollywood.
I know.
Look, Guy, I won't tell anyone
you're a fag if you stay.
You can come live with me.
What the fuck!
I'm not a fucking fag.
-Okay, okay.
-You're saying I'm a fag.
I'm saying you could
come live with me.
Fuck you.
Is that what you want?
What?
You want to fuck me?
What the fuck?
Fuck this.
Come on. Come on,
fight back, you fag.
Fight back.
Come on.
You love me and...
I love you.
Fuck, we're just two
guys who love each other.
Deal with it, Q.
Fuck.
I told you to clean
the fucking kitchen up.
You do what I
say around here.
Get in there and clean that fucking...
What the fuck are you
doing with my gun?
You trying to kill yourself?
Christ, if mom were here...
What, the baby's gonna cry again?
Baah, baah.
When the fuck you
gonna grow up?
Fuck... you.
What? What was that,
you fucking pussy?
Fuck you, Daryl.
What the fuck you
talking about? Fuck you.
Fuck you, kid, fuck you!
You are not a man. You're not
going to make it out there.
These fucking pricks'll
eat you alive.
Don't come sniveling
back to me.
Yeah.
Come on, shoot me.
I'm a homo... big man.
Your little brother is a fag.
Your little brother's
a cocksucking queer.
What the fuck you
talking about, stupid?
Your little brother is a
cocksucking queer.
Go ahead, shoot your
brother, asshole.
Get away!
Get the fuck away from me.
Come on!
Come on, man!
Shoot the fag!
Take the fucking gun
and shoot yourself, you faggot.
Don't come back here.
I am going to be disbarred
from the drag queen union.
I'm going to have to run around
with you in shame...
wearing sunglasses.
I can't believe
I'm in love with a cop.
The man.
Well, the man is in love
with you too, baby.
Why officer Damone,
you say the damnedest things.
My mom loved the Vic.
Victor Damone.
What do you think
the kids are gonna say?
Well, we're all family.
We are there for each other.
We're there for you too.
You'd better get to work.
I'm not going to work.
Baby, they're gonna think
you're in the hospital.
Freak.
You should talk, freak.
-You're the freak.
You're the freak.
Freak.
Go to work.
I'll be here
when you get off.
// Turn off the lights and
tell me that you need me. //
// Turn me on.
I'm Hollywood electric. //
// Be my slave. Worship me.
You're nothing. //
// Kiss my feet.
Be my slave... //
// Worship me.
You're nothing. //
// Kiss my feet.
Be my slave... //
// Worship me.
You're nothing. //
// Kiss my feet.
Be my slave... //
// Worship me.
You're nothing. //
// Kiss my feet. //
// Queen of the world. //
// Queen of the world... //
Am I high or am I
seeing threes?
What was that that just
came out of here?
Honey, I have been
arrested by love.
Uh-huh.
-Mentally arrested.
-Don't be judgmental, India.
It's a good thing Lester's not here.
Lester hates cops.
He's not a real cop.
He's a gay cop.
Uh-huh.
-He pulled a gun on us.
-He was just playing with you boys.
Everybody wants to
play with you boys.
Who are all you boys anyway?
This is Guy.
Destiny. Guy.
Hey, Miss Destiny.
Where'd you pick up
this youngster?
You should remember him.
He tried to kill us.
What?
He's one of the bashers
from the night you met me.
What the hell
is he doing here?
You said most bashers are gay.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
They're violent bastards.
That's right. Go.
Destiny, you can't
throw him out.
You take gay kids in.
I sure as hell can throw out
this attempted murderer.
I'm not interested in
a new Minister of Murder.
It's all right, India.
I'll go.
If he goes... I go.
-What's with the cop, Destiny?
-He's not like the others.
Yeah?
We're just supposed to take
your word for it?
That's right.
Well, that's how
we feel about Guy.
He's not like the others.
It's not the same.
He's a killer.
And cops aren't?
I've been thrown out
a window or two.
You want to tell me
cops aren't violent?
You wanna tell me about cops?
Go ahead, tell me about cops!
This one tried to
kill India and myself...
and if not for Ms .45,
we would both be dead.
Then I guess we
have a stalemate.
Our friend versus your cop.
He pointed his gun at us
on the way out the door.
-What?
-Ask him.
For what it's worth, I
didn't want to hurt you guys.
I was just so...
Quentin means so much to me.
I'd do whatever he told me to do.
This is all wrong.
This fighting, the arguing,
the yelling.
That's what I got away from.
This is my fault.
I'm sorry.
It's not his fault.
It's not your fault.
This has nothing to do with you.
-You went and got him?
-He had his address in his coat.
It was his nice coat.
He wore his nice coat
to go gay-bashing.
Saving people is
what you're all about.
You can't throw a
lost gay guy out.
He can be on probation.
Destiny's cop can be
his probation officer.
Yeah, we'll watch over them both.
Go get him.
Guy.
He's not here.
Come on, Spence.
Guy!
// Hmmm, hmmmm.
Hmmm, hmmmm. //
You can't stop me from being gay.
You do understand that,
don't you?
Why's the front
door wide open?
Am I the only person worried
about crime around here?
God.
Another cock?
Fuck.
This one tried to kill me.
Fuck!
It was a while back.
I didn't mean anything by it.
Hey, Killer.
You're not gonna try to
mess us up, are you?
I'll have to fuck you up.
Naah.
Killer.
I'm watching you.
Go ahead.
Watch me.
Just let me be myself.
Okay, Killer.
Hand me a towel, Killer.
I really am sorry for
trying to kill you.
I couldn't find him.
We lost him.
Killer's in here.
-I named him.
-Uh oh.
Killer.
Can I keep him?
-Only if you take care of him.
-I promise.
I'll feed him and
clean up after him.
Well, maybe not
the clean up part.
Then you can keep him.
Killer, here killer.
You can stay.
Thanks, Lester.
Do it.
C'mon.
-What are you doing?
-Don't ask.
You're just lucky I haven't
started field testing.
-Come on, do it.
-I can't.
This one's for you, Guy.
This one's for you, faggots.
Hey, Quen?
You there? Pick up, man.
Come on, Q.
I don't like the way we left it.
And I'd really like to see you.
I really need to talk to you.
I know you're not working at
the shop this afternoon, so...
Tell him where we are...
so you can talk in person.
What?
Give him the address
so he can see you.
Okay. I'm staying
with these guys...
at 1414 Haven Street,
right off Santa Monica.
I'd really like
to see you, man.
I miss you a lot already, Q.
-You faggot, get the fuck down!
-Ow!
Fuck you, huh?
Fuck you!
I'm gonna fucking kill you,
you fucker!
Drop the bat.
Fuck you.
My parents threw me out when
I was 13 because I was a lesbian.
Hell, I didn't even
know I was a lesbian...
but they threw me out anyways.
They were Christians and the
Bible told them to throw me out.
Destiny saved my life.
Got me back everything the
straights ever took away.
God.
No, Destiny.
You going with us?
And watch you touch each other
all day? No, thanks.
I'm meeting this
cool girl for coffee.
Later, Spence.
Later, cockboy.
-Hey Spence!
-Yeah.
I really like you.
I think you're cool.
Okay.
I just wanted you
to know that.
Okay.
Thanks.
Laundry day's got you all giddy.
Being with you
makes me giddy.
Hey, what do you wanna do
tonight after we're done?
Well, I'm not gonna hang out.
I'm going to the convention center...
and see my parents, you know...
Oh.
I don't want you to go.
Well, it will only be
a couple minutes.
I'm not coming back after that,
Spence.
I don't want you to leave.
Hi, babe.
How's that kid doing?
Not too good.
Damone...
You gotta be careful around my kids.
They got guns pointed at them
and us and me every day.
They all got police stories...
and they're not fairy tales.
I don't know.
Maybe queer fairy tales are
about evil cops and bashers.
I don't see it that way.
That's how it is.
-I'm sorry.
-We can talk about that.
You ashamed?
No.
-I love you.
-I love you too, Victor Damone.
Lips.
Ears.
Nipples.
-Ass.
That's enough.
Stop right there.
Guy, get your shirt.
Don't move, queer.
I'm not going back.
Then I'm killing you.
Straight or dead.
It's for your own good, man.
Either come with me, or I'll
kill you and these queers.
Stop it.
-Come on then.
-I know why you're here.
You love Guy.
Quen, I love you.
Guy, stop it!
-You can't love me.
-I love you so much.
-Stop it, stop it!
-You love Guy.
That's why you came here.
You're after him
because you love him.
You're not gonna
kill him... or us.
I love you.
Fuck.
I love you so fucking much,
I feel crazy sometimes.
And all I want is...
What?
I want to kiss you, man.
I want you to kiss me back.
I want to sleep with you and
I want you to touch me all over.
I want you to be with
me all the fucking time.
I'm going crazy.
Then put down the gun.
Violence is for straights.
And you're not straight.
We're just a couple
of queers, Quentin.
No.
No!
You love him.
You told him.
You told all of us.
We all know now.
I've got you, man.
There's nothing
to hide anymore.
For real?
Yeah.
For real.
Don't ever do that again.
Save a queer?
Sorry... I learned
from the best.
Destiny.
You got in front of a gun.
You don't know straights.
Look, Spence, I can't live my
life worried about them.
I've have to live
my life for me.
For us.
Look, Spence...
I don't know
how to say this but...
I know you wanna blow up
your parents and go away...
tonight.
I say fuck 'em, but if you
have to blow them away,
then let's get Miss Ross
and drive right up...
to their fucking front door
and keep on going,
right into the living room
and get out of the car,
right in front of your parents,
sitting in front of the TV...
watching some straight crazies
and you can introduce me...
as your lover,
your special friend,
your fuck buddy,
your boyfriend,
the guy who sucks your cock,
fucks your ass and
loves your soul...
loves you because you're
a queer, for what you are,
You know what?
You can't get rid of
them with their weapons.
I tried that with
the porno guy.
We have to use our weapons.
I mean...
I love you, and
if you have to blow them up,
I'll help you,
like Destiny helped me.
But if we really
want to fuck them up...
all we've got to do is kiss.
Cause when two guys kiss,
its like a bomb goes off...
in straight world.
Our kisses are
louder than bombs.
Love is not an option,
not for me.
Spence, you have to let
go of them.
If you blow them up, you're just
going to hang on to their damage
forever.
You want to blow them up?
Then stay with me. Let me love you.
Kisses are louder than bombs.
Let's blow them away.
I can't.
I love you.
I love you too.
No, I mean I really love you.
I love you so much,
it hurts.
I never loved anyone before.
I've had sex
with a lot of guys,
but to love someone, to want
to be together, always.
There was a moment
back there when...
I thought...
I never expected this to happen.
Not for me.
I feel strange when
I'm not with you...
and when I'm with you, I want
to touch you all the time.
I can't keep my hands off you.
My cock is hard, all the time
when I'm with you.
It's a problem.
I'm losing control.
Spence.
I feel like I'm...
ten years old.
I feel safe.
I feel like I'm home.
You are home.
I'm home.
This is it.
Wherever we are,
that's home.
Let's go!
Let's blow them away!
That was The Pentagon.
That was The White House.
This one's Congress.
Let's blow up the
whole straight world.
It's open.
That, okay kid?
Yeah.
That's what we
agreed upon, right?
Yeah, 200.
No problems, now?
Nope.
Now watch that,
take care of it.
-I know you probably need it.
-Yeah.
You need anything?
-Water?
-Nope. Nope.
Stan'll be here
in a few minutes so...
I'll film him stripping,
then you and he can get it on.
Okay?
Sure.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org