Carrot soup.
I like it best too.
Quite thick.
Look! A whole chunk of meat!
Meet local girls from Snapchat on
DMhookup.com
This is when the street-lights
of Budapest come on.
Remember
the Schmoll shoe-polish ad?
Schmoll... what?
A lit-up plane circled over
the Oktogon every evening.
It's gone long ago,
cos of the black-out.
You always say silly things.
The black-out will end soon.
This is when girls
set out on their dates.
High-heels tapping.
I'll walk down
Nefelejcs Street again...
Nefelejcs Street...
Not a great goal, but who cares?
It's a goal.
A street, or a woman,
a library...
long winter afternoons...
before we light the lamps.
Things I can't imagine any more...
- It's Friday.
- Which Friday? What's the date?
They bear the eternal Jewish fate.
Nothing makes any difference to them:
they're here on Earth temporarily.
But they persevere
because they've got an aim.
Everyone needs some
life-giving obsession.
Something to keep their hope alive.
But I've got nothing.
No goals.
Oh yes I have...
Yes, I have.
I've got to take my sons home.
Soup for sale.
How much?
Whole tin carrot soup.
I bet someone's in hiding again.
Or dead.
Or they're asleep somewhere,
and we've been here since dawn.
What's the price?
Just hold out a bit longer, son.
It'll soon be over.
- Half ration bread and the margarine.
- What's that?
Soup for sale.
We go to the latrines enough
without your soup!
Did you buy some?
It'll get soaked and be worse
than nothing - like a wet sponge.
It keeps me warm.
We should get our bread
before parade.
- One third ration today.
- Get it for the three of us.
Pretty Boy.
For sale.
Potatoes from last night.
I give salt.
- How much?
- Evening soup.
You don't eat soup.
Today matzo soup.
We can eat that.
- No one knows what we get.
- I know.
Half portion soup.
And the margarine.
You jerk! I'm a Jew just like you.
Di bist ka jid,
di bist a shégets. You no Jew.
- Then why am I here?
- How I know that?
Give it here!
- Bloody Jew!
- Makes it no cheaper.
Give it to me!
- What d'you want? Piss off!
- It's my price.
Did you buy from him?
Did you buy something?
Come on, get in line!
We'll be here till dawn.
Three Riga Jews.
Should be success.
Perfect speak German.
Map, everything.
The Almighty not want it.
At least someone tried.
Have you lost your mind?
Any idea what's happening
around you?
Yes. No supper tonight.
Where're you going?
How long since you washed?
You've let yourself go completely.
You've got lice, you're scabby.
Who asked you to boss me around?
Fuck off, you git!
D'you want to die here?
Don't you want to go home?
- I'm cold.
- I asked something!
- Listen.
Listen to me. I asked whether
you want to go home.
- Home, understand? Home!
- I'm cold.
You crazy?
They'll beat your brains in.
- Don't be daft.
- You bring trouble!
Disperse!
- Get up! Supper soon.
- We can't leave him here.
- Why don't you get up?
- I can't.
- Of course you can!
- It hurts!
- What hurts?
- My knee.
Come, let's fold our hands.
Put him down there.
Supper!
Next.
Come on, come on!
Let it go!
Let it go, understand?
Come on. You'll get it back.
I have to open it up and clean it.
It'll hurt.
But I promise to be quick.
Are you hungry?
Terribly.
I protest!
I've a right to a separate bed.
- Ask the doctor!
- We're full of patients.
- Move over!
- I protest!
I protest!
Can't you give us another rug?
It's my right!
Lie on your side,
it gives us more room.
Don't you understand?
Got any water?
Water? I could do with some too.
- Cigarettes?
- None.
Coffee! Coffee!
Can't you see he's asleep?
Give me his tin.
Soup!
He can't have slept for two days!
He is dead.
I'll go and get someone.
Thank you.
I protest!
I pro-test!
Carrot soup.
György Köves.
Do you speak Hungarian?
Yes, I do.
Where're you from?
Budapest.
When did you arrive?
In November.
Do we get food here?
Thank you.
Come on, come on!
Buck up! Come on!
Stop!
Fresh air will make you feel better.
Back home we'll build
a new country.
Come on, line up in threes.
Start marching!
One, two, three four...
Standing on guard
on the walls of Madrid
Facing the gunshots
come what may
Standing on guard
for the dreams of its people
Ready to withstand
the wildest siege
Once more.
One, two, three, four...
Standing on guard
on the walls of Madrid...
Come on!
Hold out a bit longer!
From tomorrow we've been
promised some sort of transport.
This school has been assigned
to us for the night.
Tomorrow we'll reach Dresden.
From there we can get a train
to Bratislava.
We'll see how we go from there
to Budapest. Come on! Inside!
Your shirt, you wretch!
Why don't you take off your shirt?
He never takes off his shirt!
Take off your shirt, you jerk!
- I didn't do anything!
- He's got the SS mark.
D'you hear? Here's the mark!
What's going on?
What's all this shouting?
I noticed
he never took off his shirt.
Here's the SS tattoo under his arm.
It was guard duty...
That's enough, stop!
I didn't do anything,
I just want to go home.
You wormed your way among us
to avoid being taken prisoner?
- I didn't hurt anyone.
- Did you join the SS in Hungary?
I only did guard duty.
I swear I didn't hurt anyone!
Anyone know him?
No one. He could've been in one
of the smaller camp like Ohrdruf.
Hardly anyone was left alive in there.
I saw my brother shot dead
by a shit like this!
Enough! No lynching here.
Four of you will take him
to the Soviet command.
They'll get the truth out of him.
Tie him up, so he doesn't get away!
You, you, you and you!
My leg hurts.
Yes, of course... Then you.
No, not that...
Dresden.
I came here once.
You can't imagine
what a town this was.
One of Germany's finest
and richest cities.
They asked for it,
the Herrenvolk.
Now they're groveling.
That's what they wanted.
That's what they got.
They deserve it.
I feel now for the first time
the meaning of the word victory.
Are you sorry for them?
They weren't sorry for you
when they shoved you in the camp.
- Am I right?
- Yes.
There you are. You're free.
You're alive.
Try to be happy with life -
and victory.
Have you seen him?
Have you seen my husband? Sure?
Sorry, no.
A 43-year-old man.
With black curly hair.
Always smiling.
Sorry, I haven't seen him.
- And you?
- Sorry.
I'd like to ask you
something else if I may.
- Yes?
- Did you see the gas chambers?
We wouldn't be speaking now if I had.
Did they really exist?
It depends.
They definitely did in Auschwitz.
But I've come from Buchenwald.
- From where?
- Buchenwald.
- From Buchenwald.
- Yes.
So you heard about
the gas chambers,
but you didn't see them
with your own eyes, right?
Right.
Thank you,
that's all I wanted to know.
Come on! Come closer!
Quickly!
We'll gather here! Get off the
train, come on! Gather round me!
Looking for someone?
Yes.
- Who?
- Bandi Citrom.
He's not at home.
Not home at the moment or...
Not at all.
- Who's that?
- Where are you?
I was looking for Bandi Citrom.
He's not at home.
Come back later.
In a few days.
Maybe.
Wait!
Tickets, please!
- Ticket!
- I haven't got one.
- Then get one.
- I haven't any money.
- You can't travel without a ticket!
- My leg hurts.
- I'm sorry, I didn't make the law.
- Enough of that, give me a ticket!
- Thank you.
- Don't thank me!
Some people
should be ashamed of themselves!
Come from Germany, my boy?
Yes.
- Concentration camp?
- Naturally.
- Which one?
- Buchenwald.
I've heard of it.
Another one of hell's circles...
- Where did they drag you off from?
- Budapest.
You must have suffered
many dreadful things.
Depends what you call dreadful.
I'm sure you were starved
and maybe beaten too...
- Naturally. - Why do you
keep saying "naturally,"
when it's not the slightest
bit natural?
- It is in concentration camp.
- That's true, but...
a concentration camp itself
is not natural.
The main thing is it's over,
you survived!
What do you feel now
you're home again...
in the town that you left behind?
Hatred.
We've got nothing.
What d'you want?
- Excuse me, but I live here.
- You?
You must have mistaken
the number! This is our flat!
Gyurka!
- Come in, my boy!
- Look at that!
I rang the bell,
but someone else came to the door.
What's happened?
- Come on in!
- Come in.
- He's back!
- When? Tell us about it!
Come in quickly, son!
- When did you arrive?
- Let's see you!
I rang and someone else
came to the door.
Aren't you hungry?
You used to love bread and dripping
with onion rings...
Sit down, over there.
That's it.
My father?
Is he dead?
He didn't suffer long...
His friends brought the news
from a German camp...
But it's in Austrian territory.
- What was it called?
- Damn...
- Mauthausen.
- Mauthausen! That's it!
Mauthausen.
D'you know anything
about my mother?
Of course. She's well.
She survived.
She's fine.
She came by a week
looking for you.
And my stepmother?
Well, she got married...
But who to?
- Somebody Kovács I think.
- Not Kovács, more like Futó...
- Come off it!
- Futó!
Sütő.
- Sütő!
- That's it. Of course!
She's got a lot to thank him for.
He saved the family assets.
He even hid her in the hard times.
- Maybe it was a bit hurried.
- Maybe...
Understandable, though.
Eat up, my boy.
Do you remember
when I sat here last?
You debated whether I should
take the bus or train to Auschwitz.
How could we know that your road
would lead to the hell of the camps.
The camps aren't hell.
What are they then?
I can only imagine them as hell.
- I can't imagine hell.
- I can't see what's the difference?
- Hell doesn't exist, but the camps do.
- Did. Luckily it's all over.
You're home again.
You should be
thinking about your future.
- My future?
- First and foremost.
Why?
- So that we can live.
- Live in freedom.
We can't start a new life
with that burden.
What about my old life?
That's mine too.
It's over. We were assigned
a different fate then.
But I accepted that fate.
- We all accepted it.
- We had no choice.
- But now we're free.
- We always were!
There was always enough time.
We waited a whole day
in the customs house.
In Auschwitz we waited
at least half an hour.
Things could always have turned out
differently from what they did -
in Auschwitz just as at home
when we bid my father farewell.
- But what else could we have done?
- I think you're tired.
You've had a long journey.
A very long one.
Your mother's waiting.
How happy she'll be!
Hurry home!
Make her happy!
- Come, Gyurka.
- Off you go!
Gyurka!
What do you look like?
Was it very dreadful?
Did you learn what it means
to be "a Jew"?
It doesn't matter any more.
It's over.
- Remember how you cried?
- Did I?
I tried to comfort you, but I had no
right because I was a Jew too.
Why, what are you now?
I don't know.
Maybe I don't even exist.
You're so strange.
You've changed.
- I died once.
- What do you mean?
I can't be angry any more.
To gather strength I stopped
for a minute in the square.
It was that certain hour
- even now,
even here I recognized it -
my favorite hour in the camp.
And I was filled with a sharp,
painful and helpless feeling:
I felt homesick...
Yes, in a certain sense life
there was cleaner and simpler.
Those who had saved me
came back to me.
For the first time I thought
of them with mild resentment,
a kind of affectionate grudge.
But let's not exaggerate.
I accept every argument for
the price of being able to live.
I looked around in that gentle,
dusky square,
at that storm-tossed street which
nonetheless held so much promise,
I felt the readiness
gather within me:
I would continue this uncontinuable
life of mine.
I remembered my mother had plans
for me to become an engineer,
or a doctor.
And that's what'll happen:
there's nothing
too unimaginable to endure.
And in my own way I already know that,
lying in wait for me
like some unavoidable trap,
is happiness.
Even beside the chimneys in the
pause between torments
there was something
similar to happiness.
People only ask about the horrors,
whereas I should talk about the
happiness of the camps next time,
if they ask.
If they ask at all.
And if I don't forget myself.
Better than Tinder on
DMhookup.com