Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Fay?
Are you okay?
I'm afraid.
Why? Has something happened?
I'm afraid for my son.
He's 14.
Boys have been known to survive that, Fay.
I'm afraid he'll grow up to be...
...well... like his father.
I know... I know what you're thinking.
Forgive the man...
...nobody's perfect.
But I go forgive him.
I always did.
That's my problem.
I mean, like, who was Henry anyway?
We lived together for 7 years.
Had a child. Shared a home.
And I don't even know where he came from.
You must miss him very much, I think.
Excuse me.
Hi, it's Fay.
Fay.
Thank you for coming.
This is the end of the line for you, Mister.
- But, Mom...
- Sit up straight.
Let's step inside.
Ned brought this pornographic
device to school today...
...and was caught showing it off
to the other children.
- What is it?
- See for yourself.
- Mom, you got to turn it on.
- Where?
It has a crank thing on the side.
Wow...
That's cool, huh?
Where did you get this?
It came in the mail.
- Whose mail?
- Our mail.
- Since when do you open the mail?
- It was addressed to me.
Well, then who sent it to you?
I don't know.
There was no return address or letter or anything.
It's an orgy.
Yeah, I know that, Ned.
Fay, where he got it is not the issue.
The point is he can't bring
this sort of thing into the school.
You're grounded like... forever.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Fay.
Can I have a word with you in private?
It's no secret in this school,
or in this town, of course...
That Ned's father was no model citizen.
Tell me about it.
I took back my maiden name.
Yes... your maiden name.
But it is also not lost on your neighbors
or Ned's classmate that his uncle...
...your brother, is the notorious
and controversial poet, Simon Grim.
Yes. We're very proud of Simon.
Fay, your bother is in a state penitentiary.
So?
Well he's hardly a role model.
Ned can't help who his family is.
Fay.
Have you ever thought of moving
to a different town?
Hello.
- Good afternoon, Fay.
- Hi.
Mister James is expecting you.
Can I take these?
This way please.
Fay, Hello. I'm Angus.
It's nice to meet you finally after all these years.
You're not going to stop publishing
Simon's poetry are you?
What? No.
His royalty checks are the only thing
we have to live on, we just moved to a new home.
No, no, not at all. Please. Fay, no.
Simon's been a gold mine.
I'd be insane to drop him.
And don't you worry about those royalty checks.
And if I may say so...
I consider Simon my friend.
Oh. Yeah. Okay.
Nevertheless,
and you might be surprised to hear this... Fay.
Iconoclastic avant garde... poetry of
the kind your brother has come to personify.
This marginal yet vital form
of artistic expression...
...is becoming less and less popular in America.
- Oh no, really?
- Yes, but I have an idea.
Fay, are you aware that I once read
your husband's book? His Confessions?
Yes, Simon tried to get you to publish them.
That's right, he did.
And I decided against it...
...even though Simon threatened to renege
on our deal to publish his own poetry.
I remember.
It was a trying time.
To be perfectly frank, Fay...
...I must tell youl thought
Henry's book was quite bad.
- Simon thought so too.
- Yes, he did.
Nevertheless...
Since your brother's trial five years ago,
things have changed.
Simon, you're being charged with the
willful obstruction of justice...
...aiding and abetting a known criminal...
...of falsifying official documents.
Why would a world... famous poet,
a literary celebrity,
stoop to help a man of such
negligible redeeming value
at such cost to his
own reputation and livelihood?
He was my friend.
Or was it what he was carrying was more
valuable in your eyes than the pursuit of justice!
What was he carrying, Simon?
What did Henry Fool have with him...
...as he boarded that flight
to Sweden pretending to be you.
His book. His Confessions.
Eight or so notebooks.
And some extra shirts.
As a result of all this,
Simon Grim fans the world over...
...as well as his most fierce
and dedicated detractors...
...have seized upon this mysterious friend,
Henry Fool, and his fabled Confessions...
...as an essential key
to the deeper understanding of the incarcerated
garbage man poet of Woodside, Queens.
It's been great for business.
But, you see, it won't last forever.
Henry is larger than life now.
And his Confessions a desperately sought
after commodity now.
The time to strike is now. We've got to get
our hands on those books and publish them.
But they're bad, right?
Not worth publishing.
You said so yourself.
Well, we can't be too hard-line
about these things, Fay.
Anything capable of being sold...
...can be worth publishing.
You haven't...
I mean... Henry hasn't...
you know... Been in contact with you.
Has he?
No.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I realize you must... well, miss the man.
I hope I never see him again.
Really...
I mean it.
I'm single.
Sort of.
I was wondering...
Yeah?
Well, I was wondering if, perhaps,..
I was wondering if you'd care to have dinner
with me some night this week?
You mean, like, you know... a date?
I'm afraid so.
Agent Fulbright, CIA.
This is Agent Fogg,
but you can call him Carl.
Hi.
How did you get in here?
We're professionals, Fay.
They teach us stuff like that, at the Academy.
Fay, we'd like to ask you some questions
about your husband.
When will this end?
How long are you going to harass me!
I have no idea where my husband is!
I'm single. Sort of.
Yeah, we know. But the case
is still open and new evidence has arisen.
Evidence of what?
Fay, where were you...
...when Henry boarded that plane for Sweden?
At home, I didn't go to the airport.
Only my brother Simon was with him.
We went over all this during the trial.
But Simon didn't actually see him board
the plane. Did he?
Your brother last saw Henry at the departure
gate, having by already then...
...successfully forged documents permitting him
to leave the country under a false identity.
Well, yeah. But so what?
Well so, maybe he never got on the plane.
Why wouldn't he have gotten on the plane?
He was in trouble. He was running away.
That was the whole point.
Last minute pangs of conscience?
Conscience? Henry? Please.
He may have suddenly felt full force
the love that he had for you, his son...
...his friends, the community.
Easy, Carl.
Henry would have gotten on that plane.
And, anyway, if you ask me,
its what he should have done.
Fay, he killed a man.
It was an accident.
He was defending himself.
The man he killed was gross.
Do you really have so little faith in society?
I mean... why are you so certain
Henry wouldn't have been exonerated?
Carl, that's enough. Fay, look.
It appears that Henry boarded
the plane posing as your brother Simon.
But he didn't get off the plane in Stockholm.
Which makes us think that
he had an accomplice at the airport.
You mean, besides Simon?
Does the name Konchalovsky
mean anything to you?
- No.
- Bebe.
Bebe Konchalovsky.
We understand that Henry kept a diary,
some kind of a journal, many volumes.
What he referred to as his Confessions.
Yeah so?
Did you ever read this book?
These Confessions?
A little. Once. By accident.
Could you tell us about what you've read?
I'd rather not.
Was it treasonous?
Did it seem to discuss subjects potentially dangerous
to the security of the United States of America?
I just read the dirty parts.
The dirty parts?
You get that, Carl?
Got it.
What are you saying,
that Henry was some sort of a spy?
Or worse...
Look, Fay...
What?
Fay, Henry's dead.
Ma, you okay?
Yeah.
Did you eat?
I'll make something.
What time is it? Where have you been?
It's 7:30.
I was at the library. Didn't they call you?
Who?
The school.
I had my cell phone turned off.
Why? What happened now?
I've been expelled.
Ma?
Ma? You okay?
Go eat.
Don't do anything... drastic.
Like what... drown myself because
you've been expelled from school?
Go away and leave me alone!
Conceited little monster.
Then after all that the school calls
and tells me Ned's been caught getting a blow job
from these two 16 year old girls right down
the hall from the Principal's office.
Now he's expelled.
Wait a minute. Back up.
They actually said Henry's dead?
When? Where?
Berlin, Germany. Two days after he ran away.
And you believe them?
They're the CIA, Simon.
The Government of
the United States Of America.
God! Get with it.
Do you have the package from Angus?
They think there was an accomplice
at the airport.
- You mean, besides me?
- Yes.
There was no accomplice at the airport.
But you didn't actually see him
get on the plane, did you?
Well, no, not exactly. But...
What wouldn't he have gotten on the plane?
He was running away.
That was the whole point.
Maybe he had, you know, second thoughts.
Maybe he felt all at once the... the ahh...
What?
Forget it Simon,
you've got to get out of jail.
I can't handle all this on my own.
Ned needs a father figure or something.
What do you want me to do, escape?
You might be eligible for early parole
on account of your good behavior.
Ask.
I won't be eligible for another couple of years.
We can't wait that long!
They'll send Ned to reform school.
He'll be in prison before he's...
...old enough to get a driver's license.
Look, if you need anything at all,
just ask Angus.
She's got a date with him.
What?
He's taking her to the theater...
...and supper and stuff.
Calls her all the time.
Evaporate.
See you later.
You're dating my publisher?
You got a problem with that?
Simon.
I spent a lot of time
and money tracking this book down.
I'm fairly certain it is book
six of Henry Fool's Confession.
If it's for real, keep it with you.
It's safer there.
I'm beginning to think
your suspicions are correct.
I chose not to tell Fay everything.
Perhaps the less she knows the safer she'll be.
We'll talk soon.
Yours, etc. Angus.
I want Simon released from prison.
That's not as easy as it sounds, Fay.
The Governor's gonna kick and scream...
...if the feds try to negotiate his release!
You understand, don't you, Carl?
I mean, he is up for parole soon.
Years from now. Forget it.
Carl, go take a walk in the rain.
Bye Carl.
Leave him alone.
He likes me.
That's his problem.
I won't cooperate unless Simon
is released from prison.
Ok. We'll see what we can do about your brother.
But I'm not promising anything.
Now, will you do it or not?
What do you want me to do, exactly?
I mean, what's this all about?
That's not how it works, Fay.
We tell you just enough
for you to complete your mission.
Then, if all goes well and
we decide to move on, we tell you more.
It's called plausible denyabilty, Mom.
Why isn't this kid at school?
- Ned, go upstairs.
- I'm hungry.
Here. Go buy yourself a pizza, scram.
French Secret Service have
two books of Henry's Confession.
Really? Where'd they get them?
They were found in the possession
of a notorious drug smuggler
who swears he got them
from Bebe Konchalovsky.
And who is that?
Nobody knows for sure.
A terrorist.
Wanted by the Russians,
the Israelis, the French, and us.
What would terrorists want
with Henry's notebooks?
What would anybody want
from Henry's notebooks?
Got me.
The books contain information the French
can use to blackmail the United States.
With what?
Who cares with what. Besides, it's classified.
Fulbright... Henry was a garbage man.
Yeah, for five years here in Woodside Queens,
he was a garbage man.
And?
So, what the hell was
he doing in Afghanistan in 1989, for instance?
- What?
- We have evidence Fay. Witnesses.
Luckily we got some bad dope
on the French at the moment
which might urge them to back off
if we get compromised.
Really? What do you need me for?
The French are in a tight spot.
The German's, the Belgians,
the Israelis, China...
...nobody wants the French to hand
over those books to the U.S.
However, there's a treaty, an old one,
and a loophole in that treaty...
...which prevents the French government
from impounding an American citizen's property...
...under certain narrowly defined conditions
which we have recently had broadened...
...due to the current unstable international
terrorist situation, etc.
So, the books written by Henry...
...and you are Henry's widow,
the books obviously belong to you.
The French will take a lot of crap
from the European Union...
...for a week or two, but then so what.
Believe me, Fay, this is critical.
And you're the only one
who can do what needs to be done.
I want Simon released from prison.
I think it's real.
Are you sure?
Angus, has it ever occurred to you...
...that, perhaps, Henry's Confessions were
simply too completely awful to be true?
You mean as in bad?
- Inept.
- Idiotic?
- Right.
- Oh yes, that was my first impression, certainly.
Try to remember what you read.
Try to peel away the layers of
masturbatory self indulgence.
The ego-maniacal rant, the paranoid obsessions,
the sexual preoccupation.
Would there be anything left?
Look over my left shoulder.
There's a prisoner down the row reading a book.
Yeah, I see him.
His name is Herzog.
He once worked for the CIA.
He was what they called...
...an encryption specialist.
He invented codes.
Go talk to him.
Ask him about operation Inferno.
He's expecting you.
I was the chief attache to the US operative in...
Bitch!
...in a certain South American...
country during it's first free and open elections.
Put that thing down.
Ned look, if I do this thing for them in Paris,
they're gonna get uncle Simon out of jail.
- No way!
- Yes way.
And besides it will give me
an opportunity to wear this nice coat...
...that Angus has got me.
Did your father ever tell you...
Unusual bedtime stories when I wasn't around.
Sure. All the time.
What were they about?
About the places he'd been to.
Things he got away with.
Those were the best ones.
Like what things?
He told me not to tell you.
Come on Ned, I mean it.
I promised.
You were 5 years old.
He had no right to make you promise anything.
But I did.
Do we have like a map of
the world or something?
Where's Afghanistan?
There.
- Did your father ever tell you about Afghanistan?
- Yeah.
Really?
Sure.
See, the mountains, here,
leading up to the Hindu Kush,
across the Himalayas, then on to Tibet.
He said he'd been there too?
He'd been everywhere.
See Jerusalem here.
Mecca. Iraq.
Rome. The Vatican-city.
The Pope threw a chair at him once.
Okay. Stop. That's enough.
Do you believe them?
Who?
Fulbright. You believe Dad's dead?
Hello?
He was shot in the street, returning to the office.
He'll be ok, they think.
He was very lucky. But he's raving.
They're getting ready to operate now.
- Angus!
- Fay, thank God!
Milla, get my trousers! Let's get out of here!
Angus, cool it! You've been shot. Calm down.
Listen, Fay, think!
You, Simon, and myself... are the only people
who ever read the Confessions.
You think you've been shot
because you've read Henry's notebooks?
Yes. Isn't it obvious?
No, it isn't.
Look, Fay...
I found one of Henry's books
and I had you smuggle it into Simon.
He's right, Henry was in South America.
In the 70's.
That's impossible.
He was an eye witness to
the overthrow of Governments there.
He mentions Fulbright by name.
Twice. And there's more...
Sorry, miss,
we've got to get him into surgery right away.
Fay, I'm sorry.
Someone knows we have that book
and they will kill to get it.
When you disembark at Paris
you go directly to the ladies room.
Before you clear customs.
It'll be on your left as you enter the terminal.
The operative will establish contact.
How?
Impossible to say.
Check the time before you enter the ladies room.
Wait only 5 minutes.
If contact isn't established in 5 minutes, abort.
If these guys don't get Uncle Simon out
of jail by six o'clock this evening...
...call me right away at the hotel
and leave a message.
Okay.
- You've got the number, right?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
You don't fly much do you?
I do, often.
It will be over in no time.
My name is Andre.
- Fay.
- Enchanted.
What's this?
Angus bought Mom a new couch.
Come on, Check out my new computer.
Simon, what are you doing out of jail?
What are you doing out of the hospital?
I'm a sitting duck in the hospital, Simon.
Someone's trying to kill me, haven't you heard?
You'd be safer in jail too.
Where's Fay?
She cut a deal with the Feds.
She's on her way to Paris
to retrieve two of Henry's books
How could you let her do that!
I didn't know until an hour ago.
She negotiated for my release.
Here, take a look at this. It came in the mail.
Wow.
- It's an orgy.
- It sure is.
You see, it was not so bad after all.
Thanks so much. I really enjoyed myself.
I am in Paris for the week.
- Perhaps I can see you again?
- Sure. Okay.
- Welcome home Simon.
- Thank you Father.
Sorry to get you out of bed so early.
We need your help.
You have to look into it and turn the crank.
Sorry Father.
We need to know about the writing on the wall...
...behind the three people, you know, on the...
Yes, on the wall behind
the two girls with the goat.
We thought it might be Latin.
Old. Ancient.
Hebrew maybe.
Semitic, certainly.
No, Slovak.
I can't tell really
with all the foreground debauchery.
Why is this important?
We think Henry might have sent it.
They told Fay he was dead.
And offered no proof.
Just hear-say. A rumor off the Internet.
Why would they deceive her?
Because the only way they can get those books
away from the French is if Fay is a widow.
The French?
What the French got to do with it?
And which books?
Simon, what's going on?
We think Fay's been roped in to some
kind of international espionage, Father.
By whom? And why?
I was mistaken about Henry's book
when I read it seven years ago.
It was not what I thought it was.
Keep this phone with you.
Clear customs, retrieve your luggage...
...and meet Monsieur Picard
and his people from the Ministry Of Security
just outside the baggage claim.
I will be in touch.
Father...
Look, father, this is book six.
Simon's fellow inmate, Herzog,
claims that in 1973...
Henrry was taught a basic but now
outdated CIA encrypting method...
...by one of his associates probably
this guy Fulbright.
You mean, its code.
Sort of, an old fashioned technique
of composing sentences...
...in some sort of consistent but
obscure relationship to a pre-existing text.
Whereas in the original text,
what's called the concordance...
...there is a noun,
in the new communique there is a verb.
Likewise, the placement of adverbs
and adjectives are reversed.
The result is usually gibberish
Well, you've both read it.
Is that how you describe Henry's Confession?
No. Illogical. Pedantic.
Contradictory. But not gibberish.
Using this method, only a certain type of
idiot savant would be capable of constructing...
...an intelligible alternate meaning,
however crazy, for the length of,
say, a sentence or two.
Henry wrote eight volumes.
How do we begin?
We'll need this to start.
Milton's Paradise Lost.
I believe it's the concordance.
Hello?
Listen carefully.
At the Ministry Of Security...
...the French will give you two books.
In one of those books, on the 17th page...
...two paragraphs from the bottom,
there will be a paragraph written
in blue ink rather than black.
The third sentence of this paragraph
will be in quotations.
Do you understand me?
Repeat it for me.
Page 17, second paragraph from the bottom
in blue ink, third sentence in quotations.
Good.
Afterwards, as you leave,
you will see a woman on the staircase.
She will drop her pen and
lean down to pick it up.
If either one of the notebooks have
a paragraph written in blue ink...
...on the 17th page
with the third sentence in quotations...
...hold the package containing them
in your left hand.
Otherwise, hold them in your right.
Do you understand?
- Yes.
- Good.
And then what?
Keep this phone with you,
turn off the ringer and put it on vibrate.
Place the books in the hotel safe.
Your work will be done.
What do you got Ned?
I've created a program,
where we type in the confession...
...the computer translates all the nouns
and the verbs and everything.
As long as it can recognize the concordance.
That means we'll have to type
in all of Paradise Lost too, won't we?
This could take days.
I found it online, Angus.
Now we just have to see if we can download
and import it into Ned's program.
Oh that's easy. Let me see.
My apologies. But it's crucial I think.
I bet.
What is it Rabbi, can you read it?
The dame with the big caboose
is always in the way.
Hold it!
There it is.
I see it. But I can't read it.
It's not Hebrew.
- Maybe it's Chinese.
- That's a Roman alphabet, Rabbi.
I'm not so sure.
Father, you know
I think this might be Arabic.
I am happy to say
they are not the words of the prophet.
But you can read it, right?
Yes I can.
But not because it's Arabic. It's Turkish.
- No!
- Oh yes.
Let me see that.
Am I wrong?
Well... No.
Maybe.
It says... how to translate?
It's a complaint.
The truth teller...
it's much more than that...
the one who says what is...
...will always be... what?
Odds with the world... against the grain.
An honest man is always in trouble.
Yes. In fact, yes, that is a rough,
but accurate translation.
Simon!
What is it?
An honest man is always in trouble.
That's the first line of Henry's Confession.
This is not just an orgy, Simon.
It's a harem.
Don't worry. It's just a precaution.
Having just narrowly escaped...
...death by torture in Chile during
the overthrow of the government there...
Henry surfaces in Nicaragua amazingly
and accidentally...
...as a double-agent for the Sandinistas
and the US backed Contras.
Soon enough, he's wanted dead
or alive by both sides.
Pursued by as he says the infernal "F" whom
I think we can take to mean Agent Fulbright.
He crosses Honduras, enters Belize,
and at the last possible minute...
...is given safe passage to Cuba by
some Hungarian Communists who later claim...
...that Henry sold them information about
the Iran Contra guns for hostages scandal.
Which later, here, in part 7, Henry denies,
claiming he knew nothing about it...
...and that the Hungarians were only
interested in his radical re-interpretation...
of Blake's Marriage Of Heaven And Hell
and, it seems certain of his chemistry experiments.
For which reason,
they promptly fly him to Bucharest.
Thanks, Milla.
Henry was a chemist?
More to the point, Father,
how old a chemist was Henry?
He drank too much and smoked constantly.
He slept little, ate badly, and lived hard.
It's difficult to say but Henry could
have been a ravaged man in his early 30's...
...or a well preserved 50 year old.
Didn't he have a driver's license, Simon.
- A passport?
- Not that I know of.
Hold on... Here it is.
Their marriage certificate.
What's it say?
Husband's date of birth, 1591.
A common error.
Surely he mean 1951.
That would make sense, right?
Barely, let me see that.
My American friend has a reservation.
Miss Hopper.
Like the painter.
Oh yes, Miss Hopper.
We have your luggage already in your room.
May I ask you for your passport?
May she place an item in the hotel safe?
Bien Sur.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry about this Fay. I really am.
So am I like, you know,
a hostage or something?
This is your receipt. Your passport.
This gentleman..will show you to your room.
Have a pleasant stay Miss Hopper.
You are not a hostage.
But you would not be safe if anyone
knew you were in Paris with these books.
I wish we had met under
different circumstances.
Me too...
Vous etes extraordinary.
Thanks.
Madam?
Yes?
Where are you?
I don't know.
Another hotel. Some other part of town.
Where are the books?
In the Hotel safe.
I have the receipt.
What's happening?
Don't worry. I'll find you.
Keep the phone on. I can trace it.
- Simon it's me.
- Fay...
...you should not have done this.
I had to get you out of prison,
Simon and see it worked.
Now Ned can get home schooling from a you
and I won't have to send him to reform school.
Listen, Fay,
this Agent Fulbright
has not been telling you the truth.
I don't care!
I'm just so glad that you're out of prison, Simon!
Fay. Henry's alive.
Fay?
Simon.
I'm sorry I realize that...
I was just getting used to the idea
that he was you know... dead.
- He isn't.
- How do you know that?
How can any of us know that?
This toy, this binocular thing
that came in the mail...
Hold on. There's someone at the door.
- Hello?
- Fay, it's me.
Andre?
Fay, please. We must talk.
Hold on, Simon.
- Simon, I gotta call you back.
- No, Fay wait.
Your contact is an imposter.
Fulbright's been tricked.
You know about Fulbright?
I worked with him in Afghanistan.
I was, in fact, a double agent...
...leaking his secrets to the Russians.
But he doesn't know that.
So what, you're like a spy or something?
You sound disappointed.
I thought you liked me.
I do.
I do like you.
That's why I feel I must warn you.
About what?
This woman who contacted you,
her name is Juliet...
...she's an agent of the Israeli Secret Service.
And so, is that like a bad thing?
Your husband seemed to know a good deal
about global satellite positioning systems.
Really?
Does that surprise you?
Each of those books you read today,
when placed side by side...
...list the exact coordinates of three US
satellites over a 10 month period in 1994.
Towards the middle of each,
certain words are written in red ink.
That's right.
But she told me to look
for a blue paragraph on page 17...
- With the third sentence in quotations.
- Right.
Proof that its the wrong book.
A decoy.
And it's not, is it?
There was no blue paragraph in either of them.
Now she knows they're real.
She will come for them.
You're in great danger
What's the big deal about
these satellite coordinates anyway?
They indicate the location of
an Israeli nuclear missile base.
And that's what, not allowed?
It's a violation of treaty?
- The missiles?
- And the satellites.
Look, I want to give you these.
Books one and two
of your husband's Confession.
The Russian Secret Service extorted them
from the North Koreans.
Who were led to believe
they contained instructions for scrambling...
...the radar for American Spy planes.
Why are you doing this?
Convince your friend Angus James to part
with the volume in his possession...
...book six. We know he has it.
You shot Angus.
Not myself, personally.
I'm sorry.
We needed to impress him.
Henry was working at a top secret facility
near Bucharest in 1988.
He disappeared driving a truck
carrying two tons of a poison no one else
in the world even knows about yet.
- It's still missing.
- You're lying! I knew the man.
I was married to him.
He was never in these places!
There was a scandal. I don't know the details.
A girl, her mother, the girl's cousin.
Anyway...
Think about it.
Think about Angus.
We need book six.
You will go to the concierge and present
your receipt for the item you placed in the safe.
Once you have received the item, we will
cross the lobby and enter the service staircase.
I will take the item and descend it
to the parking garage.
You'll continue to your room.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
There is a gun at your son's head
this very moment.
Pull yourself together. Let's do this.
It'll be over in a minute.
Mademoiselle?
Oh it's nothing. Sorry.
A man was just run over in the street.
I'd like the package I put in the safe please.
Shall I keep these?
Yeah sure, whatever. Thanks.
Well done.
Au revoir. Now, don't get me wrong.
I like Americans.
I'll take the notebooks, please.
Drop the gun Amin and hand me the books!
Milla, how can this be! I trusted you!
There will be no peace before Israel
is safe within its borders!
All right, come on. Get her out of here.
Hello.
Hey Ma! You won't believe
what's just happened!
Carl just arrested Milla.
She was about to blow my brains out!
Fay?
Miss Hopper?
Ca va?
It's all right, Miss. We'll take care of her.
- Sir.
- Picard?
He's been hit. Looks bad.
He's on the way to the hospital.
The Arab kid is wounded
and trapped in the alley.
Who gives a damn.
What about Konchalovsky?
- We lost her.
- Fuck!
They've apprehended the accomplice back
in New York.
Good. Keep me informed.
Fulbright! They were going to kill my son!
Fay, trust me,
we never would have let it go that far.
What?
Look what they did to her face.
- Is it bad?
- It becomes you.
Don't you dare flirt with me, Fulbright.
What happened in South America?
- What?
- And what's it got to do with Henry?
Who have you been talking to?
He mentions you by name. Twice.
I thought you hadn't read the Confessions.
Like I said, a little.
Once. By accident.
Yeah, I remember. Just the dirty parts.
He mentions you in the dirty parts.
Why are you asking this?
Because I want to know what's going on.
Oh yeah, since when?
Since you've decided you can use me
and my family as bait...
...for capturing some scary chick in high heels.
Henry was an operative of the CIA in Chile...
...during a time when it became necessary
for the United States...
- ...to help overthrow the government there.
- Why?
Why what?
Why'd we have to overthrow the government?
It was inappropriate
to the needs of the American economy.
Hey! Don't get all fuckin' sensitive on me...
...that coat you're wearing was most likely made
by a bunch of seven year-olds in Kuala Lampur.
- Really?
- Damn straight.
And you don't see the Malaysians going out
and electing communist governments, right?
I don't know.
Exactly, you don't know...
Civilization, Fay...
Shit happens.
Henry had been a janitor
at the University in Santiago...
...with his eyes on the chief librarian job.
We led him to believe
that we could help him with that.
That is, in exchange for information
he could gather from the school
which was crawling for Russian "advisors".
But aren't the Russian's our friends now?
Nobody's our friend, Fay. Remember that.
Times change. Alliances shift.
Something we were proud of a year ago...
all of a sudden becomes something we've got to
apologize for in front of the United fucking Nations.
Anyway, things went wrong.
Our contact in the military assassinated
the president's top general...
...and we were forced to back him up
and instigate a civil war.
Henry disappeared in all that.
It seems he was captured
by the opposition and tortured...
...forced to write a confession which reliable
sources indicate ran to something like 136 pages.
As far as we know, laying out the details of the
entire US espionage network in South America.
They tortured him?
Are you listening to me?
He was so afraid of pain.
You mean to tell me he never let
on to you about any of this?
Sometime he'd say things, but you know...
...Henry said all sorts of stuff.
It was hard to know what to believe.
Look Fay.
...look, I'm sorry we had to use you
and Ned to draw fire.
We've had Milla pegged for months nothing
would've happened to you or your son.
What about Angus?
Ok, I admit, that took us by surprise.
What we have to do now, though, is figure
out who exactly Konchalovsky's working for?
- The Israelis, apparently
- Impossible.
Whatever, Fulbright. It's your party after all.
Okay...
Suppose your right. How do you know this?
Andre told me.
Andre who?
You know, Andre from Afghanistan.
He sat next to me on the plane.
- Why didn't we know about that.
- Sir?
Get Washington on the line and tell them Andre
Soltani was in New York yesterday afternoon!
- Right.
- Fuck!
- Relax.
- Will you see him again?
Maybe.
I under-estimated you.
Imagine that.
What else did he tell you?
- Andre?
- Yeah.
He leaked your secrets to the Russians
back in Afghanistan.
Well, I knew that. I was feeding him
bad information anyway. What else?
Sir.
This just in from Tel Aviv.
Milla's a runaway agent of
the Israeli Secret Service.
Suspected operative of an ultra right
wing Zionist pressure group out of Brooklyn.
It's all Greek to me, Fulbright.
I'm going home.
Anything on Andre Soltani?
He was killed twenty minutes ago,
three blocks from here.
Shot in the stomach and hit by a car
When does she fly home?
First thing in the morning.
- Direct?
- Yes.
Notify the authorities.
Have her detained when she lands in New York.
- Suspected murder?
- No.
Espionage.
- Are you Bebe Konchalovsky?
- Yes.
I am Bebe Konchalovsky.
And I am in big trouble.
Come on, we got to get out of here.
He ruined me.
- Who did?
- Henry.
But I deserved it, I guess.
Fay, we are in love with the same man!
I do not love that man. Got it?
It was all just a...
Besides he's dead. They said so.
They're lying. And you are too.
You wouldn't be here
if you thought he was dead.
if you didn't love him.
He's alive and he needs our help.
He did unspeakable things to me.
I'm sure he did.
Why?
I stole them.
I stole the Confessions.
I thought they were the notebooks
of the famous Simon Grim.
Sir, you'll have to stow your luggage
in the over head compartments
or let me store them in back.
What's in them?
Books.
That's all he's taking with him to Sweden,
a bunch of books.
Asshole.
Bebe, he's Simon Grim.
You mean the poet?
He's getting the Nobel Prize.
I fell in love at once.
He told me everything.
How he wanted to be alone.
How he was misunderstood.
How for him...
fame has become such a terrible burden.
A curse even.
He needed me to help him find some peace.
We drove all night and made it
to Berlin the next day.
I was tired of being a stewardess.
I knew some drug dealers in Paris
who would buy the notebooks...
...of the famous Simon Grim.
Don't worry about him.
He cheated me. He deserves worse.
I went to Hamburg and got a regular job.
Oh... the things he did to me.
You can not imagine.
I told him everything.
He forgave me.
And by then I loved him impossibly anyway.
Is that crazy?
No. Here, have another napoleon.
Thank you. I am so hungry.
And I have a sweet tooth,
which of course you know is not
so good for the figure of a stewardess.
And you never heard from him again?
No. And then those drug dealer
friends of mine told...
...everyone I am some kind of spy or something!
They think you're a terrorist.
Yeah, it's impossible.
I can't go anywhere with my actual hair color.
Is Bebe Konchalovsky your real name?
No... My name is Olga.
But call me Bebe. It's prettier.
Fay, please don't let
this Juliet woman find me.
If she catches me
they'll send me back to Chechnya.
She told the government
I am a spy for the rebels there...
...helping with weapons.
But that was only once.
I had no idea.
I am not a spy. I am a stewardess.
Really! Sometimes a topless dancer...
...but really a stewardess. I was trained.
Look... take this money...
Go to the airport tonight.
Get a room at the hotel there...
...and meet me at the information center
tomorrow morning at 7 am. Okay?
I knew you would be good.
I just knew it.
You are my idol.
Hello?
Simon, the world is a mess.
It's your mother.
I just want a normal life, Simon.
A totally normal life.
That's impossible, Fay.
I know.
Fay, this toy that arrived in the mail.
- There's...
- Simon.
We might not be, you know, alone.
If you know what I mean.
Carl, she's onto us.
The... party was wild.
Our friend was there.
Yeah. When?
On Thanksgiving.
The new couch arrived.
Oh yeah? How's it look?
Foreign.
Goodnight, Fay.
You got to be kidding me!
Fay. Help me. Please.
Well, you see,
that's what you get for being a terrorist.
My arm is broken.
So's your leg, I think.
How'd you get away from those guys?
I have a mission. I must complete it.
Oh shut up, you can't even stand.
It must be set.
What?
I need your help.
I can walk with a stick.
You need help setting your arm, you mean?
Yes. Please.
Why should I help you?
Okay. Look...
You know how to do this?
You must pull my arm straight, then...
tie it to something so that it is... you know, bent.
Right.
At the elbow. I get it.
I saw this on TV.
You know this is gonna hurt, right.
I am a soldier of God.
Well that's a relief.
Bite into this.
Hold onto something.
You are a good woman, Fay.
Thanks.
Someday, when this is all over,
and we have destroyed Western civilization...
It's her. Juliet.
Fay, my life is worthless.
But don't allow her to have these books
Promise me.
Where are you hurt?
I was lucky...
It was just a flesh wound.
This is pretty bad.
I think we should get you to a hospital.
I've had worse.
I'll do it myself.
Help me to the bathroom.
Sorry.
Sacrifices need to be made occasionally.
Oh yeah? For what?
For a better world perhaps.
What kind of better world is made
by shooting a 14 year old boy in the head?
Children are dying all over the world, Fay.
Lift your leg.
Shit!
Those thing become human, Fay.
Some dirty work needs to be done.
Civilization ought to thank those of us
who are willing to do it.
Why is it whenever someone starts talking about
civilization I hear the sound of machine guns?
You Americans are soft.
Still, I appreciate your help.
I just don't want you to die in my hotel room.
I've got to sleep in here tonight
There. It's done.
Get out.
What happened to the porter?
- What?
- The Arab kid.
You were the last to see him.
He fell off the side of the building.
Here. I want you to have these.
Are they real?
Perhaps. Who knows?
The Arab kid has what I need.
I seem to have bled on your couch.
Actually, that's an ottoman.
You Americans,
you know all about home furnishings...
...but have no clue what's happening
in the world around you.
I know I don't want the killing to continue.
And you think that's generosity of spirit,
don't you?
I thought you liked Americans.
That's true.
It's said they can be so easily used.
She's on her way.
I'll see you in New York.
- Where is she?
- We don't know.
I swear to God, Fulbright,
if you've lost Fay we'll cripple you.
It was me.
My bright idea.
To create a series of convincing forgeries...
...of the confession Henry
was supposed to have composed
for the interrogators in Chile back in '73.
But the Russians caught on and followed suit.
And the British.
So did the Chinese.
Pretty soon the Pakistanis got hold
of a German translation...
...of a British forgery and followed
coded instructions found within it...
...to build a nuclear bomb that almost worked.
So you see, your Dad's masterpiece
is a collection of fakes...
...of a book that has never itself been written.
A self perpetuating literature of obfuscation,
hearsay... rumor,
innuendo, and out right lies.
A best seller for sure.
Settle down, you lunatics!
It's fucking psychological terrorism.
A kind of germ warfare of the brain.
And we've got to get our hands on...
...whoever's orchestrating this.
Henry?
- Not necessarily.
- Who then?
Yesterday a freelance Russian spy,
an Iranian named Andre Soltani
was found shot to death in a Paris side street.
You think there's a connection?
Unfortunately, yes. I do.
Fay had been with him earlier in the day.
So?
You have anything to drink?
Thank you.
The bungled coup in South America got me in all
sorts of trouble with the brass back in Washington.
And, well, for my sins,
I was sent to the middle of nowhere.
Fulbright,
we're not clear on the American position.
Yeah, well, neither am I.
So, I've got to get over to the US Embassy...
...in Pakistan and find out.
I'll be back in a few days.
There may very well be a new government
here when you return.
No. Andre, can I give you my own
personal estimation of things?
Of course.
When the present government collapses,
there will be no new government.
Only chaos. Unless...
Unless what?
You've got to organize the rebels.
Get someone now, before the shit
hits the fan, who's reasonable.
And by reasonable you mean someone who
will do whatever the American's want him to do.
Yeah, well, maybe. Why not?
Look, Fulbright, there are reasonable men.
Even men who are not reasonable...
...but who will do whatever America wants.
But these are not the men
the people will listen to.
These are not the men the population will follow.
Who will they follow?
Jallal Said Khan.
And who's he when he's at home?
A garbage man from Kandahar.
He wrote this.
What is it?
A sort of manifesto,
written under the guidance of a foreigner
who is his closest adviser.
- Here in Kabul?
- No. In Herat.
The government had him imprisoned
for pornography as a result...
...but I managed to get him released.
It is a powerful document and
has attracted many followers to him.
Where is he now?
Jallal Said Khan?
In the north.
His group has been troublesome
for the Russians as they retreat.
Capturing weapons and even some tanks, I hear.
Is this foreigner with him?
It's hard to tell.
Who is he? The foreigner?
He got a name?
No way!
Incredible!
And he was gone from Mazar e Sharif...
...when I got there 2 days later.
But you found Jallal Said Kahn?
Yeah. But I couldn't get near him.
He was already an anti-western threat.
Pressure from his allies forced him
to split with Henry...
...whom our best intelligence has
crossing the border into Uzbekistan in 1989.
In the meantime, Said Kahn's
become a superstar Mujahedin...
A sort of cowboy holy man with a stolen AK-47.
You think Henry's working
with Said Khan again?
Connect the dots, Simon.
Henry to Khan, Khan to Andre.
And now... well, Andre to Fay.
- But surely you don't think...
- Yes, I do think.
Just hold on a minute, Fulbright.
Face it, Simon.
Fay's gone over to the other side.
The other side of what?
The other side of the playing field, wise guy!
Khan's operation has become a magnet...
...for every anti-American
hoodlum in existence.
You're saying you think Fay's a terrorist?
Look, Simon, people do these things
for funny reasons.
Love, for instance.
I think
she'd do anything to be with Henry again.
Sorry, Angus.
You set her up, you sent her out there.
She could've come back in.
Her work was done.
Work with me.
Tell me what you know.
No charges will be brought against her.
In the meantime,
she might lead us to Said Khan.
What about Henry?
You know where Fay is, don't you?
What's the agency's directive regarding Henry?
I can't tell you that, Simon.
You're going to kill him.
The guy's wanted for manslaughter
and he might very well be collaborating
with international terrorists!
Sir, Picard came to in Paris.
He admitted they issued Fay a fake
passport under the name of a... Emily Hopper.
Any leads?
Yes, a Emily Hopper boarded a plane
in Paris this morning.
Where to?
Istanbul.
Thank you, Miss Hopper.
When will the room be ready, you think?
In about an hour.
Can we store your luggage?
Yes. Just this one.
Very well.
Bebe, don't wander off like that.
Can we buy some baklava?
I'm so hungry.
We haven't even had breakfast yet.
Come on.
But it's good for breakfast! It's so sweet.
With a nice cup of black coffee. Perfect.
No. Come on. We don't have much time.
Thank you, Miss Najinski.
- Do you have any luggage?
- Yes, this one.
Wait for my call.
Don't leave the room.
Don't talk to anyone.
Can I check my email anywhere?
- Fulbright gone?
- Yeah.
Go check your email.
There she is!
Palas Hotel. Istanbul. Room 315.
She's got a good head start.
This is from 7 hours ago.
Ned, go distract those guys in the van.
As soon as I'm gone,
you call the hospital, right?
Yeah. Yeah...
Does this mean anything to you?
No miss. It does not.
It's not Turkish or Arabic or anything?
Not miss, it is not.
H F
Is everything all right, miss?
H-F.
Excuse me?
It was upside down.
It's the letters H, and F.
Ahh yes, So it is. That explains it.
- Explains what?
- What it is.
- What is it?
- Initials.
I know it's initials. But...
whose initials are they?
He's kind of a puppet, do you say.
On strings and wires.
Traditional. Very old.
Here, I'll show you.
There is a shop in the bazaar near the palace...
...just under the old harem.
I'll get you a taxi. He'll bring you there.
Call the hospital.
Yeah. Now go!
So ahh... you really think your Mom likes me?
Yeah. Definitely.
What about this Angus guy?
She just keeps him around for his money.
Rich bastard, huh?
He's okay.
She's concerned about my education.
Yeah, right. Yeah, I can understand that.
You are an American.
Yes, I am.
I can tell by the way you walk.
Are you blind?
For many years. Yes.
There's always this character.
The one with the big mouth.
That's him.
The "Harem Fool."
That's our specialty.
He is a popular story.
A legend.
Like Scheherazade.
Many centuries ago...
...a stranger, a westerner,
found his way
into the harem of the Sultan's palace.
He had seduced all the sultan's concubines...
...by the time he was discovered.
The sultan was about to kill him
when the stranger asked...
...to be allowed to confess
his sins before he died...
...as he was, so he said... a Christian.
The sultan was an open minded tyrant...
...so he sent for a priest
from the Christian community...
...just outside the city walls.
The confession took many years
to complete because the stranger...
...had committed so many sins
that the sultan couldn't believe it
and always wanted to hear more.
Finally, everyone forgot that
he was a prisoner awaiting his death...
...and he was thought of as the harem fool.
I have one of these toys.
They are quite popular.
Yes.
Have you been here before, then?
No. I've never been here before.
The toy was sent to me.
By a friend, I think.
What story does the toy tell?
The toy tells the story...
...of the harem fool...
...seducing the sultan's concubines.
You have come a long way
and put yourself in great danger.
Where is he?
Where is Henry?
That is not for me to say.
Lock the door and turn the sign around.
Lower the blinds.
Ghesam?
Maybe we should call the hospital now.
Nonsense. I'm fine.
If we call the hospital,
it'll alert what's his name out there...
- Carl...
- Yeah, Carl.
They'll investigate and realize Simon's gone.
Let's wait at least until he gets to Istanbul.
Now we must wait.
Where am I?
You do not want to know that, Fay.
What's going to happen?
A man will talk to you.
Answer his questions honestly.
And remember not to ask questions.
Will he take me to Henry?
Don't be impatient.
Answer his questions.
If necessary, ask for his guidance.
We may have to wait some time.
Miss Hopper registered, left her luggage
and said she was going for a walk.
Where's her luggage?
- In her room.
- We need to examine that luggage.
I can not let you into her room.
That is against hotel policy.
We'll need to get the locals involved.
Notify the police.
Watch all the entrances.
What is it you have come here for?
I'm looking for my husband.
Your husband.
What is his name?
Henry.
How is it you have come to lose your husband.
He ran away.
He was in trouble.
I see.
And has this trouble passed?
No.
He's still in trouble then?
Yes.
You want to protect him from these troubles?
If I can.
You want to share these troubles with him?
If I have to.
Where do you intend to look for him?
I was hoping you might choose to advise me.
You can go now.
It's nothing. Just clothes.
Okay. Come on.
About fucking time, your Excellency!
Where's the new stove you promised me!
Hey, scum bag, go get me some more wood!
I'll freeze to death in here, Jallal,
and then you'll have that on your conscience too.
How goes the jihad you cheap fuck!
Why can't you find
a nice kerosene heater somewhere?
Save you from having to chop up
the furniture to keeps us warm.
It's only you who needs to be kept so warm.
I mean, if I were a world famous terrorist.
I am not, a world famous terrorist.
Yeah, and whose fault is that?
And... and... where are those books I asked for?
This is cruel and unusual punishment,
my friend.
If the opinion of the world
is of no consequence to you
I'd think you'd at least have enough...
self-respect to act like a gentleman.
You are not of course now suggesting
that you are a gentleman?
Hey! I was suave enough in my day.
I've lost a little of my polish,
it's true, stuck down here in this vault.
And for what?
For being a friend to you!
Exactly, for being a friend to me.
You know where I am.
No one can know where I am.
Besides, I've needed you.
That's really mighty white of you, Jallal.
I suppose you lock up everyone you need.
Incarcerate all your friends.
If I have to, yes.
There's too much at stake.
Listen. The wood, the books,
materials of every kind...
...they've been hard to get.
Our supplies have been cut off.
We're hoping for support from
our contacts across the border in Iran
I may have to return.
- To Afghanistan?
- Yes.
Are you crazy?
The time has come to stop hiding.
You'll be decimated.
There will be set backs, losses, I agree.
In the short run.
But in the long run...
They will see we can manage.
They will not be able to beat us down forever.
There is a better way.
Even you... even you came back, Henry.
I was just passing through, Jallal.
I was in trouble and you owed me favors,
whether you care to admit it or not.
Don't pin any medals on me, please.
Besides, that's just the way I am.
I gravitate to the lowest
common denominator.
On principle.
Go ahead. Insult me.
There was a time when you said
I could do no wrong.
It's true.
You were extraordinary.
I don't pretend to understand either
your religion or your politics.
...but you used to be a sensible dude.
And now look, me... your best friend.
I'm your prisoner.
Henry, you're a fugitive criminal.
An alleged murderer.
A mistake. I regret it.
But what's done is done.
Of course, when you came to me,
desperate and hurt... I took you in.
But now our friendship is well known
to intelligence agencies all over the world.
Go ahead and complain about it
why don't ya'...
And now you are not merely a wanted criminal,
but are suspected of being an American traitor.
Some of their best citizens
have been described thusly.
But, now, the worst thing possible...
you're famous!
A legend. Yes, the mythic mentor
of the notorious Simon Grim.
- Really?
- It's true.
A new trend. A sensation even.
We saw it on CNN.
You see!
They have to bludgeon a man into obscurity
before they'll acknowledge his genius!
It's a ploy.
A what?
The CIA suspects that if they find you,
You will lead them to me.
Yes, of course, it's all about you Jallal!
But Henry, it is.
You arrogant bastard!
You didn't even know how to talk
when I met you!
You were afraid of your own fucking shadow!
Your past is catching up with you.
- Fulbright?
- Yes.
That fuck...
How?
Sit down.
What?
She's here.
Whose here?
Fay.
- Are you kidding me!
- It's true.
Shit! You gotta comb?
No, wait. Hold on!
How the Hell did she find me?
We sent for her.
Why?
She seems to love you very much.
No... Did she say that?
Forget it...
Henry, I have to go
Jallal!
Fulbright was using her to draw me out.
And it worked?
She caught on early enough... and tricked him.
But he's catching up with her too.
You can't do this.
Jallal, you can't bring Fay
into all this madness.
She's already in all this madness.
You yourself made sure of that.
Hey! I just fell in love with her.
I didn't send her a note...
...and ask her to join some half-assed jihad!
Henry, it's difficult to be your friend.
Yeah, well stand in line, pal
We called Fay here to take you away rather
than to put you in front of a firing squad.
- My friend...
- I am not just your friend.
I don't make decisions by fiat.
I have protected you over
the last three years from the justified...
...if somewhat reactionary elements
of my administration.
They would have killed you back in 1989.
...if I hadn't sent you away.
Every decision I make has consequences
I can barely stand to carry.
I am not a man any longer.
I am an instrument.
A pity.
I prefer it that way.
Go ahead.
Martyr yourself.
Die a saint.
Yes, of course... I can see right through you.
If anything happens to Fay, Jallal...
...I'll torture your wives, your family,
your children and their children.
There'll be a disease upon this earth
with your name on it.
The only thing anyone will inherit
from Jallal Said Khan...
...is a long life time of intolerable pain.
Sorry.
That's just the kind of guy I am.
Hello. I'd like to leave a note
for my friend in room 315.
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Do you know who I am?
No.
Good.
Do you know where you are?
Not really.
Turkey?
Fair enough.
I'm a friend of Henry's.
Oh good.
I am also an enemy of the United States.
I don't keep count, but I've killed
at least hundreds of your fellow citizens.
Many, many more of your soldiers
and professional spies.
May we continue talking?
Okay.
Did you kill Andre?
- No! I...
- I believe you.
Did he give you anything?
Two books of Henry's confession.
Good. Are they with you?
At the hotel.
Fay...
Henry is a wanted man
in more ways than you know.
Can I see him?
Is he all right?
He's safe.
But not for long.
You said you would share
his troubles and protect him.
The time has come for you to do that.
You must decide.
If you wanna to be with him, you must decide.
There will be no turning back.
He is an exile.
You, too, will be an exile.
You will not be able to go home again.
I understand
Hasan will give you directions
to a certain pier on the Bosporus.
At 6:15 this evening a boat will dock
for a few minutes at this pier.
Be there.
Get on the boat.
Henry and you will be taken up
into the Black Sea
and sometime tomorrow...
...you will be transferred to another vessel,
bound for Odessa.
I'm afraid from there on,
you are on your own.
Fay, please, when we drive off,
stand where you are and count to twenty.
- Do you understand the directions I gave you?
- Yes.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7...
Excuse me, where is the men's room.
To the right of the elevator.
Who are you?
Are you really Simon Grim?
Where's Fay?
She should have been back by now.
She told me to wait.
Who are you, what's your name?
I am Bebe Konchalowsky, okay?
But only sometimes.
I am mostly Olga Najinsky.
And I am very hungry.
Can I get something to eat please?
Hello?
Simon!
Get your stuff.
I'll meet you in the lobby in five minutes.
Yes. Grim, Fay. US passport.
Or Hopper, Emily. Same.
No. I'm sorry. No one.
She may have been traveling
with another women.
A Russian passport.
Possibly registered as Konchalovsky. Bebe.
- No. No Konchalovsky.
- What about Chekov. Ilyanna?
No. No Chekov.
Tchiakovsky. Bernadette.
Maybe a Danish passport.
- Possibly Sweden.
- No.
How about Olga?
- Just Olga?
- Yeah. No family name. Just Olga.
- Najinsky.
- First name Olga?
Najinsky, Olga.
Russian passport.
Room 315! Okay, let's go!
I listened to you when I was in misery.
When I was lost.
And it helped me to see the light and to win.
But when I was winning,
I chose not to hear you anymore.
I know...
And I'm sorry for that.
Where's Bebe?
Where is Fay?
I don't know.
Perhaps you would prefer being handed over
to our Russian Associate here...
...and being taken back
to face charges in Chechnya?
Please! Enough!
Bebe..
My government will offer you and Fay diplomatic
asylum if you can lead us to Henry Fool.
Hold on, what is this?
- Fulbright?
- Picard, you can't do that.
Fay's an American citizen!
Only Fay has this number.
Come on, let's do it then.
Fay?
Put Bebe on.
I can't. It's dangerous right now.
I'll call you back.
No.
She's not letting me.
Put Bebe on.
Fay... don't let them send me away.
Bebe, no one is going to hurt you.
Do you understand me?
- But they...
- They will let you go.
I promise.
When they do...
...go to where the sweet things are.
Understand?
If you understand don't say anything.
Put Fulbright on.
Fay, let me bring you in.
This has gotten out of hand.
Let Bebe go.
Where is Jallal Said Khan?
I don't know. Nearby. I think.
But he's going away.
Khan's nearby and he's on the move.
Fulbright, let her go, she's unimportant.
No! Where's Fool?
We need Fool! You don't understand!
We cannot help suppress related
terror groups if Khan is not in custody.
We must have Khan.
Fay, you're in no real position
to strong arm anybody, you know.
Bebe has told us everything.
Listen, you jerk,
that entire building is wired to explode.
Bomb threat.
She's bluffing.
Maybe, but she's been able
to make contact with Said Khan.
None of us in London have managed that.
Not even us, with all our contacts in Moscow.
It seems she's better connected
than we imagined.
Shit, what now?
Sir, the power's been cut.
All communications are down.
Fay, listen... take it easy.
Let Bebe go. Now!
And if anyone else leaves
that building before 15 minutes...
...the entire place explodes. Got it?
Okay. Where are the books?
Let Bebe leave the building.
She's gone.
Give me that quick...
Call back the number.
We'll have the exact coordinates.
Angus?
Wait! They've got Khan!
- Where?
- In Diyarbakir.
On his way to the border with Iran.
- Captured?
- Surrounded. He's wounded.
You must keep him alive!
Let's go!
To the airport! Call ahead for ground support!
Oh, I just knew you would be good.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/7kk6r
Help other users to choose the best subtitles