[Man Narrating] Eighty-six
years of banging our heads
against the big green wall,
but we finally did it.
That part you know.
That part everybody knows.
But I got a story
you don't know.
It's about this schoolteacher
friend of mine named Ben.
This is him, back in 1980,
when he was a kid.
The little guy
was going through
a tough time.
His parents
had just got divorced,
and his mom
dragged him up here
to Boston
where he didn't know nobody.
One day Ben's mom says,
"Enough mopin' around,"
and she calls her brother Carl
to take him somewhere,
anywhere, just to get
the kid out of the house.
Uncle Carl didn't have
any children of his own,
so he wasn't exactly
what you'd call "kid savvy."
I'm not gonna
have to change him
or anything, am I?
Carl, look at him.
He's seven, you dope.
Come here.
Carl wasn't the kind of uncle
who was gonna take you
to the circus
or the zoo
or a puppet show,
but he did know
the greatest place
to bring any kid,
the heart and soul of Boston,
Fenway Park.
That was also the day
I met Ben.
The pretty boy
with the glasses?
That's me, Al Waterman.
I sell sponges.
Now that's
the Green Monster, kid.
Monster?
Yep.
[Narrating]
I taught the boy
what I knew about the game,
and Carl taught him
what he knew.
Hey, Zimmer, you idiot,
what are you batting
this bum leadoff for?
[Narrator]
Dwight Evans parked
a couple homers, the Sox won,
and by day's end, poor Ben
had become one of God's
most pathetic creatures,
a Red Sox fan.
Wow!
And that's where
the story begins.
Careful, kid.
They'll break your heart.
[Rock]
[Man Speaking]
I'm gonna tell you a story
I'm gonna tell you
about my town
a big fat story, baby
Aw, it's all about my town
Yeah, down by the river
Down by the banks
of the River Charles
Aw, that's what's
happening, baby
You could have gone over
right there. Come on,
you gotta be aggressive, man.
Take off the training wheels.
Hey, I got a crowbar
under the seat, okay?
So don't make me
knock your teeth out.
What are you doing?
[Girls Chatting On Phones]
Audrey and Tammy,
are you guys talking
to each other on the phone?
[Audrey]
We're conferencing Amanda.
She's home sick.
[Indistinct]
Amanda likes that song,
Mr. Wrightman.
Can you turn it up, please?
[Louder]
One, two, one, two
One, two, three, four
Wasting pretty time
Wasting pretty time always
One, two, one, two
One, two, three, four
Okay, so I asked for
no ham, double turkey,
but it looks like
they gave me double ham.
Do you want me to go back?
Uh, no. Just toss
some of it in my mouth.
And that teacher's here
with those kids.
What?
That teacher you talked to
on the phone, about coming in,
having a tour.
Oh, oh, God,
that's today?
They're here.
Oh, no.
Okay, uh, just pretend
that you're me and take them
around and... Hi.
There they are.
Ben Wrightman.
We talked on the phone.
Nice to meet you.
Yes, yes,
I've been waiting for you.
Hi, I'm Lindsey Meeks.
Excuse me.
Can I get anyone
something to drink?
Vodka martini, straight up.
Three olives, please.
Hey, I asked you
to behave.
Uh, are you allowed
to hit them?
Yeah, actually.
Do you wanna take
a swipe at him?
I'll hold him
if you want.
Maybe later.
Uh, okay. As I said
on the phone, Lindsey,
I teach honors geometry,
ninth grade.
And every year
I pick a few promising
math students
to meet someone
who's pursued mathematics as
an educational discipline
and has made practical use
of that education.
So, thanks
for having us.
All right, the client
I'm working for right now
is this really cool company
called Marquis Jet,
and they're trying
to figure out
how to make
renting private jets
more affordable.
Wow. Now that's
the way to go.
Yeah, and they're growing
like crazy,
so they'd have to
buy more jets in order
to meet the demands.
Now let me ask you guys
a crazy question.
Are any of you in the habit
of looking at numbers,
you know, addresses,
license plates, phone numbers,
and adding them up
and rearranging them
in your head to make
more interesting patterns?
Oh, my God,
she knows my secret shame.
Well, step into the light,
my friend, because this is
the church of numbers,
and every day is Sunday.
She was a major hottie.
Major?
Colonel hottie.
Yeah, she went optic
for you, Mr. Wrightman.
Optic?
Yeah, I saw her
glance to the pants.
No way.
Yeah.
What do you mean?
I mean she was totally...
No, no, not you.
You. What did you mean?
Nothin', you know.
Well, come on, man.
You saw her.
What? Wait.
Are you saying that
she's out of my league?
She is bringing
some serious heat, man.
I don't know
if you got the bat speed.
Oh, I got the bat speed.
I got plenty of bat speed.
I could hit her best cheese.
Ezra, I need those
customer satisfaction
data reports.
I put them on your desk,
Lindsey.
Good lad. Keep me posted.
You got it.
Those kids were cute.
Which kids?
The ones
from earlier today.
Oh. Yeah.
Maybe I should become
a teacher or
a college professor, you know.
The hours would be better.
You get summers free.
It's so much less competitive.
Oh, my God,
Jack is leaving.
What?
Jack is leaving
the company next summer.
[Gasps,
Mouthing Words]
What that... So, do you think
they're gonna bring someone
in from the outside?
I have... I don't know.
Or do you think they're
gonna promote from within?
I thought you were
becoming a teacher.
[Scoffs]
Low blood sugar.
I didn't eat yet.
Hi.
I didn't wanna interrupt.
It sounded like
you were involved with
some major corporate hoo-ha.
Oh, well,
there's a position
about to open up,
so it might get
mildly murderous
around here.
Oh. Wha... wha... wha...
I want your job!
I'm the boss!
Wha... Wha...
[Chuckles]
Yes. So, um...
Why am I here? Um...
[Clears Throat]
I just wanted you to know
that you really got through
to the kids today.
You know,
they're really juiced.
[Cell Phone Ringing]
Oh, thanks. They were...
They were great.
Well, you're welcome.
Thank you.
So, is the
conversation over?
You mean
'cause neither of us
are speaking?
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
No. Yeah, I also...
I came back because
I just...
I wanted to ask you if I could
ask you out sometime.
Socially.
I won't be bringing
the kids.
Oh!
Uh...
Hike.
[Man]
Get him! Get him!
[Man] oh!
All right,
good "D." Good "D."
I know why she wouldn't
go out with me. She thinks
I'm not in her class.
She said that?
No. I could see it
on her face.
"Like I would really
date a schoolteacher."
Ouch.
Down, set, hike.
[Man]
Yeah, go, go, go!
Ben, what are you doing?
It's two-hand touch.
You were down back there.
And back there
and back there.
What's the matter
with you?
Come on, guys.
Sorry. Sorry, guys.
[Syncopated Beat]
All right, Lindsey,
so what's the matter
with this one?
He's not smart?
He's not attractive?
He was.
It's just, you know...
I don't know.
It's hopeless.
Oh, boy, here we go.
You're right, I'm an idiot.
I'm about to turn 20-10,
and the dating market
is, shall we say, bearish.
And instead of becoming
more open and available,
I'm becoming less open.
Come on, people.
Talking isn't
burning calories.
Let's go.
Start pedaling.
Come on.
Maybe you should date
a different kind of guy.
Why?
What do you mean?
Well, all the guys you date
are sharp and competitive
and successful.
It's like
you're dating yourself.
Ding, ding, ding.
Wh... What's wrong
with the schoolteacher?
Well...
He's a schoolteacher.
Which means he has
a small... Income.
All right, people,
let's shut your piehole
and speed it back up. Come on!
Come on!
Die, you Nazi spin-bitch.
[Bell Rings]
[Whistling]
Hey! Go, run a post. Go!
Oh!
[Chuckles]
Who did that?
That's it.
You're coming with me, Mister.
What do you think,
this is your own
private playground?
Get in here.
Thanks, man.
I owe you one.
Go ahead.
[Whistling]
Hey, Ben, are you going
to watch the Celtics later?
Uh, I don't know.
You know,
there are other sports
besides baseball.
I would debate you, Ed,
but that would only lead to
me being dragged away
in handcuffs.
Hey, speaking of baseball,
Ben, wanna help me coach
the J.V. Team this year?
Why? You're doing a great job.
I mean, you can't just go
by wins and losses.
Aw, come on, Ben.
The kids listen to you.
I think it's going good
the way it is, you know?
You coach the team,
and I help out whenever I can.
Then, if I don't
make it or...
Hey, Rita,
when did I get this message
from Lindsey Meeks?
A tip might be
where it says
"Time called: 2:30."
[Whistles]
Come on, pull!
So, do you think it'll be
a problem that you're more
successful than him?
Who says I am?
Well, I mean,
at least financially.
It's not like he's playing
a flute with a hatful of
dollar bills in front of him.
He's a teacher.
Teaching's
a cool thing.
Yeah. Besides, why does
everything in my life
have to be a trophy?
I mean, who am I
trying to impress?
Hey, we're on your side.
No, I know.
It's just that I hate
when people... [Gasps]
Ow!
Oopsie.
[Lindsey Groaning]
Oh, just kill me.
Just take a hammer
and kill me.
[Groaning Continues]
[Doorbell Rings]
Oh, shit.
Who is it?
I... It's me. It's Ben.
Your date?
Oh, God, no.
Oh.
[Door Lock Clicks]
I'm sick. Come back.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Go away.
Wait, wait, wait.
What kind of sick?
You okay? You in pain?
I... [Swallows]
Ate at this new place.
I think...
[Vomiting]
Are you faking it?
'Cause we don't have to
really do this if you don't...
[Vomiting Continues]
Mommy.
Ernie, go away.
Ernie, don't eat that!
Oh, shit.
Uh...
So, you wanna pull the plug
on this thing or...
[Vomiting, Choking,
Coughing]
All right, here we go.
Come on.
All right,
we're almost there.
Okay. Okay.
Now sit right here.
Oh, God!
All right. Okay.
Here. Pick your head up.
[Groans]
Up. Okay, up.
Uh, all right. Um...
Do you have any, like,
pajamas or a nightgown?
In the top drawer.
Top drawer. Okay.
All right, here we go.
[Chuckles]
Well, Wonder Woman's
been looking for these.
I gotta call her.
Let her know they're here.
Okay. All right.
I'll help you up.
Mm-mm.
Get up.
[Groans]
I'm sorry about this.
Don't worry.
Come on. Come on.
I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna help you change,
all right? I won't look.
I promise.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Okay, I looked.
[Chuckles]
Let's get this on.
Get your arms through.
Okay, here we go.
You're gonna be okay.
There's nothing left
to throw up, I promise.
And if you do,
here's Mr. Hamper.
Okay? All right.
Sooner or later
I'm gonna
get through to you
[Sighs]
I'm tellin' you, baby
Here. Drink this
when you feel like
you can, okay?
Thank you.
Thank you, Bill.
All right.
It's Ben.
Okay, go back to sleep.
I've got time on my side
Along for the ride
And everything was certain
like the sunbeam
And this moment
has just begun
Ooh
Sooner or later
Gonna soothe you
turn you on
I'm gonna turn you on
Sooner or later
[Fades]
[Snoring]
Hey.
Hi.
How you feeling?
Uh, I mean,
I'm not about to enter
any pie-eating contests.
Did you clean up my bathroom,
or did I dream that?
Me? No.
Uh, the vomit elves came in.
And, uh, really adorable.
Really cute little things.
I mean, little caps
and little barf bags.
Well, thank you.
I mean, you really,
really went above and beyond.
Uh, no, please.
It wasn't a big deal.
You were very ladylike.
Hardly any "chunkage."
What's in the bag?
I got some, uh...
I got some movies
just in case you woke up.
Not in case you woke up.
I knew you were
going to wake up.
In case you woke up
in the middle of the night.
Yeah?
Anything good?
Uh, mostly animated
pornography from Japan.
And a little something
I like to watch too
when I feel sick.
Well, for me,
it's Annie Hall.
Wh... What did you say?
Annie Hall.
Whoa, this is like...
This is unbelievable.
Road House.
[Chuckles]
Are you feeling...
Is this crazy?
I mean, what are the odds?
Spooky.
No, she cannot
have my assistant.
Because I trained Carrie.
I like her.
Listen. Do we have to
settle this right now?
I'm with a... Person.
Yes. Thank you.
Okay, I'll speak to you
tomorrow. Bye-bye.
[Phone Beeps]
I'm really, really sorry.
Actually, I'm sorry.
I ate everything cool.
I just left you
a pile of sauce.
That's okay.
Actually, I'm the worst.
I eat off everybody's plate.
In fact, my friends,
they call me "the seagull."
[Imitates Seagull Cawing]
Oh, hi, seagull.
[Both Chuckle]
Nice.
No, really,
I appreciate you being cool
about the phone thing,
because I once went on a date
with this guy who got so angry
I was on the phone
that he grabbed it out of
my hand, and he threw it
in the fish tank.
I would never do that.
What are your pet peeves?
What stresses you out?
Mm, I got...
And I'm only asking
because frankly
the men I meet are highly...
I date poodles basically.
And I'm really relaxed,
you know? Totally.
[Cell Phone Ringing]
Son of a... Stop ringing.
I got it.
Let me do it.
Hello?
Uh, no, she isn't.
May I take a message?
This is Ben.
I'm her houseboy/sex slave.
Okay. You betcha.
Bye-bye.
Call your mother.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
So you don't have
a cell phone,
a Blackberry,
a pager, nothing?
No.
Well, what if some
sudden crisis occurs,
like your father
has a heart attack
or something?
My father died
two years ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just found out this morning,
so it's been a rough 24 hours.
You know, maybe I should
get a cell phone.
That's a good idea.
You're funny, Ben...
Wrightman.
Wrightman. Yeah.
Yeah.
You forgot my last name.
No, I just blanked.
I know why you forgot.
That's all right. I bet
when you talk to your friends,
you call me
Ben the schoolteacher,
am I right?
Well?
That's okay.
What do you call me
to your friends?
I call you Lindsey,
the vomit girl,
the puker, pukey.
Everyone says, "You going
out with pukey tonight?"
I'm like, "Yeah. Why?"
"You wanna play video games
or something?"I'm like,"No,
I'm going out with pukey."
That's horrible.
Hey, anything I've said
about you would be
an understatement, really.
Hey, Lindsey!
Hi!
Hi.
Hi, I'm Ben
the schoolteacher.
Ian. Sarah.
Steve. Molly.
Oh, thanks
for having me.
Robin and Chris.
Welcome aboard.
Well, let's start
the interrogation.
No, no,
it's not like that.
Here.
It's for the urine sample.
Shoot, I wish you would have
told me. I just took a whiz
in your bushes.
[All Laughing]
Do you want to...
Show him the house.
I like it when it rains
It's always
on the windowpane
Lindsey, this Ben guy
has got such a good vibe.
Good.
And he's nothing like
the guys you usually date.
I know.
[Sarah] and how cute is he?
Yeah? Well, I'm really glad
you guys feel this way,
because if you didn't,
I was gonna have to find
three new friends.
No, no, no, I really think
you've got something here.
Me too.
Yeah, but... Something's
not quite right.
Robin.
No, no, he's great.
He is. I love him.
He's a doll.
But he's not 22.
So?
So, where's he been?
Why is he still
on the market?
Um...
Maybe he hasn't found
the right person yet.
Well, by now he should be
with the wrong person.
How has he not been
tranquilized and tagged?
Let me get this straight.
You got two season tickets
behind the Red Sox dugout?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
My uncle left them to me.
Behind the dugout?
Yeah. Well, not really behind,
like next to it.
Fifteen feet away.
You can see right into it
at a certain point.
It's pretty awesome.
Let me ask you this.
Do you find my wife
attractive at all?
'Cause we could work
something out.
Well, do you?
You know what
you need to do?
You need to
go to his apartment and
go through his things.
You need to go through
his closets, sofa cushions.
You need to
get on his computer.
And what exactly
am I looking for?
Anything that explains
why he's still single.
My company can run
a credit check on him.
You know, he could be
a deadbeat dad.
This is
an insane asylum.
So, uh, when they
wheeled out Ted Williams
at the All-Star Game...
I was there.
I was 10 feet
away from him.
Old men crying.
Tears.
Tough old guys.
I even started
to lose it, you know.
I got a program.
I could show you.
If Lindsey ever breaks up
with you, I'll kill her.
Lindsey, do you remember
that guy Maureen Durst
went out with?
Uh, sort of. Why?
[Molly]
Terry what's-his-name?
We all thought
he was great too.
Well, what happened?
Oh, my God. She went
to his apartment and...
Shh. My story.
Stand by.
She's at his place.
He's in the shower.
She wants to make the bed,
so she goes to the closet.
Guess what she finds.
Oh, I don't know.
What'd she find?
Two large plastic bags
containing all of the hair
and nail clippings
from his entire life.
Eww!
That's a true story.
I'm telling you,
there is a reason
this Ben guy is still single.
Come on, baby
[Alarm Clock Ringing]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Come on!
I promised him we'd wait.
We're always
waiting for him.
I gave him my word.
You guys wait?
Yeah.
Come on, man.
Did anyone die
because you're here?
No, no, no.
I got
another anesthesiologist
to cover for me.
[Ben]
All right, are you ready?
Hey, come on!
God.
[Sniffs]
A new season.
A clean slate.
[Sniffs]
Yep, this smells
like the year.
[Sizzles]
[Imitates Seagull Cawing]
Hey, you wanna
know something?
What?
I like you.
No, I mean,
I really like you.
I even wrote down
a list of all the things
I like about you.
You made a list?
Yeah. I don't have it with me,
but I can remember it.
I'll skip down
because the first six
are all body parts.
Uh, number seven:
I like that you drink
in the afternoon.
Number eight: I like sometimes
you talk out of the side
of your mouth a little bit.
And it's like...
It's like an adorable
stroke victim.
I do?
No, it's very cute.
It really is.
Uh, number nine.
You know, when you're getting
ready in the mirror, just when
you're about finished,
you go like...
It's so cute,
I wanna kill myself.
It's fantastic. Uh...
Hey, when's your break?
Hmm?
For your school vacation.
When do you get off?
End of March.
That's when
you're in Baltimore, right?
Yeah.
Well, it's a really big deal
in my family,
because it's
my dad's birthday
and Easter,
and my sister's anniversary
all in the same week.
A cluster.
Yeah. Uh...
So, uh, how would
you like to come?
Ooh, too fast?
Too serious?
No, why?
Did I look like
I was just...
You were a little.
No, 'cause...
No, I... I made...
I have a previous commitment.
Oh, plans?
Yeah, yeah.
Um, see, I didn't tell you
about it, 'cause I knew
you were gonna be away.
I figured it wouldn't matter,
but every year
during Easter vacation,
uh, me and my friends,
we go down to Florida.
You and your buddies
go down to Florida for
spring break? At your age?
No, no, no, not spring break.
Spring training
with the Red Sox.
Oh, you get to train
with the Red Sox?
Are you allowed
to do that?
Well, we don't actually...
We watch the games.
Aren't those
just practice games?
Yeah, yeah, but there's
more to it than that.
We scout the players.
We... We say which players
they should keep,
which they should
get rid of.
And the Red Sox
ask your opinion?
Well, not yet.
But if they ever do, uh...
Okay, I've been
avoiding this.
There's something
you don't know about me.
Oh, God, here comes
the bag of hair.
The thing is, uh,
I am a Red Sox fan.
Yeah?
No, I'm like a big,
big Red Sox fan.
I know.
I mean, I've been
to your apartment
and seen the Red Sox
dish towels and glasses
and the Yankee toilet paper.
It's like you live
in a gift shop.
It's worse.
See, when I was a kid,
I moved here from New Jersey,
and I didn't have
any friends or anything,
so my uncle Carl started
taking me to Fenway Park.
I just...
I got lost in the game.
I mean, the ballpark
and the people.
The color, the sounds.
The smells.
And then he got cancer
and he died.
He left me
his season tickets.
And it's a passion.
I mean, it's a very,
very big part of my life.
And it's been a problem
with me and women.
Oh, ah,
I know those women.
The "pay attention to me"
and "why aren't you
talking to me?"
Yeah. Exactly.
God, those women
are so pathetic.
Yeah, it's like,
"What are you getting
so worked up for?
I mean, you're not even
doing it, you're watching it."
Yeah.
It's like,
"Hey, how about sometimes
I like to be 11 years old."
Yeah.
I like being part of something
that's bigger than me,
than I.
It's good for your soul
to invest in something
that you can't control.
You're a romantic.
Hmm?
You have a lyrical soul.
You can love under the best
and worst conditions.
I don't know.
Well, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I guess so.
Hey, uh...
You took a really big chance
inviting me
to meet your family.
[Sighs]
Now I'm gonna take a chance.
A big one.
Lindsey, will you
go to opening day with me?
[Giggles]
Yes.
Yes. Yes!
You hear that?
She said yes!
[Imitating Jimmy Stewart]
Mary, look. Merry Christmas.
Clarence, look how
everyone showed up.
It's amaz...
We're going to opening day.
It's official. We're going.
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo!
[Gasps]
What did Dad do
to his hair?
I can't even look at him.
I know.
How could you let him?
He's 60. It's a big
psychological milestone.
He's struggling with it.
He thinks he looks good.
[Barking]
Now don't start with me.
Listen, I forgot to tell you
that Donna...
[Growling]
Stop it! Out!
Outside! Out.
I don't know
what's with him lately.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I forgot to tell you.
Donna called.
And they're
on their way.
Okay.
Good.
[Both Chuckling]
He is scaring the dog.
How can you stand it?
He fanned me with a magazine
for four years when I was
going through menopause.
I can put up with this.
Go back in
and talk to him.
He misses you.
Okay. One more.
[Man On TV]
Yeah, but do you see him ever
playing in a Yankee uniform?
Hi.
Hey, kiddo.
Want a cookie?
No, thanks.
[Man On TV Continues]
Your mama says
you've been busy.
Ooh.
No Red Sox fan
has forgotten last October
and Aaron Boone.
Hey, is this
about the Red Sox?
Yeah.
That next year
is the year.
Steve Levy is in Fort Myers
with some of the members
of the set
known as Red Sox nation.
Down here
in Fort Myers, Florida,
the story is always the same.
When the calendar page
flips to March...
[Continues]
[Dad] Are you interested?
No, I just, you know...
I mean, I have a friend
who is interested.
Oh, the schoolteacher.
When are we gonna meet
this future breakup?
Thanks, Dad.
That's really encouraging.
Well, I thought
you would have
brought him with you.
Well, you know,
he wanted to come.
It's just that, um, well,
he has this tradition,
you know.
And it's very important
to him every...
The Sox are right there!
[Continues Indistinct]
Where do the Sox rank
in terms of importance
in your life?
I'd say Red Sox,
sex and breathing.
I have season tickets to
Fenway Park. I haven't missed
a game in 11 years.
I love the Red Sox.
They're gonna win.
All the way this year, baby!
Do you have a job?
Do you work for a living?
Of course I do.
Yeah, I'm a teacher.
I mold young minds.
Can you help these guys out?
Can you believe
this asshole?
[Indistinct Yelling]
[Ben]
29th of May, Seattle,
all right?
You know what?
I gave it to the lady
down at the bakery.
Ben, all I got so far
is the 21 st and 22nd, man.
We're only on May.
We've been here
for four hours.
Let's try to speed this up.
30th of may,
we're still at Seattle.
Who wants a Sunday game?
These guys can have
whatever games they want.
All I ask for
is the first Yankee game.
You went to six
Yankee games last season,
you selfish pig bastard.
You got to go
to every great game.
Lowe's no-hitter.
Your mother's hysterectomy?
I put her out for free,
remember?
She had insurance for that.
Attention, morons.
You went last year.
You guys want Yankee tickets?
You wanna talk Yankee tickets?
Yes.
Really.
Okay, well, I wanna
see you dance for me.
[Overlapping Chatter]
You don't wanna dance?
I don't wanna embarrass you.
I'll just take this.
Everyone just go.
I'll go talk to some kids
in the street. I see a little
bit there. That's pretty nice.
That's it. The doctor
is giving me something.
The doctor is giving me
some magic tapping there.
Oh, I like that a lot.
Yeah, that's... Oh!
All right, Little League,
you wanna go?
You want some of this?
How's this, Ben?
This is dancing for tickets.
I'm dancing, Ben.
Troy, sit on
the beanbag, please.
Hey, I started, Ben.
Dance, dance, dance, dance
Gerard, I guess
you don't want them, huh?
This is worth tickets.
I'm not dancing.
This is totally stupid, man.
Fine. Hey, hold out
for the Royals, huh?
You are on
a total power trip,
you know that, man?
This is totally
ridiculous, man.
I was dancing first,
remember?
You said dance,
I started dancing.
You call that Yankee dancing?
No, no, that's like
Devil Ray dancing, okay?
That's Devil Ray.
I'm talking about
Yankee dancing.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yeah, get into it. Yeah!
How bad do you want it?
Yeah, that's nice.
I love it. Come on in.
[Knocking]
That's it!
Come on! Whoo!
Latin hustle to
Yowsah, yowsah, yowsah
That's right. I'm...
[Stops]
Hey, what are you
doing here?
I thought you weren't
coming in until tomorrow.
You look fantastic.
I got in last night.
You know Troy,
Kevin and Gerard.
Everyone else,
this is Lindsey.
Hi.
Hi, Linds.
Party?
No, it's draft day.
This is the day we organize
the whole season, who gets
to go to what game with me.
But don't worry.
You're still going
to opening day.
Yeah, thank you.
Can I talk to you about
something really quickly?
Sure, yeah, no problem.
Quick break, everybody.
There's some nice
Pakistani cold cuts there,
courtesy of Mrs. Segal.
I still don't think
they're worth
two Sunday tickets.
Whoo-hoo!
Hey! Hey!
Come here.
Wait, I got you something.
I set aside
some great games
for you too.
Hmm? For when we go
to the games together.
Thanks.
It's what
the players wear.
It's authentic.
I gotta be honest.
This is getting me hot.
Listen. Um, you know,
I saw you on ESPN.
Oh. We looked like
morons, didn't we?
Uh, yeah, yeah, total.
Not you so much, but...
Well, it's very hot,
you know. It's Florida.
[Chuckles]
You start seeing things.
Um, you know, Ben,
I didn't realize how big
this Red Sox thing is
with you.
What?
Hey, I told you.
See, this is...
This always happens.
Every time I...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
don't jump off a building.
We're just talking.
Sorry. Knee jerk.
[Troy] Ben, come on, man.
The cold cuts are gone.
Let's go in there.
Two minutes!
Wow. I really hit
a nerve there, didn't I?
Uh...
[Clears Throat]
Yeah.
Come here.
Thank you.
I think there's
a better approach
to this whole Red Sox thing.
Really?
Yeah. After all,
if I want this promotion,
I am going to
have to push myself
really hard this summer.
And I've never really been
very good at servicing myself,
my job and a relationship.
Wait, wait.
We're not breaking up,
are we?
No, no,
this is a good thing.
Okay.
You're gonna be
so consumed with all of this
that you won't
feel neglected all summer.
No, no, yeah,
I'm not gonna
feel neglected.
And I won't feel guilty
for having to do my job.
Yeah, you shouldn't.
So, what I'm saying is,
I think this is perfect.
[Chuckles]
All right. Go, Sox!
Two, three, four
Tessie
Nuff Ced McGreevy shouted
We're not here
to mess around
We got 'em right here, folks.
Come on down. Cut your deficit
and balance your budget.
Hear the crowd roar
to your sound
Programs here!
Get your programs here!
Don't blame us
if we ever doubt you
You know we couldn't live
without you
Tessie, you are
the only, only, only
Hi. Hi.
Hey.
[Man]
Peanuts! Cracker Jacks!
Who wants peanuts?
Who wants Cracker Jacks?
Peanuts! Cracker Jacks!
Who wants...
It's unbelievable, right?
You can't even believe how...
Look, right here, go.
This is it.
Thank you.
Is this amazing?
Is this crazy? Would you
look at these seats?
They're...
They're very red.
No, I mean, their proximity
to the field.
This is Fenway Park.
Oh.
You can't buy these seats.
You have to,
like, inherit them.
It's like a guy
offered me $100,000
for these once.
And you didn't sell them?
No, if I ever need
the money that bad,
I can always call up
a rich old lady and give her
some sweet lovin', you know?
That's what I'm all about.
Hey, what's up, Al?
How you doing?
I'm on dialysis.
Right on, buddy.
Hey, Al, this is Lindsey.
Hi. Al Waterman.
Here, have a sponge.
Thank you.
Al is the first guy
I ever met
at my first
Red Sox game ever.
Really?
Yeah, he's aged horribly.
Hey, the Belnaps.
This is Artie. Viv.
This is Lindsey.
Hello.
Hi, Lindsey.
Been divorced 20 years,
still share the seats.
Really.
Hey, Ben.
Sheri!
How you doing?
Where's Teresa?
She's right here.
Oh, my God.
What happened?
You look fantastic!
I lost 200 pounds.
I had my stomach stapled shut.
A doctor
or you did it yourself?
Oh, real funny.
Hey!
This is quite a little group
you have here.
Well, it's
my summer family.
[Boy]
For the land of the free
And the home of the brave
[Crowd Cheering]
[Announcer] Let's hear it
for Jordan Leandre.
Ladies and gentlemen,
throwing out
the first ball today,
New England's own
Stephen King.
[Crowd Cheering]
[Announcer]
Right down the middle.
Did you tell Schuyler?
Okay, all right, listen.
Um, excuse me.
What time is the game over?
Uh, it's not like
a Broadway musical
where it ends with
a big Hawaiian number.
It's like you're missing
all the ambience
and all the fun.
I know.
The players
are right there.
I have a meeting at 5:30
and had to leave work at noon
to meet you here,
so my people
aren't prepared.
Right. Okay.
You know what?
I left work early,
so you're gonna have to
figure it out for yourself,
and I'll call you later.
[Announcer]
Wakefield.
[Groans]
That's a foul.
What makes that a foul?
See that foul pole there?
That's Pesky's Pole.
That's this guy
Johnny Pesky.
Yeah!
Hey, what are you doing
on Saturday?
Mm, you tell me.
You know what's really great
about baseball?
Hmm?
You can't fake it.
Anything else in life,
you don't have to
be great in.
Business, music, art...
I mean, you can get lucky.
Really?
Yeah, you can fool everyone
for a while, you know?
It's like...
Not... Not baseball.
You can either
hit a curveball
or you can't.
That's the way
it works, you know?
Hmm.
You could have a lucky day,
sure, but you can't have
a lucky career.
It's a little like math.
It's orderly.
Win or lose, it's fair.
It all adds up.
It's, like, not as confusing
or as ambiguous as, uh...
Life?
Yeah.
It's... It's safe.
Oh, yeah! Yeah!
[Whooping]
Hey.
Hi.
What, did you buy out
the bookstore?
Actually, I bought
every book they had
on the Red Sox,
because I'm tired of being
the most ignorant person here.
Now who is
Carl Yaz-a-strezem...
[All] Yastrzemski.
[Mouthing Words]
She's not a genius,
this one.
No.
Johnny Damon!
You got the sweetest ass
in the league!
Very nice.
[Scoffs]
Do you believe in this?
"The Curse of the Bambino"?
Hey, that's not funny.
That's enough of that.
But Babe Ruth
was the Bambino.
That's right.
He played for the Red Sox.
They were great.
I mean, they were
the Yankees.
They won the World Series
in 1912, 1915,
1916, 1918.
They were royalty.
The elite.
Al should know.
He was there actually.
He's 136 years old.
He looks great for his age.
1919, their miserable,
greedy pig of a boss
decides to sell Babe Ruth
to the Yankees to finance
a Broadway musical.
No, no, Nanette.
I would never ever
see that piece of crap.
And since 1918,
the Red Sox have not won
a World Series.
Yeah, the Yankees
have won 26.
And the thing is
the Sox don't just lose,
they raise it to an art form.
Tony C.,
best young player in baseball,
catches one in the eye at 22,
he's finished at 26.
Armbrister runs into
Carlton Fisk,
costs us the Series.
Bucky friggin' Dent.
[Viv Groans]
You remember the time
Roger Moret went catatonic?
The grounds crew
had to carry him out
in a wheelbarrow.
Buckner.
[All Groan]
Grady little sticking
with Pedro
in the eighth inning.
Ooh, stop it.
You're killing me here.
And that, milady,
is the Curse of the Bambino.
[Announcer]
Number 19, Gabe Kapler.
Okay, I'm ready.
Let's go meet Mom and Dad.
[Scoffs]
Nothing.
A laugh? A giggle?
This is not
a man's closet.
What do you mean?
You have one pair
of dress shoes.
You're like a man-boy.
Half man, half boy.
You should see the way
my sister's husband dresses.
He had a professional
come in and do his closet.
It's like suit, suit, suit...
All right, okay, okay.
I see what this is all about.
You want your parents
to like me more than they
like your brother-in-law.
No, it's not...
Yes!
[Sighs]
Is it so horrible that
I want my parents to like you?
Okay. I think we have
enough stuff in this closet.
We can fool 'em.
[Mom]
He looks like a skunk.
You're the one that told me
to grow it out.
Well, what else could I say?
It looked ridiculous on you.
A man your age...
Now, I understand
that you're a teacher, right?
You were?
Yes, for 27 years.
And, okay, now you're
the principal, right?
Mm-hmm.
And you...
Did you ever tell me
what your dad does?
I sell golf carts.
Wow. Okay, that gives us
nothing to talk about.
I don't really know much
about it.
That's funny,
'cause every other guy
she's gone out with
has tried to get
a free golf cart
out of me.
No, I like golf. Great sport.
It's just I don't really
get out much, you know?
We love it.
Yeah?
They play all the time.
We tried to get on
the country club here,
but it's very difficult.
It's almost impossible.
I had to call the manufacturer
of my golf carts,
a guy named
Dave Johnson, and said...
Jensen.
No, Dave... Dave Johnson.
Jensen?
Hi. Sorry we're late. He was
watching the Red Sox game.
How'd they do?
No, no.
La, la, la, la, la!
Help me! Help me!
Help me!
What's wrong?
Oh, help me! Help me!
Help me! La la la la!
[Man, Indistinct]
La la la la.
[Making Noises]
Okay. Okay.
It was awesome.
Struck out the side.
Okay, it stopped.
It stopped. Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Whew!
Um...
Thank you.
Yeah. Ben tapes
the Red Sox games,
so he doesn't wanna
know the score.
And he can't
cover his own ears 'cause
he's got lobster fingers,
so I do it.
That's sweet.
Hey, how'd it go last night?
Fabulous.
Mr. Myerson
wants to see you.
Oh, God. If one of
the windows would open,
I would jump.
And your mom's
on line one.
Hi, Mom. Hi.
Listen, where are you?
Can I call you back?
What? You had
a 10:00 a.m. Flight.
My Ben?
Yes, he has been great.
He took us out to breakfast.
Right now he's washing
your father's balls.
What?
Here's one.
Thanks, Ben.
He got us a 10:00 a.m.
Tee time at the country club.
How?
One of his student's fathers
has something to do
with the sprinklers.
Can I talk to him
for a second?
Oh, sure.
Benny? Lindsey.
Oh, thanks.
Hi, Linds.
Hey, what are you doing?
Took a sick day.
All right.
Well, I'll see you
tonight then.
All right. Bye-bye.
Honey...
Uh, sweetheart,
don't talk in my backswing.
Well, you were
lined up wrong.
I wasn't lined up, I...
Please, don't talk
in my backswing. You know
better than that.
Just take a mulligan.
Lighten up.
He's so short with me.
I know. I know.
But you know what?
You talked in his backswing.
Did you talk in his backswing?
Yes, I did.
Don't even look at him.
Look this way. Let him swing.
Okay.
[Crowd Cheering]
Where it began
Manny! Manny! Manny!
I can't begin to know when
But then I know
it's growin' strong
Wasn't the spring
And spring
became the summer
Who'd have believed
you'd come along
Hand
Touching hands
Reaching out
Touching me
Touching you
Sweet Caroline
buh, buh, buh
Good times never
seemed so good
So good, so good, so good
I've been inclined
To believe they never would
and now I
Oh.
[Breathing Heavily]
[Man] She handled a project
for a food service company
like yours a few months ago.
Gave them a model
predicting the impact
of every possibility.
Sounds like what I need.
Morning.
You'll love her.
This lady is a dynamo.
Unstop... pable.
[Clears Throat]
When she wakes up,
I wanna see her.
Well, let's go
for a coffee.
You know
what's happening here?
You're being colonized.
What?
Colonized. It's like...
It's like in the old days.
When the French
and the English would go
into Asia and Africa,
and they'd
raise their flags
impose their culture
and they'd colonize.
It's like, Sarah, when you
cut your hair off because
that guy liked short hair.
Wait a minute.
I mean, you guys are married.
Isn't that a part of it,
accommodating each other?
You know, how many kids
are we gonna have?
Where are we gonna live?
What pizza place
are we gonna order from?
Doesn't it require
some pliability?
Because maybe that's something
I've been lacking in my life.
Isn't it affecting your work?
No, not so much.
You know what
I just realized?
You're rooting
for her relationship to fail.
No.
What?
That's right.
Why would I do that?
Never mind.
No. No, come on,
tell me.
All right. You and Lindsey
are both very competitive,
especially with each other.
She's more competitive
than I am.
I am not.
And when you were both
starting out, you were
the more successful one.
But now Lindsey's career
has skyrocketed,
so she's more successful.
But you've had
the personal success,
the marriage.
And if Lindsey
gets that too, then she's
definitely the winner,
so you're rooting
against her.
[Gasps]
Oh, my God.
What did I do?
What the...
That's it.
We are so
not coming here anymore.
[Crowd]
Let's go, Red Sox!
[Cheering]
[Crowd Jeering]
Hey, Ump, get off your knees.
You're blowin' the game!
Al Waterman.
Have a sponge, young man.
She's killing me
with the laptop.
Sitting there
doing her homework.
So, when do you find out
about this promotion thing?
Uh, next month.
Oh, cool. I just wanted to
know how long I gotta put up
with this at the ball games.
Ben, this is my third game
this week.
Oh, no, I know that.
And I always have to leave
at 6:00 to be here on time.
And then we don't get home
till 11:00, then you and I
go at it all night,
and then that's
all time lost.
Really?
Well, when I say lost,
I mean it's time
that I have to make up.
I know.
You know? I already
got my ass chewed out...
Hot dogs here!
By my boss
this week, okay?
Yo!
Hot dogs!
Fenway frank?
Blech.
One, please.
Mustard, please.
Thank you. What do I owe?
[Crowd Cheering]
[Machine Whirring]
No, they didn't find anything.
She's fine. I swear.
She's lying down right now.
[Phone Beeps]
Molly? Okay, there's
another phone call
coming in, okay?
Check in later.
Okay, bye-bye.
[Phone Beeps]
Hello. Troy.
You're kidding me. Now?
All right, thanks. Bye.
Honey,
you're on television.
[Man On TV]
Come and get 'em
at Cerrone Cadillac.
The Red Sox
picked up the "W."
There was a scary moment
though in this one
in the sixth inning,
when Miguel Tejada
hit a vicious foul ball
off Mike Myers
that actually hit a woman.
[Announcer]
The 0-1 is fouled off
back into the seats.
[Woman] That had to hurt.
Oh!
She was transported
to a local hospital,
but fortunately
she was released
and she's gonna be all right.
[Theme Music]
[TV Off]
It wasn't that bad
actually.
It was actually
very ladylike.
I mean, you just kind of...
slinked out of your chair.
It was pretty limber.
All right.
I'll let you sleep.
No, Ben.
Gah!
You have a whole
nother head up there.
Yeah, well,
the one that can talk
needs to say something.
I don't think that I should go
to the games anymore.
Why?
Because of this?
No, because I'm becoming
someone that I hate.
Someone who gets a boyfriend,
and poof, their entire
prior life just vanishes.
I have to focus
on my work right now.
I have to.
And besides, you'll have
such a better time if you go
with Troy or Gerard
or the bald anesthesiologist.
Come on.
You have to go. Please?
Listen. You go to the games,
and I'll stay at the office.
And when the game is over,
you'll come racing home
like you're scoring
the winning run,
and I'll be here waiting.
Waiting?
I'll be waiting.
[French Accent]
What, you'll be waiting
for me?
Yeah.
Ooh.
You know, all this talk
about waiting is making me
not wanna wait.
Ben, I'm concussed.
Yeah, that's kind of
the way I like it.
I have to keep the peas
on my forehead.
Okay, try to balance it.
Okay. It's...
[Knocking]
Hi.
Hello.
I told your bosses,
but I wanted to tell you.
The work you did for us
was brilliant.
Oh. Well,
I really appreciate
you saying that.
Uh, Patrick Lyons,
this is Carrie.
Nice to see you again.
Nice to see you.
Excuse me.
You know, they're really
very lucky to have you here.
Oh, I feel
the same way to be here.
I feel very lucky.
Here, I got it.
Um, thank you.
You're welcome.
I was, um, just trying
to get comfortable.
Well, don't get
too comfortable,
you might fall asleep.
[People Cheering]
[Ben] Come on! Come on!
Use your brain!
Oh, they're in the lead.
We almost have an answer.
Who's ahead?
Oh, Tammy's in the lead.
We might have a winner!
We might have a winner
right here!
Tammy won!
37' 2", the Green Monster.
Audrey, I'm very sorry,
but you can have
our home game.
Don, what does she win?
Excuse me.
It's a little loud,
don't you think?
Sorry, Mr. Ennis.
The kids' drugs
just kicked in.
[All Laughing]
[Mr. Ennis] Oh, ha ha.
Teenage drug use.
That's great fodder
for comedy.
[Mouthing Words]
[Students Laugh]
All right, you guys.
We're almost out of time.
Pack up.
Remember, we got a big test
next Tuesday, so St...
[Students Groaning]
Hey, back off!
Back, back, back, you animals!
[Imitates Whip Whipping]
Back! Hey, one of the
10 problems on your handout
will be on the test.
I'm not gonna tell you
which one, so you're gonna
have to learn all of them.
Seven.
[Mouthing Word]
[Bell Rings]
All right,
study, you maniacs.
Remember, this Saturday is
fall tryouts for next spring's
J.V. Baseball.
Just to avoid the confusion
we had last year,
let me say this year
we're looking
for good players.
Hi.
Hey.
How are you doing?
I have very exciting news.
I couldn't wait to tell you.
You got the promotion.
No, no.
Mr. Myerson did call me
into his office
right after we spoke.
I was trying
to play it cool.
But between you and me,
I was ready to wash his balls.
Yeah, see, that joke's
not fun for me.
[Giggles]
I'm sorry.
Let me explain.
There is this European company
that we're trying to make
a deal with, okay?
And what they do...
You know what?
The point is
they're sending me to Paris
to close the deal.
Wow!
And I am taking vous.
Moi?
Oui!
Taking me to Paris?
Oh, this is gonna
be so great.
Okay, I'm gonna cash in
my first-class ticket
and get two seats.
All you have to do,
Mr. Wrightman,
is call in sick tomorrow,
and we're on our way.
Wait, it's tomorrow?
Mm-hmm.
This weekend?
It's now?
Yeah, we'll fly back
Sunday afternoon,
but with the time change,
you'll be back at work
on Monday morning.
Oh, yeah, uh,
I... I gotta be honest.
This isn't
the best weekend for me.
I'm kind of swamped.
Oh, no.
Do you have a lot of work?
Uh, we're two games
out of first,
with three weeks left.
Seattle's coming in
this weekend, and, I mean...
This is when
they need me.
They need you?
Wait a second.
I was just thinking
about it. That's all.
A tip, Ben.
When your girlfriend says,
"Let's go to Paris
for the weekend," you go.
All right, all right.
I'll go. I'll go.
You'll go? You know what?
I have a better idea.
I think I'll take him.
Hey. Just slow down
a second, okay?
Just go and enjoy
your ball game.
You know, this is
the second day in a row
you've snapped at me.
I'm late.
Fine. Go.
No, Ben.
I'm late.
How... How late?
Um, a week and a half.
Okay. That's not
that late. Right?
No. It is for me.
Okay. Well, you know what?
I mean, we're not
the first people to...
To, you know... To... 'Cause,
you know, when two people...
You know.
Deep breaths, Ben.
[Clears Throat]
Yeah. Why...
Why didn't you say something?
Why? So we could
both freak out?
I mean, I wanted to wait
for the right moment.
And then when this trip
came up, I thought,
we'll go to Paris,
and I'll tell you there,
because that did
seem special.
But, no, you don't see us
tangled up in the sheets
with the Eiffel Tower
in the window.
You see the Mariners
are coming and Pedro's
pitching Friday night.
[Mumbles]
Saturday.
Schilling's on Friday.
Look. I...
I admit I should have
reacted differently.
If I ever build
a time machine,
that's the first place
I'm going back to.
I'll be like,
"Paris, whoo! I'm in."
Uh, I...
Really, I'm sorry.
That's all right.
[Sighs]
But I have a 4:00 flight
that I have to catch.
All right. I can pack my bags.
We can put some stuff
together. We can make this.
No, it's okay.
The trip is already off
to a weird start.
Y...
Let's just talk about it
when I get back.
You sure?
Yeah.
You're sure?
I could tell them
I'm leaving right now.
We're going.
No. It's okay.
You gonna be all right?
If you give me a kiss
and wish me luck.
Good luck.
Way to go, Mr. W.
Yeah.
Okay. I'll see you
in a couple days. Okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
Are you smoking?
What are you doing?
I'm a teacher.
That's an insult.
Put it out.
Get back in class.
Come on.
[Man] So, the 30-year-old
is on course.
He is the four-time...
[Phone Rings]
Hello?
[Lindsey] I got it.
Linds?
Mmm.
I got it.
The promotion?
My period.
I can tell you were sleeping,
so I'll call you later.
No, no, no.
I'm up. I'm up. I'm up.
No, it's okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey, Linds.
Yeah?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Safe flight.
Okay. Bye.
[Line Clicks]
I'll get it.
No. I got it.
I got it.
Thank you.
Want me to take it up?
No. I'm okay.
I'm just gonna
go upstairs.
Bye.
Hey. Linds. Uh...
Did, uh...
Did you want a baby?
Eventually.
Well, eventually you will.
Well, it certainly
got me thinking.
That's for sure.
What do you mean?
Ben.
If I'm with a guy
for 11 months,
and I think I might be
having his child,
I'm gonna ask myself,
"Is this the guy?"
And if it is,
"What's this
going to be like?"
You know, if we're to be
Mr. And Mrs. Ben and Lindsey,
How's this going to work?
It's like Robin's
birthday party.
The minute
I got the invitation,
I had to run to
the refrigerator and check
the Red Sox schedule.
And the Yankees are playing,
so I know I'm going stag.
And that's okay.
I'm fine with that.
But how far does it go?
You know,
"Grandma, don't die
because
"the Red Sox are
going out on the road,
so please wait until
they come back to die."
And, "Doctor, induce labor
because the Oakland A's
are coming in tomorrow."
Do you remember last winter?
This is exactly
what you liked about me.
That I was capable
of having a passionate
commitment with something.
Uh, a devotion.
Yes, but you feel it
for the Red Sox, and I was
hoping that someday
you might redirect that.
All those things
that you feel
for that team,
I feel them too,
for you.
You know what she's saying
to me, Ryan? She's saying
I have an addiction.
Really? Well, you work
90 hours a week.
You know, that... But I guess
that addiction's more
socially acceptable, you know.
Am I wrong?
Well, nobody's really wrong
in these situations.
I mean, you have
wants and needs.
She likewise.
Wait for
your pitch, Miosky!
But she's great.
She's great.
[Ball Strikes Bat]
Definitely the best girl
I've ever gone out with.
The... The smartest,
the funniest,
the best-looking.
The sex is like
the... Well...
But there's a reason why
she's 30 and not married.
I mean, you gotta see
the big deal
she's making about
her friend's
birthday party.
Oh, God. She's making
a federal case about it.
I'm, like, hey, what if
I had to work that night?
What if I had a second job?
You know?
What if I was doing
charity work? Is that cool?
What if I'm, like,
finishing a painting?
Is that...
You understand me now?
See my point?
It's not the time.
It's she doesn't respect
how I'm spending my time.
And now she expects me
to miss a Yankees game?
[Laughs]
Whatever.
[Man]
Let's go, Murph.
You're up.
All right,
Mr. Wrightman.
I gotta bat.
Let me just leave you
with this thought.
You love the Sox.
But have they ever
loved you back?
Who are you, Dr. Phil?
Get out of here. Go hit...
Go swing the bat.
[Man Announcing]
The Red Sox
started off tonight
three games behind
the Yankees.
Pedro delivers. The ball is
lined over Bellhorn's head
into right center field.
That'll get another run across
as the Yankees extend
their lead.
[Jazz]
[Jazz Continues]
Benny boy,
I still can't believe
you're not at the Yankee game.
Yeah, well, if the Yankees
looked that good in a dress,
I'd be at the game.
[Glass Clinking]
There's no way to measure
what she is worth.
I'm the luckiest man
on the face of the Earth.
[Crowd Murmuring]
Her, uh...
Hang on. Hang on.
Okay. "I'm the luckiest man
on the face of the Earth.
"Her face, her form,
her sweet, loving smile.
And she even lets me
dance around in her panties
once in a while."
[All Gasp]
My parents are here!
[Cheering]
Really embarrassing.
Really bad.
I love you,
birthday girl.
I love you.
[Big Band Jazz]
[Pop]
And so the conversation
turned
Until the sun went down
And many fantasies
were learned
On that day
Keep feeling fascination
[Jazz]
Have I a hope
or half a chance
To even ask
if I could dance with you
Yoo-hoo
Would you greet me
or politely turn away
Would there suddenly be
sunshine on a cold and
[Vocalizing: "Dirty Water"]
[Man On Radio]
Yankee bats
have come alive tonight.
What's up, my man?
Oh. The game.
No, no. Hey.
It's fine. It's fine.
It's fine.
Okay.
[Man] None have been
successful so far against
this powerful Yankee offense.
6-0, Yankees.
[Chuckles]
[Man] Timlin ready to face
the left fielder,
Hideki Matsui.
Timlin to the belt.
Here's the pitch.
[Ball Dings Against Bat]
Swung on.
A drive hit high and deep.
And this one is gone.
7-0.
Matsui has hit his second
home run of the night.
Hey. It's only a game.
That was like...
Yeah.
I mean...
I mean, you were...
Thank you.
Not... Not just physically.
I mean, it felt like...
Like we were...
Mm-hmm.
[Chuckles]
I think this might be
the greatest night of my life.
[Phone Rings]
Hello.
[Men Shouting]
Hold on.
I think it's Troy.
It's really noisy.
Hey. Do you want
some food?
Yeah.
Okay.
Hello?
Hey, what's that noise?
Ben, we won! We won!
We were losing 7-0
in the bottom of the ninth!
We scored eight runs!
Ten straight hits!
It was unbelievable, man!
It's the greatest night
in the history of Fenway Park!
Can you hear this?
It's bedlam here, man!
Yes! By... by the end,
the stands were
literally shaking!
The fire marshal
had to get the...
[Indistinct]
To stop jumping up and down!
The one game you missed!
You missed
the greatest game ever!
[Yelling]
[Beeps Off]
[Cheering On TV]
This is an historic night,
Natalie.
And word is these
tickets stubs are already
getting $200 on the street.
I have seen at least
a dozen women celebrating
topless in the streets.
Moments ago I witnessed
a nun dancing on top of
a moving vehicle.
I have seen police officers
toasting beer
with underage children.
It is absolute bedlam
down here.
Right now I think
we're witnessing
the largest conga line ever.
I tell you what.
If you are not down here
right now,
you're missing
one heck of a party.
[Whimpers]
There are three eggs
in Spanish omelet
[Whistling]
Hi. Would you like
an omelet?
They... Won.
The Red Sox?
Oh, good!
This really is your night.
No. You don't understand.
They scored eight runs
in the bottom
of the ninth to win 8-7.
It was the best game ever.
I... I can't...
I... I never miss a game.
Ever.
This is like a nightmare.
No, this is beyond that.
This is like a punishment
from God or something.
Two minutes ago you said
this was the best night
of your life.
Yeah. Two minutes ago
it was.
Hey. I didn't tell you
not to go.
Oh, no. No, no.
Of course not. No.
You had nothing to do with it.
I just suddenly had a whim,
after 11 years of never
missing an inning, to suddenly
not go to a Yankees game.
[Lindsey] Hey.
[Whimpers]
Wasn't it you yourself
that said just tonight,
"It's only a game"?
Oh, that's great.
That's great.
Pile it on. Yeah.
Kick me when I'm down.
That's great.
It is just a game.
Clearly, it's not
just a game!
If it was,
then obviously I wouldn't
care about it this much.
Twenty-three years.
Do you still care about
anything you cared about
23 years ago?
How about 10?
How about five?
Name me a single thing
that you've cared about
for 23 years.
Yeah. No, um,
there isn't actually anything
I've wanted for 23 years
because 23 years ago
I was seven,
and if I still wanted to marry
Scott Baio, I would think that
my life went terribly wrong.
I... I just thought tonight
was so different.
You broke my heart, Ben.
Hey.
[Shouting, Faint]
Awesome!
Whoo-hoo!
Wow!
Yeah, baby!
[Man Announcing]
Well, the Red Sox's
once-promising season
has certainly taken
a turn for the worse.
Losing the last three games,
and today trailing
to the Texas Rangers.
Curse of the Bambino.
To think we quit our jobs
for that road trip.
It's not a curse.
Did you know the Titanic
sank the same week
Fenway Park opened?
April 1912.
Oh, you...
[Crowd Booing]
Well, that's it.
The Yankees officially
clinch the division.
Seven years in a row now,
we finish with our faces
in their butts.
Hey, hey, hey.
It's not time to jump off
the Tobin Bridge yet, okay?
We still have the wild card.
Oh, that's easy.
First we gotta beat Oakland
or Anaheim, on the road.
Then we gotta play
the Yankees
in the house of pain.
Why do we inflict this
on ourselves?
Why?
I'll tell you why.
'Cause the Red Sox
never let you down.
Huh?
That's right. I mean...
Why? 'Cause they haven't
won a world series
in a century or so?
So what?
They're here.
Every April, they're here.
At 1:05 or at 7:05,
there is a game.
And if it gets rained out,
guess what.
They make it up to you.
Does anyone else
in your life do that?
The Red Sox
don't get divorced.
This is a real family.
This is the family
that's here for you.
You know, I don't ask her
to give up her family, do I?
Come on!
Let's get some runs!
You know the best part?
I can get over her
because I am a Red Sox fan.
I mean, I'm tough.
I've been through a lot
in this park, man.
I can take this.
Because I am bulletproof.
[Music]
Carl Yastrzemski
[Announcer
On TV, Indistinct]
Carl Yastrzemski
the man we call Yaz
we love him
Carl Yastrzemski
[Man Announcing]
Behind the bag!
It gets through Buckner!
Carl Yastrzemski
Here comes Knight,
and the Mets win it!
[Continues]
[Knocking]
[Troy]
Open the door, man!
[Yelling]
Little roller
up along first.
Behind the bag!
It gets through Buckner!
Oh, my God.
The Buckner game?
I thought you took
that away from him!
I did!
Behind the bag!
It gets through Buckner!
Carl Yastrzemski
The man they call Yaz
And the Mets win it!
It wasn't just Buckner.
Stanley screwed him.
He didn't cover first.
Where'd you get this?
I... I don't remember.
Don't lie to me.
Right. Do you have
any more of these?
Huh? Where's your stash?
Ben, this isn't
helping you.
You understand that?
This solves nothing!
Ben, look at you.
Yeah, leave me alone.
All right.
Let's clean him up.
[Gerard] Come on.
I let her down.
Let's go.
I am the Red Sox.
You're not
the Red Sox.
I am the Red Sox.
You're not the Red Sox.
Get him up on the shoulder
there, Gerard.
I got the
shoulder right now.
What are you doing?
Relax. I'm a doctor.
Yeah, well, not to pry,
Doc, but why are you
shaving my balls?
Well, if you don't
want me to...
No, I don't want you to.
Whatever.
Hey.
[Man #1]
Bottom of the 10th.
[Man #2]
Swing and a fly ball
to left field! Way back!
Way back!
The Red Sox are going
to the American League
Championship Series
on the back of David Ortiz!
All right. You've been
waiting all year for this.
The Yankees, Red Sox,
the best rivalry in sports
starts tonight.
8:00, Yankee stadium.
Let's get it on.
[Man Announcing]
The 2-2 pitch.
Mueller back to Rivera.
To second for one.
On to first. Double play!
And the Yankees take game one.
[Man Announcing]
The Yankees are a strike away.
Here's a 1-2 pitch.
Struck him out swinging
that'll wrap it up.
For the second night in a row,
the Yankees have beaten
the Red Sox.
Here's a 2-0.
Mueller flies to center.
Bernie Williams is there,
and the Yankees have won it.
The end of a long night,
and perhaps the end for
the Boston Red Sox,
losing tonight 19-8,
now falling in the series
three games to none.
I mean, this thing is over.
They keep swinging the bats
the way they are, Don,
this thing's done.
19-8. Good God.
Will you stop
saying that? Okay?
Now, who we pitching
tomorrow?
What's the difference?
We're losing
three games to nothing
to the Yankees.
In a hundred years,
no team in the play-offs
has ever come back from that.
It's over. It's finished.
Bye. Wave to it.
Bye, Charlie. Bye, Charlie.
Oh. Isn't that
Jason Varitek?
[Kevin]
Yeah. That is him.
With Johnny Damon and Trot.
[Troy]
They're eating.
So what?
So what? We're sitting here
dining on our guts
over the Red Sox.
And there three members
of the Red Sox are eating.
With gusto?
Ironic.
Ironic?
Ted Williams would roll over
in his freezer if he saw this.
[Gerard]
Would you please be cool?
Why shouldn't they eat?
They... They played hard.
They did their best. Move on.
I kind of envy these guys.
You know. No.
They understand something
that we don't.
Their whole life
isn't out in that field.
It's their job.
It's not an obsession.
My God!
It's official.
I'm an idiot.
[Laughter]
[Lindsey]
That's funny because
I was gonna...
[Doorbell Rings]
[Lindsey]
Can you get the door?
[Man] Sure.
[Speakers: Pop]
Hello.
Uh, is... Is Lindsey...
Who are you?
I'm Patrick.
I'm Ben.
Oh, Ernie.
Stop it, Ernie.
Please.
Hey, Ern.
[Growls]
Ernie! Ernie, be nice.
You be a good boy now.
[Music Continues]
Uh...
Come on. Sorry.
Ben.
Hi.
[Continues]
Uh, what are you...
What are you, having a party?
Uh, a group of us, um,
just had this work thing,
and then some of us
came back here after.
Um, I'm gonna
talk to him, okay?
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm good. Thanks.
Are you...
Are you on a date?
No. It's...
It's a work thing.
I didn't want to go alone,
so, you know... Carrie
and Ezra are here as well.
Oh. So it's a double date.
Well, that's...
That's perfect.
That's great.
Ben, what are you
doing here?
I... I wanted to
talk to you. I...
I can't believe
you're on a date.
This is like...
I'm not.
Yeah, well, you know what?
Look. I'll call ya.
Sorry I bothered you.
I'll call ya.
No, no.
This is crazy.
I'm sorry.
I came here for a reason.
All right. Look.
I love you, Lindsey.
And I think that we should
give this another chance.
Did you hear me?
Ben...
Oh... Look, look, look.
You finish your evening.
All right?
I'll hang out here,
and when you're done
with your date,
we'll get married.
I don't think so.
Hey. What are you saying?
I mean...
You know, you said
you wanted more.
I mean, this is
as more as there is.
There is no more.
Yes. But this isn't you.
This is the other guy.
What other guy?
It's October.
They're one game from
elimination. You're becoming
Winter Guy again.
I already know
I like Winter Guy.
It's Summer Guy
that broke my heart.
Summer Guy is gone.
Yes, until summer.
No, no, no. Look.
Lindsey, I realize, like...
Ben,
just too much
has happened.
Oh.
All right.
Look, look. Uh...
When the whole
baby thing happened,
I admit I froze.
All right. I thought of
a million different reasons
why I shouldn't be a father.
But then I thought of
a reason why I should.
Because it would be ours.
You know, it's pieces of us.
And I got so excited.
I mean, like, I went,
and I got a whole bunch
of Red Sox toys...
And a little
size-one Red Sox jersey,
like, for a player
to be named later.
I still have it
for... Whenever.
Ben, I just got so hurt.
Really hurt.
And sometimes,
when that happens...
[Sighs]
Something inside
just shuts off.
I'm sorry.
[Sobs]
I never felt magic
crazy as this
I never saw moons
knew the meaning of the sea
I never held emotion
in the palm of my hand
Or felt sweet breezes
in the top of a tree
But now you're here
Brighten my northern sky
Oh. None for me.
[Robin]
Oh, come on.
Since when did
you stop drinking?
Yeah.
Since I... Got pregnant.
[All Gasp]
Molly.
I knew it!
You did not.
Mm-hmm.
I told Lindsey. I said,
"Her boobs look engorged."
Was Steve excited?
Are you kidding? He ran out
and bought him... Her...
A little train engineer hat.
[Cell Phone Rings]
Oh, I'm sorry.
They do that, don't they?
Little hats...
Hello. It's Chris!
You gotta come with me.
Molly's pregnant.
Mr. Myerson just announced
you got the promotion.
Oh, God! Sorry.
Oh, my God.
Now my breasts are engorged.
That was Lindsey.
She got her promotion.
[Carrie] He's waiting.
He's holding champagne.
Everybody's got a glass.
I told him you're in
the ladies' room.
Oh. Thank you. Okay.
[Laughs]
Well... Wait.
I gotta... I'm so sorry.
I gotta go.
Go, go.
Guess what Chris is
doing right now.
He's buying Ben's
baseball tickets.
What?
Ben is selling Chris
his Red Sox tickets.
Lindsey, please. Let's go!
Wait. You mean, like,
um, for today.
No. I mean, like, forever.
For 125,000,
it better be forever.
Are you guys that rich?
Yeah.
Why don't you
dress better?
Wait. Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
Ben... My Ben... is selling
his Red Sox seats?
To hell with the seats.
They're holding champagne.
Come on.
[Crowd]
Let's go, Red Sox!
[Clapping]
You know,
what you're doing is illegal.
That's right. Technically,
if you give up your tickets,
you're supposed to give 'em
to the Red Sox.
Hey. We're friends. Okay?
They'll still be in his name.
They'll mail them to him,
then he'll give them to me.
Does the guy with
the big squash always sit
in front of you?
He's new.
I don't know.
You want the tickets or not?
Come on. Ow!
Shame on you.
Your Uncle Carl
saw 3,000 games
from these seats.
He's gonna come back
and haunt you for this.
[Applause]
[Man] Speech!
Let's go. Come on.
Well, first,
thank you, Mr. Myerson.
Um...
[Clears Throat]
The truth is
I... I like it here.
I like this work.
I know what I'm doing
when I'm here.
In fact,
it's the only place...
Where I know what I'm doing.
This is, uh, controllable.
It's safe.
Oh, my God.
He's selling
his Red Sox tickets for me.
What have I ever
given up for anybody
that meant that much?
I'm sorry.
I know this seems crazy,
but I gotta go.
You realize
you're selling your seats
for exactly the same price
they sold Babe Ruth for.
You said it yourself.
Relationships come and go,
but the Red Sox are forever.
I want my sponges back.
Would you be selling these
tickets if we were winning?
I bet you wouldn't.
We're never winning.
That's the point.
We're down three games
to nothing. It's 4-3.
They got Rivera warming up
in the bull pen. Look.
[Man On P.A.]
Designated hitter. Number 18.
John Olerud.
Look. If I keep
these seats,
all I'll think about
every time I'm here is...
Is what I gave up for them.
[Tires Squeal]
[Tires Screech]
Excuse me.
Is there a ticket window
somewhere?
Sold out, sweetie.
It's the play-offs.
All right.
Hey. Hey.
You need tickets?
Oh. You too.
No, no.
I got tickets.
We... Then why the sign?
That's for the cops.
Everybody knows when you say
you need tickets,
means you have tickets.
Okay. I need a ticket.
Calm down.
I got two. 300 apiece.
What?
Hey. The only reason
they're that cheap
is because
it's the eighth inning.
Fine.
I'll take one.
I can't split 'em up.
Thank you.
Hey, hey.
You know what?
Since you only need the one
ticket, I'll buy the other one
back for, like, 50 bucks.
Oh, okay.
That sounds good. Oops.
Enjoy the game.
[Cheering]
Ben, how do you know
she'll even take you back?
It's... It's not just
for her, okay?
It's also for me, okay?
I gotta get
my life in order.
Some perspective.
Some balance.
Hey. We've got a deal.
I'll buy your seats.
It's a real ticket.
Oh, it's a real ticket,
but you're at
the wrong entrance.
You're way over
in center field.
I just gotta get in
for a minute...
That's a ploy.
I know it's a ploy.
You're in center field.
Fine.
[Man Announcing]
Ground ball
to the right side.
A race to the bag.
Rivera is there.
And the Yankees are three
defensive outs away
from the World Series.
Into the ninth.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Ooh. Sorry.
[Woman]
Watch it.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Can I borrow these
for a second? Thank you.
Yeah.
Sure.
No.
Why don't you have
a cell phone, you idiot?
Sign by the red tab.
Initial by the yellow tabs.
What are you buying,
the stadium?
Look at that thing.
Floyd the Barber,
we're not in Mayberry, okay?
Thank you.
Hey. Down in front.
Come on, sweetie.
Hold your horses, buddy.
[Panting]
Robin. Wait. No.
I can't talk right now.
Listen. I just need
Chris's cell phone number.
[Scoffs]
[Cell Phone Rings]
That's odd.
You're having a stroke.
Good.
I don't want to talk now.
I'm at the ball game.
Chris!
[Beeps Off]
Damn it!
[Sheri]
Ben, come on.
Don't do it.
This is crazy.
Think about it, Ben.
Check's all made out.
I'll invite you to
some of the games.
I'm sorry, Uncle Carl.
[Pen Scribbling]
Another idiot.
And when you think
it's all over
[Groans]
It's not over
When you think it's all over
[Crowd Cheering]
It's not over
Hold it. Hold it.
Don, I hate to interrupt,
but something is happening
in center field.
It's not over
[Man On TV] This young lady
jumped out of center field.
No. No. The TV.
Give her a little credit.
She's pretty impressive.
[Man #2]
She took her heels off.
[Whimpers]
Pretty good-looking too.
[Continues]
Go on!
You see that?
She just grabbed
Johnny Damon's butt.
Oh, cool!
[Continues]
Hey!
Ben!
Lindsey.
Ben. Ben!
What are you doing?
You're gonna get arrested.
Don't sell
your tickets, okay?
That's why you ran
across the whole field?
Yes. To stop you.
What?
You're out of here.
Just give me a second, okay?
Just give me a second. Please!
You gotta tell me. Wait.
The outfield- the grass-
is it spongy?
Ben, focus.
Sorry.
These seats are
important to you, okay?
This is your summer family,
your Uncle Carl.
You love these seats.
No. I fell in love with this
when I was seven...
because I had nothing else.
Now I'm in love with you.
I don't need this.
I don't want this.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
You love me enough
to sell your tickets.
I love you enough
not to let you.
What do you say
we try to do all of it?
Let's try to jerk one
out of the park.
That's the sexiest thing
I've ever heard in my life.
Ma'am, you're gonna
have to come with me.
Ben.
Yeah?
I'm being arrested.
All right.
Let her go, buddy.
Never.
[Cheering]
[Rock]
[Man Singing]
Hear the crowd roar
to your sound
Don't blame us
if we ever doubt you
[All Cheering]
[Continues]
[Al Narrating]
Well, you pretty much
know the rest.
Rivera walks Millar.
Roberts pinch-runs
and steals second.
Mueller drives 'em in.
Ortiz in extra innings.
Extra innings again
the next night.
[Continues]
[Clapping In Rhythm]
Schilling's bloody sock
in New York.
Lowe and Pedro
find their form.
Damon's grand salami
in game seven.
Bye-bye, Bambino.
[Man Announcing]
Boston Red Sox
have won the pennant!
[Al]
So what am I saying?
That it was all karma
because Lindsey
came back to Ben?
Look. All I know is,
when the Red Sox went to
St. Louis for the Series...
me and the girls
and Artie told them...
"You two gotta be there
to keep this thing goin'."
[Continues]
And they went,
and lo and behold-
[Man Announcing]
Back to Foulke. Red Sox fans
have longed to hear it.
The Boston Red Sox
are world champions.
[Al Narrating] And that
night there was a blue moon
and a total eclipse.
And those are the facts.
[Man Singing]
[Al Narrating]
Oh. One more thing.
You know that little player
to be named later?
Ben says if it's a boy,
they'll name him
Ted Williams Wrightman.
If it's a girl,
Carla Yastrzemski Wrightman.
Let's all pray for a boy.
[Continues]
[Radio Dial Switching]
[Man On Radio] Come to
Washington Square Tavern
on Beacon Street...
where Sox fans hang-
[Radio Dial Switching]
[Country]
[Man]... cars, S.U.V. S,
trucks and work trucks.
Come and get 'em
at Cerrone Cadillac.
[Dial Switches]
[Rock]
[Man Singing]
[Continues]
[Radio Dial Switching]
[Man] Ask for Kevin,
and get your first drink free.
Remember.
The Deluxe on Chandler and-
[Radio Dial Switching]
[Pop]
[Woman Singing]
[Continues]
[Radio Dial Switching]
[Man] WEEl in Boston,
the Dennis and Callahan
program.
[Radio Dial Switching]
[Man] Rolling.
One, two, three. And-
[Vocalizing]
[Man Singing]
[Continues]
[Vocalizing]
[Man Singing]
Let's go, Red Sox!
[Clapping]
English - US - PSDH