Are you ready?
SEVEN MONTHS EARLIER
Constantly we promised that you will change, not
mijenjaš it. - Shatters from liability, I will quit!
I am guaranteed to you in this business.
And what time will it achieve?
Look, tomorrow you have no more excuses.
If we do that, then do it.
You should see a boxer...
Thank you, thank you...
Thank you, my favorite classes.
"It is better to die in that gaping infinity
but infamously rush lee
even if it is security.
What do you think that the message of the novel?
Does anyone know?
Enjoy the holiday.
Pleasant Ijeto you, Mr. P.
Dad is not feeling the best.
The first day of the rest of your life.
Let's go.
It's on... called Martinez.
Undefeated.
Professor, how are you?
Well, hecto, all the "bueno".
Good look, bro.
What can I say.
I'm glad to see you back in business.
This is my partner, Diane Stone. It's nice to meet you.
I brought the boy to be seen sparring
my boxers. Later we'll talk.
Come on, girls. It is not
so bad.
Come on, man, get up.
Let's go!
Fuck off out of my gym.
Do not go no money.
Nothing I will not pay you. Bugger off
here before and I take out.
Professor, it was a cheap trick, you know?
Get out of here!
Professor, give my boyfriend a couple of minutes. He will be ok.
It will take more than a few minutes, Hector.
What the hell are you doing this?
Are you looking for talent? There he is.
Who is he to hell. Nothing about him we do not know.
Stop it. Call it.
Hey, boy, come here.
Tell that bastard son, that I will not.
It does not interest us.
We are not here because of that.
I'm Diane Stone, and this is
my partner Marty Goldberg.
Good work in there.
Tommy.
Hi, Tommy.
I know who you are. Once you're trained Silas,
is not it? He fought for the title 1999th Mr.
Prior to this he was an excellent boxer.
Can you?
I read about you in the newspaper.
What are you doing here?
Good question.
I watched the match.
Was supposed to win.
We almost did.
"Almost" is a bitch.
We both pretty impressed with what you did there.
Who trained you? - Self-training.
- Do you have any manager?
Do you see that razbacujem dollars this way?
Are you razmišIjao to
professional boxing you do?
Yes, then I wake up
and I have to work like everyone else.
We are looking for a good middle-weight.
Let us treat you dinner.
I have to go home. I'm late.
Please wait.
Call us in the morning. Ugovoricemo something
to earn some money, to izvuceš
from these holes. Do you need transportation? - No, thanks.
I'm glad to meet you, Tommy.
And you're right, "almost" is a bitch.
There are a lot of talent
that at his age would not be used.
He still needs a lot of
work. I do not know.
The kind of person with stroke even better...
They can sell it immediately.
Workout here. With the worst.
Damn it, Marty. Do not start with that crap again.
In the end, you're uvukao me into this.
I do not know if I have it in you anymore.
I believe in you.
Hello.
Sometimes with was so passionate...
full of life.
We no longer know who you are.
As for anything that does not exist.
I do not know what you feel or think
because you just exclude me.
I do not know what else to do.
The fact that I moved did not help.
I love you, Tommy, really
with all my heart and soul.
But just like
no longer can.
Ok, do not fit. Do not forsake bag.
Will tell you when to hit,
just as the opponent. I stop.
Right side holds back as if waiting for an attack.
Yes, sir.
Call me Marty.
Yes, sir, excuse me, I think Marty.
It is my habit.
It's okay.
Let the shoulder to move.
Kid looks good, Professor. But the bag
unresponsive shock. - What she said, grandparents?
Decline, Mobley.
Learn to control that anger.
It seems to me a better boxer.
If you are a professional,
then and Behave.
OK, enough.
Vacations bag.
Are we finished?
I saw everything you need to see.
Will I sparingovati?
No, I saw enough.
I know I'm a little rusty, it's been a long time...
You do not need me to sell.
What does it mean?
Anything you say will change what you see.
Tell me about yourself.
What are you doing?
Expands computer cables.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
What do you want?
What do you think?
Why are we here?
Why boksuješ?
I have nothing else to do.
You're talented, but talent is given to you.
The question is what do you want to do with her?
You have chosen to come here.
Because I see potential, but it does just that.
Understand what you are talking. Continue.
No! I do not understand.
I would not even their Tracie neither my
time I do not think you're special.
You will work hard.
I work hard. - Then listen. - I listen.
Do me a favor.
Do me a favor. Sit and silent!
Whatever the "special" is in
the madness, I think that you have.
If you want to iskoristiš that you've got,
shut up and listen. I think we have something here.
I had several conversations about Tommyja
and received three bids, but I think we should...
Do not do anything until
do not see in the ring. Pepper!
Mobley?
Test this guy.
No fractures.
Tommy... three rounds.
It's okay.
I do not care how much you're fine. Make it.
Ready? Go.
To hit harder, a bastard son?
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Lucky strike.
For today is enough.
You said three rounds.
Oboricu it. I'm fine.
I'm there to worry about whether you're good.
If you continue so, you will have to present the sale.
I do not want to think about...
Come on, you were good. Come on, go to the opera.
I'll take it.
He was good.
What was it the hell?
Hey.
How are you?
I'm fine. I'm sorry for what...
No, my job is to worry. Come on, I'll help you.
Here it is.
I sought you in the archives.
You did not tell me that you fought for the Olympics.
Yes.
I?
I'm lost.
What happened?
The first time I then knocked out.
This is all happening.
Not me.
This tattoo. What does the "S"?
Stephanie.
Girl.
I do not know. It's a long story.
What are you doing for dinner?
I am preparing myself home.
You Kuvasz?
Spaghetti, pasta, soup...
Purchased items.
I'll make you something once.
I am a great cook.
Maybe too good.
Ovoda gotta see. I think
to smop may bet on the wrong horse.
What is it?
Qualifying for the Olympics, 1999. Mr.
Riley entered the finals as a
knocked out Antonio Castilloa.
A good first Round of Riley. Both boxers
using short strokes, but Riley dealt several blows stronger.
It seems to be disagreed Rileyov angle.
Again we see treberov temperament
Riley is almost
disqualified in the semifinals.
What is wrong? When the game starts,
let the guy to boksuje.
This is a psychological confusion. You need to keep him focused.
Hitherto it has brought, there may be some of their methods.
Kane attacks Riley
Raging blows.
Riley does not use your instinct and
what led him this far,
I mean, the guy looks like
is not afraid to make mistakes.
Kane hitting Riley in the head and
Riley was shot down.
Coach Riley to scream to get up.
What to do? This is stupid. Amateur.
Keep the boxers on the floor
while counting judges and give Man
opportunity to return to his legs.
Referee checks and Riley
lets continue to fight.
Kane Zasip blows...
so it must be finished off.
After one nokdauna Kane has an advantage.
I would be in skin Ruleyovoj now.
Because he needs a knockout in the last round that won?
No, because they must return to the corner.
This is an abuse of boys by the coaches.
Riley almost can not participate
the qualifications for the preparation of the
Coach Holt clamored to him
"Teaching" him not to be hit.
I could not believe it
when I heard, but I believe now.
The doctor approached Rileyevom corner of the judge and
check him your hand. Riley jauce of pain.
The match is over.
Referee stops the match
and Leroy Kane goes to the Olympics.
I'm glad for Kane, a good boxer,
but I was sorry about Riley.
He had complete control from beginning
while his coach did not enter into combat confusion.
But sorry Riley...
Steph?
Zdavo, what happens?
How are you?
Good.
You were sleeping?
Yes.
You're a little wear.
Take care of themselves?
Yes.
You have a lot of good fighters here?
Since when is this?
Ago.
I watched clips from
qualifications.
Who is the coach?
Stepfather.
Boxing is a team sport.
Most people do not realize
because they see only one man in the ring.
But ask any of them,
have never been alone
Kane was alone,
but you were.
If you are not part of a team, better
not pojavljuješ.
Have you read Moby Dick when at school?
No. But I watched the movie.
It is a novel. Podsjecaš me in a paragraph.
"It is better to die in that gaping infinity
but infamously rush lee
even if it is security.
One day, not now...
when you are older
when you really understand what is important, when it
too late, when the osvrneš and wish that you made a different choice.
I appreciate that you came and care,
but I'm fine, because...
I was the champion of the Marines and I got
many offers to boksujem professional.
However, did have
unfortunate things, and say
I felt that you do not deserve
to me all these good things happen.
I could not understand what other people
saw in me, I did it I could see.
So I hand proturio
through the window, damaged nerves...
I have done it
I no longer have to spar.
I'm talking like you now. At that time
I did not believe in what and no one.
I see where it led.
In you I see the light that is
I long ago came from.
Doing to regret for what could
be a dream what can be.
We will do this together, eh?
Come here.
What?
I want to kiss you.
I do not need a hug.
Maybe I should, tough guys.
I believe in you.
Anger is the wind, which turns off
lamp of the mind.
You have to control your anger, Tommy,
that he would not control you.
If you want to conquered the best, you can only
boksiješ, Tommy. You have to learn how to nadmudriš.
When you come into the ring, I will be there with you,
will look each of his movement, will seek the hole.
And it still exists.
I find it and I will give to you.
We are a team, Tommy, the two of us together,
nothing can stop us. Nothing.
What was no longer.
You should see this.
D all get an offer.
Soon more will not be able to afford it, believe me.
I knew you were smarter than
you are talking about. See you on 17
All you have to do is that we believe.
Vjerij, perform.
What is this?
When you did this?
Lucy helped me.
How about this, huh?
Last week, this place was rubble.
Check this out!
Fine.
Now we can do alone. No one can
study. Maintenance element of surprise.
But now you have to start to train full time.
Yes, I'm ready.
You will leave the job.
I can not leave the job. Work is all I have.
Do not worry about work, work is past.
This is your future, Tommy.
Do not worry, Diane and I will take care
on your costs and you, ok?
I came just to see how you are.
Tommy, this is Brad.
Brad, this is Tommy.
Tommy, stop!
Tommy!
I was passing by...
Yes, go.
You sure?
Yes, certainly.
Lucy, this is Tommy.
Tommy, this is Lucy.
Enter. Are you hungry? Will have something to eat?
No, thanks.
Are you actually read all these books?
The most part.
If you see something you like,
go ahead and take it.
Here's something you will perhaps be interesting,
"David Copperfield."
The magician, right?
Not really.
Sit, let's eat.
It was the first person who really got me.
I understand, made to feel the...
like I'm ok.
Come to all my matches,
adored it.
I feel so good with it there.
And then I lost the qualification, and we planned
to go in the pros after the Olympics, so...
Your stepfather?
Sometimes I like to boksujem.
And the match I pobjedivao.
When I returned home,
all my things were ahead.
We have always been
a favorite topic of your neighbors.
Steph then decided to move here
and we seemed like a good idea to come with her
to help her to put
and that we may give an opportunity
to come up with what I will do that.
Three and a half years later...
What a pity. The idea that all that talent went out of the ring.
It is good that I encountered.
Tommy, the discipline.
Tommy, hands up!
Not rising to the end of the countdown.
Get up, Get up, jeb'o you!
Get up!
Use the countdown.
Are you okay?
What is going on, Tommy?
Give it to me, come on.
What's happening?
Hand me slomnjena. Quit match.
What?
Right?
Quit match. I can not fight.
Do not interrupt the match!
You only life to throw you
can not go back there, understand?
I can not...
Listen to me.
"If you can keep your head up when you think you lose,
if you can trust yourself when all doubt you,
if you can force your heart and
mind and nerves that those tears,
long before disappearing,
you'll be a man, my son. "Kipling.
On body and mind,
and finish it this right.
What is your arm hurt?
To the right.
That's what I thought. The first boxing rules and
first rule of life, and tonight you learned it.
Never cease to beat.
Just hit. Dudes you hit, you will always have a chance.
Who is it written?
I.
Give us a couple of minutes
and we will be ready for dinner.
Listen, Diane, if mnorate to save
honor your servant, will go to dinner.
But I have to be honest with
you, this will not happen.
It will take him three or four buckles, but it's nothing.
Lie down, you will, Tommy?
Thank you.
She touches you.
Maybe you have a milder concussion,
therefore probably should not be alone tonight.
Do you have a code to be with you?
No.
Would you stay with me?
Yes, of course.
Marty, I'm afraid of needles.
Do not be afraid of you nothing.
Closes his eyes and not move.
For the moment you go from here.
Blow when you do not see that coming
causes the most damage.
Is that right?
Yes, it's good.
You are relaxed, Tommy.
Never spuštaj hand.
But it worked,
Sugar Ray did it.
Well, you're not But not Sugar Ray.
Oh no.
Stupid, huh?
No, just another lesson learned.
Yes, this hurts.
The good hurt.
Cheers. - Tomorrow when you wake up I keep the movies.
What do you say to that?
Tomorrow, no training?
Got a couple of days free. - You're darežIjiv.
Just do not tell anyone.
Agreed.
Where did you get all that?
I got up early and went shopping.
I filled the fridge.
Even I myself bought a low fat breakfast. Proud?
Yes, every honor.
I see it around.
Seems to be fine.
Just to open.
Hello.
I thought that you need it.
God, what happened to your eye?
Nothing...
Oh, God, sorry...
It's not what you think. Enter.
Marty, this is Stephanie.
Stephanie, this is Marty.
I have heard many things about you.
Marty is my coach.
We won last night.
We knocked out type.
That's great.
About these horrible looking.
No, it's okay.
BREAKFAST, so I will...
No, stop. Stay.
It's OK, Marty, there are a lot of food.
Yes.
You'll be all right?
Yes. Everything is fine. I'll call you later.
Yes, of course. Do not do anything... It does not matter.
Marty seems fine.
To a great head.
When did you know?
He and his partner have come to train at Al Raya.
Now that you're best friends?
What are you, Ijubomorna?
No.
As soon as I came to see you,
in the kitchen preparing a stranger you breakfast.
I do not know what to think.
Marty is my coach.
You are vidaš with other people,
and you make me guilty?
It was not out, was a charity dinner and
Brad I just connected. - Yes, I bet it is.
Sorry.
Why did you come here?
I just wanted to see how you are.
I missed me.
Am I missing you?
You look different.
How?
Otherwise good.
Steph, what's going on?
You're poludio.
It is an investment. Write-off.
We do not need write-off. We need a subscription.
How much this cost me?
This is my personal savings.
Your guy has beaten a night.
We won, right?
This call victory? We lost
they jerk from HBO's.
What ciljaš?
- We cut off the Tommyjem losses and move on.
I do not think the winner and I think this does to himself.
Now you are an expert?
No, but I talked with other people and they agree.
Do not talk to other people but with me.
You do not see clearly, get rid of him.
I do not do.
I remember the girl who was too
shy to look at other people's eyes.
Fleeing from the school, the drugs.
Predozirala pills and stuck to rinse the stomach.
Do it be? Do you remember "experts"
who told me that I need
out of school because not worth anything?
But I do not listen to experts.
I listen to your heart. I was with her.
It seems to me that it goes quite well
because someone gave her a little Ijubavi, religion
and opportunity.
We do not need another opportunity,
I know what I see.
I see potential in this guy and let
damned if I let you fail.
It's a good guy. Only
I do not want to be injured.
It will not allow it.
What's next? - Kaneo have posted a bid...
- Kaneo have posted a bid? Accept it!
Are you sure it's ready?
Accept it! Accept it!
Hey, Marty, this is business, not personal.
I know.
Tommy, Marty said. I have wonderful news.
We managed! Diane contract
Leroy match with Kane. For four weeks.
This is serious. - And that's how.
- Is that enough time?
Yes, do not you read? Kane's
broke both of the article during the training.
It turns out, you upadaš. They think that you
be an easy opponent. But they think wrong.
Hi, Marty.
God, I'm sorry. I did not know that...
I tried to call, but
the phone was busy.
Yes, we remove the headset.
Can we razgovarmo in the hallway?
No, I'm already going to the bathroom.
I have a hut on the lake. I think it would be
good idea to go from here briefly.
Less interference. You are right on time
we do not have much time to prepare, because...
Pens like Kane,
We can shoot at Norris.
Whatever you think is best, ok?
This place is unbelievable.
Are there bears here?
I do not know about bears.
No! No spuštaj below.
Sorry.
Add me.
No, you did not know.
She had an accident when she was
rat. Not seen in the left eye.
Some squirrel was chased.
Go.
It is too vulnerable.
Tommy, take one down the room.
I think the warmest.
I'll take this one.
I love that I'm close to the bathroom.
Okay, go. One hour, a minute longer.
Give it to me, please.
Music, please.
You have to learn to motivate himself.
That the environment affects you. Do not block it.
Okay?
The ring will be no music. Is that right?
OK?
All right.
Here it is again. Left hook.
This is his big shot.
Pomjerice to
to set them for the left hook.
How do you stop it?
To keep my right hand up.
That's it. This will help much.
Here we like it.
We should be moving here.
Lived the good life.
All serious boxers usually
complete living with coaches.
Bllo would be great.
It would be like this every day.
You stand up and trciš, I am preparing breakfast.
Let's go to the movies.
I would maintain about you. Took care that my champion is
all he needs. - Is Silas lived with you?
Yes. I cooked every meal for him.
What happened?
Sharks šcepale him.
Seduced him great promises
They told him that it inhibits.
After a while they started to believe.
Kicked and after which you have
led to the match for the title? - It happens.
Jerk.
Have we been Ijut, that upset, yes.
But in the end I tried to understand.
Do not judge people, try to understand them.
Why?
What is the purpose of it?
From a real world place a lot of hatred.
And that's enough.
You never know what tragedy is waiting for someone after awakening.
What you see is what you get. - So I see?
Talk about it. - No, on all of us.
- No, I talk about it, okay? You're not fucked him.
You think you know everything about me?
Yes... no, I think I know who you are.
You know just what I am allowing you to see.
What does that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
What do you want to say?
Only that people not always what you see.
I am more than what you see.
All of us.
What you talking about?
Do you know why I like the rain?
Because it gives me a reason to stay inside.
I like winter because the days are shorter and night falls in 4 hours.
Sometimes the only thing that I am rising from the bed
utiješna thought that I will return to it when night falls.
Then every night I wake
terrified, mute, paralyzed.
I lay there and how razmišIjam
I can not come to the pill.
really know what the hell.
I'm afraid of loneliness, I'll die alone.
Nec never be, no one cares.
D I'm afraid to sleep,
but are too scared to be awake
because they can not isboriti with
own thoughts with them himself.
Do you know that I have most of his life
I spent wanting someone else?
Do I have never had the courage to
I like someone who would not back Ijubav.
I love dogs. My dog
life companion, Tommy.
Do you know why?
Because when I wake up in the morning,
she was there, waving his tail. No matter what.
Every day. I like to watch me
I am the only thing that matters.
I am her everything.
I can not sleep knowing that she
will never reveal anything about me
why will not escape.
So razmišIjaj, Tommy, before osudiš someone.
People are naive and stupid.
We all make mistakes,
Sorry...
Silas was a good guy.
He had problems.
We had problems.
But he did just what
thought that it must do so.
What problems?
It does not matter now.
It is important to understand
of which you speak.
Ok, I understand.
He won the title that stayed with you.
We will never know.
Yes, we will.
Stop!
Stop, stop...
OK, enough.
That's all for today.
We are a real team, huh?
Well we go, right? - Yes.
You know what, Kane is in distress.
The trouble is. It has to go back
broken nose in Philadelphiju.
Too much talk. Relax.
Relax a little.
Breath.
That's it.
This is better.
Marty, I just want you to know...
If it was not you...
It's okay.
What was that?
Marty? You're kidding, right?
Lord, I'm sorry, Tommy.
What's happening?
Sorry... I thought...
You're kidding, right?
Blla was a mistake, I thought...
Sorry.
What happened there?
Nothing. Forget it, please.
Shit! What was that?
I do not think I'm...
No, Tommy, no. It was my fault.
Sorry.
Please, tell me why we did not here.
No, of course not. It was a mistake. You're not done nothing wrong.
Razumjecu if you wish to proceed to train with someone else.
What you talking about?
We are a team, right?
Like you said, we're a team, right?
Say it was a coincidence, right?
Yes, it was an accident.
So everything is fine then?
None of which should be talking about?
You sure?
Yes.
What's happening?
Packing up.
Why?
We return.
Tell me about the road.
Just a lot of hard work, that's all.
Are you are you and Marty argued.
It seems as if the Ijut.
No, I think it is probably only
nervous about the match. That's all.
I'm nervous.
Yes I am.
Be patient. Not attacked too.
Keep away from his reach. Now try to knockout.
Wait it. It will not be able to compete
with your fitness.
Frustriraj it. Be patient.
Stick to the plan. Let it chase you.
If you the opportunity, go,
but do not force anything and do not spuštaj right hand.
If you get to the seventh round,
izmoriš his feet, it's yours.
It's okay, Marty. I do not want to
too relaxed.
All right?
Yeah, right.
Ladies, time to go.
Hey, ladies sticking out.
Can you kiss, for luck?
It's probably a bad idea.
Well, break it.
It is time to go, champ.
How do you feel?
Ok, Tommy. Focus.
Breathe.
Please fix it.
Stick to our plan.
Persistent zavlaci me. - Screw it.
Do not play with him, it's too dangerous.
Do not give him that came out.
Just moving. - You have a hook.
Frustriraj it. Natjeraj him to the chase. Let izmori.
Stick to the plan.
Focus. Well you go.
Come on, Kane! We worked hard for this.
All right, Tommy.
Perfect boksuješ.
Want to pobjediš match, Kane?
You have to nokautiraš.
You brought it to where we wanted. Now is our turn.
This is the seventh, just as we planned.
You want me to fight against Norris? Will you?
Man is constantly moving. - Screw it. They are moving with him. Nokautiraj it!
Listen.
Krode left him tied with the right shoulder.
Shoulder down before krošea.
As soon as the shoulder down,
hook coming.
Victory means the cash, baby.
This is our reward. You can do it.
Just as planned. The seventh round.
Let's do it now.
Entering inside.
We need the hospital. I want to get inside secure.
The guy can odaditi ten rounds tonight.
All is well. Good you were there.
Thank you. Thanks to this man here.
I booked us a dinner celebration at Taylor
tonight. - No way. I have always wanted to go there.
I know. Well, you deserved it.
We have earned.
Bob Silver. We definitely succeeded.
It pleased them to your beautiful face.
They want us all out.
His limo is outside.
About a half mile long.
That's it! We managed.
We will have a crazy night.
Idemjo Silver-Mobil. All entered?
Marty, what are you doing?
I'm going home to feed Lucy.
Come with us, at least briefly. We won.
I am proud of you.
Proud of us.
Come with us.
Some other time perhaps.
You're had your plans. I'm sorry.
I'm lost in this. - It's okay.
We will do it some other time. You may save a few hundred dollars. - Are you sure. View this fucking
limo. I got my limo. - Are you sure? - Yes, I'm sure. Absolutely. Go. It's nice to Spend.
Tommy...
Come on, you two. All waiting.
Tonight, you become a boxer.
No one can stop now.
None. But you alone.
Do not forget that.
Everybody loves a winner.
Voljece and me, right?
Marty does not go with us?
Lucy has to feed.
What have you done now?
Marty, go home...
feed the dog.
Bob said najnevjerovatnije things about you.
Maybe you'll get a chance to fight for the title.
Diane recently to push through the one your cigars.
Come here.
All is well.
He's asleep now.
Why did this?
Thus shall these things.
Is this because of what is
happened in the hut?
What happened in the hut?
He told me.
What?
Come on, Diana, I know.
When I was a boxer, a bastard
threatened to expose him,
because he put his hand window.
Then he graduated
and began to teach.
So we are upozali.
I was pulled because of it.
This job is a way to be seized
to bring him back to his feet.
Did you gave a speech about Moby Dick?
Yes. And you?
I do not think there is a person you know, and that it was not heard.
You have to love it.
Are you okay?
Good.
Check this out. I brought your pills, juice,
low fat ice cream.
Creepy said.
I know, but it is good for you.
And soy milk.
Soy milk?
Tommy, I'm sorry for all this.
Why?
We have a job. I can not afford
to be more zezaš.
We will put it in the kitchen.
I thought I was sleeping on the couch.
You do not have.
If you need something, I'll be there.
Ok. You do not have. Thank you.
Like you said:
"Just hit".
Jab. One, two.
Rotate. They move around with a bag.
Bag is your opponent. I tell you that you gain by going.
Smart.
Rotate. One, two...
You know what? Not bad for an old man.
Will a little water?
Yes, thank you.
I learned that everything we know, but not everything I know.
Is that right? Let's check.
Funny.
Good look. Not bad for a
old man, huh? The news of Silver.
Willing to give Tommyju
match with Norris for the title.
He wants to arrange a meeting immediately.
Contracts that. May at any time.
They want to be found with Tommyjem alone.
Why?
It will.
No, I told you, any other
Wednesday we do not like.
We will do this together. Only
question coordinate plans.
Tomorrow? No, I can then, great.
Doleticu later. Yes, so I have enough
time for all the crap before we go out.
So, call Jennifer.
It takes a book.
Yes, I see you. Dock wallet.
Tommy, it's good to see you again.
Great game from the night.
Tommy, I will not pricatii nonsense.
You're a championship-caliber boxer.
I want to be in the business Tommyja Riley.
Here's how we will.
Sign an exclusive contract with me and my
center for training, three games guaranteed
permission to go to the title
one million dollars.
How do you like it?
I will arrange the purchase of your current manager,
and you tell me how much time you need to clean up.
I think I do not understand.
Shopping? I can not leave Martyja.
Ok, I understand loyalty.
In fact, I respect it.
I mean, sitting here in part because of him.
Absolutely.
To gain by going to a completely new stratosphere
I take great risk.
I need to know that you're surrounded by people who know how
to take care of you. Real people, my people.
You will not be a boxer in the backyard.
I control the three titles, four
first-class competitors.
Ask any of them that brought them there,
they will tell me. They have come through this office.
Marty and Diane did a great job.
Have agreed to make educational games
opponents that made me look great.
They played very well and
you see where it led.
I can not leave Martyja.
Is there any way to continue to train me?
Tommy, what you need to know is that
Marty in this business has some sort of stain.
I am not interested in private Necin
lives until they begin to affect business.
The fact is that coach Marty devilish good, but fucked
by Siles, it can be done to you. Plain and simple.
Marty is a great guy. Arrange
to be well taken care of.
Only talk about the element
for whom boxing would never be ready.
Will never be ready for it.
I smao not...
Think about it. That's my offer.
Can you believe? Just me
care who he is. I will not do.
These things may be the only opportunity that you get.
Ugojicu ten pounds and fight against Varelle.
Silver does not have it. - I do not know either
whether you accept it. You do not have enough matches.
You spent two years preparing for anything.
You guys are all in the same bed.
Tommy, think.
Prespavaj it. All of us will.
I moved into a new apartment, I went...
Wait a minute. What kind of crap on educational games?
It's nothing, just a story, do not worry about it. Shit. What is thought?
Only say what it is. As we brought you this far.
We agreed with opponents who matches made me look good
Manještaljke? - Of course not. - Marty,
honestly I got those games, right? Absolutely.
Absolutely.
You were great. now you fucking greatest promoter in the business
wants you to pay a million dollars to fight for the title.
You must be delighted.
I do not want to do it. No, do not fight without Martyja and that's it.
Technically, it's not your decision.
What does it mean? - The contract was our decision.
He's right.
Do not fight it without you and hurt me what it says in those
contracts. - Not to me it does not matter what the contracts. - What then one story?
Listen to me for a moment. We will not sell you,
understand? Why do this? You know that.
I appreciate that you're doing, it's a venerable thing,
but I really want to accept the match.
I do not want to miss environmental opportunity. I considered that
took him as far as I could. Okay?
Silver can give you what you want. Can you give large
boxers. It will give you what you need and so you have less interference.
I told you I do not care for it. We completely understand.
If I go there without you,
then I am going.
Sam. All the things you said, "We're a team, boxing
is a team sport. There will never be alone "
Do to it. I assume that you thought, huh?
Tommy, what I did in the ring with you,
does not mean that I'm not with you.
Accept the offer.
Do not leave you.
I'm not a fucking Silas.
Do not fight it without you.
See you tomorrow in the hall, right?
Have you seen those contracts
with Martyjem and Diana?
I can not find them.
Why did not you said to offer?
I will not be accepted.
Marty says that if you do not accept this offer, you may
you will never have the chance to fight for the title.
Is it possible that it does not want?
Damn!
So you worked hard for this. Do
Do not how much you were unhappy?.
You know what I want. I want to boksujem more than any
nothing. I have to find the fucking papers.
Help me understand, ok? I am here for you, but if we
do not talk about these things, which we then anyway?
What is so afraid of?
Nothing!
I will not do. I will not accept the fucking offer.
Leave me alone!
Hi, guys.
How are you?
Good. This is Alex.
Tommy, this is Alex and Victor.
Will work with us. Put the bag there.
Marty? We work here.
Just to make sure these guys first.
Let's go one-two combination
three minutes.
Well you go.
Let's go one-two again.
Not a bad short direct.
Continue.
It's good, very good.
Three-two-three.
Come again. Be not sloppy.
Lord, did I also learned that, huh?
Come on.
Lord, boksuješ like my dead grandmother.
What do you think will happen? Be like hitting the
match with Norris, you think you have a chance?
I do not believe. Come on. Cheer up!
Small lessons. Cheer up.
Cheer up, you understand?
Wake up, Tommy.
You can move the old man. Lord.
Hit, or you can zabušavaš?
What you talking about?
What is it? You're a slacker, Tommy. That's what you are.
Come on, guys. Come on, damn it.
What do you do?
Razbucacu you to fucking fat ass.
I'll kill you. You hear me? I'll fucking kill you.
Marty?
Marty, opened the door, please.
Open the door, Marty!
Dotrcao I am here.
What do you want?
I think we have nothing more to say to each other, Tommy.
I think everything was very clear last time you were here.
I have no more that what you learn. I think the
time to both go their own way.
Yet I was not too late to call Silver.
I know what you're trying to do.
You will not succeed.
What I said, I apologize.
I did not mean, sorry.
Marty, can we, please, to
get back to how it was before?
No. I'm sorry.
For it is too late.
All right.
I'll give you anything you want.
Whatever you want.
What? What did you say?
I'll give you anything you want.
To think about me? After his time that I gave.
Sorry...
Get out of my house.
Marty, opened the door, please.
I did not mean that.
Please.
O Lord my God!
Why in life, once I was happy?
One way?
One! Lord.
Tommy...
Oh, my God. Marty!
Hello. Stephanie said.
Leave a message. Thank you.
Hi, Steph. I am.
I called just to tell you that I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I clamored.
I'm sorry for everything.
Marty's dead and I...
I'm sorry.
And I just wanted to know.
Are you ready?
Tommy!
Wait...
I have to go.
translation and processing:
@ Rose; @ miroslavR