30 years old
and no driver's license.
Fucking ridiculous.
I could have stayed
and hired another cameraman.
Have some jerk with
a shitty camera and no eye shoot it?
Forget it.
Look, we'll bail him out,
drive him to the rehab,
and drive right back up.
We'll just be a little late.
I don't understand...
the lawyer got a deal...
that he got six months in rehab
or three years in prison, and he...
And the judge gave him
10 days to enter the rehab,
and on the seventh day
he got arrested again.
Genius.
What am I supposed to do?
He's my brother.
I didn't even know
you had a brother, Milo.
I got an idea.
We could interview him
about his experiences.
No, that's not the film
I'm making. I'm not interested...
in some privileged white kid
who got himself into trouble.
Just because he's white
doesn't make him privileged, Bella!
- Stop pigeonholing people!
- I'm not pigeonholing him!
He's a victim of the very system
we're trying to expose with our movie!
He's a victim
of his own stupidity.
If he doesn't get to
the rehab by 8:00 pm. tomorrow,
he's going to prison.
Do you hear that clunking sound?
Yeah, my car's been
doing that. I don't know what it is.
- Have you checked the oil?
- Yeah.
When's the last time
you checked the oil?
I put veggie oil in it yesterday.
Not veggie oil.
Engine oil.
But what about your mom?
Can't she help him with it?
Our mom
lives in a cave in Greece,
our father's dead, our grandmother
has Alzheimer's, and...
don't even ask me
about his friends.
God, I hate L.A.!
It's so barren.
Just wait
'till you meet him, okay?
He's such a character.
Milo!
Sam?
Is that a camera?
- Yeah.
- Ah.
It's okay?
Oh, yeah.
- How ya doing?
- Hi. Uh, cash or credit?
Uh... credit.
Okay. This... huh.
So, do you mind if I ask you
how you became a bail bondsman?
It's a family business.
Sign here, print here, initial.
So, uh...
why do you pack that gun?
- This?
- Yeah.
- Oh, this is a...
- Oh, you don't have to pull it out.
insurance policy.
What do you mean?
A lotta people think
bail bondsmen carry the money.
We don't.
It's all paper.
If a brother doesn't show up to court,
I could go after him.
- If I no find him, I go after you!
- Oh, okay!
- Like Rambo! Boom!
- Oh, okay, okay.
Okay.
- All right. Take care.
- All right, then, Leo.
What's up, Leo?!
Each day better than the next.
We're in the Volvo right here.
Come meet my girlfriend.
Her name's Bella.
Drove all the way down here
from San Francisco.
Bella! This is Leo.
Hi, Leo!
Glad he's so appreciative.
- Sugar?
- No, thanks.
Just finish this,
and we should go.
Fuck you!
"Fac eu"... means "I'll do it"
in Romanian.
Thank you.
So, uh, why were you
arrested this time?
It's 'cause I'm black.
And what happened
to your shoes?
I don't know.
You were in a cell barefoot?
They gave me shoes,
but they were awful,
so I prefer to go barefoot,
you know?
I was running from the cops, right?
I fell over a wall... boom!
Fucked up my ankle,
the pigs caught up to me,
and my slippers were gone.
They were my favorite slippers, too.
Blue and a little gold.
What happened to your shirt?
It's fuckin' hot as balls in here.
I'm cold.
My shirt?
Fucking cigarettes!
I fell asleep
with a lit cigarette in my hand.
I wake up, and my favorite
fucking pajamas are ruined.
I feel sick.
Hey, do you have any laxatives?
- No.
- "No," no? Or "what," no?
Should we get the check?
Milo, we need
to go to the market.
I need to get laxatives,
cigarettes, and shoes.
Okay, but... can you
do that fast, 'cause we gotta go.
- I saw a market next door.
- OK, let's go, let's go right now.
Okay, I'll pay the check.
Just go fast.
- Alright. You want anything?
- Nope.
- You all right, babe?
- Yup.
- Okay, we'll be right back.
- Okay.
It hurts
to see you again like this, Leo.
Still addicted
to the camera, I see.
Thought about seeking help?
Admitting you have a problem
is the first step.
You're not gonna help me?
You're just gonna film me?
Okay.
Do you have any laxatives?
28.50.
Milo, do you have any money?
Did I go the right way?
Is this Anaheim?
You're heading the right way.
Okay, pull in right there.
- This is it?
- Yeah.
- Oh, perfect! All right, cool.
- I gotta get my car outta the impound.
- Left right here.
- Impound?
- Yes.
- Oh, this is the impound.
- No, no, no, no.
- Yeah.
- Oh, you have a car?.
- Yes.
Alright, perfect, you can drive yourself
to rehab, because we gotta get back...
- to San Francisco.
- No, no, no, no!
He's not driving himself.
He doesn't have a license, insurance.
Look at him.
Leo, we're not... we're not getting
your car outta the impound.
What do you want me to do?
You want me to drive both cars?
I have a 1960 black Impala.
It's beautiful...
- We're not gonna make it.
- It's a 20,000 dollar car...
- This car's a great car.
- It's a 20,000 dollar car.
You can have it to go up north.
I just need you to pay the impound fee.
It's only 800 dollars...
I can't leave my car here, Leo.
What do you want me to do?
- It's 800 even?
- Mh-hm.
Um, baby, are you sure
this is a good idea?
Are you kidding?
Did you see that car?
Yeah, but it seems
kind of crazy to leave my car here.
- I don't even know where we are.
- Baby, your car was falling apart.
All right.
I'm gonna go check on the Impala.
No, I'm coming.
Don't leave me. I'm coming.
Fuck!
Do you have a card?
It's okay.
Leo, that car is so cool!
What's wrong?
- Get in.
- Leo, you can't drive.
Get in the car.
You can't drive. You don't
have a driver's license or insurance.
- I don't have patience for you.
- What're you doing?
Get in the car. I'm gonna show you
how to drive it.
Where're we going, brother?
Shut the fucking camera off, Milo!
Don't fucking tell me
what to do, tell us where we're going!
Could you slow down
just a little bit, please?
Can we go back, because
I left all of my shit in my car...
because I didn't know
you were gonna fucking kidnap us?
Hey, yo, what's up, man?
How you doing?
Hermes wants to
wash that jail off him and shit...
'cause he's not feeling too good.
You guys are making
a film about him?
- Who?
- Your brother.
- What'd you call him?
- Aw, fuck. My bad.
I called him Hermes, man.
He got that name
'cause he's always wearing...
that fancy scarf of his and shit.
Crazy-ass white boy, man.
He keeps a stash of them
in my closet.
No, I'm not making a movie
about my brother.
This camera is just a bad habit.
Tell me about it. We are creatures
of habit, aren't we?
Hello there.
They call me Black Aries.
Hi. I'm Bella.
Do you mind
if I, uh, take a walk?
Oh, go and do your thing.
- Thank you.
- Where you going?
I just need to cool off a little.
You mind if I ask you
how you know my brother?
Aw, shit. I know your brother
from back in the day.
We used to do graffiti together.
You can still see
big-ass giant signs...
Hermes and Black Aries pieces
everywhere, man.
It was a beautiful thing. Lovely.
You mind if I ask
how you got injured?
Yeah, sure, man.
I was a contractor in Afghanistan.
After being a soldier
in the First Gulf War,
I realized I'd make
a lot more money
working for them damn devils
in the State Department
as a mercenary,
you know what I mean?
I was in Helmand Province.
You know, that's
the real rowdy side and shit.
I was over there doing this thing...
what they call "Crop Substitution".
Man, I'm telling you,
just out of nowhere... boom!
Drug lords just hit us real hard,
or some kind of fucking lords, man.
They definitely
were running the place.
You must have been
in a lot of pain.
But they got some real good
painkillers down there.
Real good.
We ready?
Yeah,
we're just waiting on Leo.
Shocking.
- Need some help?
- Oh, man, please.
Thank you so much.
I've been meaning to get this place
asphalted and shit, you know.
It's going to happen one day.
Thank you so much.
- You're good?
- Oh, yeah. I'm good.
Thank you, Bella.
What's up?
Milo...
- Yes?
- What are we doing?
We're... waiting on my brother.
I told you.
You know what?
Put the camera down.
I wanna talk to you.
- Put it down!
- It's down. It's down. It's down.
Your brother has some
serious fucking problems, Milo.
I know. That's why we're here.
Yeah, I get that.
I get that...
but I really thought I was gonna
fucking die in the car back there.
Jesus Christ!
I mean, you didn't tell me
that he was like, like...
Like the very same people
we're trying to help with our movie?
Oh, please, Milo.
I know you're smart enough to know
that there's a difference
between trying to expose
a systemic problem that affects
hundreds of thousands of people
and risking our lives
for one lone maniac.
That makes sense,
coming from someone
who doesn't speak to her own parents
for political reasons.
Look, baby, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, okay?
Look, my brother's just part
of the package for a few more hours.
Please, just bear with me.
- Fine.
- Please?
Fine.
Where is he?
Leo, let's move it, man! Come on!
I'm gonna wait in the car.
Come on, man.
I gotta get my ass to rehab.
Let's go!
Aries!
- Whee!
- Oh, come on, man...
Keep looking out, man.
I'm gonna hit the Hollywood sign.
Ooh, you better do that shit, man.
Like old times, man.
Put me up, too.
Don't forget the Black Aries, baby.
Hey, each day's
better than the next.
It's gonna get better, man.
Or worse. La-la!
You drive.
I don't have a license or insurance.
Ha!
Ma'am...
Come on, Milo.
You wanted to go so badly.
Andale! Andale!
Which ones?
I don't care what shoes you wear.
Okay, how do I...
how do I get to the rehab?
Come on, which ones you like?
Are we going the right way?
Is this the way to the rehab?
I don't know.
I have to ask my lawyer.
What?
Well, where's that?
It's on the way.
It's only going to take a second.
Come on, you're like a sister to me.
Which ones do you like better?
I'm not your sister.
If I had to choose,
I'd pick the shoes.
The boots are fucking hideous.
Are you crazy?
These are endangered stingray.
You asked for my opinion.
I'm telling you.
They may even be extinct
after this pair was made.
- Oh, fantastic.
- Look at the eye.
- The eye is watching you.
- That's not the eye.
That's their fake eye
for predators.
Sorry.
What were you doing up
in The City of Brotherly Love, Milo?
Prepping a documentary
on the American prison system.
Something you're going
to get to know real well
if we don't get you
to rehab in time.
So, put the camera on me.
I'll tell you how I got busted.
Oh, pray tell.
You know that park
that we just passed?
That park right the fuck there.
The one we just passed?
Yeah, yeah.
I fell asleep underneath
a picnic table there...
Shit, I can't reach the...
...and I was awakened to laughter
by a gaggle of giggling girls.
The next thing I know,
they invite me to a pajama party.
How old are these girls?
They were, you know?
- I go to their house...
- Where?
That one right there.
I put on my pajamas.
And it's on the second story.
I'm trying to get used
to my new wheels here.
Ten o'clock, two o'clock, Bella.
It's like a gun... just aim and shoot.
I can handle it fine.
We're getting our swivel on,
and suddenly,
the chick's boyfriend comes home
and, um, he's not happy.
I'm jumping out the fucking window,
I blaze off in the Impala.
I'm going a buck-twenty
down Burbank.
I hit Chandler, Colfax.
The cops are on my ass.
So I ditch the car.
I'm running down Topanga
in my fucking pajamas.
And I, uh...
Where do I go after that?
Slam! I fall over a wall
that's connected to an alleyway.
10 seconds later I had one
of those Nazis boots on my head.
And the rest is,
as they say, a mystery.
Wow, but we picked you up,
like, 30 miles away from here
all the way
in a place called Calabasas.
I don't... well.
Maybe it wasn't here.
I don't know.
L.A. looks all the same to me.
No shit.
- This is for you, Bella.
- What the fuck is that?
You look like you need a friend.
Bill, Bella.
Bella, Bill.
Vivian!
- Hey.
- Hi.
That's my brother, Milo.
- How are you?
- Hello.
He's making a movie,
and he wants you to star in it.
I'm sure he does.
Harry is waiting on you,
and, boy, he is not happy.
Where have you been?
You know, the usual.
Swimming in the Los Angeles sticks.
Has he been treating you well?
No, but what else is new, right?
You just give me the order,
and... I'll make him dead.
- Really?
- Forget about it!
What do you want?
- Let's talk later.
- All right.
You smell nice.
Thank you, Leo.
Hey, I got you a little gift.
What did you get me?
From my travels.
It's a...
I found it in Nigeria.
- And it will bring you luck.
- Thank you.
Africa ain't just a country
that gave us Bob Marley.
All right. Follow me.
You don't get it?
It's funny!
Vivian, Vivian, mi amor.
Vivian.
Give me a twirl, Vivian.
Just one.
Come on.
All right.
Have a seat.
Harry's gonna be with you
in a minute.
You're gonna want to put that away.
Milo, she's not fucking around.
Put that away.
Five minutes, in and out.
Wait a minute, get a shot of the bear.
Quick!
Where's Bella?
She's waiting in the car.
- What?
- She's waiting in the car.
Harry...
Hello, Leo.
Oh, thank you.
You have my file?
Got your file right here, Leo.
That camera's not on, is it?
- No, no.
- Milo...
- How is your day?
- Excellent, Leo.
- So, Leo.
- Yes.
I gotta ask you something, okay?
Shoot.
Who the fuck
do you think you are?
What do you mean?
Well, you know, you're fucking me
like a Thai hooker on payday, right?
- Are you serious?
- Yeah, a little bit.
Well, you know,
do you think that that judge
agreed to send you to rehab
because he thinks
you can get rehabilitated?
Are you asking me?
Yeah.
No.
"No"?
How about "fuck no"?
: How about he agreed
to send you to rehab because of me?
Because of Larry K. Rothstein!
Because he knows me!
And with that hanging on the line
and with me making it
abundantly clear to you
that my reputation
hangs in the balance,
you, in your infinite fucking wisdom,
disappear for three fucking days!
Then I find out that you
get arrested in Calabasas?!
So, you tell me,
you shit for fucking brains,
don't you think
that I got better things to do
than work for you,
you stupid fucking junkie cunt?!
Harry, Harry.
Milo, can you go
into the lobby with that?
Yes.
Now?
I get a little
worked up sometimes
because I really believe in my work.
I know.
Now, I want you to be...
clear...
absolutely clear
that you're there by 8:00 pm.
And do not forget
the 5,000 in cash,
or they will not even admit you.
Got it, H.R.
Will do.
Thank you.
All right.
Get out of here.
Scared the shit out of my brother
is what you did.
But he's all right.
Leo, where the fuck
are you gonna get $5,000 in cash?
I got it covered.
Just head down to Mulholland.
You guys want a tan?
What?
What are you doing?
It's gonna get way darker,
and no skin cancer.
It's fucking cool as fuck!
That shit's
gonna make you orange.
Wait, is this Mulholland up here?
No, keep going straight.
We're gonna hit it.
Do I look orange?
No, I look tan.
Listen, it contains
a gentle tanning agent
that blends
with your natural skin tone
so your color change is subtle.
See? Subtle, not chalky.
Well, why do you want to be tan?
- He wants to be black.
- I am black!
I'm supposed
to be in Hawaii right now,
so... uh, I got to look the part
for the homies in rehab.
Wait, you know
the people in rehab?
Yes. It's always the same people
at these places.
Actually, it's where
we first tried heroin.
She's a little friendly.
- Hello!
- Leo!
Hey! It's so nice to see you.
Maybe I'll come up and... hi!
What're you doing with the camera?
Are you making a movie?
Oh, I love cameras!
Get in here!
Hi. I have the most beautiful,
bitchin' house.
People just really love my house.
After all, I'm the bad girl.
- Oh, okay. Sorry.
- Sure, no problem.
You, um, are extremely gorgeous.
- Would you like some carrot juice?
- Yes!
Carrot juice is good.
Why don't you go get some, sweetie?
- God, you smell so yum.
- Really?
Bella, why don't you come in here
and help me with the carrots?
- Okay.
- Here you go.
Thanks.
Here comes director Daphne.
Come on, don't tickle me.
I'm trying to, like, film here.
Oh, wow. Too bad we can't hear
what they're saying, huh?
So, what's going on with you, bud?
I'm going to rehab.
Don't laugh at me.
I'm serious.
Really?
Yeah. Really.
Well, then, why don't we go
have one last going-away party?
Cut!
- I told you guys not to worry.
- Yes! Thank you, Daphne!
- 5,000 dollars.
- Bella.
- What?
- The check's made out to you.
Let me see.
- It's made out to you.
- What?
Why the fuck
does it have my name on it?
Well, actually, it's
from Daphne's husband, Ernie.
Daphne doesn't have
a checking account,
or at least,
that's what she told me.
Ernie's a producer
and an arms dealer on the side. Shh!
Daphne let me borrow his car,
and he's pissed.
So he knows my last name,
thusly, Milo's.
- And so on and so on and so forth.
- Can you please stop, really?
La, la, la, la, la.
You got your check?
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Leo, be careful with that.
Nice girl.
She's a breeder.
What's wrong, man?
Nothing. It's just, like,
nothing has changed.
Nothing.
It's like you expect me to be your...
...your nurse, your caretaker,
your banker,
whatever else the fuck
I can come up with.
Milo, don't.
I'm not always going to be there
to bail you out, you know?
- Yeah, you will.
- No, I won't.
It's like you have no idea
how your choices affect people.
Me or Mom... or Bella now.
Can you stop? Please?
Oh...
What? Is this annoying?
Stop!
Stop. Put it away, please.
It's not a toy.
Please? Come on.
- Now you know what's it's like.
- Fuck you, man!
No, no, no, no...
Means "Go fuck yourself' in English!
We good?
No.
What do you mean, "no"?
Maybe you should call Ernie.
The thing is useless.
I felt like such
a fucking idiot in there.
Hey, have you ever thought
about just fucking giving up
and just doing your time?
Kill myself before I go back to jail.
I almost got stomped to death
for speaking with a fellow black man.
The white dudes
didn't realize I was Italian.
- Where am I going?
- Head up to King's Road.
It's in Hollywood.
Now we stick to burglary?
Max!
Open up!
Open up, bitch!
Leo?
It's open.
I was still sleeping,
you fucking cunt.
How's it going, Max?
It's... What the fuck is this?
Hello.
Max is going to save a brother
from incarceration, aren't you, Max?
MAX: What?
Search that shelf, Troy...
- What, did I wake you?
- Yeah, you woke me.
Well, wakey, wakey,
eggs and bakey.
Max. Bella. Milo.
- Hi.
Sit down.
It's okay. Sit. It's okay.
We're friends-ish.
Aren't you going to introduce us
to your friend?
MAX: That's Troy.
Troy, this is Leo, Stephanie.
Bella.
Got a light?
No, there's...
So, uh...
My brother says
you're gonna help him.
With what?
Help you with what?
What the fuck do you got...?
What do you want from me, man?
You know what I want, Max.
Oh, come on, man.
You know... you hear,
it's not about the fucking $3,000
that I "apparently" owe you?
$3,000?!
- For what?!
- MAX: Aw, Jesus.
It was a fucking drunken night
of backgammon, okay?
I was pissed off
my fucking tits and...
It was stupid, okay?
I'm... I don't own him $3,000.
What are you doing, man?
Come on.
Giving you an opportunity, Max.
I don't have
a fucking housecleaner.
One more round,
11 points, double or nothing.
You win, we're even,
I win, six grand...
five for rehab,
and one for my brother and his wife.
I'm not his wife.
Just his partner.
Most people think
it's a game of luck.
Actually, it's largely
a matter of nerve.
Where's your nerve, Max?
MAX: Leo, Leo, Leo.
Just listen to me, man.
Leo, just listen to me,
okay, buddy?
We're not playing
backgammon, okay?
I've got no fucking money.
I've got zero money.
There's nothing, okay?
Leo, are you listening to me?
I mean, I haven't had
a fucking audition in, like, a year.
Ask Troy... I haven't had a fucking
phone call in a month from my agent.
He's probably fucking dead.
You're a fucking actor, Max?
Fuck you.
What, you want to see
my fucking show reel? I'll put it on.
No, no, it's okay, Max.
I don't want to see
your show reel.
MAX: Listen, listen.
I've got a solution here, okay?
I'm gonna get you guys
an espresso,
and we will calm down
and fucking talk this out.
Do you want
an espresso, Stephanie?
- Steph...?
- Bella. Yes. Please.
MAX: All you guys
are fucking... just relax.
An espresso machine?
MAX:
No, just an espresso.
This is a graduation present
from my mother,
and I'm not gonna give you...
this is my baby, okay?
Looks like your baby
is taking a trip, Max.
MAX:
Give me the cup.
Leo! Leo, Leo!
MAX:
Leo! For fuck's sake, man!
You fucking cunt!
I'm a cunt
with a new cappuccino machine!
MAX: It's an espresso machine,
you fucking moron!
What the fuck are we doing?
This is insane!
I don't know about you, guys,
but I'm collecting on a debt.
That baby's worth at least $1,000.
You stole it, Leo!
We're accomplices!
This is fucking bullshit!
I know.
Did you see the look on his face?
You're fucking heartless!
It was the only thing he had
in his entire apartment.
It was a present from his mum!
Oh, my God!
Look, why don't we just find
somebody to buy this car legally?
That would make
a lot more sense, I think,
than fucking stealing
espresso machines.
- That might be tough.
- What do you mean?
I mean, uh, it's complicated.
Let me guess.
The car's not really ours.
It belongs to someone
who doesn't exactly exist.
- What?!
- What do you mean?
Well,
what're we gonna do?
We're gonna sell the car.
I got a place.
I got to drive it in.
They know me.
- Oh, okay.
- I got to drive it in. Yeah.
Hey, what's this shit?
That's my brother.
Don't worry about it.
What's it for?
He's, he's like Mr. Arty.
It's his personal diary.
No one sees it.
How you doing?
Plus, I got a little surprise.
Careful.
- Bella, I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Mikey? Will you grab the cups
and the thing?
It's the cardboard thing, to the left.
There's cups and saucers.
Yeah, that's it.
Wait till you taste this shit.
What's, uh...?
What's going on in there?
Uh...
I think they're selling my stolen car.
Milo? Can you turn
the camera off?
Will you please turn it off?
Turn it off, please, please.
What's up?
What's your name?
It's all right if I film?
- Yeah, don't trip. It's cool.
- You sure?
Since you're Hermes' brother
and all, it's cool.
Cool with you
and your heina over here.
Fools around here call me Diego.
- How do you know my brother?
- Hermes?
Everybody know Hermes.
So, you guys jack cars, too,
and shit?
You know, like some
Bonnie-and-Clyde-type shit?
No, no, no, no.
That's, that's...
...Herme... I mean, Leo...
Hermes' car.
Yeah, yeah. Whatever.
You wanna hear some crazy shit
about your brother?
Yeah, for sure.
Check this out. Like 10 days ago, right,
he bring me a 2004 Maybach.
Cherry.
He was up in the hills
with some producer's wife,
or some shit, you know,
doing his thing, his Hermes thing.
So, he's about to jet,
and he sees the keys,
space, missed opportunity, right?
I'm telling you,
this motherfucker's a beast.
So, he snatches up the car.
Now, this is a 350,000 dollar car
we're talking about here,
and he's high as a kite.
I mean, loaded.
Balls of steel, man.
So, you guys are here
to double your money, too, and shit?
Double what money?
Hey, check this out, dawg.
Be careful
with that footage there,
'cause ain't nobody got me
or my operation on tape.
You know, it's gonna be worth
a million bucks someday.
- All right.
- Hey, D, Bella.
From the homeland.
Wow. Thank you.
Be careful. It's hot.
What the...?
- It's your new machine.
- Decaf?
You found the way to my heart.
Vince... Vince and I
talked it all out.
Let me just grab something
from the car real quick.
What is that?
Hey! $3,500 in cash,
plus this beautiful car.
Better than the Impala.
I don't know.
I think I like the Impala better.
Are you crazy?
This is a classic waiting to happen.
Get in.
- All our shit's in the Impala.
- It's in the trunk. Get in.
- Feel that?
- It's ugly.
It's like you're
on your favorite sofa, you know?
You're gonna fall asleep in seconds.
You'll enjoy it.
Milo! Stop filming me,
and get in the fucking car.
Hey, Hermes!
I think we're even, bro!
You think you've
got up on me, D, don't you?
See you next week!
Just a minor malfunction.
She hums like a kitten.
Get in, Milo.
I think Bella's got to drive, though.
- Why's that?
- Isn't this her car?
Borrow?
You didn't borrow shit, Leo!
You stole Daphne's husband's car
and took it to a chop shop!
It's not a chop shop.
It's a parts place.
Who do you work for?
The FBl? The CIA? The IRS?
How do you expect
to stay out of prison...
- The AARP?
- stealing Israeli arms-dealer's cars...
and selling them
at fucking chop shops?!
What did you do with the money
from the Maybach?
I spent it.
I can't believe you only got
3,500 dollars and this car for my Impala,
which you said
was worth 20,000 dollars.
You're not gonna get
Blue Book prices at a parts place.
And this is a beautiful car, Bella.
La-la-la.
Leo, where we going
to get the rest of the money?
First, let me pay my debt to Bella.
I owe her, uh, $800?
Hold on.
20, 40, 60, 80...
That's 100
for my debt to Bella.
Just stop.
Just keep your money.
Consider it my donation
to the Keep Leo Out of Prison Fund.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
We'll probably waste
the next couple hours...
trying to make
that 800 dollars back.
You married a saint.
We're not married.
I keep telling you that.
Whatever you guys are,
she's a saint.
- Are you guys hungry?
- No.
Yes! I'm starving. That's what
you can do, you can buy me lunch.
This place has the best
octopus dumplings on Earth.
Better than in China. I swear.
We're in a Vietnamese restaurant.
It's both. It's a hybrid.
Could you bring us
some Arctic Circle clams...
with sesame chili oil,
crispy, deep-fried
pork intestines,
deep-fried duck tongue
with spicy salt,
half a dozen
hundred-year-old eggs,
pan-fried sea cucumber
with supreme gravy,
one order of chicken feet...
I always like to do like...
experiments.
Su Gong and Hot Pot
with rice noodles.
You guys want anything?
Leo, we don't have time...
Hold that thought.
I got to hit the head.
- Leo, we don't have time.
- Bella, I gotta run.
Can I just get
some noodles or something?
Oh, I think we're good.
Thanks.
I can't believe
he ordered all this food.
Do you think he's okay?
He's been in there awhile,
like, 20 minutes.
As soon as he gets back,
we're gonna drop him off,
we're gonna go to the airport,
we're gonna fly to San Francisco,
and we'll be there in time
to do our interviews this afternoon.
I cancelled the interviews.
You did what?
Hours ago.
Why would you do that?
Because we were never
gonna make it.
And I should have known that
this morning at 5:00 am...
when I agreed to do this.
And you should have known it...
because you know
what your brother's like.
You knew we were never
gonna make this happen.
gonna be able to come down here,
swoop him into rehab,
and drive back up there in time.
This is our mission now, okay?
We're gonna...
Leo, what is your plan?
What do you wanna do?
Milo, come on.
You've been pretty chill all day.
Why the sudden bout of anxiety?
Bella, you have to try
the hundred-year-old egg.
Yeah. It's fermented in straw
and horse urine for, like, 6 months.
It is wonderfully,
wonderfully perverse.
A little too perverse for me.
No, thanks.
Come on.
Live a little. Bella?
- It smells like ass!
- I dare you, Bella.
Bella, what are you doing?
You're vegan!
She's living life.
I can't believe you're eating that!
Oh, my God.
It's good, right?
Not as bad as you would think.
A world without hundred-year-old
eggs is not worth living in.
That, and truffles found by dogs
and imported from Italy.
- I think pigs find truffles.
- The best are found by dogs.
I want to try something else.
All right.
How about the chicken feet?
If I could, I'd weigh 600 pounds.
I used to weigh 220,
until I started using again.
- What?
- Yeah.
You?
I don't believe it.
I lost 60 pounds in 3 months.
What's your secret?
I could put you on the diet,
but I don't think you'd be happy.
Not likely.
Yeah, you don't want
the diet that he's on.
- Pay the check.
- What?
Meet me around back.
I may have solved
our money problems.
What the fuck?!
I knew there was something
up with this place.
That's disgusting!
- Our worries are over.
- You stole a dog now?!
I bought him, 100%%% legal.
Rescued him from an uncertain fate
as a Lo Mein side dish.
- You did what?!
- It's just 500. Relax.
Taco's a champion English Bulldog.
He was trained in Germany.
He's a police dog.
We'll get 2,000 for him, easy.
Watch.
Taco! Platz!
Platz!
Taco, platz!
No, he doesn't feel like platzing.
Okay, come on, Taco!
- Inside! Inside! Come on, Taco!
- Here we go!
- Inside!
Come on.
I can't believe
you bought a fucking dog!
- I think he's cute.
- Oh, my God!
He just slobbered
all over my camera!
Oh, no!
Oh, fuck!
He sneezed!
Bella, take a left.
- What time is it?
- It's, like, 12 something.
- Perfect.
- What do you mean "perfect"?
Just take a right right here, Bella.
- What's going on?!
- These are my boys!
Jesus Christ!
One of them will buy the dog for sure.
Just pull into the gas station.
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck?!
What's up, brother?!
You guys, pull in over there!
Qu hubo? Qu pasa, loco?
- Nada, homes!
- What's up?
What's up with the camera, man?
New reality TV show?
Don't mind him.
I have this dog.
His name is Ducati.
He's born in Italy like me,
trained in Germany.
He's like a 6,000 dollar
police dog.
- Police dog?!
- Yeah. You better watch out!
Listen, I'm in a little bit
of a situation.
So, I'm willing
to let him go for, like, 2.
200?
- 2 stack.
- Damn!
I'll give you two bills
right now, ese. Sold.
Can't do it, big homie.
Hey, where's Dizzy at?
Dizzy? He's over there.
- Hold Taco a sec.
- Taco?!
Ducati!
His nickname's Taco.
- Just watch him, all right?
- You're trippin' and lit.
Who's that crazy guy?
Does he really think someone's going
to wanna buy a dog for 2,000 dollars?
This poor dog's
gonna die of heat exhaustion.
Can you
give me the money, man?
We're not gonna have anything left
at the rate you're spending it.
What? You don't trust me?
It's not that.
It's just that we both saw you give
that guy Dizzy money.
I owed him.
It's just 20, relax!
And then you went
into the bathroom and... and...
To shit!
You don't know what it's like
trying to come off drugs.
- I had the runs, you know? Damn.
- Oh.
- You're such a pushover.
- Who, me?
Yeah.
"Oh... oh, okay".
Take a left right up here.
What about Bill?
Does he still live in Venice?
- You read my mind.
- Who's Bill?
Does he want to buy a dog?
Bill is a very rich,
very eccentric family friend.
Leo, are you going to ask him?
No, you ask him.
I'm not going to ask him.
All right.
Where the fuck is he?
Oh, there you are, Bill.
Oh, hey, Milo.
How are you?
- Hope you don't mind the camera.
- BILL: No, I'm used to it.
I wouldn't know you without it.
So, um, what are you working on?
I'm working on kind of these
ol' mini-handcuffs here,
and I was wondering
if I could make
some thumb-cuff
kind of jewelry, you know?
Just not sure how to...
you know, you can't really put them
like that 'cause you can't do stuff.
I know you
haven't seen much of Leo lately,
but he has developed
a bit of a drug problem.
Well, you know,
life's been a little easier for you
and a little harder on Leo.
I feel an affinity with Leo,
and I also understand, you know,
what it is to deal with a,
with a drug problem.
I've got a lot of friends
that just ain't here anymore.
A little miscalculation here,
a little error there.
It's not like doing some big,
noble deed to help someone,
but you know that if you don't,
then, you know, he could be dead.
Leo got himself
into a little trouble,
so we've come to ask you
for a little loan.
Sure, no problem. 5, 10 dollars?
What can I do?
We gotta get him into rehab,
and we need $2,500.
Well, fuck him!
Hey, Carmen!
Just tie him up.
Baby, come here!
Oh!
Oh, my God!
Oh, Frederico
said you got arrested.
That it was serious.
Serious is what's going
to happen to Frederico
if he keeps telling people
my business.
Leo!
I'm not other people.
When did you get out?
I escaped.
Don't tell anyone.
Oh...
This is my brother, Milo.
Camera crew following you.
Hi!
Hi, hi! I'm Milo.
- This is his wife, Bella.
- Hi. Partner, actually.
Hi. Carmen.
Partner, actually.
Come in.
God, these paintings are amazing!
Thanks.
You did all these?
Wow!
I'm about to have
my first one-woman show.
Oh, that's so cool!
So, Brad's not going to be home
for a couple of hours,
so make yourselves at home.
- So, who's Brad?
- Brad's her boyfriend.
I've never met him...
...and I'm not jealous.
I've been trying to get her to run
away with me to Inner Mongolia.
I'd wear, like,
a black suit with red trim.
She'd wear a red veil.
There'd be little ponies everywhere.
I'm totally "twitter-pated,"
can't you tell?
"Twitter-pated," huh?
Ain't you ever seen Bambi?
Bye.
Hello?
Yes, this is she.
Can you hear me?
Yeah, I don't...
Hold on one second, please.
Hi. Yeah, hold on...
What's up, guys?
Milo, how about
a little bit of privacy?
- Sorry, sorry!
- Jesus.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
There you are!
Leo, get dressed! We gotta go!
- Let's go! Come on.
- Oh, okay.
Well, Carmen,
it was so nice to meet you.
Thank you for everything.
Listen, Leo told me about the little
money problem you guys are having.
- Yeah...
- I think I can help.
Really?
I need a shave.
We're not gonna smoke it.
We sell it.
We break it up into four quarters
and sell it
for about twelve-fifty a pop.
Yeah, that adds us to 5,000
and turns us
into total drug traffickers.
It sounds worse than it is, but it's
how I paid my way through art school.
- Really?
- It's only pot.
It's practically legal
in California, anyway.
Wait. Let's just figure out
if this is our only option.
No, it's not legal.
It's not legal.
I mean, even if
we had a doctor's note,
it wouldn't cover us for transporting
a pound of marijuana.
This is insane.
We do a drug deal,
get me into rehab,
and then the student
becomes a teacher.
Listen, I have
this lawyer friend up north
who got this guy off
for having 150 plants,
and, to top it off, at the end, the
government gave him his plants back.
- Can I have his number?
- It's a she.
See, men get into trouble,
women get them out.
- Sound a little familiar?
- Can I have her number?
- I think I might need a new lawyer.
- Listen, you guys, we can do this.
It's only a phone call away.
I even know people
who want to buy it.
Let's just focus on selling Taco.
This is becoming...
No! No one's gonna want
to buy that stupid dog, Leo, Jesus!
It's not a stupid dog.
If I had feelings, I'd be hurt.
You guys, look. Listen.
I'll carry the stuff in my purse.
If we get busted,
I'll take the responsibility.
You guys just play dumb.
- Are you sure?
- Mm-hmm.
Whatever.
You know what I think?
All right. I'll call him
and see what he says.
Are you seriously okay with this?
Milo, I mean, we do our best,
and we hope for the best.
If we get busted,
we're completely fucked.
Milo! I can't believe
you're saying this now!
At this point today,
we have driven a stolen car,
sold the stolen car,
sold the stolen espresso machine,
and let a convicted felon
buy and use drugs.
Either we commit a crime,
or we watch Leo go to prison.
He's busy now.
He'll call us back in an hour
with the spot to meet him.
All right.
- We're gonna get you into rehab!
- Let's go swimming.
Swimming actually
sounds like a good idea.
Bella, what has gotten into you?
That's why we came down here, right?
To go swimming?
I don't even recognize you
right now.
Milo, come on!
There's nothing more we can do
about our shoot today, okay?
It's fucked.
And at this point, we just have
to wait for Carmen's friend to call,
and it's hot and I have not showered,
and I'm exhausted,
and, yeah, swimming actually
sounds like a good idea.
Leo?
- What?
- Let me ask you something.
Do you feel at all guilty
for getting us into this mess?
Let me ask you something.
When are you gonna stop
living your life
like one giant fucking
documentary, huh?
- Come on, answer me!
- Answer you?
You're looking through a lens.
For fuck's sake,
who am I talking to? You?
You're talking to all of us.
You're talking to her, to her.
You're talking to the camera.
You're talking to me.
Come on! For the record.
Speak!
I appreciate
you guys came down here.
Fuck!
I do, but I didn't make you.
Excuse me?
I didn't make you guys
come down here.
- I gotta hear this.
- It was your choice.
Face it... the only reason why
you came down here in the first place
is you don't want to feel guilty
about not helping out your brother,
plus the fact...
That's the most warped
reason I've ever heard.
you still feel bad
about the time you sent me to jail.
That's really
why you're here, isn't it?
No.
All right, that's the biggest
fucking piece of horse shit...
I've ever heard.
I care, he cares, we're here.
Goddammit, you are
the most ungrateful person
I've ever met in my entire life.
I can't believe you.
- Ungrateful?
- Yeah! Ungrateful!
He doesn't really care.
What the fuck
are you talking about?!
How can he not care?!
Listen, he'll call my girlfriend
and say, "I'm worried
my little brother's dead,"
and she'll say, "Come over
for dinner. Talk to him".
And he'll say, "Ah, that's okay,
I'll call in a couple weeks".
- I'm out of town!
- A couple of weeks!
- You're always out of town, man!
What does he mean,
"sent me to jail"?
- I didn't send him to jail.
- The worst idea ever.
- Next time... I'll kill you.
- What?
I got arrested at this motel,
and cops said,
"You live over on Laurel Canyon?
Your brother sent us
three days ago".
It was your friend who called
saying, "Your brother's gonna die.
He's been doing speedballs
for 10 days, and he's gonna die,
and if you want to live with yourself,
and you know you could have
done something to stop it,
that's up to you".
And what happens
when I get stabbed in jail...
because you called
the fucking cops?
Does he cop up to that?
To that phone call he made saying,
"Your brother's gonna die
if you don't call the police"?
Why didn't he call, then?
He said, "I'm not his brother.
You are".
Wow, so, riddle me this, Sherlock...
What happens
when I find a dirty needle in jail...
and get some kinda weird disease?
People don't shoot up
in jail, do they?
What?
People shoot up in jail?
Yeah. The whole dorm.
We all share one needle.
I didn't know that.
What you don't know
could fill up the Staples Center.
- This it?
- This is it.
- Come on, Taco.
- This is one of his new spots.
What is this?
It's his not-so-legal operation.
He used to have one
in Diamond Bar,
but there was just way
too much heat on the operation.
Cops?
Feds.
Do you think he'd
let me come in there and film?
Um, I doubt it, but I'll ask.
She's so cool.
She's nice, huh?
What the hell
does she see in you?
I don't know.
That's a good question.
- He said yes.
- He did?
Yeah. I can't believe your luck.
- Carmen, my sweet!
- Ivan.
This the man
with movie camera, obviously.
I used to go to film school
in Ukraine.
Lots of fun those days.
Frederico probably told you
about Leo's
little scrape with the law.
- Yeah...
- So his lawyer...
Rothstein.
I hooked him up with that guy.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
He got him into rehab.
Problem is, we're a little light
in the admission-fee area.
- How light?
- 25 hundred.
So, you see...
We were hoping
you would break us off...
2,500 in Pretty Pussy product,
so we can go door-to-door.
Just to raise the funds for Leo.
You want me to front you
2,500 of Pretty Pussy.
No. Not front.
We want the wholesale rate.
- Like what you sell it to Petco for!
- What do you guys make here?
Cat toys.
For cats.
Toys that cats like.
Take.
- That's a big business, huh?
- Big business, cat toys. Take.
I would never ask,
but you know how I feel about Leo.
Give tour.
So...
What happens in here?
We grow.
We clip.
And here, they finished.
Do you like to smoke it?
What do you think?
You like green.
You match.
It is the color of money.
Got it!
Holy shit!
Oh, my God!
There's this
design studio downtown,
full of ex-gang members,
graffiti artists, editors.
Great friends of mine.
They'll want some.
All right. Let's go.
- What did you say?
- Who feels like smoking a fatty?
I do!
Aren't we risking enough,
like, carrying it?
Do we have to actually
smoke it in the car?
It's bad enough
that we're holding all this.
Come on, Milo.
Such a naysayer.
Look at this.
It's so cool.
"I believe today
is gonna be a wonderful day.
Each day better than the next.
I am always in the right place
at the right time".
Can't argue with that.
"My mind has unlimited potential".
Very true.
He's down the hall.
Thanks.
Sandy, come read
the affirmations with me!
- Hermes?
- Oh, my...
What the fuck are you
doing here? How are you?
- I heard you were upstate.
- I heard you were dead, man.
- Who told you that?
- Jessica.
She wants me dead.
It looks good.
I mean, what's
with the paparazzi and shit?
Oh, it's just my brother.
He's got issues. Don't worry.
How are you?
It's like his own personal diary.
- Don't worry.
- All right.
No one will see it.
I am very impressed.
Very cool.
Yeah.
I'm a computer designer now.
Well, I'm trying
to get into rehab myself...
Well, this ain't it.
This isn't rehab. You're lost.
And, and, um...
I'm selling some weed
to raise funds to get into rehab.
So you want some?
No, man.
I don't do drugs anymore.
I'm three months, five days,
and two hours sober.
- No one's going to see this!
- You know what? I'll sponsor you.
Okay, you could sponsor me.
Fuck the weed.
Just come check out this dog.
He's a police dog.
His name is Cereberus.
You're gonna love him.
Come on!
Did you not read
the "no soliciting" sign at the door?
Are you gonna report me now?
When was
the last time I saw you?
- Was it at The Coach and Hound?
- Horses! Horses!
Milo.
No dice. Let's go.
Y grapes, tambin.
- Y watermelon!
- Y watermelon, sanda!
I knew that, I think.
- "Watermeloney".
- Gracias.
Muchas gracias!
Qu calor! A ver...
Qu caliente!
No. How do you say "heat"
in Spanish?
How did it go in there?
You didn't sell any?!
No!
Dealing's a tough gig, man.
I'm not made for this shit.
Copping's a tough gig, lady.
- Nobody wants to buy weed.
- They want the harder shit.
Right, Leo?
Hey, is this the, uh...?
Is this the South Central Farm?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, what's left of it.
I read about this.
: That's it now?
Do you know the story?
Some developer
bought the land 15 years ago,
then the city took it
under eminent domain...
to build a garbage-incinerator site.
The community protested...
and then built the largest
urban farm in the United States.
Then the developer sued the city
to get his land back, won,
and then refused to sell it
back to the community...
even though they raised
16 million dollars to get it back.
People are so deceptive and greedy.
The only thing you can do
is get as intoxicated as possible...
until it's all just fucking over.
That's such bullshit!
You can actually
do something about it!
Like what?
Make movies?
For example, yes.
- Can we drive around, and shoot this?
- No. We're in a hurry.
Look at that.
They're pulling out the last tree.
People go to the movies
to be entertained, that's it.
Nobody wants to be whipped.
People were protesting that farm
for months.
The bitch didn't eat
for, like, 28 days.
Please don't call her a bitch.
Did that make a difference?
Should have killed the developer.
Violence just begets violence.
It'll just perpetuate the cycle
of oppression and inequality.
- What does that get you?
- Yeah, that's one to grow on.
What?
So, Leo, you're saying...
he should have
been motivated by fear?
Fear may be
the one thing stronger than greed.
- Are you all right, Leo?
- Yeah, I'm just cold.
You're cold?
You're all sweaty.
- It's freezing.
- It's as hot as balls in here.
- Yeah.
- I'm melting.
Just hold on a little longer.
They got good meds in rehab.
You'll do all right.
I'm serious.
You're serious.
My life's like that accident.
You're just slowing down to look.
- Where are we?
- Jordan Downs.
- You think I can film here?
- Yeah, they'd love it.
- What's Jordan Downs?
- The projects.
- This is Milo, the cameraman.
- Fuck you!
This is Bella.
I can give you
a better name than that.
MAN 2: What's up, baby?
Where the fuck you been, man?
Leo, what you doing, baby?
Chill out, brother!
You know
I like to come and hang out,
but I do have a problem.
You know, you bring problems.
We'll fuck you up right here.
You know
I wouldn't bullshit you, right?
Barbeque!
Oh, you guys hungry?
Yeah, I'm starving.
The one
with the snake-looking ass.
Desert-horse-looking ass.
This is the don around here.
You see me, man?
This the don.
These my, these my goons
right here, man, making this money.
You see us, man?
Why don't you tell the world
about Jordan Downs Projects?
Fuck them if they don't love us.
- What's it like here?
- Like hell.
It's like hell.
It's crazy.
So much shit can happen.
You could get shoot right now, man.
Big homies and shit
just chillin' , you know,
living the good life
out here, though.
Getting money and shit.
That's all we tryin' to do.
- You feel me?
- Why's it like hell?
Man, this shit crazy.
Police can come snatch you up.
Police don't let a nigga live out here.
- We ain't got no freedom.
- None of that and shit, man.
What do the police
most bother you guys about?
Shit. Gang injunction.
- Everything.
- What's that?
Shit, you can't be
around three people.
They can come get us right now
if they wanted to.
- For nothing.
- For what?
- For being like this.
- For being too deep.
Plus, I got purple on.
- What's the purple signify?
- Grape...
Red and blue make purple.
You didn't know that?
Want two crayons to see?
We definitely gonna sell
this motherfucking weed,
you know what I'm saying?
I got you. I got some
little hungry cats over there.
They probably suck that right up.
- You guys play for money?
- Yeah, we shoot for money.
Can you get arrested for gambling?
They can take your money
out your pocket
and the dice and all that.
We live
for this shit right here, though.
Living the ghetto life.
Twelve-fifty for a motherfucking
quarter pound, man.
That's all we going for, man.
Whatever.
You want four?
Man, call your bosses, man.
We don't want to be getting
into this bullshit, man.
25, big homey.
We got 23.
Why you trying to haggle me for this?
- Do you know where this is from?
- Pull that shit out, man.
Let them see that, man.
That's real shit.
Did you smell it?
If you guys want
to do some stuff, man...
She'll come back for the two.
Two gonna be right now, man.
We got three,
fucking three, man, last week.
She ain't take it, daddy.
No luck, huh?
No.
This is it for me.
You worried
about him going to prison?
Me too.
I can't believe he never told me
he had a brother.
So, how come
you guys aren't... together?
You know what it's like.
To love an addict?
Yeah, to love an addict.
- You want the real shit, right?
- Follow me.
Where's Bella?
- She's in the fucking...
- She's where?
She's with Carmen.
She'll be fine.
Leo, we got, like,
an hour left.
You wanna make
a documentary, right?
Not right now.
Follow me.
Leo...
Time's running out, man.
What are we doing here?
I don't wanna make...
I can't film in here.
Come on in.
These are my friends.
Come on in!
- I can't talk to these people.
- Just talk to them.
You Hermes' brother?
Yeah.
You mind if I film you?
Yeah. You want me to look
in the camera, or what?
You know, your brother's,
like, an angel.
Takes care of, like,
nine people down here.
Keeps, like, a constant supply
of clean needles.
People use
dirty needles otherwise?
We use whatever
we can get, you know?
The government
don't give us clean needles.
They want us dead.
Your brother...
about two weeks ago, he, uh...
helped a sister buy a house.
- What do you mean?
- Yeah.
Yeah, he, uh...
See, her baby's daddy O.D.'d, right,
and left her...
homeless, and she had, like,
all this debt,
and he shows up
one day with, like...
like, fuck, 20 G's, man, boom!
- Just gave it to her.
- The Maybach...
- Hmm?
- Nothing.
Doesn't that just allow people
to keep living like this...
instead of getting sober
and cleaning up their lives?
- I mean...
- What?
You rather...
they get AIDS?
Bring it home
to their family and their kids?
- No.
- You sure you're his brother, man?
That didn't come out right. I mean...
You'd be surprised how far
a little love and just care goes.
People need that.
Come on in.
- Oh, shit!
- It's okay. You can film this.
This is like your office, huh?
What're you doing
with the water?
I'm... uh,
getting ready to cook.
I've never seen this
in real life before.
That is so nasty, dude.
It's not what it looks like
in the movies at all.
You always see a bunch of guys
getting all euphoric after they fix.
Bunch of dramatic movie bullshit.
- What does it feel like?
- Used to feel fucking amazing.
Imagine...
floating on...
a billion tiny satin pillows.
And then imagine,
when you weren't that high,
what used to just feel normal...
now feels...
lower than you've ever felt before.
It used to give me this... uh,
sense of meaning and oneness...
about everything,
but...
now I just fix not to get sick.
I don't even get high anymore.
A little high.
Whoa, are you shooting your foot?
Dude, it's all infected.
What're you doing?
Well, I can't watch.
It makes me nauseous.
That's right.
You get nauseous
when you see a papercut.
Come on, man. Let's go.
We'll figure something out.
We'll get you to rehab.
You don't have to do this.
Dude, we still got,
like, an hour and a half.
We're gonna figure something out.
We always do.
I can just take one more big shot
and go to sleep for good.
No, don't be ridiculous.
Yeah, and then, uh...
it'll all be over,
and you'll go back to your life.
Oh, no.
Don't say that, man.
Please.
Come on. Let's go.
There you guys are!
Where the fuck have you been?
Get in the car.
I have an idea.
Where we going?
Come on.
Carmen left with Brad,
but I got the weed,
and we have a plan.
What is this place?
Where'd you hear about this?
My new friends in Watts
told me about this guy.
This guy will buy...
anything for anything.
It's a last-ditch effort.
We gotta get rid of this weed.
We gotta see if it's gonna work.
Just follow my lead, okay?
- Carmen gave you the weed?
- I have an idea. What?
- Yeah, it's in the car.
Do you see a door-bell?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm coming.
I got my gloves on...
Hi! Mr... uh, Shasta?
Yeah, that's right.
Well, what you be doing here?
What y'all be filming?
- We are, um...
- You got a license for that shit?
Yeah, absolutely.
Actually... um, we're here...
Disturbing me on my day of rest.
I'm so sorry. We're here...
a friend of yours recommended you...
because we're actually
from a new cable reality show,
and we are doing a segment
on high-rollin' strollers.
Kind of a "Cribs"- type show.
Ziggy sent you?
It's not Ziggy. It's a friend of yours
actually down in Watts.
Oh, yeah, that's right. Watts.
That's the real shit. That's
the down low, man. That's the real...
We can maybe come in
and talk some business propositions?
Yeah that's right.
Watch the feet. Watch the feet.
Watch the feet. And then,
watch the... bam!... right in the face.
- Mr. Shasta?
- Yo.
I just wanna check out your facilities
and see if they qualify.
Oh, yeah, I'm so sorry.
My hospitality was all down.
I was meditating.
I was thinking about Buddha, ganja.
I was thinking about Yoda.
Welcome to the Shasta domain.
That's right. Shasta domain's
always ready for a fight.
Ready for somebody
to come in here and fight it.
Bam!... right in the face.
You found the number-one
rolling crib in the house, man.
This shit is rolling, rolling.
I got my fine piano here.
I got real magical fingers.
You can't hear right now...
Mr. Shasta, we don't actually
have that much time.
We just need to make sure
you're a high roller.
I am a high roller!
I roll like I'm tall.
And I got TVs.
I can watch
The Brady Bunch, Jetsons,
I can watch all five
big screens at once.
I got to take this.
You know,
I be getting calls all the time.
Oh. Yeah, please,
take your time.
- Yo, who this?
- Oh, my God!
No, I had to erase it
because people be calling.
Ich hab" nicht gesagt, Mami,
ich brauch" dein...
Look, Mom, I'll call you later.
I got people from the television here.
It's really important.
Ja, ich ruf' dich an spter.
All right. All right, girl.
Peace.
But, as you can see,
we are in the front room here.
This is where magic be happening...
over here, over here.
It be happening all around.
And we are stars.
Everybody's a star.
Come here.
Check it out, Cameraman.
This right here...
that look beautiful, don't it?
That is the eye.
Now, that's made from the skins
of an endangered species of stingray.
Actually, that's the fake eye
to mislead the predator.
You calling my cover "fake", man?
I paid, like, beaucoup for that, man.
That's the real deal, right there.
- That's the real deal.
- The eye is fake.
Don't be coming into my house
and telling me my shit is fake.
I let everybody in here, and now
you be saying my shit is fake?
No, Mr. Shasta,
I think he's just admiring that.
The eye is fake
to mislead the predator.
Okay, I hear
what you're saying, man.
I was just playin'.
Fantastic.
It's... yeah.
It's, it's, it's... I love it.
This my baby.
Shasta, is there any way we could
sit down and have a little chat?
Because we have, I think, an offer
that you might be interested in.
Oh, yeah, man.
We could be sitting, like...
you know, let me slip into something
a little more comfortable,
and then, uh, you know,
we could, uh,
we could talk about shit.
Please have a seat.
Please, Producer, have a seat.
Cameraman, come on over.
Don't be shy.
So tell me... what do you do?
Well, I'm an artist.
I mean, Shasta's an artist
and producer,
a rapper, a hip-hopper,
I'm a fighter.
I know heads in, like,
N.Y.C., L.A., Denver...
So, how do you make your...?
I have been blessed,
I've mean,
bless-ed, blesses, blessings...
Trust fund?
That's right.
I'm a "Trust-afari". Shast-i.
So, we may have
some party favors...
to offer you for your next soiree.
Right, right.
Like firecrackers, like...
My producer here has some tree
that you might be interested in.
I got... you want to trapeze?
I got trees outside
that can swing into the pool.
- We did that at one party.
- Some marijuana.
Oh, yeah, right!
I was just playin'.
Yeah, that's right! Marijuana!
Shit! Of course!
I mean, you can't have no party
without no trees!
All right. My partner and I
happened to come across...
- a pound of medical-grade chronic.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God... bless Allah.
Be praised, Rastafari!
Thank you very much!
This ain't legal, is it?
Man, we can't be like...
Oh, yeah.
We're talking medical grade.
Oh, the legal illegal!
The new medical grade!
The new... that shit,
they chemically enhance it.
- That's really strong.
- Oh, it's strong.
And I think we can give him a deal,
because, you know?
All right, we're willing to let it go for
156 dollars and 25 cents an ounce.
- 32 ounces in a pound.
- That's right.
- 156 times 32 equals 5 G's.
- Right.
I feel like I'm being...
BOTH:
Robbed.
Excuse me one second...
- Are you sure you want...?
- Talk amongst yourselves.
That's a pretty amazing deal.
- He seems cool.
- We can get way more.
He's got a very nice house,
and we are in a situation.
5 G's, one pound...
Let me see... one, five...
It's gonna be... carry the...
Um...
Can you tell me
the numbers again?
Obviously, we need cash.
- There it is.
- Oh, my God!
- There you go.
- Oh, my God! That...
Oh, my God!
Oh...
Oh, man, that's the sticky-icky!
That's the Bin Laden armpit!
That's like cave hopping...
Plus this to seal the deal.
To match your bike.
Aw, you shouldn't have, man.
We gotta go.
You guys are, like,
my nice best friends.
Come here, you!
Come here!
Holy shit! Run!
Run before he changes his mind!
I think we're gonna be early, guys!
Like, 20 minutes early.
What you eating, Taco?
What you eating?
- Oh, shit.
- What?
He just ate the laxatives.
- What?!
- The Mexican laxatives.
Oh, my God!
He's gonna have an ass-plosion!
Poor Taco!
Oh, no, Taco!
- You better pull over.
- I can't.
I'm on the fucking freeway.
How am I going to pull over?
Yeah, that's gonna smell bad.
You're not going to like that at all.
- What the fuck?
- What? What is that?
- What?
- Is that a cop?
- Is that for me?
- Shit! Fuck!
Oh, my God,
we're so fucked!
Was I speeding?
- Bella, just switch with me.
- No!
- No, no, no. Be reasonable.
- What? No! Leo!
- Better me than you.
- No! Are you crazy?
I'm not switching with you!
You don't wanna fucking go
to prison for a stolen car, Bella!
- I'm not moving!
- You don't want a fucking record!
I'm a first-time offender.
I'll be fine! Leo!
Stop it! Are you fucking crazy?
Stop it!
- Leo!
- Are you crazy?!
We'll just explain to them
what happened... Leo!
- Just switch with me!
- No Leo! Stop it!
Get the fuck off of me!
What the fuck are you doing?
This is insane!
You're gonna go to fucking prison
after everything we've done today?
- Stop!
- Leo, Leo! I got an idea.
Just tell them you're me.
Tell them you're me!
I've done that. That's why
you don't have a driver's license.
- Stop.
- Just relax.
No!
- Do you know why I stopped you?
- No, Officer.
A couple of reasons...
your left taillight's out, and you
almost hit two cars back there.
- I'm sorry, I...
- You been drinking tonight?
No, it's our dog.
He's been jumping up and down.
Taco, platz!
Platz!
Your license and registration.
I don't have
a license and registration.
I'm gonna need you
to step out of the vehicle.
Okay.
Milo, turn it off.
All right? It's up to you,
but I have 10 minutes to get there.
We'll walk there.
My brother and his wife,
they have a dog...
Hey, shut that camera off now!
What's going on
with the police dog?
How did you come up
with a police dog?
We're trying to raise money
to get into rehab.
We're trying to sell him.
No one would buy him.
Actually, he's trained in Germany.
- Bye, Taco! Bye, Taco!
- Bye, Taco!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
We gotta hurry!
That was insane!
See?
It's dangerous living with an addict.
- Now you"re shooting.
- I'm just a casual user, see?
- I can stop whenever I want.
- Yeah, right.
Bella, we got 10 minutes.
Come on!
How far is it?
All right, let me get a shot
of the brothers' triumphant arrival.
Do you know
how annoying that is?
We made it!
Should we come in with you?
- I got it.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- You got the money?
See you in six months.
Each day better than the next, right?
Exactly. Every day gets worse,
like I always say.
Bye!
Hey, hey! What's the matter?
Handshake ain't good enough
for you?
Tell Carmen I love her.
Bye.
Thanks.
Now what we gonna do?
- We'll figure it out.
- We don't have a car.
- We'll make it back.
- Should we take a bus?
Do they have buses in L.A.?
Come on!
Let's see how he's adjusting.
It's been an hour.
We just dropped off my brother.
About an hour ago.
Leonardo Strombo.
Yeah, Leo!
I just wanna see
how he's doing.
What do you mean?
Okay.
Thank you.
What happened?
He left.