Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
MAN: We saw you fall.
CHILDREN: (SINGING)
Oh, come let us adore him
Christ, the Lord
Sing hallelujah
All ye choirs of angels
Sing all ye blissful ones
of heaven above
Glory to God
In the highest glory
Graeme!
BOY 1: Pathetic.
BOY 2: Scum !
MRS. OBREE: It's happened again.
MR. OBREE: Oh, I don't believe it,
not again. This has got to stop.
Get him downstairs now,
I want to talk to him.
I understand you were in a bit
of bother again today, young man.
You're still not prepared
to give me any names?
You're just gonna have to learn
to stand up to them.
This should keep you out of trouble.
This is your Christmas
from your Dad and me.
Maybe it'll make up for... You know.
Merry Christmas, son.
Graeme!
Now I'm going to get to you.
So, if you just take the lift
behind you up to the third floor...
Thank you.
How's that for service?
Six minutes from Dobbie's Loan.
Then it'll only be 12 minutes
before you're back with the right one.
Hi, there. How can I help you?
Hey!
Dispatch give you the wrong parcel?
Okay, so what you do is,
you wait for her to go off on her lunch,
then you nip back in,
get them to sign for it
before you hand it over,
then dispatch can sort out their own mess.
- I'm Malky McGovern.
- Graeme Obree.
Yeah, I know who you are.
I'm a big cycling fan.
Come on, Graeme!
Well done, Graeme!
Look, there's Daddy.
We just got here a minute ago.
I'll put the kettle on.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Don't let him rip you off.
Make it 300, you got a deal.
MAN: Look, son, you've gone bust.
Maker your mind up,
it's either 200 or nothing.
Okay, 200 it is.
I'm sorry,
you're better off going up the road.
Oh, not with this antique.
Aye, right. What can I do for you?
Well, I need a new...
An old crank.
I don't think so, but let's see.
Oh, aye. Once upon a time, eh?
I'm afraid I don't follow cycling.
I heard of him, though.
Boardman. He's good, isn't he?
Aye, well, he was always the man to beat.
And still is, the bugger.
Right.
These young boys, full of bright ideas,
but they cannae stand the pace.
You mind if I deliver that one myself?
Haven't got time, son.
I've got a buyer coming to the yard.
That's okay, be there before you.
Are you trying to be funny?
Tell you what, you get there before me
you can keep the 200,
I get there before you,
I get the other hundred I wanted.
This gentleman here can hold the cash.
If you've no objection.
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
He's done.
Maybe not.
The little...
Oh, come on.
- I'm fine.
- That was mad.
It's been said before.
Well, it's gonna cost 300 to repair the van.
- You could have killed him, man!
- It's all right.
I would have won anyway
if he hadn't have cheated.
You weren't perfect yourself, son.
Anyway, have to grab your chance.
And trust to the Lord.
When it comes to religion,
Karl Marx got it right.
I'll find a crank for you.
Drop by sometime next week.
We're in the flat above the shop.
- Mr...
- Baxter. Douglas Baxter.
All right, Chris?
So, what are you doing with this lot?
Putting food on the table
and paying the odd bill.
But you're famous.
You still hold the British one-hour record.
But I gotta make a living
like everybody else.
Have a sandwich.
Cheers.
But all the same.
Oh, Jesus, what have you got in this?
Is that marmalade?
Enough sugar to keep you going all day.
Aye, but it tastes horrible.
Couple of these for breakfast,
I'm up the road in no time.
That's 30 miles away.
Thirty-two and a half.
And if you're not gonna eat that,
I'll have it back.
What about Chris Boardman, then?
He's going for the world one-hour
later this year.
But then again, that record hasn't
stood for nine years for nothing, has it?
You've been head to head
a few times with Boardman, haven't you?
You think he can do it?
If anyone can do it, God can.
Right, time's up.
Fair enough.
What's the problem?
On you go, I'll catch you up.
Is something wrong?
I can fix it, I'm good at that stuff.
No, there's no problem. Just got an idea.
On you go!
You're wasting a good head start.
What the hell have you done?
Been out with Graeme, I see. He's inside.
Do you want fish and chips?
- And a pickle.
- This is Katie.
Hiya.
What do you think?
Yeah, definitely got something.
Look at him.
Is that her bike?
Oh, no, she just borrows it off her granny
at the weekends.
Where are we off to now?
- GRAEME: You got that tube?
- Yeah, yeah, got it.
See, I told you it would be okay.
So, Katie's a biker, eh?
I suppose she's got tattoos
and all that stuff?
Bikers are into that kind of thing,
aren't they?
Then again, I suppose she's got
a Hells Angel for a boyfriend.
Who's is it?
(BANGING ON DOOR)
I just dropped by and I was wondering
if you'd found that new crank for me?
One second.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
And you dropped a few bits and pieces
when you took off like that.
- It's for a new bike I'm building.
- They were throwing that out anyway.
- It's really not stealing...
- That'll have been in the dump...
...just bits and pieces...
...in a few days and
- we're in a hurry because Graeme's...
...and rubbish
- that they couldn't sell.
...got a new idea.
- Who's this?
- It's Malky.
Malky McGovern.
What new bike?
Why do skiers crouch like this?
Better aerodynamics.
Exactly. So why not for cycling, too?
I tried reversing the handlebars
but after about 20 miles or so
I realized it's not enough.
Gotta go the whole way, build a new bike.
Forget all the rules, start from scratch.
But to what end?
Break the world one-hour record.
Which stands at?
Fifty-one and a bit kilometers.
It's thirty-two miles, more or less.
Well, nobody can accuse you
of thinking small.
But hold it, hold it,
before we all get carried away here.
Even if you could do it,
this kind of thing takes lots of money.
First, there's the money to build the bike.
Then you need to find
a world-standard velodrome
which we don't have around here
and pay for that.
Including all the time keepers
and all that...
Okay, you got the job.
What job?
Well, Anne used to be my manager before,
but she's got enough on her plate as it is.
You can take over.
Where do you plan to build this bike?
Well, I hadn't got that far yet but...
I do have a tendency to hoard.
So, anything you can use, go ahead.
This is fantastic.
BAXTER: A toast...
To a new world record.
Eight weeks from now.
Oh, wait a minute.
What do you mean eight weeks from now?
Your man Boardman's
going for it in nine weeks.
Well, then, let's do it in eight.
- Morning.
- How are you doing?
You tell me.
Aye, that's what I'm after.
I'll leave it in the shed for you.
I didn't know you were into hi-tech.
Make do and mend.
That's the Obree approach.
It must be a killer.
Going at that rate for an hour.
Killer's not the word for it.
Francesco Moser set the record,
it stood for nine years.
Eddy Merckx held it before Moser,
said it burned three years off his life.
Merckx swore he'd never go through
that kind of torture again.
And he was the greatest cyclist ever.
He won the Tour de France five times.
Before him there was Archambaud,
Baldini and Coppi and Anquetil.
MAN:... falling behind at seven hours,
29 and a half minutes from the start...
Baldini.
Okay, fine.
The PR Manager's running a bit late,
his secretary says,
so if you could just wait a few minutes.
No problem.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
- No, I don't think so.
- Yeah, I'm sure I've seen you.
- Thanks.
- Usual routine, darling.
- Okay.
- Cheers.
- Malky, my man. You here for a job?
- No.
Oh, I remember now.
You were in here last week.
You're not running
a personal management company,
you're just a delivery boy.
No...
We'll just leave it.
Is it about Malky taking over?
No, I'm delighted about Malky taking over.
I know we need the money.
I know I've got to keep on at the hospital.
Are you sure this is the right thing to do?
Going for the record?
Sure, why not?
'Cause in spite of all the hassles,
things have been quite good recently.
I don't want them spoiled.
It won't spoil anything.
I can handle it, I promise.
How did you catch the cycling bug?
Oh, same as any other wee boy.
I got a bike for Christmas one year.
There must be more to it than that.
Did you go cycling with your pals?
Better get on.
- Hiya.
- Katie.
- Cappuccino.
- Thank you.
- Tea. Thank you.
So what are you dressed up like that for?
Just walking the streets.
You raising sponsorship for Graeme?
How's it going?
Well, how much have you got so far?
To be honest,
wouldn't pay for these coffees.
Go and see this guy.
- Tell him that Katie sent you.
- Who is he?
A serial parking offender
who has seen the light.
You meet all sorts in my job.
It might appeal to him.
Can't hurt to try.
That's great.
Thanks.
Listen, I was thinking maybe we could
go out and get a drink sometime.
A drink?
Did you think I'd show you my tattoos
if you bought me a drink?
How can I go out with a man
who shaves his legs more than I do?
(GRAEME PANTING)
No, Graeme,
your bum does not look big in those.
Well, that was a sexist remark.
What are you gonna do about it?
Lie down here on your back
and close your eyes.
How could I resist?
Now raise your legs.
Right. And pedal.
This better lead to something memorable.
Now, you see how close
they are together...
No, no, bring them back. There you go.
Keep going, yeah.
Now, check that.
The natural, comfortable way
is one banana wide.
So why are pedals
made two bananas apart?
That's why you got me
down here on the floor?
To give me a lecture
about pedals and bananas?
Why, what else could we do down here?
Graeme?
Are you all right?
Yep.
Just got a design problem.
Just trying to figure it out.
Oh, aye.
Seems like Dark Night of the Soul to me.
Everyone gets a bit down sometimes.
Oh, aye, sure.
Listen...
I've got some work next week
and I need a cog-and-wheels type.
Fancy giving me a hand next Saturday?
Aye.
Good.
So you see, Mr. Armstrong,
cycling is universally popular.
Well, not so much in the UK, of course.
Why would you want to sponsor Graeme?
Well, because he's pretty special, really.
I mean, for a Scotsman, that is.
And, cycling could be
a lot more popular if he wins...
That's about it, really.
Francesco Moser, eh?
What a man.
What a cyclist.
I mean, that one-hour record...
Pure brilliance.
You've gotta take your hat off to him.
But to think of that record
being held by a Scotsman.
Eh? By God, what a thrill that would be!
I'd offer you a drink, but...
I must get off.
Club outing tonight.
I'm going out to the Trossachs and back.
That sweet highland air.
Rapid Employment will be proud
to assist such a splendid initiative.
How much have you raised already?
It's going a bit slower than I'd hoped.
Nothing, then.
- Yeah.
- Excellent.
Rapid Employment will get
all the publicity.
- Great.
- Come by tomorrow, same time.
We'll talk figures.
Great.
Thanks.
Yes!
Oh, you beauty.
(CLATTERING)
Graeme.
What is it exactly you're doing?
How does a washing machine spin
at 1200 revolutions a minute?
Bearings.
Beautiful bearings, in their own casing.
What does your wife say?
- She was all right about it.
- Well, you're a lucky man.
- You were never married?
- Aye, she died.
- I'm sorry.
- A long time ago.
So, this sponsorship deal
that Malky's landed, it is enough?
Just. It'll get us to Norway
well before Chris makes his attempt
on the record at Bordeaux.
And we've got the stadium
and the timekeepers for 24 hours.
And now we've got the machine.
Okay...
Let's hear it for...
Now, most of the tubing
is actually from the BMX bikes.
And these rear ends
are part of an old padlock.
And my washing machine.
Well, the bearings are in here.
But this bit's
part of the washing machine frame.
Gives it extra strength.
So, you gonna get on it?
And off we go.
So what do you think?
Well, you're right.
Nobody's ever seen
anything like that before.
(CARS HONKING)
Not bad for a first day.
Okay, could have been better,
but I'm beginning
to get the feel of the bike and...
That is the last place
we should have been testing a bike.
That was stupid.
It was the only bloody place.
Okay, if there was even
a bog-standard track
within 50 miles of here, fine.
Will you just get off my case
and do your job?
For God's sake, Graeme.
The bike that Boardman's going on
cost half a million to develop
and it was designed by a computer.
So how the hell is that thing
that's made out of scrap
and washing machine parts
going to break a record
that's stood since...
Well, since before they were born?
BOY: What's that for, big man? The circus?
Aye. Aye, that's right, son.
You get one thing straight, Malky.
I know what I'm doing here.
Maybe it doesn't look like it,
but this bike's been built
according to the laws of physics.
There's a scientific reason
for every single bit of design.
And that's how I'm gonna break the record
with or without you.
Graeme, he's trying to help you, that's all.
Well, I don't need his help.
I can do this on my own.
DOUGLAS: Lord, Savior, Holy Spirit.
Upon us, and upon this world.
We ask you to bless Jonathan
and to keep him within your sight,
as he grows into manhood.
And though we cannot ask you
to keep him from all harm in this world,
still we hope,
that you will stay by his side
in difficult times.
And give him the strength
to rise from despair
and self-doubt.
Jonathan, I baptize thee
in the name of the Father and of the Son
and of the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
You've done a good job, Malky.
Couldn't have done it
without phoning you twice a day.
And the tickets.
- This one's for me, I'm not coming.
- Yes you are.
Katie says you and Graeme are a team
and that's good enough for me.
There isn't enough money
for the three of us to go to Norway.
Yeah, well, I'm paying for myself.
Malky I really appreciate it,
but I've got no one to mind Ewan.
Katie's gonna take some time off.
She'll look after him. It's all sorted.
Are you still worried about the bike?
Yeah.
And that is why you have to be there.
You see, I've got a contingency plan
that Graeme doesn't know about.
I thought if you knew right away
you might think I was after your soul.
And aren't you?
Souls are God's business.
Mine is people.
So, how are you feeling?
Under control.
Well, the hour is almost at hand.
Bring it on.
I'm raring to go.
Good turnout.
It's not for me. They're getting ready
to announce the world championships.
Moser's over there.
Francesco Moser is over there.
GRAEME: He's on the WCF council now.
Who's that with him?
I don't know. Some suit.
Right, let's get Old Faithful put together,
give them all a heart attack.
Can I talk to you first?
What about?
Actually...
Can I show you something?
I got onto Mike Burrows,
told him what the situation was
and he said okay, he'd take a crack at it.
I didn't know
if it was gonna be ready in time,
that's why I haven't said anything till now.
I gave him all the specs.
It's exactly the same as Old Faithful.
All the ideas that you built into it,
but it's the work
of a world-class bike builder.
And I think you should...
You know...
What do you think?
Well, it's not exactly the same
as Old Faithful.
Burrows has used 32 mil not 16.
- So it's heavier.
- Right.
Hey, the wheels... Specialized made them.
And if you beat the record,
they'll sponsor you for a whole year.
Just give me a minute, will you?
Sure.
You knew about this?
You always said
Mike Burrows knows what he's doing.
Don't use it if you don't want to.
FRANCESCO: Graeme!
My friend!
Allow me to introduce Ernst Hagemann.
- It's nice to meet you.
- Hello.
You built this yourself?
No, it was Mike Burrows.
I did the design
and put together the original model.
What is wrong with the original?
It took a bit of a battering
in the road trial stage so...
Don't worry,
it conforms to every WCF regulation,
I made sure of that.
It doesn't worry me, Mr. Obree.
It would only matter if you were
to break Francesco's record.
Graeme, wait, please.
OFFICIAL: Okay, ladies and gentlemen,
clear the track please.
MALKY: Okay, 205 laps...
OFFICIAL: Graeme, this is it.
MALKY: That's what you've got to beat.
OFFICIAL: Set's ready.
OFFICIAL: Give me a nod and I'll give you...
MALKY: Fifty-one...
OFFICIAL:... a five second countdown.
MALKY:... point one five kilometers...
That's 31.7 miles.
Which is almost exactly the same
as the journey from Prestwick to Glasgow
but no hills.
No traffic, no roundabouts.
And when the gun goes off,
you've broken the world record.
OFFICIAL: In five, four,
three, two, one. Go!
Come on, Graeme! Come on!
Come on, Graeme!
Come on, Graeme, you can do it.
I know you can do it, come on!
MALKY: Go on!
ANNE: Come on, Graeme, come on!
MALKY: Go on, Graeme!
ANNE: Come on, Graeme!
Come on, keep going, come on.
(PANTING)
Go on, Graeme! Go on.
Go on, Graeme!
Come on, Graeme!
Well done, Graeme.
Well, he's missed it.
ANNE: Graeme!
Graeme, are you okay?
MALKY: That was a brilliant effort, Graeme.
Just two laps off, that's all!
You did bloody great.
It was the bike, it was that new bike.
It wasn't the bike, it was me.
Okay, get all these people out of here.
Just do it, Malky!
Look, just step back.
Give him some air. Come on!
Step back.
This is total fucking failure again.
Don't do that. Look at me.
Graeme, don't do that.
Don't do that, Graeme.
Okay. Okay.
REPORTER: Wait. No, he's going over here.
MAN: Get out of the way, you.
REPORTER: Wait, wait, wait.
Graeme, how are you feeling?
- FRANCESCO: Bravo, sandwich man!
- I'm going again.
Impossible, the WCF must have access.
Well, 24 hours, that was what my manager
agreed with the people here.
So, we've got the stadium
till 10:30 tomorrow morning.
- But Graeme...
- 9:00 tomorrow morning.
You English are mad!
You wanna know what mad is,
try calling me English again.
I'm a Bavarian,
I'm very proud to be called German.
But I know you Irish Scots
are always fighting
you can't help it, ja?
What are you doing?
GRAEME: Making sure I exercise
every couple of hours
to stop my legs seizing up.
No alarm clock like a full bladder.
We've slept in! We've slept in!
We've gotta be on the tracks
in 30 minutes.
Where in the bloody hell's Malky?
(BANGING ON DOOR)
GRAEME: Malky! Malky!
We're late.
MALKY: I've rebuilt Old Faithful for you.
She's ready if you're ready.
Malky, you wee beauty.
That clock should be set.
What's wrong with it?
- ANNE: I think he slept in as well.
- This is a shambles.
Excuse me! He's going for it now.
Excuse me! He's going for it now!
- MAN 1: Oh, please, after you.
- Thank you.
MAN 2: I haven't had breakfast.
This is insanity, Graeme.
You will cripple yourself,
maybe something even worse than that.
Right, you ready? Go!
ANNE: Come on, Graeme!
Come on, Graeme!
MALKY: Go on, Graeme! Go on.
ANNE: Keep going, Graeme!
Come, you're doing great. Go for it!
- Same as yesterday.
- He's a slow starter.
Come on, Graeme! Shift it!
Come on! Move it, Graeme!
Come on, Graeme! Come on, keep going!
- This is where it went wrong yesterday.
- That was yesterday.
ANNE: Come on, Graeme! Move it!
FRANCESCO: He cannot continue like this.
MALKY: Yeah, you're right.
ANNE: Come on, Graeme.
It's time he really started to pile on.
Come away, Graeme!
ANNE: Keep going, baby! Come on!
MALKY: Come on, Graeme!
ANNE: Come on! Move it, Graeme!
- Come on, Graeme!
- ANNE: Come on, keep going, Graeme!
You can do it, Graeme. Come on.
You're nearly there. Come on, Graeme!
Keep going, Graeme!
He's a whole lap up
on where you were at this point.
Come away, Graeme! On you come!
ANNE: Come on, Graeme! Keep going!
MALKY: Come on, Graeme! That's a good...
(GRAEME PANTING)
He's gonna do it. He's actually gonna do it.
- Come on, Graeme, you're gonna do it!
- MALKY: Come on!
You're gonna do it!
MALKY: Go, go! Faster!
Come on, Graeme!
(PEOPLE CLAPPING)
(CHEERING)
- You did it! You did it!
- Bravo!
Yes!
ANNE: You did it!
Congratulations, Graeme!
Absolutely amazing!
On behalf of Specialized,
I'm proud to give you this check,
and to announce a year's sponsorship.
Go on!
- Graeme.
- Malky...
- Just leave him.
- Why? He's missing the party.
(SOBBING)
Graeme, congratulations!
I see you made the front page.
Well, the local paper, anyway.
I just wanted to say thank you
for your help.
Oh, I didn't make much of a contribution.
Which would seem to be the way
in other cases, as well.
What do you mean?
Do you remember what Karl Marx said
about surplus value?
You're looking at it.
Apparently the powers that be
feel that this town is too small
for two congregations
so there's gonna be a merger.
One of the churches is gonna be sold off
to a property developer.
Agnes, go in. Be with you in a minute.
Now, Graeme, I've got work to do.
Will you excuse me?
One of my parishioners,
her husband has just passed away.
She's got a few problems coping.
Hi, sorry we're late.
Guess who kept going on
about keeping inside the speed limit?
What? Well, there's plenty of time.
It doesn't start for another half an hour.
- So, where's Graeme?
- Going for a run.
Said he'd better things to do
than watch a non-event.
MAN ON TV: The English rider,
Chris Boardman,
Great Britain's Olympic champion
is certain to break the one-hour record
so recently established by Graeme Obree.
Here he goes!
And how devastating this must be
to his arch-rival Obree.
But the world one-hour record holder
is now an Englishman.
Excuse me, excuse me. Sorry.
Sorry, thanks.
- Cheers.
- Cheers, thanks.
Is that not Obree?
Hello, yes, I'd like to make
a reverse-charge call, please.
All right, Graeme?
Yeah, it's 01632960433, that's Prestwick.
I knew it was you.
You're a world champion now,
some shite like that, eh?
- I'm just trying to make a call here.
- Oh, right, aye, aye.
So, what you doing back here then,
champ?
Just come back to show us, did you?
Fuck off.
Hi, Anne, it's me.
Aye, listen I've got a puncture,
could Malky come and pick me up?
Yeah.
Malky? Yeah, I'm back in the valley of
the damned at the pub in the main street.
Aye. Yeah.
Okay. Listen, what did Boardman do?
Seven hundred meters more?
That's more than the margin
I beat Moser's record by.
Right, I'll see you there. Okay, bye.
- What the fuck do you want?
- See, here he is.
Thinks he's the big man now, eh?
But I can remember
what we used to do to him.
Yeah, you made my life hell.
Are you proud of that?
Come on, Graeme, eh?
It's just a bit of fun, mate, that's all.
You wee shites! You dirty bastards!
- Steady!
- Fuck off! Fuck off!
- Go on, then!
- Fuck off!
Supposed to be world champion, man.
You know what?
You take a good fucking look at me.
'Cause this is the closest you'll ever get
to anything worthwhile.
Okay, it's a pain in the arse,
but this is what I was thinking.
We book Hamar again for, say,
the end of the year,
after the Specialized money's run out.
Then we announce
you're going for Boardman's record.
You'll get plenty of people
to sponsor you then.
- We'll get them to make bids.
- No.
They'll be lining up around the block.
The man from nowhere returns.
- The Flying Scotsman rides again.
- No, I'm gonna go for the worlds.
But you don't do that kind of racing.
Not the four-kilometer sprint.
You're a long-distance man.
Fifty-one kilometers or four,
it's still what I do.
Yeah, well...
Right enough, I suppose.
Twelve months to get ready for it.
- I'm going for it this year.
- What?
No, that's... That's totally impossible.
You've only got five weeks.
That's fine. Pressure works for me.
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
Chris Boardman.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
As you know,
the annual bring and buy sale
is gonna take place in four weeks' time.
ANNOUNCER: You have to be impressed
that novice Obree
has even made it into the semi-finals
of the World Championship.
But of course,
Boardman's the clear favorite
with his half-million pound,
computer-designed carbon-fiber superbike
that he rode to a gold medal
in the Olympics.
Two riders chase each other from
opposite sides of the track for 16 laps.
It's 4,000 meters of agony.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Five, four, three,
two, one, go!
The Christian band were really rocking
with the Lord...
ANNOUNCER: An astonishing time.
4.:22.668.
A new world record for Graeme Obree,
- who goes through into the final.
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Please forgive that short pause.
I get quite excited by the prospect
of the annual bring and buy sale.
ANNOUNCER: He's beaten
the other semi-finalist, Chris Boardman,
by 2.384 seconds.
You've broken the record.
It's a new world record!
GRAEME: World record? You're joking.
Oh, my legs.
Congratulations, Graeme. Awesome ride.
But you need a better helmet.
Here, use mine for the final.
And the best of luck.
Thanks.
ANNOUNCER: Another world record,
a new world champion.
He won!
Your dad's a world champion!
(COUGHING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Graeme?
Sorry, didn't mean to make you jump,
but the reception's...
And don't we look like a couple of swells.
Listen, Malky,
I know Anne's told you about me.
Good. We should get downstairs, eh?
I just get really down sometimes, and...
Then I tell myself, "Get a grip, man."
And I pull myself out of it.
I mean, there's nothing
really wrong with me, you know.
(WHOOPING)
- Love you.
- Hello.
Hello.
Hey, Anne.
Someone called Bourget's been on
the phone about exhibition rides in France.
Money up front,
accommodation for all of us,
that's what he said,
anything for the new champion
and we can go in our new car.
What's wrong with the one we got?
Have you actually looked at it?
This time we get something a bit better.
MALKY: Think we should turn left here.
KATIE: Malky, who's driving?
- Oh, aye.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my word.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
ANNE: My goodness, Graeme,
is this for real?
MALKY: Almost like there's some sort of...
I don't have a pen.
Hello.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
When you tried to beat the record
of the one hour
we all wanted you not to stop ever,
to continue for always.
And even if you had built eyes
for the bicycle,
oh, for sure, they would have been crying.
Yes.
Is it gonna be like this everywhere?
Why not? We deserve it.
You deserve it.
But how can manufacturers
persuade people to buy the right bikes,
when a washing machine on wheels
can break records?
Is he cheating? Drugs, perhaps?
No you can forget that. He takes nothing.
We even tested one of his sandwiches.
Just oranges and sugar.
You know, I loathe seeing him ride.
His position is so grotesque, so ugly.
- And unstable. He fell off last week.
- Oh, yeah?
He fell off?
We have come to the conclusion
that the riding technique ofHerr Obree
could cause him to hurt himself
especially if he were to fall
from his machine at high speed.
And not only that, such an accident could
cause serious injury to other cyclists.
It has therefore been agreed
that the riding position ofHerr Obree
will not be allowed under W...
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
Please, let me finish, under WCF rules.
Thank you very much.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
It's ridiculous to say it's unsafe,
I've only ever fallen once
and, you know,
it's no miracle machine, either.
- Otherwise I'd win every race.
- No way.
The bike meets all the WCF's regulations,
so now they're just making up new ones.
Okay, I'm going.
You know you don't need to work.
What am I supposed to do
when you're away on tour
with all your cycling groupies?
- I wish.
- Oh, do you now?
The way things are going,
I'll be spending a lot more time at home.
Hagemann and his pals
are really out to get me.
Well, you're a threat.
You got to the top the wrong way.
A few more like you and those people
won't be running things anymore.
- No more gravy train.
- Yeah, that's what makes me so angry.
Well,
that's healthier than being depressed.
You'll find ways to get one up on them.
GRAEME: Now, because of the WCF's
concerns about safety,
I've made a few modifications.
So, ladies and gentlemen I give you
the new, ultra-safe Obree bike.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Let's see the back.
He thinks he's so clever, this Mr. Obree.
Stand back, stand back.
We must not allow him
to make fools of us.
But every time we change the rules,
he changes his bike to comply.
Yeah, then you try again.
- That's as far back as it'll go.
- Oh, great.
Your bike contravenes the regulations.
Saddles must be five centimeters
behind the center of the bottom bracket.
Christ's sake,
you inspected the bike yesterday.
You okayed it.
Five centimeters.
All saddles must be complete and intact,
Mr. Obree.
If I use this. First thing I ever designed.
It must be possible to purchase all parts
in the commercial market.
That's just not true.
All the top cyclists have their bikes
personally made for them.
They would cost thousands
to buy in a shop.
Oh, yes.
But if you had thousands you could buy it.
That is the point.
The changes I had to make
to the handlebars
mean it's very difficult
for me to get into position
on a commercial saddle,
'cause they're so big.
There is no rule
about the design of a saddle.
Well, it...
It doesn't break the letter of the rules,
but it breaks the spirit of the rules.
- "The spirit of the rules"?
- Exactly, the spirit.
This is from a 12 year-old's mountain bike,
so we're not breaking any rules.
Sound.
- What's this?
- Bastards!
Hagemann just invented a new rule.
There has to be a gap
between the rider's chest and his hands.
A gap? How much?
He won't quantify it.
Is it strange that I'm the only one
who rides with his chest on his hands?
Yeah, exactly.
I'll tell you what the new rule is.
Nobody called Graeme Obree's allowed
to win the World Championships.
Here's what we're gonna do.
We'll replace it with the tri bars.
They can't object to that.
You can get down low enough on these
and you'll still win.
No.
I'm sticking with Old Faithful
the way she is.
You'll be out of the championship.
I won doing it my way,
I'll lose it doing it my way.
What's that supposed to mean?
That's a lot of bollocks, Graeme,
and you know it.
Look, I'm your manager, right?
It's my job to organize things so you win
and I'm asking you to use these bars
and just go out there
and give it the Obree magic.
Graeme, it's your only chance.
I'm doing it my way, Malky.
Win, lose or get disqualified.
To hell with you, then.
(CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER: So, a red flag will be raised
by an official if his chest touches his hands.
Three red flags and he's out.
- Come on, Graeme.
- Come on, lad.
I have to say that the whole thing
is utterly mystifying to me.
Only one more flag
and the world champion's championship
will be over.
Obree has fallen and it's a bad one.
They've broken him.
Graeme Obree is now
an ex-world champion.
Graeme?
Malky.
Here, you can take this stuff with you
next time you're down to see Anne.
Oh, take it yourself,
it's got nothing to do with me.
For God's sake, Katie,
it's got nothing to do with me either.
I'm not his manager anymore.
I'm shot of that pig-headed,
bloody-minded pain in the arse.
Which means,
I could not care less about any of this.
You still read it all, though, don't you?
And listen, if you think
that you can shout at me like that
then it's time you move back
to your own flat and sorted yourself out.
ANNOUNCER: Obree has fallen
and it's a bad one. They've broken him.
Only one more flag
and the world champion's championship
will be over.
Obree has fallen and it's a bad one.
They've broken him.
Graeme Obree is now a...
(BANGING ON DOOR)
MAN: Graeme!
Graeme, are you there?
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
I've come down all this way to see you.
You havenae been back for a bit,
Graeme, eh?
I seen you fall on the television, big man.
Did you know my old man got done again?
See...
It was your old boy that done it, Graeme.
Had to have him put away, eh?
Thing is, mate, old boy's not coming back.
'Cause he died inside.
He just couldn't take it.
You did make something of yourself,
Graeme, eh?
For a bit there, eh?
I can see you hiding there.
You're good at hiding and running away,
you silly wee shite.
Running away,
you still think you're too good for us.
That's all you ever do
on that bike of yours, eh?
Run away.
No wonder you're a champion.
See, all that stuff we done to you.
That was just 'cause of your dad,
you do know that, eh?
But you're not really a hero, are you,
Graeme?
You're still a wee shite.
You're a nothing, mate.
And you still think you're too good for us.
You're a nobody.
You're pathetic.
(SHOUTS )
MALKY: Graeme!
ANNE: Graeme!
MAN: I saw you fall.
Oh, my. Stay there.
(GRAEME GROANING)
Listen. Listen to me, I'm going for help.
All right, an ambulance, a doctor.
Do you understand me?
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Just lie there and take it easy, all right?
Wait here, I'll call an ambulance.
(GRAEME COUGHING)
Anne. Anne.
Graeme, this can't go on.
We have to do something.
It's all right, I'm okay.
No, you're not okay.
Hey, this is an ex-world champion
you're talking to.
- There's not many people can say that.
- Graeme, you need help.
I told you before,
I'll sort myself out in my own time.
Yeah, that'll make a great epitaph.
That's very good.
Hey, how you doing?
Hey? Hey?
You've been working hard. You should rest
when you come in, you know.
Especially since you're
paying the bills these days.
- Have you been a good boy?
- Yeah, we both have.
I phoned the courier people.
I'm starting Monday.
It's only a month's contract,
but at least it's something.
Back to square one, eh?
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
I'll get it.
"Dear Mr. Obree.
"The track at Hamar Stadium in Norway
is being resurfaced.
"In recognition of your historic
cycling achievements at the stadium
"breaking the one-hour record
and smashing the world record
"to become World Pursuit Champion,
"we hope you will accept
this piece of the old track
"as a souvenir of your wonderful triumph.
"It has been a pleasure
writing to you with this news
"and I wish you the very best
for your future.
"Yours sincerely, Irga Olsen."
Graeme, the boss wants to see you.
Something about a special delivery.
- Graeme, how are you?
- I'm all right.
- Got a delivery for you, needs a signature.
- I'll get my glasses. Come in.
Look I'm not stupid. What's this in aid of?
If I suggested we get together,
what would you have said?
What's going on?
I told you.
I'll be leaving at the end of the month.
Tea?
I'm going up north.
Some friends of mine from
the Merchant Navy have got me a job.
Teaching disturbed kids how to sail a boat.
Oh, is that what I am? A disturbed kid?
I was gonna tell you about her.
- GRAEME: Your wife?
- Aye.
- What happened to her?
- She drowned.
I was 39 when I met her.
I left the Merchant Navy and I was
studying for the ministry in Australia
and one summer's morning
down by Sydney Harbour
I saw this young woman
not much more than half my age and...
Oh, boy,
I felt as if I was struck by lightning.
All I knew was I wanted to
spend the rest of my life with her.
Amazingly, she felt the same way.
We only had three short years together,
that's all.
You said she drowned. Was it an accident?
Oh, no. She could swim like a fish.
WOMAN: Graeme.
She killed herself, Graeme.
She had the same illness as you.
She couldn't take it anymore.
She said it was like being in a swamp.
Alone in the darkness,
slowly being sucked down, inch by inch,
the life squeezed out of her
and knowing that nobody was ever
gonna come and save her
because nobody knew she was even there.
You see, there were things in her life,
in her childhood, she would just,
would not talk about.
I thought, maybe...
Maybe if we had a bit more time together,
I could have done something.
- We can talk about it.
- What's the point in talking about it?
Have you ever talked about it before?
So, why do you think there's no point?
They made me feel worthless. Like...
Like I was nothing.
Just something to be...
Used?
Who's "they," Graeme?
It's all right, you know, it's like...
It's like your first time on a bike.
Just keep going. You'll be fine.
- Are you gonna talk to him again?
- Probably.
Although he says
I should see a professional therapist.
What do you think?
Maybe you could fix me up
with someone at the hospital.
Yeah, I could.
- Malky called today.
- Yeah? What was he saying?
Just wanted a chat.
It's funny,
I was thinking I should give him a call.
Yeah?
See what he thinks about going in
for some wee events.
Nothing serious, just a toe in the water.
Bloody hell.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Superman,
Superman, Superman, Superman...
ANNOUNCER: The crowd is chanting,
"Superman, Superman"
and Obree's new position does indeed...
- Hiya.
- How are you doing?
All right.
Oh, aye, Sparkling Highland Water, please.
Okay, so what's the plan?
What do you think?
Forget Colinelli.
The only person you need to worry about
is that stubborn bugger Graeme Obree.
Come on, you beauty. Just one more time.
So, no signals till halfway.
MAN: On you go, boy!
(CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER: Obree is 0.7 seconds down
on his first lap.
He's not making it very easy
on himself or us.
Excuse me.
ANNOUNCER: This is a man
who's got something to prove.
Any chance of a lager there?
What a recovery! Two laps...
Go on, son!
Deficient air here 8,000 feet up
is incredibly thin.
Two laps left. I can hardly look.
They're absolutely neck and neck.
There's nothing in it.
Has Colinelli got anything left?
Has the Flying Scotsman?
Still level!
Come on, Graeme.
Come on, you can do it, baby.
(BELL RINGING)
You're level.
Come on.
One or two turns of the wheel
will be the difference
between these two great athletes.
The Flying Scotsman has won
the World Championship for the second...
This is surely his greatest achievement!
One of the most exciting races
I have ever seen.
Yes!
Yes, mate!
Obree is once again World Champion.
A remarkable man on a remarkable bike
that he reckons cost him no more than L50
against the opposition of the WCF.
What a ride. What a rider.
Astonishing ride by Graeme Obree
to take the World Championship.
You would have liked him.
Graeme Obree is surely Scotland's
small town hero.
Well done!
Well done.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org