Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
My Lord
How dare you...
can't you see I am busy?
The devine staff of legend...
It was seen in the Middle Kingdom...
Impossible.
The villagers are beginning to
whisper of prophecy...
Mortals are always whispering of prophecy.
It's their opium.
What other offending news
do you have for me?
That is all, My Lord.
Summon the Witch...
The one born of wolves.
Where were we?
He's not even Chinese.
We are all the same inside,
Aren't we Monk?
Heaven help us.
What, you find it a sin?
Yes, it is sinful not to share.
Cheers!
An old man and a boy,
They had tea here, Yes?
A Soldier Monk rides with them
Who else?
I do not know
who you speak of...
Men are such liars.
Sparrow...
...where do you nest?
It is them.
They're headed towards the desert.
They are between me and the River of Sand.
Isn't it just like King Monkey...
...summoning a boy to do a man's job?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org