Way to go, Rick!
Get in there!
Go with him! Go with him!
Yeah, nice! Way to hustle!
Good job. Good job.
Highland Rugby, One, Two
One, Two!
Beniamin, Adam,
off the field, now!
- Way to stick with it.
- How did you miss that?!
What are you guys doing?
Get it together!
Okay, Roundy.
Let's go! Let's go!
Hustle, hustle!
Get back in there.
Let's go!
A little rough on his kid, huh?
- What the heck was that, huh?
- Go!
That's rugby, man.
- What?
- You...
- Oh, no!
- He spit in his face.
Let's go!
Come on, guys, let's go!
- Oh, no way, man! Come on!
- You're out of the game.
Forget it!
Forget it, man!
Dude, it's not worth it!
Come on!
We'll have to take a blood sub.
I'm not sitting.
No. Sub him out.
Wait, wait, wait!
Way to go, Ricky.
That's your best hit of the day.
Let's go!
No blood. I'm ready.
We're good, yeah?
He stays?
- He's good.
- Okay. Let's go.
Come on! Come on!
Way to be Highland!
Hey, Coach?
Nice game.
Played a good game, guys.
And great kicks today.
They're idiots.
They won.
Great game.
Tough loss?
They didn't lose.
They rolled over and died.
They gave up,
like scared little girls.
- No offense, son.
- We tried.
What do you mean you tried?
You try, you sit.
This is about doing.
Coach!
Yeah.
Tried.
Your dad just wants you to win, hon.
He wants to win.
That has nothing to do with me.
Hey!
Hey, Rick!
Oh! Oh!
Oh, they are way too drunk
to be in the water.
Somebody get them some wings.
Okay. All right.
So anyway, it gets better,
because this coconut has just got
it hanging there on his face, right?
And this guy is huge, all right?
Like Yeti big. He's big.
So, he wipes it.
Wipes it off with his hand.
He wipes this loogie off
with his hand.
And licks it.
And I swear
it's thick enough to chew.
- Oh, Mark, that's disgusting!
- Sick. I'm gonna barf.
Yeah, well...
All right!
Listen up!
Hey! Listen to my mouth!
We present this oh-so-delectable
trophy to the guy
who's gonna take us back
to nationals next year, baby.
Yeah!
And, and!
Sh, sh, sh!
And a complete massacre
of Highland!
Rick, what are you doing?
Yeah! Whoo!
Come on, baby!
- I don't think I'm this drunk.
- Yes, you are!
Yeah-hoo!
Tami, you okay?
Tami?
Tami!
Natalie Penning, do you have
anything further to offer this court?
He's better than he seems
on paper, Your Honor.
I just hope you can see that.
Does the young man's father
have anything to add?
He was unable to attend.
Then, we'll proceed.
You may be seated.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Richard Seymour Penning, Jr.
He prefers Rick, Your Honor.
Counselor,
considering this young man's
drunk-driving career,
he is fresh out
of what he prefers.
Do we understand?
Yes, Your Honor.
Stand up.
Mr. Penning,
this is your second D.U.I.
You have now
compounded that travesty
by seriously injuring
a passenger.
Had this happened when you
were 18, you would be in prison.
So, effective immediately,
you are a ward of this Court.
I have therefore determined
that you will be transported
and placed in the Wasatch County
Juvenile Detention Center
in Salt Lake City, Utah.
Prior to your 18th birthday
there will be a review to determine
whether you will be placed
on probation
or transferred
to an adult correctional facility
until such time
as this Court deems you
no longer a danger
to yourself and society.
Nice to meet you, Rick.
I'm Marcus Tate,
Administrator here at Wasatch.
You can call me King Tate,
Sir Mark, Marcus,
whatever you like.
Where's my stuff, Marcus?
Why, I had the bellhop
take it to your suite.
Lmportant.
This is Bingham,
my right hand at Wasatch.
Hey, haole.
You'll be dealing mostly
with Bingham, myself,
a couple of interns --
anyone else? No. That's about it.
I'll show you the rooms.
Here you go.
No doors.
No secrets.
It's a part of "Listen Right".
Well, I'll let you get settled.
Dinner's in a half hour.
Oh! No spinning!
I said no spinning from the beginning.
...the front-running flyers
ripped the Sabres, 143.
...Dan Quinn scored three times,
helping the Penguins
throttle the Jets 8-3.
The Leafs throttled...
I just want to say hi.
And, uh...
I just wanted to see
how you're doing.
I'm sorry.
I miss you.
Bye.
I'm telling you, let's jack him.
Nah, he's too much
of a pretty boy for jacking.
A guy like you,
what would you say?
Oxy? Vics? Percs?
Or maybe he's just in here
for his own protection.
Hey, we all say
why we're in here, man.
Ernesto here,
stealing Girl Scout cookies.
Me, for beating up Ernesto.
You?
For being a pretty boy?
Hey, get off him, punk!
Come on!
Are you gonna yell at me or what?
Shh. Just listen.
Deep down.
Was it right?
What?
Hey, it wasn't me.
Those freaks started it.
You offended the home.
This is retarded.
You just offended the home again,
not to mention me.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Are you and the home happy now?
Almost.
About 10 minutes. Lights out.
Better hurry up.
You take forever.
Now, I want you guys to take notes.
I'm talking about something
really serious.
I need you guys to pay
attention, yeah? Okay?
You want me to say
I love it here.
Fine.
Great. I love it. It's...
I really don't even think
I want to leave.
I want you to be honest, Rick.
You want me to be honest?
I hate it.
Every day
for the last six months.
I deserve it.
I know that.
I didn't say that.
Is Dad there?
Hey.
He wants to talk to you.
I thought he'd be home by now.
Don't worry. I get it.
Merry Christmas, Mom.
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
Go, go, go, go!
Hey, Penning!
You too pretty to play?
Come on. We need you on "D".
We'll play touch if you want.
- He won't play.
- Come and play with us.
He's afraid of messing up
his pretty face.
I only play rugby.
All right. Listen up.
We usually play with 15 sides,
7 backs, 8 forwards.
But we're just gonna have to
make do with what we got here.
All right. All you guys
in blue shirts on my left.
All the guys in the gray shirts
on my right.
Line up about 2 feet apart.
You, back up about 5 yards.
You're gonna throw the ball in.
Now, if you get tackled
and you go down,
you must release the ball
back to one of your own guys.
Then he takes it and goes.
We don't stop. There's
no huddles, no time-outs.
So it's kind of like
football and soccer.
It's kind of like rugby.
You always have to pass the ball
sideways or back, like this.
- Nice catch.
- You just keep going
until you score, the ball
goes out, or someone dies.
Man, this is just
a bad rip-off of football.
Actually, Americans
ripped off rugby,
then they added
sissy pads and helmets.
Whatever.
You're going down either way.
Yeah. We'll see.
Throw it in
over your head like this.
Actually, you know what?
You should back up about 5 or 6 feet.
All right. You guys ready?
Down for the count, son!
He's down for the count!
107 days, Darren.
Oh, come on.
You can get through it, man.
Don't need to teach you
the same thing every day.
Sounds like
he's in a good mood.
Better!
Well, you better get back here
in time for nationals, buddy.
Man, my dad's
not gonna let me play.
Oh, come on. He wants to win.
He'll play you.
Hey, I'm sending
something your way
that I think
might cheer you up.
Hey, brah.
Marcus is waiting, yo.
I'm still on the phone.
Dude, they check my mail.
- I know that. I'm not an idiot.
- You're not?
Aloha 'Oe.
Marcus is waiting.
Hey, man, what's
so important that--?
Rick Penning,
this is Kurt, "Q" and Tumo.
I know you love rugby, and I know
you've heard of Highland.
They started their practices
a week ago,
- so I thought--
- Oh. You thought wrong.
- As usual.
- Yeah. Well, we win.
Yeah. We beat you.
You can come and find out how.
I already know how.
You cheat.
Man, you don't know anything.
Seriously.
Well, then, you can come find out
how we cheat.
- How about that?
- Not interested.
What's up, dude?
Back up, man!
We both know
that you've done all you can
to avoid learning anything
while you've been here.
The upside is we've got the cleanest
bathrooms that we've ever had.
All you've wanted to do
since being here
is go back to Arizona
the same kid.
So?
So if going home
is all you're about,
you ought to know that the judge
can reduce your time here
based on my evaluation.
Sometime check out
the back of your closet.
252.
I carved one of those a day
when I was 16.
I didn't always have my head
screwed on straight.
Rick, most of what we do here
I learned playing rugby
from Coach Gelwix.
I owe that man my life.
I wanted Kurt and the other players
to talk to you for a reason.
How much sooner?
I don't know.
Maybe before the end
of rugby season.
Belt up, brah.
I'm not your "bra",
so quit calling me that.
Okay, okay. No problem.
Belt up...
...sister.
Ain't hardly no worries. I get paid
by the hour, not the mile.
Holoholo!
Let's get them going!
Knees up! Pick it up!
Let's have a good practice!
Let's do it! Focus!
Up! Up! There you go!
Keep it going! Nice!
Rick Penning?
It's important for you
to know right up front,
if you spend a whole lot of time
in the gym, you work your hardest
with a complete commitment
to do your best,
you eat smart, get enough sleep,
and you work your tail off,
and someday...
someday you can
have a body like mine.
Glad you're here. It'd be great
to teach you how to play rugby.
I already know how to play rugby.
Oh, yeah? Okay. We'll see.
You're gonna be late.
Come on.
- Good job, Root!
- Come on!
- Get 'em up! Get 'em up!
- Keep 'em high! Keep 'em high!
Griggsie!
You're late!
Let's go, guys!
Let's see it higher, higher, higher!
There you go!
Addison, four corner!
Let's go!
All right, guys!
Hey, come on! Go!
There you go. Good.
Pop it! Come on, pop it!
Yeah, keep it going!
Five! Down for five! Let's go!
Good job, rookie!
Thataway!
Let's go! Come on!
Randy out, Penning in.
Make 'em work, guys!
Rugby passes!
Rugby passes! Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
- Oh!
- Down for five!
Take a left! Take a left!
Right, right, right!
Go left! Go left!
That's all right. But one day
you'll learn how to go left. Yeah?
There you go, Farley!
Hey, man, shouldn't he
be down here coaching?
He been doing the coaching, brah.
Go, go, go, go!
Hi, you've reached the Pennings.
We can't get to the phone --
One, two, one, two...
All right, guys.
Bring it in. Let's go!
Keep it going!
Bounce those feet off the turf
like it means something to you!
Knees up! Knees up!
Our season starts in three days
with New Haven.
We ready?
Yes, Coach!
Coach Gelwix asked me
to offer up a reminder.
Do we drink?
No, Coach!
Do we smoke or use drugs?
And with the girls, do you keep
yourselves clean and out of trouble?
Yes, Coach!
You got to give your word
to yourself
and to your brothers
on the team.
What are you laughing at?
Coach, how are you gonna know
if we drink or get with the honeys?
Because you'd tell
Coach Gelwix yourself.
Do we cheat? Do we lie?
No, Coach!
We got to have complete trust
in each other.
You lie, you burn the bridge.
Any player who lies or cheats
is gone for the season.
The only lies allowed
at Highland Rugby, gentlemen,
are by me about my rugby career.
Who are we?
Highland Rugby!
Till the death.
All right, guys, take a knee.
Randy.
Thanks, Coach.
- Phipp.
- Coach.
Opetich.
We're about winning gentlemen,
and not just in rugby.
And for that reason,
you will obtain a laserlike focus
on and off the field.
That means discipline
over every part of your life.
So, if you want easy, go play lacrosse
or football or join the Marines.
Welcome, gentlemen,
to Highland Rugby.
Coach!
Gladly. Hit the field, boys.
Let's go!
- Positions! Let's go!
- Let's go! Let's go!
Don't be lazy!
Let's not be lazy!
They're like freaking choir boys.
Yeah, I know they are, Rick,
but you got to open your eyes.
Yeah. You're in the inner sanctum.
No, man. Unh-unh.
I am done.
Early out's not even worth it.
You know, you're not there
to just suck up some judge.
Get over yourself.
You're there to glom their secrets
and find out how they win.
They run everyone to death.
That's how they win.
Okay, so what?
- Gina, chill, would you?
- Get off the phone.
You, uh, get a little present yet?
It should make you happy.
Yeah, it's cool, man.
Thanks.
Did you see Tam's message?
You wrote that, you loser.
She won't even talk to me.
That's her mom, man.
And I didn't write that.
Tami did.
Think about it, Rick.
Don't stress.
Don't stress, Rick.
Let's go, guys! Keep it tight!
Looking good! Looking good.
You've all earned yourself
a three-second break.
One, two, three.
All right, you know the drill.
Start unloading stuff.
Grab something
and keep it moving.
Pass me that shovel.
Wear that, Sanchez.
Here you go, buddy.
Come on, man!
Let's go, guys.
Clean all the trash.
Grab those rakes!
You're not into landscaping?
It's one thing to run my guts out
for you not playing rugby,
but this sucks.
They can pay someone to do this.
Son, when are you gonna dig down
and first-string
the real Rick Penning?
I'm not your son.
Hey, guys, let's finish up!
Got to get to the sixth floor.
What's on the sixth floor?
You don't get what Coach Gelwix
is doing, do you?
It's what he's not doing.
He just wants you
to do your best.
Well, running until you puke
isn't my idea of rugby.
Well, maybe someone
who's coached 31 years
has some good ideas.
What are you doing?
Did he put you up to this?
No. What are you
talking about, huh?
I'm an only child.
I don't need a big brother.
How about a friend, hm?
Is that what you are?
Yeah.
How about that one?
You're gonna help out, right?
All right.
It's not my thing.
First game!
Look at number 12.
So, you ladies
must be rugby fans.
What makes you say that?
Well, because you're sitting
in my fan section.
So, are you?
We're Highland fans, yeah.
Well, then, today's your lucky day.
I'm their new wing.
Really?
Are you any good?
Well, yeah.
I'm the best.
Wow. Then I guess I'll have
to keep my eye on you, huh?
You know, rugby's not
the only thing that I'm good at.
Let's go, guys! Come on!
Bring it together!
Let's go! Hustle, hustle!
Hey, Penning!
Get your butt down here!
Sorry to cut this short, ladies,
but they need me on the field.
Try not to hurt yourself!
Hey, I'm gonna say this once,
all right?
Back off.
Hey, baby. Don't stress.
They just want to meet me.
Bring it in, guys!
Let's go! Hustle.
Hustle, hustle, hustle.
Let's go.
Okay, listen up, guys.
We've got a couple
of changes today.
We're starting Sanchez at 13.
Penning, you're at 2.
2?
Ah, give it up for him, guys.
Good iob, brah.
Peter!
Let's go.
Riggs.
- Thank you.
- Penning.
First game, gentlemen.
Play it like your last.
No regrets, all right?
Bring it in.
Highland Rugby on three!
One, two, three!
Highland Rugby! Whoo!
All right, guys.
Let's do it!
Let's go!
Congrats, man.
Read it. It's from a guy
that used to play your number.
I don't play hook.
You read it.
Look, brah, position
is everything, okay?
Coach Gelwix knows.
Just trust him.
No. He doesn't know.
He's been sitting over there
on his stupid lawn chair
ever since I've been here.
What don't I know?
I play wing.
I score.
That is what I do.
I doesn't matter who scores.
It only matters that we score.
The team is the star here,
not any one player.
Rick, if you can't handle
or don't want to handle
our coaching or our rules,
that's fine.
Rugby's hard enough.
We're out to make it harder.
It's your choice.
Just give it a shot, okay?
I'm on your side.
Crouch and hold...
...engage!
Hey, get down.
Number 2!
You got to stay low. Get down.
Crouch and hold!
Engage!
And the New Haven
scrum half-sets the ball.
Line captain. Warning, number 2.
Dangerous hit.
Come on.
The way we practiced, all right?
I don't play hook!
Come on, Penning!
Position, position!
An excellent pass
to Kurt Addison
results in New Haven
standing him up into a maul.
Oh, Highland's
number 2 rips the ball out,
but he's clearly offsides.
I'm sure the refs
gonna call this one back.
Forward pass.
I don't know how
you did it in Arizona,
but here we play as a team.
Okay, I don't play for your team.
I play for myself.
That's great! Real great!
We got to pull him.
They'll work it out.
And our score,
New Haven 21, Highland 14.
New Haven scores
again, giving them a 26-14 lead.
And it is evident the crowd
is not pleased with Highland's
new hook, Rick Penning.
Highland not playing well
under the pressure.
You're willing
to take a loss for this kid?
It's not always about rugby, Cal.
10 minutes in the bin.
What?!
What are you talking about?
Just let it go.
Let's just play, okay?
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
Come on.
Let's get it, fellas!
ANNOUNCER, ON RADlO:
It's over, folks.
New Haven
crushes Highland 47-14.
After 23 consecutive wins,
it was bound
to happen sometime.
Did we do our best out there?
ALL, MUMBLING:
No, Coach.
If they were bigger, stronger,
faster, that would be one thing.
If they just plain beat us,
we could keep our head up.
No regret.
But we didn't play
our game today.
We didn't put up our best.
We didn't leave it all
on the field.
We owe more to the guys whose
numbers you got on your backs.
So, let's go see
what you got left in the tank.
Practice doesn't make perfect!
Practice makes...
Permanent!
Who are we?
Highland Rugby. Kia kaha.
Yo, Kurt.
What's that mean?
It means you don't belong here.
- Hey, what's your problem, man?
- You!
This isn't worth it!
No, you're not worth it, Penning.
But don't worry about it, all right?
'Cause every burnout
we've ever had quits.
By the way, you're bleeding.
All right, let's go!
Come on, let's go, let's go!
Hey, what's the secret sign,
my Arizona brother?
Well, you asked for that.
You're real funny.
Hey, brother number 2.
I have a beautiful wife
and great kids.
I love them all very much.
There's a brotherhood
on this Highland Rugby
that you're not going to feel
any other place or time.
Love it while you got it, brah.
You're not alone,
never on or off the field.
I'm always with you.
I care.
So do a couple of thousand others.
Make us proud.
Make yourself proud.
Is you ready, man?
- Ready for what?
- Personal running.
Four miles a day,
ten 100-yard sprints, ten 50s.
Coach upped the numbers
after you left.
I didn't leave.
I quit.
Yeah, but we didn't quit, man.
Leave me alone.
It's 5:00 in the morning.
How did you guys
even get in here?
Well, let's just say Coach Gelwix
called in a favor.
So, we're gonna
be going or what?
You guys are both insane.
And, man, you stink!
Yeah, that's me, baby.
Tradition. Griggsie
doesn't shower during season.
Why?
Well, it's bad karma.
Do you want a hug, buddy?
No.
Come on, man.
Let's go. Get up.
Come on. Get up, man.
- Yeah. That's right.
- All right.
Let's do it!
Hey, Ricardo!
Come on.
Let's pick it up, guys.
I got an early class today.
No. He would
never play for Gelwix.
Uh, well, I talked to him.
I guess the judge
will let him out early if he does.
But, you know, this way he'll be
out in time for nationals.
Yeah, and back here
to play for us.
And loaded with all their strategies,
secret plays, and stuff.
Maybe he wanted to surprise you.
What position?
Huh?
What position is he playing?
Hook.
I think. I don't know.
He was moaning about it.
All right, guys.
Let's hit the field.
See you out there, Coach.
Father in heaven, bless us,
to do our best,
to play well,
to play safe.
Bless the other team
from Sweden...
Scotland.
...whatever,
to do the same.
Thank you for past brothers
who are with us.
Help us to remember
what has been done by them before,
to feel the ma'na,
the power of family,
those living, those gone,
like my father and my mother,
Amen.
All right, everybody up.
Bring it in on, Kurt!
Let's go, guys!
Highland Rugby on three!
One, two, three!
Highland Rugby! Whoo!
- Brother...
- Is something wrong?
Yeah, we're doing that dance,
the chant. I don't know it.
You know it now, brah.
What's it mean?
Respect for our family
and our ancestors.
We stand on this field
ready for battle,
Heh!
At our backs,
we feel the might of tradition,
remembering to honor our family
and our ancestors
who have gone before.
Over our hearts...
...we bear the emblem to die for.
This challenge
is now thrown to you.
Let's go.
Whoa!
Ka mate! Ka mate!
Ka ora! Ka ora!
Tenei te tangata
Puhuru huru
Nana i tiki mai
Whakawhiti te ra
A, upa... ne!
A upane, ka upane
Whiti te ra... Hi!
Let's go!
Attack! Attack!
Highland has the ball,
passing now to their fullback,
Quentin Owens,
who slides...
That's it, kiddo!
Owens with another 5 points,
and Highland's starting
to put this one away.
Every time they try
to get something going,
Highland just crushes it.
- Was that you?
- Yeah, man.
Great tackle.
Thanks.
There's been good scrapping
on both sides,
but at 29 to Scotland 7,
this exhibition has turned
into a Highland clinic.
Yeah!
That was so good!
Way to play tonight, brah.
That's what I'm talking about.
You was in the zone tonight.
Hey, I'll be back, now.
Give me a second.
You just can't seem to stay away.
How did I do?
Not bad for a rookie.
I know this is gonna be tough on you,
but I don't have another game
until next week,
so you're gonna have
to hang in there another six days.
Ooh. Yeah, you're right.
I just don't know
if I can wait that long.
- Can you?
- Oh, never!
Rama!
Griggsie's leaving
within 10 minutes, so...
...come on, let's go!
What's a Rama?
I'll show you. Come on.
I'll see you later.
Bye.
Wow, muchas gracias, senorita.
Welcome to Ranch-A-Rama.
Would you like one or two pieces?
Huh?
She wants to know
how much you want, bud.
Whole thing.
Well, yeah, but...
Well, it is all you can eat, right?
Honestly, is it me, or did Rick
actually pass the ball tonight?
Yeah, good iob!
Hey! Hey!
But that's only 'cause
he thought hisself was open.
Kurt, start it up!
Ohhh!
Highland, my main man!
Huh, huh, huh, huh!
Hey, wait a second.
Pull over real quick.
No bus, my car.
I don't want to pull over.
Just pull over, all right?
C'mon, man. It's kind of late.
Just pull over.
Always trying to kill my vibes.
I thought we had a jack.
Oh, don't worry about it.
We got two.
Oh, good.
I still can't get
the wheel off, though.
Okay.
Let's go.
Go. Ooh-uh.
Ooh, cool! Let me try!
What did I tell you?
Stay out of the street.
Hey, Kurt. You need a hand?
Don't worry about it.
I got it.
I want you to stand
right over here.
Soccer is for kids.
Football is for wussies.
Rugby's for men.
You keep that, eh?
- What do you say?
- Thank you.
Lift open the trunk.
Thanks.
Kurt!
Kurt, Kurt, come on.
Come on, man.
You'll be okay.
Tumo, go get help! Go get help!
Kurt!
Stay with us, man. Come on.
Stay with us.
What's going on?
What happened? What?
It's Kurt, man.
He's in surgery, man.
He just needs to run it out, son.
Never had a player
who wanted to win more.
Incredible athlete.
Rugby was in his blood.
He didn't always like to listen.
He blew out a knee
a game before nationals,
and all his dreams
for an overseas pro rugby career
just gone like that.
Your father would swear
to this day that he got hurt
because I played him
in the wrong position.
Why haven't you told me
about this?
Better question --
why hasn't he?
Well, I tell you what, guys.
Let's bring it in, okay?
Come on.
Bring it in.
Now, "Q"
what do you say, buddy?
Come on, "Q".
Penning.
"Q".
I tutor him, if you have to know.
I don't.
Let's go! Pick up the pace!
Let's move it!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move, move, move!
Penning!
Coach?
Rick, step into my office.
Rick, I want to ask you
to be a captain.
"Q" is already captain.
We always have at least two.
But he can't stand me, the same
with half the guys out there.
This isn't about them.
It's about you.
It's about being the best Rick.
Well, what about Tumo?
He and three or four other guys
came to me suggesting you.
The team doesn't get
this kind of stuff wrong.
I know Kurt would have wanted it.
I don't get it.
You know exactly why I'm here,
and you still act like you care.
I'm just a no-good spy
who cheap-shotted
your star player last year.
First of all, I attribute that cheap
shot to your coach, not you,
and second, let's focus
on where you could end up,
not where you were or are.
And... God doesn't make
a no-good anything.
You just got to learn to listen
and pay attention
to that spirit inside you.
And learning to listen,
that takes a lot of discipline.
So that's why all the rules?
We only have one real rule --
don't do anything
that would embarrass you,
the team, or your family.
I can't be captain.
Some friends of mine
sent me some stuff.
Vicodin.
But I don't have it anymore.
I got rid of it.
Man!
I cannot believe
you made me tell you that.
Much to your credit, Rick,
I didn't make you.
And good decisions
don't make life easy.
But they do make it easier.
You're gonna have
to sit out the Boise game.
But I'm sure you'll find a way
to captain your forwards
from the sidelines.
Welcome to Highland Rugby, Rick.
Thanks.
Kurt was with me
when my father died.
He told me that although
his body was gone,
his spirit would always
be with me.
Every time I do the haka,
I call on the power
of my family spirit.
We'll call upon Kurt's spirit now, too.
Kurt...
...he was a real friend.
If it wasn't for him,
I wouldn't be on this team.
He made me want
to be a better person.
I'm gonna miss that.
You boys might think
I coach because...
...I love rugby
and I love to win.
Both true.
But I keep coaching
because of you guys.
That's why I'm more interested
in turning out champion boys
than champion teams.
I want you to be forever strong
on the field
so you'll be forever strong off it.
Kia kaha -- forever strong.
Kia kaha.
Ka mate, ka mate
Ka ora, ka ora...
Come on, Phipp! I want a nice toss!
Give me a nice toss, baby!
Let's go, Griggsie!
Bring it down!
Protect the ball!
Protect it!
Get it up! Get it up!
Run! Run! Go!
Go!
Yes!
That is what I'm talking about!
Whoo!
Yeah, give me some!
Yeah! Whoo!
I think I liked him better
on the field.
Well
much of the story this season
has been Highland's
commitment to team play,
and after crushing
the Boise team today,
they're in the Pacific Coast
drivers seat
to be the number-one seed
at the nationals
in Colorado Springs.
Settle down! Settle down!
Hey, nice win, guys.
That's the way
to take care of business.
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, Griggs!
You stink, man!
Take a shower!
What you say, huh?
- Yeah!
- Griggs, man.
To the back of the bus.
Hey, come on, Griggsie.
A little mercy, man.
It's a winning tradition.
It's a stinking tradition!
You know where the losers sit?
In the front of the bus, yeah.
That's right.
How'd you like to scrum with that?
Since the tragic death
of team player
Kurt Addison eight weeks ago,
this Highland team has been
nothing but unstoppable.
They'll be returning home
with the regional title
and be headed
to the USA Rugby Nationals
later this month.
What about you?
No family, Griggsie?
No, my parents split up.
My dad's in prison.
My mom,
she's a stripper out in Vegas,
or Reno or something like that.
I don't know. I don't remember.
Man, I'm sorry. I thought
that I had it bad, but you --
It's all good.
You loser. You lied?
You know,
this little trust bridge we had here
just burned
and went right down the river.
But they're always late, so...
Oh, look. It's my mother.
That's a big mama.
Ooh, put your tongue away, dude.
She don't like the drooling,
'cause I already tried that.
- Yeah, how long have they been--
- Together?
- Yeah.
- Since birth.
That's "Q's" sister Emily.
You did not know that?
What?
This has got even better.
I wouldn't touch it, man.
She's twitchy as a bunch of nuns.
- She's the Holy Grail.
- Yeah, uh-huh.
I tried.
You must be the sisters
that "Q" has been telling me about.
What are you doing?
No, I've never said a word
to him about you.
Well, you should have.
Yeah. You should have.
No. I shouldn't have.
Rick Penning.
Emily Owens.
You know,
I've been watching you play.
You're actually really good.
Well, thank you.
It's very nice of you to notice.
- Oh, well--
- "Q": We're going.
Okay, I think I'm leaving now,
but it was nice
to officially meet you!
No, it wasn't.
Hey, "Q"!
I'll see you tomorrow
at 4:00 for practice
where we usually
hang out afterwards
and grab a bite to eat!
You a pineapple, brother.
What?
All hard and ugly
and spiny on the outside.
Nothing but sweet
and mushy under.
Oh, you got it bad.
It's not even like that, brah.
You know, you guys
are going to nationals.
Making Marcus
one happy brother.
Hey.
Dad!
What are you doing here?
I'm taking you home.
Marcus, I told you I wanted
to finish out the season.
I know,
but based on the last two
positive evaluations I gave you,
the judge released you
from the wardship,
placing you back
in the custody of your parents.
So what does that mean?
It means grab your stuff.
You're coming home.
Dad, I can't.
I'm the team captain!
You're still the captain,
of the Razorbacks.
I'm sorry.
Look, see the positive here.
You did it.
You got probation. You're
not going to a county lockdown.
Thanks for everything.
Okay. Okay. That's real sweet.
This isn't summer camp.
Let's go.
You keep listening right, okay?
All right, Bingham.
Enough with the kumbayahs,
all right?
Nice.
It's good to have you home.
Thanks.
You know, tomorrow at practice,
Rick is gonna
lay out Highland's playbook.
You know, whatever you've got
that you think we need,
you know, specific plays,
zoning, substitution strategies,
you just let it rip, okay?
You know, we're gonna
end up playing against them
at Colorado Springs.
This is our year.
We deserve that title.
What do you mean "we"?
My team is Highland.
Okay, you see,
you don't get to choose.
You will leave this house or not
if we say.
You will drive that car or not
You will go to Colorado or not
if I say,
and right now I say
that you will be at practice
with your Razorbacks tomorrow.
Rick, sit down.
Have me arrested.
What was that about?
What did I say wrong?
He's been gone a year,
and the only thing
you can talk about
is having him teach
some stupid plays to your team?
Stupid plays? Okay, look.
It's his team, too.
Didn't you hear him?
The Razorbacks
aren't his team anymore.
He doesn't know
what he wants anymore, honey.
Have you asked him?
I only want him
to have what I never had.
And what makes you think
that he wants what you never had?
What about what he wants?
What he wants landed him in jail.
What is more important, Richard?
A game or two or your son?
Look at him.
If playing for this team
is making him more like the man
that we want him to be,
if it's making him happy --
It's in his eyes.
Just open yours, and you'll see it.
Okay, I'll try. Okay?
You try. You sit.
This is about doing, Coach.
Hey, Rick!
What's up, man?
When did you get back?
Here, let me look at you.
Oh, Tami, I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I just want you to kiss me.
Oh, Tami, come on.
Baby, what's wrong?
Aren't you excited to see me?
Tami, please.
Guys, I'm on probation, man.
You guys got to lose this.
Put it in the truck or something.
Oh, come on, Mr. Paranoid.
You really see a probation schmo
around here?
I missed you.
- No.
- Lars.
Lars, I'm serious, man.
Don't put it in here.
Okay, well, you're still taking us
for a little ride afterward.
Come on, man.
You owe us one.
Rick, this is it.
This is our year!
This is it!
- Am I right?
- Absolutely.
Seriously, though, the team --
We're pure stoked
to have you back to give us
the Highland hookup
on all their plays and stuff.
You want the Highland hookup?
One, there's none of this, all right?
It's about character and honor.
What's he talking about?
I'm sorry, uh...
...character and honor?
Yeah, and we also don't do anything
to embarrass ourselves, our families,
or our team.
Hey! Whoa!
What, so, you don't drink now?
Rick, you're talking
like you still play for them.
You want to know what Highland
teaches? Well, I'm telling you.
Yeah, yeah, we want plays.
Maybe illegal hits.
You really think we want you
to come around here
and start teaching Sunday School?
Come on, man.
This ain't you.
You know what, guys?
I'm going to practice.
Lars, man,
let's just get out of here.
Well, the old Rick used to take it
any way he could get it.
You should suck it up.
Rick, what's wrong with you?
What's happened to you, Rick?
Where's the loyalty, man?
I mean, we've been talking about
beating Highland for the title
since we were little kids.
Lars, man,
let's just go, all right?
Let's just go, okay?
Highland is a bunch
of choir boys, Rick!
Yeah, and you're drunk.
So?
So, we're not doing this.
I'm going to practice.
No, Rick. Come on!
All right, well, maybe we
just don't want you at practice.
Maybe you should, uh, hightail it
back to Highland, huh?
Lars, don't be an idiot!
Come on, you guys!
You know, a year ago you
would have killed me for that.
I said, "I'm not doing this".
No...
Lars! Stop!
You guys, stop!
Get a little zip on that thing.
Get off of him!
Stop, you guys!
Get off him, man!
It's the cops! It's the cops!
Hey, what are you guys doing here?
Back lines! Let's go!
Move it! Go!
I give you the keys to the car,
and this is what I get.
After what I've been through
the last year,
do you really believe
that I'd be messing with drugs
and booze the day I get home?
Okay, there were drugs and beer
all over you and the car.
It was Lars and Marty.
Test me.
I haven't had a drink in a year.
Rick, do you have any idea
how much potential you had?
Lars set me up!
See, my future was stolen.
You're not even listening.
And what are you doing?
You're just throwing it all away?
For what? Drugs?
Booze? Some girl?
So, I guess what I said really
doesn't even make a difference.
Rick, it kills me to sit back and
watch you throw everything away.
I mean,
when are you gonna dig deep
and first-string
the real Rick Penning?
You want to talk
about first-stringing a Penning?
You won nationals in 1986.
You were on the original
Highland Rugby team!
You were
a Highland Rugby player.
I didn't win anything.
You were on the team.
You know what they taught.
I was on nothing.
I saw your picture, Dad.
You were on the team.
No. Gelwix made sure
that I wasn't on that team
by putting me someplace
that I shouldn't have been.
I told him,
but he insisted
that I play a forward.
He was doing what was best
for you and the team.
No, no, Gelwix stole my life!
Well, he's given me mine back!
I play for Highland.
I am benched
for drugs and alcohol,
suspended for lying.
I don't do anything to embarrass
myself, my team, or my family.
Not anymore.
Highland Rugby.
Kia kaha.
I'm done.
Rick.
Rick!
He was caught with the drugs, Larry.
He was changing.
You saw it. We all saw it.
Well, that's why
I fought with the courts
to try and keep him at Wasatch.
When I heard
they were discharging him,
I told them he wasn't ready.
Maybe you both should have
a little bit more faith in him.
Maybe.
- Good night, Coach.
- Good night.
I know how much
you cared about this boy.
And when I can't help
these young men
become champions
in their own lives, it's...
Maybe it is time.
You're out, man.
Come on. Let's go.
Move it!
Mom.
Tami, what's going on?
Larry Gelwix called.
We talked for a long time.
He wouldn't let me off the phone
until I promised
to do some digging.
Tami told the police
what really happened.
I thought you were with Lars
and Marty on this.
Maybe I didn't want
to hold you back anymore.
Where's Dad?
Your dad thought
you might be able to use this.
He also said that he knew you
wouldn't be able to respect him
unless he still tried
to beat Highland,
even with you as their hook.
Let's get out of here.
Thanks, Tami.
USA Rugby welcomes you
to the National High School
Championship Tournament.
Hello, everyone, I'm Max Griffin.
And I'm Colton McDonald,
coming to you live today
from Colorado Springs, Colorado.
Now, we've got 16 teams,
two from each of the country's
seven territories,
plus two at-large entries.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to today's US Rugby
National Championship game...
Brother Rick!
...between East Lansing
and Highland.
What's up, brother?
- Come on, guys.
- What's up, brah?
- Coach!
- Hey, Penning. Welcome back.
Welcome back.
Glad you're here, Rick.
Thanks for having me back.
All right,
look around, gentlemen.
This is what you've been chasing.
Now, I want it clean,
but these guys need to know
that they don't belong here.
I want you to hit 'em so hard,
you make 'em cry.
You hearing me, Peeta?
Yes, Coach.
Make 'em cry.
Yeah! Way to go, buddy!
Highland is just
chewing East Lansing up
and spitting them out.
I tell you, Max, you do not
want to give Highland an inch
because they will
take the whole mile.
This game is over.
Highland cleans house, 61-3.
Who's missing a tooth?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next match
will begin in 15 minutes
between Akron United
and San Mateo Ravens.
And so 16 teams are cut to 8,
leaving the 1 and 2 seeds,
the Flagstaff
and Highland teams advancing.
Hey!
If it isn't the Highland choir boys.
Knock it off, Lars.
We're just surprised to see you
out in the free world, Penning.
You know, we're actually
hoping you guys keep winning,
so we can play you in the finals,
because you will become
a very popular guy.
What's it up to now?
It's like --
What do we got? 235?
$235 to whoever
takes you out of the game.
Is that right?
You...
Uh, Peeta? It's okay.
Come on, brah. Let's go! Let's go!
It's not even worth it, man.
Not even worth it.
Trembling there a little bit, Lars.
Yeah, I think I peed just a little bit.
Just a little.
This is six!
Highland steals
the ball and passes it out.
They hit the gap and took it.
Boy, just look at Swindle
breaking the line
and putting on the gas.
He is making some serious yards.
And we have a ruck
in the midfield.
Oh, a quick ball out.
There's a kick ahead.
And there it is.
Highland's fullback, Quentin Owens,
sweeps it up
for some easy try time.
This is a big cleanup
by Highland.
They're very, very serious
contenders in this tournament.
That was for me.
Good evening.
That worked, yeah?
You guys are sick.
No, get back in, Mark.
They're coming.
They're coming. They're coming.
Griggsie?
Griggs, are you there?
Griggs, let me out of here, man!
Come on! This ain't funny!
Yee-hah!
Griggsie,
get back here, man!
Coach, any predictions
on the match?
Oh, we're looking forward
to the challenge.
My boys have worked
very hard to get here,
and may the best team win.
I understand your son
is playing for Highland.
What's it going to be like
coaching against him?
Uh...
Coach, is it true you used to play
for this Highland team?
Thank you.
Pizza time, baby!
It's more fun
when you turn it on, brah.
Hey, uh, why don't you guys
go torment some menace
in the hallway or something?
All right. Hurry up.
Peeta eat it all.
Hey, let's go
watch Sanchez work out!
Sanchez works out?
And I have a 4.0 GPA.
You want to talk
about your grades?
For the last year and a half,
I've been paying guys
to get test answers for me.
You know, I have lived
my whole life for my parents.
Line by line,
what they wanted me to do.
Highland Rugby is the only thing
that I do for me.
I mean, I have lived
the last four years of my life
so that I can play as a senior
for the national title.
And here it is.
And I'm this close.
I'm trying to stay true to my parents,
I haven't been true
to the one thing
that means the most to me...
...my brothers on the team.
I'm sorry. I just, uh,
had to tell somebody, you know?
You're not gonna tell coach, are you?
That's not my job.
Right.
"Q" just came to see me.
Thanks for being
a positive influence on him.
- That's funny.
- No, no. It's true.
And you gonna play him?
What do you think?
Well...
...he is a captain.
And he scores most of our points.
Might not win without him.
Glad I'm not the coach right now.
I'm glad I'm not Quentin's father
right now.
He just flew in for the finals.
When I was 13,
my father went with me
to a father-and-son dinner.
It was the only time he ever went
with me to anything like that.
One time.
I never knew if he cared.
I took his absence
as a lack of love.
I never felt like I was good enough.
Never felt like I measured up.
And it took me 40 years
to forgive him.
And when you got arrested...
...I told the lovely Mrs. Gelwix,
"It's time to retire".
Then I got a call from your father.
It was the first time we talked
since that 1986 season.
And he said that the son
he lost a year ago
wasn't the same one
he found sitting in jail.
You're where I was 40 years ago.
Don't spend another minute
being angry about yesterday.
Free him, and you free yourself.
Better get some sleep.
Big game tomorrow.
Ladies and gentlemen,
bringing in the game ball
for this years championship
is New Zealand's rugby
living legend,
Mr. Sid Going.
- Have a good day.
- Thank you.
It's good to see you.
Sid, how are you?
Very good.
Good to see you, Larry.
We're coming to you live today
from beautiful
Colorado Springs, Colorado,
where today two familiar teams
are taking the field --
Flagstaff versus Highland --
the winning team walking away
with the national championship.
Rick!
- Hey, Emily!
- Hey.
It's really good to see you.
I wanted to say thank you
for what you did for "Q".
He said you took the time
to listen, and you're a real friend.
He said that?
Well, you're welcome.
Well, I'll be right there,
sitting in the Rick Penning
fan section.
I deserved that.
Good luck.
Thanks.
See you after the game?
Uh, yeah.
You can count on that.
- Hey, wrong bench, Penning.
- Look who it is.
- Sweat it.
- What's up, traitor?
- Rick.
- Welcome back.
Hey, you don't belong
over here, traitor.
You shouldn't be over here.
I just wanted to say
that I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for being a disappointment
to you and Mom.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to be more
like what you wanted me to be.
Son, uh...
It hasn't been just you.
I also need to forgive you.
Kia kaha.
You will play your best game, right?
Let's go!
Better stay on your toes, Rick.
There's 280 bucks on your head.
You're going down and out, pal.
Why's he smiling?
Let's crack open his head
and find out.
Ka mate! Ka mate!
Ka ora! Ka ora!
Tenei te tangata
Puhuru huru
Nana i tiki mai
Whakawhiti te ra
A, upa... ne!
A upane, ka upane
Whiti te ra... Hi!
Get it wide! Get it wide!
At the 6:07 mark in the first half,
the score --
Highland, 5, Flagstaff, 0.
That was a cheap hit!
- Keep the tackles low.
- Oh, come on!
Number 7, 10 in the bench.
Your attention please.
Yellow-card caution issued
to Razorbacks number 7.
Let's go! Support, support!
Now, it's not really known
why Highland is going without
their star fullback,
Quentin Owens today
but the loss, I'm telling you,
has got to be felt
by the rest of the team.
And that conversion
by Highland right there
ties us back up,
so it's Highland, 14,
Flagstaff, 14.
It is anybody's game.
Ruck over! Ruck over!
And Highland puts on the skills
and makes their move.
Oh, they get the turnover
and kick it out.
Cover the line! Cover the line!
And the line-out
goes to Arizona at the 22.
They're killing us out there, dude.
We've got to take Penning out.
All right. You go high.
Oh, yeah!
Straight line! Line it up!
Hey, hey, hey!
- Throw it to Penning.
- What?
Get it right to him.
Back to first jumper!
Switch out on me.
Watch the ball! Watch the ball!
Watch it!
- That'll be 10 minutes.
- Oh, come on!
Ten minutes!
That's a red card!
Colton, the Razorbacks
are getting off easy
with a yellow card
and 10 minutes in the sin-bin.
I tell you, if it were me,
I'd be sitting the kid.
280, boy! 280!
Marty!
You're out. Sit.
- What are you talking about?
- You're through.
Hey, come on.
We're gonna lose without Marty.
One more word out of you,
and you'll be sitting with him.
Everybody stand back.
Let me check him out.
Back off, guys. Back off.
Give him some room, okay?
All right, take it easy, Rick.
Doc's gonna have a look at you, son.
Okay, I'm gonna check your neck.
Just lay still. Lay still, okay?
You'll be okay.
I think he's gonna be okay.
Coach, uh, can I...?
Can I, um...?
Thank you.
Hey.
Look, Rick,
you have a choice here.
You either get up
and finish this game,
or you stay down...
...and you end up like me.
And he breaks
the line and turns on the power.
He outsmarts them all
and takes it to the line,
so it's Highland, 19,
Flagstaff, 14.
And with time just under 5 minutes,
it is still a toss-up
as to who will win this game.
Come on, pass it out! Let's go!
Number 11's got the moves,
and he's got the 5 points!
That is the third try for Arizona,
and the second try
for Lars Murphy in this game.
Arizona's back in business!
That was the try that can
turn this entire game around.
Both teams are playing very well
under the extreme pressure
for the title.
Now this score has
guaranteed us a real cliffhanger
as we move into the last two
minutes of this intense match.
There we go! There we go!
Come on!
Go, Rick. Go, Rick!
Pick it up! Come on!
Go! Go, Rick!
Run!
Penning is down at the try line
in a huge pileup!
I can't see.
We're still waiting
for the official to make the call.
Out of the away!
Move away. Let me see it.
For the 16th time in 21 years,
your USA Rugby National
High School Champion
is Highland.
That's the Rick Penning
I knew was in there!
Way to go, buddy! Way to go!
Hey! We did it!
That's how you make
your family proud, brah!
Kia kaha, son.
Rick! Rick!
You did it!
Hey!
No. We did it.
Yay!
That was unbelievable!
For you.
No.
For the team.
Feel good, huh?
Coach...
Nice game.
Nice game, Richard.
Hey,
that was a beautiful play, brah.
Hey, what is this for?
Season's over, buddy!
What are you talking about?
Oh, ho, ho!
Hey, Griggs, you gotta pay
the price for victory, baby!
Whoo!
Oh!
I'll only do it for you guys.
I promise, I'll only do it for you.
Best bath I ever had!