Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
My father bought it
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
My father bought it
For just two coins
As the Haggadah relates
Along came the cat
And ate up the lamb
The dog choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Along came the stick
To beat the dog
That choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
That he bought
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Then came a fire
And burnt the stick
That beat the dog
That choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Then water came
And quenched the fire
That burnt the stick
That beat the dog
That choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Then came an ox and drank the water
That quenched the fire
That burnt the stick
That beat the dog
That choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Along came a butcher and
killed the ox that drank the water
That quenched the fire
That burnt the stick
That beat the dog
That choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
Then came the Angel of Death
And slew the butcher
Who killed the ox
That drank the water
That quenched the fire
That burnt the stick
That beat the dog
That choked the cat
That ate the lamb
That my father bought
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Why do you sing, little lamb?
Spring isn't yet here
And Passover neither
Have you changed?
I have changed this year
And every evening,
Like each evening,
I have only asked four questions
But, tonight,
I have thought of another question
How long
will this circle of horror last?
Tonight, I have thought
of another question
How long
will this circle of horror last?
Of persecutor and persecuted,
Of executioner and victim
When will this madness end?
What has changed this year?
This year, I have changed
I was a meek lamb
I have become a tiger
and a wild wolf
I was a dove, a gazelle
Today, I don't know who I am
My father bought it
For just two coins
The lamb! The lamb!
Our father bought it
For just two coins
And everything is starting again
Can we leave this place?
Please.
Where to?
I don't know.
Not anymore.
I'm ready.
Hello.
You're going to Jordan?
- Yes.
Your passports, please.
This is mine.
All right. Do you have a weapon?
- No.
Let them through.
Thank you.
You're going to Jordan?
- Yes.
Move forward slowly.
Slowly.
Move forward, move forward.
Move forward, madam.
Stop the engine.
Your passports.
Gently, one thing at a time.
Hello.
This is my passport.
And yours?
How did you meet?
Shall I answer?
I'm her driver.
- Sorry! He's talking to her!
You're her driver?
Yes. It's perfectly normal!
- What company?
The name's on the door.
Moshe ben Moshe.
Who's Moshe?
- My husband.
Reason for travel?
I'm going to show her Jordan.
Will you be in Jordan long?
Just 24 hours.
- I understand.
All those bags for 24 hours?
Know how many bags
they have in the back?
Calm down.
Whose suitcases are they?
It's complicated.
They belong to her mother-in-law,
Mrs. Breitberg.
I was due to drive her.
Ever heard of the foolish passenger?
She left her bags in my car!
Let's take the car apart.
What's your training?
- Benchetrit. Shimshon 1989.
I understand. Calm down.
That passenger, Ann Mary Murphy,
was married to a guy.
She didn't know explosives
had been put in her bags.
But I'm Israeli!
I ask these questions for
your security and that of the State.
Let me take the car apart!
The girl looks like a hooker.
Be polite, you.
You don't give me orders.
Stay out of this!
Where are you going after Jordan?
I have an idea.
Do you have family in Jordan?
- Of course not.
I'm just showing her Jordan.
All those cases for a day trip?
I can leave them here.
They're not ours.
I'll pick them up on the way back.
Go to passport control,
I'll check.
I don't mind leaving them.
Go to passport control.
We'll check.
Thank you very much.
A word of advice.
Change your passport photo,
it doesn't look like you anymore.
Show some respect, please!
Calm down.
What a nerve!
We'll meet again!
Hello.
Wonderful.
Welcome.
Can I help you?
I'd like...
Bachar!
Come, my son.
Fill it up. High-octane.
Thank you.
- Would you like a coffee?
No, no.
Until 1948, I lived in Jaffa.
And then...
Wash her properly!
Hey, Tsupi. Calm down.
Did you hear that noise?
Take over.
Moshe!
What happened?
Are you all right?
Moshe, talk to me.
It's just a little blood,
don't worry.
A little blood?
You're drenched in it!
Where's the car, Hanna?
- What car?
I've been working on it all night!
Moshe, you're wounded.
Forget the car.
Moshe, I'm going for help.
You're covered in blood.
I have to go to the free zone,
to the American's.
That bastard owes us money.
- He thinks of money now!
I'll get help,
I'll call an ambulance.
Lie down. Don't move.
Hanna, you have to pick up
Mrs. Breitberg.
She can wait!
I'm going...
- Hanna!
Lie down. Don't move!
I'm going to get help.
Don't forget Mrs. Breitberg!
Moshe, I'm going to call
an ambulance. Don't move.
She's arriving with Julio!
He has a head wound.
He's talking rubbish.
I'll be right back.
Stay where you are, okay?
Regional medical centre.
Please hold.
Good evening.
- It's Hanna ben Moshe.
Who?
- Hanna ben Moshe.
Oh, Hanna!
- Yes, it's me.
I need help.
- What's the problem?
In our garage...
In Moshe ben Moshe's garage...
He's seriously wounded.
Send an ambulance. Hurry.
Shell or rocket?
Don't tell the girls.
Don't panic them.
Did you have a good flight,
Mrs. Breitberg?
Liberia?
- No.
El Al is good!
Moshe isn't well.
Moshe, wounded.
Is it serious?
- Yes, it's serious.
But I am here!
Are we going to Jerusalem?
I've booked a table
at the Mishkenot Shaananim Hotel.
But before I want to go
to the Wailing Wall.
Go to Galilee,
the Mount of Olives,
Yad Vashem.
No, not tomorrow.
What do you mean, not tomorrow?
Tomorrow, me, to Jordan.
What do you mean, to Jordan?
Julio, you call this organized?
Doesn't anything work here?
I told you I wanted a driver
and a car for tomorrow
and tomorrow
I can't go anywhere!
Mom, please, speak English.
Julio, guess whom I met at
the airport on my way to Tel Aviv?
No idea. - The daughter
of your father's partner.
She has an office in New York.
I told her about you,
about your brilliant studies.
I said you'd call her.
I have her card.
You can call her
when you want.
She'll give you work.
She's a fantastic girl.
She's beautiful, she's friendly...
and, above all, she's Jewish.
Jewish?
Not Christian?
- Yes, Jewish.
Good, very good!
Hello, good afternoon.
May God's peace and blessing
be upon you.
Who's calling?
I'd like to speak to the American.
Moshe ben Moshe.
Understand?
- Yes.
Hello.
Hurry up, it's closing soon.
Go on!
The rabbis say it isn't.
Rebecca, keep out of this.
It's just between her and me.
Let's drink a toast.
Sorry...
So I want to see him.
Where's the American?
He isn't here.
He's ill.
Ill?
- Where's Moshe?
All right.
He's ill?
So is Moshe.
Fine.
They're both ill.
Illness aside, where is he?
Honestly...
What is this?
National Geographic or what?
What?
- What do you mean, what?
I'm not here to talk about this.
And before?
- Before?
Auschwitz.
My parents come from Auschwitz.
Mine from Palestine.
No kidding!
I know some Palestinians.
How do you know them?
- We have greenhouses.
Greenhouses?
We grow flowers.
We rear camels, cows,
goats and even donkeys.
I have a donkey too,
Moshe, my husband.
Okay, Leila. Listen, beauty.
I'm not here to argue,
I don't know you.
Drink your tea.
Look at me for a second.
You know what I'm talking about.
You owe me 30,000$.
I know.
- So I want to speak to the American.
Can I make a phone call?
Thank you.
Hello, Moshe.
We're here.
We're in the free zone.
I'm with Mrs. Breitberg's
daughter-in-law.
I had no choice.
I couldn't abandon her.
It's okay. We were late.
We got lost.
I won't leave without the money.
This time, it's the jihad.
No. Everything will be fine.
Don't worry.
And I asked
that he wait for us.
He isn't here.
I've noticed!
Thank you.
Go with her, I'll follow you.
These fools set fire
to the farm and the houses.
What can I do?
- Where is he?
I don't know where he's vanished to!
Hurry, save the animals!
Are you happy now?
Are you satisfied?
Hurry!
Well?
Do you like it?
Have you got what you wanted?
What?
Show some respect, will you.
How do I have to tell you?
He started the fire so you could
light your cigarettes!
I stopped working to sort out
the problem with him!
Things are clear
with me!
How can I reach your brain?
What for?
You wonder why?
You don't understand a thing!
The problem here is her!
She shames our village.
Show some respect!
Don't make me even angrier.
I can start a fire too!
I can burn her!
Shut up!
You're going too far.
You're an animal!
Samir, calm down.
Stop!
That's an order!
What's going on?
What are all these flames?
No. I'm not staying here.
After we left Yamit...
To help in the greenhouses.
"Come and see!"
They put me down
outside his house.
"Take him too."
Then they left.
"Tomatoes".
In the nearby camps and villages,
some were saying:
Then I went to a camp
in Jenine.
News flash.
We have just been informed
of the strong probability
of a terrorist attack.
The border is closed
in the Jordan Valley.
Roadblocks are in place.
The public must remain alert
and report any suspect activity
to the security services.
I repeat.
According to the secret services,
a terrorist attack could take place
in the Jordan Valley
and the centre of the country.
Roadblocks are in place.
Be cautious at all times
and report any suspect activity
to the security services.
End of the news flash.
We shall keep you informed.
Hello.
What money?
- The money.
Don't ask what money.
I said I don't have the money.
- I know you have it.
What does she want?
You have the money.
I told you, I don't have it.
- I know you have it.
Walid took it.
Don't give me that Walid story.
Give me the money.
He started the fire
and took the money.
I don't believe a word.
Stop!
Stop! This is the border!
I told you, I don't have it!
- You do!
You were there, weren't you?
You saw the house burn?
The house was burning,
you went in and took something.
Walid took the money.
- I don't care.
You're repeating yourself.
I don't have the money.
Let me tell you...
- Go ahead.
My husband Moshe and I
have worked hard.
I want my money and I'll get it.
I don't have it!
- I don't believe you.
Subtitles:
Cinematyp Studios Ltd.
Ripped by:
SkyFury
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org