I'm gonna get those fuckers!
This ain't the Bronx, right?
I'm gonna get the motherfuckers!
I'm gonna corner him,
the motherfucker!
First one we see, straight up,
we whack the fucker!
Kneecap the fucker!
People just stood and watched.
- He stared at me.
- They're fuckin' losers.
The twins were there.
I swear on the Koran
I'll kill 'em both.
Who are these motherfuckers?
They hang out round here.
They're from Le Moulin.
We'll waste the shits.
We'll get the motherfuckers!
Right on, bro!
- They think we're losers!
- You said it.
We'll blindside 'em, straight up.
I'm goin'. You guys can come too.
You're in, right? Everyone's in?
Waste the fuckers!
Quit the big talk.
Don't say that! You're crazy!
Yo, clock Krimo!
- Come here!
- Fuckin' run!
He better not chicken out!
Right on. If he does, I swear...
What's goin' on?
Slam's had his gear bit.
- Who by?
- 8 fuckers!
The twins included. Know them?
Fucked him over.
- On the Koran?
- On me!
You in? Let's go!
Come on, let's go!
You in?
Come on, move it!
I'll get my nunchucks.
Meet us there! Go on, hurry!
Magali!
You're there?
Yeah, I'm here.
- Where are you off to?
- Just a second.
I'm gonna see Krimo.
What's up?
Don't play innocent with me.
What's wrong?
A week I've been lookin' for you.
You don't answer my calls.
Hey, I wasted all my credit.
- All gone.
- Yeah?
I couldn't call from home,
the old lady just got the bill.
Your mom never said I called?
Sure, I believe you!
And the guys? Makou didn't say?
Fathi didn't say?
Are they against me?
Your phone was always busy.
Stop lyin' to me!
I never used my phone.
I was waitin' for your call.
You think I'll fall for this?
I've had enough of you. Get lost.
Come on, let's forget it.
Leave me.
C'mon.
Just for a week.
It's over.
You come here,
you think I'm your slut?
Shithead!
Motherfucker!
Abdelkrim!
Hurry up, we have to get going.
- Where?
- To see your father.
I'm not coming today.
Why?
What's wrong?
Nothing, I'm goin' out.
I'll go next week.
What are you doing?
Seein' the guys.
Guys? Girls!
- No, guys.
- Sure.
You'll get some privacy today.
Privacy?
In a prison visiting room?
I've made dinner. Just warm it up.
- What is it?
- Pasta.
- Again?
- Yeah, again.
It's okay, thanks.
See you.
- What?
- No messing about.
And tell Dad
that I said "Hi"
and that I'll see him next week.
Mom!
You're doing your hair?
See you later.
I wanted the flounce down to here.
It's a real sloppy job.
Longer, I said. Fuck!
- Remember.
- I noted it.
Go on, lengthen it.
- I can't now.
- Lengthen it.
- I can't.
- Please.
- That's what we said.
- I wanted it to here.
I noted it.
C'mon, lengthen it.
Someone here can do it.
- We can't.
- You're kiddin'!
She can lengthen it. Ask her.
Can you do the flounce?
No, I'm too busy.
We're too busy.
C'mon, lengthen it.
- Work something out.
- There's no time now.
Krimo, come and take a look at this.
Be honest, how does it look?
- Weird.
- You don't like it?
It's not that,
I'm just not used to it.
You don't like it.
Is it for the play?
- It's fine for that.
- It looks good?
It's pretty.
Shouldn't the flounce be longer?
It's very pretty.
It looks good?
It's good, it's perfect.
We said 70.
No, brother, 50.
No, we said 70.
- We said 50.
- I want 70.
We talked and agreed on 70.
- Make it 50 now.
- I can't.
You can't make it 50?
50 euros...
- We talked it over.
- Please.
We agreed on 70.
70's expensive!
50 euros is fair.
But that's all I have.
What'll you do now?
Take it off.
No way, I'll give you 50.
No, I want 70.
It's just not possible.
Lend me 10 euros, Krim.
Don't be a cheapskate!
Expensive, huh?
- Look at this thing.
- It's fine.
- You'll take 60?
- All right.
Done!
It's a real beauty.
Excellent.
I'm real happy. Thanks.
- You should be!
- I am.
Lili! Is your sister in?
Fetch her!
Don't tell her.
- Get her.
- It's beautiful.
- See you.
- Wait. Tell me when she's here.
Zina!
They want you.
Lydia wants you.
She's coming.
Hi, Krimo. Okay?
Yeah, great.
What's happenin'?
What's up?
Nothin'.
So why're you here?
Oh, wow, Lydia!
Incredible!
How's it look?
Wicked!
- Seriously?
- It's fly.
- You mean it?
- On my mother's life!
Seriously? I'm so happy.
A real Miss France.
That's so sweet!
- Who made it?
- Slant-eyes.
Is it beautiful?
It's fantastic.
It needs more lace here.
I wanted a longer flounce.
I told him to lengthen it.
Know what the fucker said? "No".
Right?
That fucker wouldn't lengthen it.
Who gives a toss?
It's great like that.
Are you nuts, girl?
Leave it as is!
The motherfucker.
With a flounce,
it wouldn't look so good.
- Did it cost a lot?
- Guess.
30.
60, the motherfucker!
I coughed up the loot.
Motherfucker!
I'd've spat in his face!
You saw me. I was wicked.
I didn't want to cough up the loot.
Who gives a toss?
It's fly, he did you right.
The colors ain't too flash?
You're stupid. They make it.
The color's bad, are you nuts?
Any other color,
it'd suck big time.
It's wicked! It brings it out.
It's phat!
That's sweet, I'm happy.
Straight up, it looks great.
Coming to the rehearsal?
I've a shitload of cleanin' on.
- I'm watchin' the kids too.
- Come on!
I swear, I have to watch the kids.
- Mom's going out.
- They're big.
My sista called by earlier
to ask me to go with her.
Mom said no way.
Not for long...
You don't hear her yellin'?
She won't let me,
on the Koran she won't.
Usually, I'm free
but she's goin' out.
Some other time...
See ya.
Okay, quit bitchin'!
Comin' with me?
Right now?
- I can't.
- Why?
- I'm busy.
- Please...
It's good for us
when there's an audience, see.
I get off on the audience.
Come on, come with us.
Me, Rachid, Frida...
I don't ask a lot, right?
Come with me for once.
Please, come with me.
I dunno...
I've got my new costume too.
It'll be cool!
- Forget it.
- Please...
Okay.
- Not for long.
- You won't regret it.
Hiya!
We've been here an hour!
- There.
- Fantastic!
- Ace!
- Phat!
- Pretty?
- Really bad!
It works?
Real fly, that's for sure.
Wicked!
- It's phat, all right!
- Seriously?
Ace!
- It's good?
- Deadly!
Seriously? I'm happy.
- Okay, Krimo?
- Fine.
It looks real good on you.
Thanks. D'you like it, Frida?
Yeah, but that's no reason
to be late.
Is it pretty?
- Yeah.
- Seriously?
That's sweet.
You crossed the hood like that?
You bet.
With people around?
You're nuts!
What do I care?
I'm more into the character
this way.
You're crazy!
I'm more into the character
in my dress.
It's better for actin'.
I get mine tonight.
- Really?
- Straight up.
It'll be phat
with us all in costume.
Costumes don't mean shit.
You need to show
your character's inner feelings.
Feel its spirit, like.
It's what you give off
that matters most,
not the threads you wear.
It's not the appearance,
it's the heart.
It depends, you know.
- Remember that interview.
- About the shoes?
Yeah. We saw an interview
with this actor
who got into a character
when he had his shoes on.
See, it depends.
Watchin' us rehearse, Krimo?
I'm jus' takin' a look, like.
You could've said.
Why?
You could've let us know.
He's watchin' the scene, okay.
It bothers me, him bein' here.
He'll just watch, like in class.
He can watch if he wants
but you could've said!
Rachid said Hannan'd be here.
Does Krimo bother you?
He's just gonna watch!
Well, he bothers me!
C'mon, it's Krimo,
not the friggin' President!
- We're here to rehearse!
- I'll go.
No, Krimo, you stay.
Let him stay,
we need to get used to an audience.
What's your problem?
Here, sit yourself down.
Quit freakin' out!
We fix a rehearsal,
we get here on time...
- He's just watchin'.
- You keep us waitin'...
- It's okay.
- Chill!
What's up? You're pissed?
You bet! You're late,
you bring someone...
But at school...
At school,
it's part of the class.
Think this is
some dating agency here?
He's watchin'. What's wrong?
- Screw that!
- She's freakin' out!
- You bet I am!
- You're crazy!
Sure I am! Fuck, she's too much.
Frida, please, let's get started.
I have a soccer game after.
- It's a rehearsal.
- So let's rehearse.
He can come to the show.
- Concentrate, instead of yellin'!
- Concentrate?
Let's not waste any more time!
Where were we?
Hurry it up.
Chill.
- Before...
- Act 2, scene 5.
Take it from here.
"I should be surprised... "
Okay?
Frida, you're not on.
Let's go.
- She's pissin' me off.
- Go on!
Bismillah...
I should be surprised in turn
by your prompt homage.
Once acquainted, it will fade away.
In that case, madame,
any loss will be to my disadvantage.
You overestimate me.
As you do me.
I should be on my knees to speak!
We do not control our fate.
Our parents pay us no heed!
My heart would have chosen you,
whatever your credit.
An easy choice for it.
May I hope that you feel likewise?
Were you but Perette or Margot
when I spied you, whip in hand
on the cellar steps,
you'd be my princess yet.
Can such feelings endure?
To strengthen them mutually,
let us swear undying love
despite all the spelling mistakes
committed upon my person...
I lost it.
Never mind, keep going.
To strengthen them mutually,
let us swear undying love
despite all the spelling mistakes
committed upon my person.
I prize such a sweet vow
and make it most willingly.
I stoop
before your dazzling kindness.
Stop. I cannot bear
to see you humbled.
It's most absurd. Stand up.
Someone is coming.
Frida, where are you?
Step back a bit.
What, Lisette?
A word, madame.
Enough, dear girl.
Come back in fifteen minutes!
Maids in my land
wait to be called.
I must speak to Madame.
No, Frida, you're overdoin' it.
It's too flash, it sucks.
You come on and say your line
but you're overdoin' it.
Bustin' my balls already?
You're a maid in this!
When you come on,
you're hoggin' the spotlight!
Hey, look at yourself first,
with your fan and all!
I can do that, I'm the lady.
Only you can criticize now?
That's the way ladies are!
- You play the maid.
- And she's a fake lady!
And you're a fake maid.
At first, she's a maid,
so she can't be a real lady.
C'mon, she comes out with stuff
like "I must..." It sucks.
Hannan, be honest,
isn't she overdoin' it?
She won't listen to me.
You see!
You overdo it as the maid!
- You're overdoin' it!
- Yeah.
- I can't with him starin'.
- Who's starin'?
- Krimo!
- He's watchin' us all.
He's not starin' at you,
he's watchin' us all.
I'm not stupid, he's makin' fun.
He's not, he's watchin'.
Why'd he make fun?
Call that watchin'?
Holy shit, she's paranoid!
I saw him laughin'
while I was waitin'. Sorry,
there's watchin' and watchin'.
I'm not dumb!
He's not laughin' or starin', okay!
No, Krimo stay!
He's not makin' fun.
- I have stuff to do.
- Stay!
There!
- Happy now?
- He's sulkin'.
- Screw you!
- Go after him, then!
Look at crybaby!
You treated him bad, I swear.
She turns up late but that's okay!
It's all my fault!
Quit yellin'.
I mouth off
when Frida's the problem.
With Lydia, I keep it shut
but when it's Frida...
- Show some respect.
- Respect?
She keeps us waitin' here on her
and never even apologizes!
- It's not right.
- Get off my case!
Lydia!
Move your fuckin' ass!
Lydia's really heated at you now.
I'm heated too.
She pissed me off big time.
Move, Lydia!
Show more fuckin' respect to people.
Quit dissin' them.
Hey, I have my soccer game.
Hurry it up!
My game!
She's the disser,
bringin' someone along,
arrivin' late...
That's respect?
Only natural I start bitchin'!
She's not with him.
I never said that,
I said she's pissin' me off!
- Frida!
- Chill, okay.
No, Frida, I mean...
- What's up?
- Who d'you think you are?
- Your act drove him off!
- Don't yell at me!
- I never made him leave, okay!
- Is this cool or not cool?
- It's not cool!
- He decided to go.
- What's your problem?
- Act 2, scene 5, let's go!
Count me out!
You're crazy yellin' at me,
the trouble's you!
Me? You're yellin' at us all,
pissin' us all off!
Sure I am! He bounced,
I never made him go!
He should take it like a dog?
Frida, please...
You're crazy, girl!
Don't even talk to me!
We're here to rehearse, okay!
I'm gonna rehearse
with this mad cow?
- You bet you are!
- No way, not with you!
Just a second...
- Get up now and get to work!
- Don't order me!
- Who d'you think you are?
- No way!
- For my sake...
- Jus' start actin'!
Chill, okay!
C'mon, move. She's crazy!
She's a diva!
C'mon, Lydia...
You know what?
Just a second...
Next time she pisses us off,
I'm outta here, get it?
Watch it, bitch!
Chill, Frida.
- Frida, please...
- C'mon!
Not another word. Quiet.
Take it from the top:
"I should be surprised..."
From the top to the end.
- I know.
- You do?
Let's go.
Take your time.
You bet I will!
I should be surprised
by your prompt homage.
Once acquainted, it will fade away.
Abdelkrim...
You're late.
Hey, it's not that late!
Where were you?
With the guys.
Make room for me.
You haven't eaten?
I have.
I ate at Nabil's.
Was Dad okay?
He didn't freak?
He did.
He wasn't pleased.
He wasn't?
There's a drawing in my bag.
Off you go, get to bed.
I have to work tomorrow.
You should go to bed too.
I'm not moving, I'm beat.
Sleeping there?
Good night.
We'll get that sailboat!
Yeah, we'll get that sailboat.
Note this in your books
for tomorrow.
Reply in writing
to the following question:
To what extent
- do you think...
- Not so fast.
To what extent
do you think that Marivaux
attempted
in Act 1, scene 5...
in Act 1, scene 5
- the one we just saw -
to favor the study of emotions...
at the expense of action?
I want examples!
Let's move on to Act 2.
We'll go straight to scene 5.
I'll need Lisette,
Arlequin and Silvia.
Get to your marks.
We're in the middle of the scene.
You follow?
Remember the situation?
Lisette has told us
at the start of Act 2, scene 1
that Arlequin fancies her.
Do you say "fancy" these days?
"May I hope..."
Take it from there.
May I hope that you feel likewise?
Were you but Perette or Margot
when I spied you,
whip in hand on the cellar stairs,
you'd be my princess yet.
Can such feelings endure?
To strengthen them mutually,
let us swear undying love despite...
all the spelling mistakes
committed upon my person.
I prize such a sweet vow
and make it most willingly.
I stoop
before your dazzling kindness.
Stop. I cannot bear
to see you humbled.
It's most absurd.
Stand up.
Someone is coming.
What, Lisette?
A word, madame.
Enough, dear girl.
Come back in fifteen minutes!
Maids in my land
wait to be called.
Monsieur...
Excuse me, I wanted to ask...
I'm the poor girl in this?
- I'm a maid acting rich?
- Exactly.
Right?
So, she's rich, acting poor?
But she comes in,
acting like she's rich.
I've just started!
Finish the scene, then we'll see.
Who says
I won't act poor later?
That's a good question.
Do you see why?
That question of hers
leads us to the heart of the play.
Marivaux has the rich acting poor
and the poor acting rich
and no one can really manage it.
It shows that we're prisoners
of our social condition.
If you're rich 20 years
and poor 20 years,
you can dress in rags
when you're rich
and in fancy dresses
when you're poor
but your language and conversation
stay the same.
The way you express yourself
shows where you come from.
This is
"The Game of Love and Chance"
but it shows there's no chance.
Who do the rich fall for?
The rich.
And who do the poor fall for?
The poor.
They recognize each other
despite their disguises.
They fall in love
within their own social class.
No chance and no love.
Love in the usual sense,
pure love, that is.
Usually, you fall in love
with the inner being,
not with what's around it.
Marivaux says that...
we're conditioned
by our original milieu.
We stick together. Even disguised,
we cannot escape our origins.
So when you play
rich people or poor people
playing those same roles,
they can manage it at times
but the origins are there
and they often fail.
- Reflexes return.
- We can imitate that.
Yes, but imitating
is only ever imitating.
Do you understand that?
These two recognize each other.
Their love, the purest feeling,
is influenced by their origins.
Lydia!
Come on!
- What's up?
- Okay?
Lydia, you owe me 10 euros.
You cheapskate!
That's why you called me over?
I've no money on me.
That's okay.
I'll pay you back.
There's no rush.
Okay, that's cool.
Cold, huh?
This fuckin' cold
makes you wanna stay in!
Want to see a movie?
I've got two tickets.
I was goin' with a homey
but he's sick.
I've got two tickets.
Want to come?
I can't. Are you crazy?
I have to rehearse with the others.
We're rehearsin'.
Forget it for today.
Are you crazy?
We're performin' soon
and you say forget it!
We need to rehearse every day.
We're on permanent rehearsal now.
It's no joke, you know.
Never mind, then.
- Some other time.
- Inch'Allah.
Okay, see you.
Hey, Krimo!
Don't worry, I'll pay you back.
There's no rush.
When you're ready...
- Straight up, okay?
- Fine.
Hey, Krimo, what's up?
Do me a favor.
Go on...
Don't tell.
I promise. Go on.
Swear.
I won't tell, okay. What is it?
On your mom's life?
On my mom's life, I won't.
Well?
- It's nothing.
- It's okay, then?
Rachid...
- On the Koran of Mecca...
- I won't tell.
Cut it out, okay,
just say what it is!
- Straight up?
- Come on...
Out with it!
I'd like you to let me
play Arlequin instead of you.
Your part as Arlequin...
Let me do it instead of you.
You wanna be Arlequin?
I'm in deep shit now.
The teacher'll freak.
Is this halal?
Let's go.
- What'll you do later?
- Be an actor.
I said actor... Well, an actress.
Actor and actress is different.
Actors are the ones
who perform on stage.
That's right,
and actresses are women
who do fights and stuff like that.
Actresses do fights?
No, you don't feel me,
you don't get
the meanin' of my words.
- Actresses do movies.
- Yeah, that's what I mean.
- They do TV and that.
- And fights.
What about you?
I really want to sing.
If that doesn't work,
I'd like to be in the movies.
And if that doesn't work,
I'll keep studying.
Inch'Allah.
Yeah, God willing.
She wants stuff
that brings in the paper!
Shut it! I'm not that cheap!
God willing, I'll get a good job.
If it doesn't work out,
I'll try other stuff
but I'll work.
You'll need to strip.
Get outta here!
Not on your life!
- You have no choice.
- You bet you do!
And half-nude?
Get outta here!
Not on your life!
What's half-nude mean?
Half-nude means nude to me.
If there's "nude" in it,
you're totally nude!
On the Koran!
Even in that see-thru shit,
you're still nude for me!
I don't wear it.
Suspenders, prostie shit...
Look at her, already into it!
I'll send my mom to slap you.
She's gonna get her mom!
If they want me to strip,
they'll need to ask my dad.
Hold on, what'll your old man say?
"Huh?"
He'll whack 'em! Take that!
My dad won't even say "Huh" first.
My dad'll bop 'em one!
Am I botherin' you?
I need to talk to you.
So talk.
Come on.
We can talk here.
No, over there.
What's up with you?
You after Krimo?
Why d'you ask?
Tell me, are you hot for Krimo?
Answer me.
Storm brewin'...
- You won't answer?
- No, I'm not hot for him.
You're not?
Krimo's actin' now!
Why is that, huh?
- So what?
- He has the right.
Sure, he can if he wants.
No, he can't if he wants.
He's doin' actin',
what's the problem?
- So what?
- What d'you mean?
He's actin'. So what?
- He never read a book before!
- So?
He ain't killed anyone!
There's some other reason.
I know him, okay?
- How d'you know he's actin'?
- Who told you?
I was told. People talk!
Watch your tone!
I know what's goin' on!
What?
You think I'm up to somethin'?
Just a second!
I'm not mouthin' off.
People have told me about her.
Me neither. Let me speak.
Turn the heat on Rachid, okay.
That bastard,
he dumped us at the last minute.
He backed out of the play.
So see him and quit hasslin' us.
Watch your mouth.
You got it in for him or what?
He has his life, he's a busy guy.
He has other interests.
Me for instance.
Know what our dates were?
Rehearsals. I'm glad he stopped.
He has a life too, outside you.
Who d'you mean, "you"?
He should just keep his word!
So? You've replaced him.
You've got Krimo now.
Hey, let people speak!
Chill out, quit raggin' each other.
Forget Rachid...
Guys like you piss me off.
- You hot for him?
- No way!
If I did,
I'd have gone out with him, right?
He asked you?
No, but I'd have asked him out.
You bet.
Cut it out,
I've known Krimo forever.
He's my homey.
You thought I'd jump on him?
I'm not some nympho.
Chill out, okay.
Old homies like them don't go out.
I hope not.
Hey, girl, she don't report to you.
She said she ain't hot for him.
Instead of hasslin' us,
why not go see Krimo?
Yeah, quit bustin' our balls.
You bet she will.
She ain't hot for him. What now?
She keeps her hands off him!
You get me?
Why keep sayin' "she"?
Talk to her direct.
You speak for her!
Talk and cease the hassle.
She gets the message.
Go on, talk to her.
Got it, Lydia?
You think I'll shut up
and listen to this shit?
Who d'you think I am?
Think I'll just take it?
Stand up...
I'll jus' say one thing.
You don't touch him, he's mine.
Get my meanin'? He's mine.
You don't talk to him,
touch him or come onto him
like I heard you were,
with all the rest.
What is this?
You think I'll stand by
and let you steal my guy?
You broke up!
You dumped him.
Why come bustin' her balls?
Go piss him off instead!
I've been with him 2 years.
We were hot for each other.
And I'm still hot for him.
Take care of your guy
and leave mine be!
I told you, he doesn't interest me!
Find yourself a guy that's single.
What is all this?
Why're you hasslin' me?
- You slut!
- Come back here!
What d'you want?
All you do all day is insult me?
Find another guy!
- I'm a slut?
- Yeah!
You take other girl's guys.
Your guy? He's your ex!
You suicidal, girl?
You are if you touch him!
Suicidal, me?
I'll fuckin' waste you, bitch!
I'll whack you and your family!
I don't steal guys,
I'm no slut, you get it?
Callin' me a slut?
Wow, tough girl!
I'm a slut?
Want me to whack you?
I jus' came to warn you.
Next time, I'll whack you.
Forget her, Lydia.
We'll catch her later.
Make your mind up!
She'll wipe the floor with her.
She'll end up in the ER.
That's what you want?
You tell her to stand up
and now back off?
She comes hasslin' us,
then starts weepin'!
- What'll fightin' change?
- It'll shut her up.
- Someone'll jus' get hurt.
- She thinks she's Miss World!
Krimo doesn't give a shit.
And she says he's hot for her!
Krimo don't care!
Like I said,
she should talk it over with him.
Understand her! You're chicks too.
You have hearts, right?
She's heated. She won't give in.
She's still hot for him!
So she sees Krimo.
She don't bust Lydia's balls.
She goes see Krimo.
Who'd want a dog like her?
My brother, he sees her,
he spits on her.
On the Koran!
She makes trouble for nothing.
Yeah, and 'cause of her,
we're fightin' now. You're crazy!
So, girl, you hot for him or not?
You after him or not?
- No way.
- There, that's settled.
Okay, Lydia, you know
you've done nothing wrong
but she's one mean bitch.
Watch her, okay?
Hey, Krimo!
Hello, ma'am.
Hello, Fathi!
- How are you?
- Fine.
Your husband?
You said I'd come
to the islands with you?
I was thinkin'...
Is he still in D block?
I'm askin'
because my sister's husband, Jacky,
is being transferred,
my sister said.
- Really?
- Yeah, to Fresnes.
He got his transfer papers.
I know your husband and Jacky
get along.
I thought he'd be pleased.
You'll tell him?
Yes, I'll tell him.
And say I said "Hi".
- I'll do that. How are you?
- I'm okay.
No worries.
Could you get your son for me?
Hold on, I'll call him.
Abdelkrim!
Fathi's here.
Go on, he's waiting.
- Okay?
- What's crackin'?
- Where were you, fucker?
- At home.
You moved out or what?
I was thinkin'...
I've got this hot skin flick,
you have to see it.
A blazin' movie, believe me,
full of hot bitches...
- I can't.
- All-out fuckin'.
- I have stuff to do.
- Listen...
Guess what else?
There's a hard-core tape.
Hard-core, straight up.
Caribbean babes and all,
you pop a fuse.
The guys'll get together
and jerk off.
A real jerk-fest.
We'll spray the fuckin' walls!
- I can't, okay.
- How come?
Cut the crap. Why can't you?
- I have stuff to do.
- C'mon!
Is it Magali?
Is it her?
No kiddin'? You fucker...
You won't come over?
You sure? Never mind.
Do your thing, bro.
- Is Lydia there, please?
- I'll get her for you.
Everythin' cool? Feelin' good?
I'm okay...
Learnin' Arlequin?
I can't do it.
You know, I learn it
but I lose it again right away.
The lines are too long.
My memory's not so hot.
Memory's nothing.
C'mon, memory's vital!
No way.
It's tough at first, only natural,
but then it all comes together.
Got a smoke?
I'm the same.
Know what?
I was scared at first too.
I really freaked out.
At first, I thought,
"Shit, this is too tough."
You think it comes naturally?
She freaked out at first.
She worked, learned her lines,
her moves. Now she's good.
Yeah, it's like she says,
it all comes together.
I was thinkin'...
Got a light?
Can you come over?
I have to go over my lines
but I don't understand them.
You see, I learn
but those lines are bastards.
Can you help me later?
Show me all the stuff you know.
The gestures and all that shit
to get into the character.
Tell him.
We're goin' to a concert, see.
- You are?
- Yeah, she can't come.
That's why.
Anyhow, there's no rush.
Besides, it's best to start
with the teacher.
She knows stuff.
If I give you advice too,
it'll mess up your head.
Jus' do what she tells you
to start off.
After, Inch'Allah, it'll work out.
She knows some crazy shit.
She's been on stage,
she's acted in musicals,
tragedies and all that.
Ask her for advice.
Lydia knows stuff
but not like the teacher does.
She can help you.
You need to listen to her first.
It's true. The teacher's a pro.
I dunno.
Gimme the lighter.
Why don't you ask Magali?
Why Magali?
She likes actin'.
She was in a play in sixth grade.
She's not busy, she can help you.
If you want advice, go see her.
Gimme the lighter.
I mean, don't start
by messin' your head up, okay?
- Your smoke.
- Gimme a break.
Put it out before we go in.
- Not there!
- Do I give a shit?
Your fuckin' sister!
- Ball-buster.
- Shut up!
Still got the tape?
I don't give a shit.
Fuck you, you faggots!
Don't say that.
Your sister said it was cool.
How's it goin'?
Magali! Come here.
What's goin' on with Krimo?
We split up.
What d'you mean?
It's over.
Sure, like usual:
You split up, you get back together.
- You say no?
- It's over for good.
Why d'you say that?
You had the big fight?
You wanna tell me why?
I never saw him no more.
He was doin'...
He was doin' weird shit.
Since when?
A long time.
I didn't even know.
He never told me.
I dunno, maybe he doesn't care.
He doesn't care?
He's always talkin' about you.
He does my head in with you.
And he don't care?
I dunno.
A homey, he tells me,
"I'm gonna take my woman
"on trips, buy her gifts,
all that shit..."
And you come tellin' me
he don't care...
No, stop sayin' that!
The guy does my head in with you.
He talks about you 24/7.
"That chick's one hot woman...
"She's one real hot woman and all.
"A once-in-a-lifetime chick."
I say, "Quit messin' your head up
with her."
Go see him, talk to him,
it'll do you good.
No, it'll be no use.
Somethin' must be botherin' him.
I didn't see him for a week either.
There's a reason he's stayin' away.
I dunno if you heard,
his old man's goin' on trial
and it's lookin' bad.
He has other shit in mind, I guess.
Don't worry.
Want me to talk to him?
I dunno.
You want me to talk to him or not?
Just say yes or no.
Well?
Yeah? I'll talk to him.
- I didn't send you.
- Okay.
See you.
All right, let's go.
Shut your mouth, I'm talkin'!
Ready?
Your turn. Relax.
Don't worry, it's your first time.
Take it slowly. Okay?
Off you go.
Any time...
Whenever you're ready.
Madame, he tells me...
He tells me to be patient.
He speaks most easily.
I find your impatience
most implausible.
It is mere gallantry
that you display here.
Love can't be so strong
so soon after being born!
You're mistaken, fair wonder,
such love soon leaves its cradle.
One look from you created it,
two made it strong
and three made it grow.
Take care of it
for you are its mother.
Just a second...
You know your lines.
That's good but...
you should try
to speak more clearly, okay?
You're rushing it.
Take your time.
Let's do it bit by bit.
Start again.
"You're mistaken, fair wonder..."
You're mistaken, fair wonder...
That's not what I said. Listen.
"You're mistaken, fair wonder..."
Any punctuation there?
What punctuation?
A comma.
Good, a comma. What do you do
in French after a comma?
You have to stop.
You pause.
A pause.
Start again.
"You're mistaken..."
You're mistaken, fair wonder,
such love soon leaves its cradle.
One look from you created it,
two made it strong
and three made it grow.
Lisette now.
"Is it mistreated..."
Is it mistreated, abandoned so?
For now, simply give it
your dainty hand
to amuse it a little.
Should we not show reason?
Reason? I have none!
Your eyes stole it.
That's almost it.
"Reason? I have lost it."
But that doesn't matter.
You know all the rest.
One thing, it's a bit glum.
Maybe you don't realize.
He's merry, he's lively,
he's in love.
She's beautiful,
so you need more joy, okay?
It needs more exuberance,
more happiness, okay? Less...
Can you manage that?
If you can, do it next time.
Work on it.
Hold on, I'm checkin' somethin'.
All right.
The audience is here
and the stage here.
These are the chairs.
You're not on stage yet.
You'll be on soon.
Okay, I'll explain.
Okay, you see, I'm on stage
and I'm fanning myself.
Then you come on
and I don't see you.
Let's go.
And now, my queen...
Hold on, you're too...
Stand like this.
They won't see you.
The audience is there, okay?
You have to get
that sort of reflex right away.
Try again.
Go on, start again.
Concentrate.
Focus on the character.
You're Arlequin, okay.
Go on.
- Know what'd be better?
- What?
You fake
like you don't see me either.
Back up.
You come on there.
I fake like I don't see you
but you don't either.
Arlequin doesn't see her.
I fan myself,
you look at the chandelier.
And then you come on, okay?
- Go on.
- What chandelier?
Any chandelier...
I dunno. You imagine one.
See that cloud?
Look at that
or at that tree there.
See where Momo lives?
Momo's place
is the chandelier, okay?
Imagine a chandelier
in your mind, okay?
Krimo, don't take forever!
And now, my queen, I stay
for I need your presence
yet you avoid mine.
Hold on, can you try somethin'?
Don't take it badly, okay.
I'll say it...
"And now, my queen, I stay
"for I need your presence..."
You act like you don't give a shit.
The guy's freakin' out, okay?
He's scared.
Show 'em you're scared.
Try to make it more...
I don't know, take your time...
Act like you...
See what I mean or not?
I told you to get
inside the character, so try, okay?
Let's start again.
And now, my queen, I stay
for I need your presence
yet you avoid mine.
I must admit, monsieur,
that was indeed true.
Sweet elixir of my heart...
Remember what I said?
- Who are you?
- Arlequin.
So what's he like? Merry.
Go on, you're Arlequin.
Look here.
"Sweet elixir of my heart,
"you wish for my demise?"
You're surprised.
Try "Sweet elixir..."
Act like you're surprised.
See what I mean? Go on.
Sweet elixir of my heart,
you wish for my demise?
It's good when you're surprised.
You put more energy into it.
Go on.
Sweet elixir of my heart,
you wish for my demise?
No, your life is precious to me.
Heartening words!
You must not doubt my feelings.
I would seize...
With Rachid,
after he said that,
Arlequin would sit down.
So when you say that, sit down.
There.
Go on.
I would seize those words
on your lips...
- That's wrong.
- "With my lips".
And Rachid would sit down
at that bit,
then Arlequin would move closer
and Lisette would shy away.
We did that and it worked.
Okay? Understand?
Go on.
I would seize those words
on your lips...
Not, "on your lips",
"with my lips".
You say, "on your lips".
You see the difference?
You have to move closer
or I can't shy away.
Go on.
I would seize those words
on your lips...
"With my lips"!
Same difference.
It's not the same!
Look.
"I would seize those words
"with my lips."
"With my lips" and "on your lips"
isn't the same.
The writer put "with my lips"
and we don't change it.
If you change stuff, I will too.
I'll say anything.
It's not possible. You see that?
Go on.
I would seize those words
with my lips.
Since your proposal,
I have awaited my father's reply.
I spoke to him
and I can tell you
that you may ask for my hand.
Before I ask him,
allow me to ask you.
I wish to pay tribute
to the kindness he shows...
You're mumblin' too much.
Forgotten it?
What's wrong?
What?
My fuckin' dress!
What came over you?
Nothin'!
I wanna go out with you,
that's all.
Well?
Will you?
I dunno.
I mean, I dunno.
I mean, I've known you forever.
I dunno, okay?
I never imagined this.
I didn't know you'd ask me that.
I thought we were homies.
I never expected you to ask that.
Well? Yes or no?
What about Magali?
- It's over.
- C'mon!
You know it's not...
- I wouldn't say it's over.
- It's over, okay.
I mean, I have to think.
I dunno.
What d'you mean?
I need to think, okay?
We can't rush into this.
Know what? I'm gonna head home.
I'll call you.
No, now, don't waste your credit.
I'll call you, okay?
- Okay?
- When'll you tell me?
I dunno. After I think it over.
You think I can tell you right now?
Not possible, brother.
I'll call you
when my head's straight.
I'll go now and tell you later.
I'm goin'.
Here she comes...
What's up?
Did it go well? Tell us.
Well, we rehearsed.
- Was it wicked?
- It was fine.
- Was it good?
- Yeah.
Tell us about it.
Tell you what?
We jus' did the scene, okay?
He said nothin' mystic, like?
Straight off!
You guys are depraved.
All he said was, "You're cute."
- No, I dodged him, okay.
- I smell a rat...
Are you crazy or what?
I thanked him and moved along.
We were rehearsin'.
We rehearsed.
What could he say?
I told him to finish the scene.
- You stopped him dead?
- No.
We finished the scene.
Any good?
In class, he was shit.
I'm here, okay.
- Bitch...
- It's true.
I'm jus' bein' honest.
Look, I was givin' him advice.
See what I mean?
He got better bit by bit.
- Bit by bit?
- Yeah, the more...
we rehearsed,
the better he got.
Inch'Allah, he'll get better
bit by bit, like.
- He'll be good.
- I hope so for you.
Inch'Allah, he'll be good in the end.
I'm headin' home, girls, I'm beat.
We'll come for you tomorrow.
See you, Lydia.
- Did you notice?
- That star attitude...
That's why I winked.
You got it.
- He didn't jus' say "You're cute."
- Right on.
He's had the guts to tell her,
that's a good start.
Hey, it's Krimo.
What's up, Krimo?
- Come on.
- I'm goin' to see dad.
Tell him "Hi".
I don't know
what's with Krimo these days.
He's hot for a chick.
Magali? There's trouble there.
What're you talkin' about?
Magali?
- That's ancient history.
- What?
He's hot for Lydia.
She's flat as a board!
- Who's she?
- A chick in my class.
He's dead hot for her.
I heard something about Krimo.
He's wicked hot for a chick.
He's all lovey-dovey.
Who is she?
She's in my class,
flat as a board, no tits,
no ass, nada.
A piece of shit.
She's dead plain
and does this actin' shit,
just like Krimo too now.
Hold on, run that by me again.
He's actin' now, Krimo is.
I promise you.
Shut your mouth, okay,
you don't talk shit like that.
I swear he's actin' now,
you think I'm lyin'?
You don't believe me?
They do actin',
old-style, Middle Ages stuff.
He's in disguise too,
dressed like a fag.
A real fag!
That Lydia's a real clown too.
They do
all that hand-kissing' shit.
He kisses her like this,
bends to kiss her hand. Crazy!
What a sucker. Forget him.
Why you sayin' this?
It's the truth, he's hot for her.
He's dead hot for her,
he'd get down on all fours for her.
In class, he don't see
nobody but her.
You call him and he don't reply.
He's hot for her.
That ho's turned his brain.
Yeah, it's like he's blind,
not seein' anythin'.
When I'm in class, I see them.
He's a desperate case.
What are we gonna do?
I mean...
Forget it.
He's hot for her, okay.
She hot for him?
Know what?
Truth is, I don't think so.
She's got him by the balls
but she's not hot for him.
If she was hot,
she wouldn't put him through that.
He falls for everythin'.
He's acting all la-de-da.
God knows why.
It drives me wild.
No, forget the chandelier, please.
She's beautiful,
you've missed her...
The chandelier's beautiful
but you don't see it.
And now, my queen, I stay
for I need your presence
yet you avoid mine.
Another chandelier?
It's just you're looking
at your feet now. Look at her.
Go on.
And now, my queen, I stay
for I need your presence
yet you avoid mine.
I must admit, monsieur,
that was indeed true.
Heartening words!
"Sweet elixir of my heart..."
Sweet elixir of my heart,
you wish for my demise?
No, your life is precious to me.
Heartening words!
- You're doing it on purpose!
- What?
You're reeling off the lines
without conviction.
"Heartening words!"
We've been over this.
- From the top?
- No.
"I must admit..."
I must admit, monsieur,
that was indeed true.
Sweet elixir of my heart...
Keep your eyes on her then,
not on the audience.
"I must admit that was true,
I was avoiding you."
"Did you no longer wish to see me?"
Start again.
Sweet elixir of my heart,
you wish for my demise?
No, your life is precious to me.
Heartening words!
Have fun!
That's all I can tell you.
Have fun! This is funny.
There's a happy mood, see.
He's disguised as a master
with all that means:
Someone with power in other words.
Try to play someone with power,
try to show off!
Put more energy into it!
You see what I mean?
Try to reach something else.
Leave yourself
to reach a new language.
He's aping someone.
Can you see how important
the language is?
Arlequin is mimicking a master!
Go on, make an effort!
From the top?
"I must admit..." Go on.
Stop turning to me
to see what to do.
I must admit, monsieur,
that was indeed true.
Sweet elixir of my heart,
you wish for my demise?
No, your life is precious to me.
- Heartening...
- More!
More...
Are you having fun?
Are you enjoying this?
Yes...
You have to enjoy the fact
of leaving yourself behind.
Leave yourself!
Have fun, find the pleasure in it.
Change your language,
the way you speak or move...
Have fun!
Where from?
"My father", just before the hand.
Since your proposal,
I have awaited my father's reply.
I spoke to him
and I can tell you
that you may ask for my hand.
Before I ask him,
allow me to ask you.
I wish to pray tribute
to the kindness...
...pay tribute
to the kindness
of which I am unworthy...
Of which...
Kiss that hand, let yourself go!
You see what I mean?
Just kiss it!
Her hand's beautiful.
Touch it, it's fantastic!
You thought you'd lost her!
Kiss it, have fun!
Give yourself!
Start again.
I'm sorry, start again.
Start again. Come on.
Make an effort.
Fuck me!
It's dead today, huh?
What's up with Magali?
It's over.
Fuck, you screwed up there.
She was way sweet.
What came over you?
She was cute.
We had a good laugh with her.
She had real respect for you.
When she went out, you knew
she wasn't into any shit.
It sucks.
Know what I imagined?
I saw us on a sailboat
with your babies,
sailing round the world.
It sucks. You see...
You shouldn't have.
Got anyone else?
You're sure? Nobody?
I heard you were hot for a chick,
on your knees to her,
doin' actin' like a fag.
Not anymore.
Can't you see
you're gettin' yourself a shit rep?
Hey, Krimo,
you're my homey, okay.
I've got you in mind,
I won't let you get fucked up.
Goin' out with her?
No, I asked her
but she needs to think.
What for?
She has to think.
Who the hell does she think she is?
Normally, you go see a chick
and ask her.
If she's hot for you,
she gives you an answer.
How long does she need
to give a reply?
Stay with her, you're fucked.
She'll jinx you.
I've warned you.
Shoulda stayed with Magali.
She's a straight chick at least.
I respected her, I swear.
You fuckin' joker!
You wished to complain about me.
For what reason?
What can I say?
My anger will be unreserved.
She believes so.
You may tell her of their bond.
I'll see to the rest.
We have nothing more
to say to each other.
Ah, my dear...
Okay?
Last time, I waited for you.
No sense in waitin', then.
We waited. You could've come.
Never mind.
Me, you and Marianne.
I dunno yet.
What's your problem?
Your friend.
What friend? Gimme that!
You know, that ho Lydia.
Watch what you're sayin'!
She's a ho, okay.
What's your problem?
- Back off!
- Watcha doin'?
What? Gimme my cell back!
You're crazy!
What is this shit?
This shit?
That ho's drivin' my homey crazy.
I mean Krimo.
Who gives a shit about Krimo?
Why you shoutin'?
It's not my problem, okay!
What's it got to do with me?
You're her friend, that's what.
Yeah, I'm her friend. So what?
- So what?
- So you can talk to her.
Krimo's old enough
to settle it himself.
He's not, he needs me.
I don't give a shit
about her or him!
I thought he was with Magali!
- Shut your mouth.
- Sure! Gimme my cell!
He split with Magali for that ho!
- Who says she's a ho?
- Fuck that.
- Just tell her...
- Screw you!
Gimme back my cell, okay!
You want your cell back,
you listen to me.
Gimme the phone, then we can talk!
You're pushin' it too far,
mouthin' off like this!
This thing's between them.
- What is this?
- Why're you yellin'?
'Cause I want my fuckin' cell back!
Stop it, please.
You gonna stop me yellin'?
Back off!
Quit mouthin' off.
Gimme my cell!
- I'll get my big brother.
- Quit yellin'!
My big brother'll nail you,
motherfucker!
My big brother'll waste you!
What's your problem?
He'll do what?
He'll nail you, motherfucker!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Back off, okay,
or I'll get really pissed!
Fuckin' let go!
Shut your mouth!
Fuckin' let go, muhfuh!
- Quit yellin'.
- Fuckin' let go!
Quit yellin'. Listen to me.
You and your friends carry on,
I'll fuckin' waste you.
It's not my fuckin' problem, okay?
You're crazy. Quit yellin'.
- What's your game?
- My game?
Let go of my hand.
Fuckin' let go of my hand!
Know what you're gonna do?
Go see that filthy ho
and tell her I'll waste her
unless she backs off my homey.
I don't give a shit. Let go!
Chill or I'll clock you.
I'm blowin' a fuse too.
She's there, teasin' him...
- You know the ho I mean?
- I know!
- I'll go see her, okay!
- Sure?
I know who!
Go see her and get her reply.
I hear you, now let go!
- Another?
- Let go, I'll tell her!
You better
or I swear I'll waste you.
Okay! Let go now!
Watch it or I'll fuck you over.
Fuckin' let go of me!
Fuck off! Keep away from me!
Gimme my cell!
Gimme my fuckin' cell, you shit!
You fuckin' joker!
Not till I get the reply.
The reply?
You're fuckin' kiddin'!
Fuck you,
fuckin' faggot motherfucker!
Fuckin' scumbag!
Nanou!
Didn't you hear me?
What's up? Catch your breath.
That asshole came and attacked me!
He pounced on me!
- Who?
- That bastard!
That fucker comes askin'
if I know Lydia. I say yes
and he says to tell her
to stop windin' his homey Krimo up.
He says he wants a reply.
Do I give a toss?
I didn't know what to do.
I kept tellin' him to keep back.
- But then he slapped me!
- Who? Who d'you mean?
Fathi, that tall fucker
who lives in B7, Krimo's homey!
He's gone too fuckin' far!
A guy who beats a chick
is no real guy.
He snatches my cell,
flings me to the ground,
starts slappin' me
and stranglin' me and all!
I couldn't even move!
- He fuckin' beat me up!
- Why'd he do it?
'Cause of that fuckin' cunt Lydia!
He asked her to go out or somethin'.
I didn't understand a thing.
That bitch plays the slut
and I pay!
She had to give a reply to Krimo
or somethin'.
He was beatin' me
and that's all I understood.
She's pushin' it,
she hassles and you get hit.
You said it.
Why's Fathi into their shit?
I told him if it was their problem,
to go see Lydia.
He threatened me. He said
if she doesn't answer Krimo fast,
- he'll fuck us over.
- Come on.
No, he beat it, he's gone.
He snatched my cell.
He took my fuckin' new cell!
My dad and brother'll hit the roof.
He'll ask where it is.
I'm in the shit here!
And he won't give it back
"till she gives her reply," he says.
What am I gonna do or say now?
My dad and my brother
are gonna hit the fuckin' roof!
What'll you do?
What can I do?
I'm gonna see that slut Lydia.
Let's go, then.
I don't get my cell
till she answers him.
She's gonna answer
or I'll slap the bitch!
And I'll set my big brother
on the fucker.
Lydia!
- Is that you?
- Yeah, what's up?
Come down.
Nano's here too.
Get down here!
Later, I'm workin' now.
No, right now!
Right now? Mom won't let me.
I don't give a shit!
Get down here!
Cool it, okay.
We're waitin' here!
I'm comin' down.
What? I came on too strong?
You lay into her on the intercom!
I should be nice? I got attacked!
Don't lay into her straight off.
You won't, okay?
That's settled, then.
You freaked me out,
yellin' like that.
What's up?
Ask her.
What's goin' on?
The shit you bring me!
What's up with her? What is it?
Her cell got robbed jus' now.
Chill, okay.
I got mugged 'cause of you.
Explain instead of saying that.
That clown Fathi attacked me.
He slapped me about,
tried to strangle me and all.
He said you screwed Krimo up,
that he's gone weird.
He kept hittin' and slappin' me!
What's this to do with me?
You got me a beatin', shithead!
Quit layin' into me!
She almost died 'cause of you.
'Cause of me? Come on...
That's right!
It's not my fault. I did nothin'.
You did nothin'?
Sure, nothin'!
You sure?
Tell me what I did.
You wind him up, turn him on.
Sure, you did nothin'.
Go on, you tell her.
You slut... Nothin'?
Watch your mouth!
You string the guy along
and who takes the rap? She does!
- It wasn't me!
- Shut it!
You say you're not hot for him
then you drag him around, you slut.
- Bitch!
- Watch it.
You turn the guy on
at every rehearsal,
then you say you did nothin'!
She's right. He started actin'
for your sakes.
Did I ask him?
Shut your mouth.
Krimo asked you out, right? Tell us.
He asked you out. Fuckin' answer!
Yeah, I guess so.
Did he ask you or not?
He asked but I didn't answer yet.
You slut, look at you.
Not even straight with us.
You never said.
You could've fuckin' told us!
Not even me, your homey.
It's not that. The fucker asked me.
I didn't reply.
Should I tell the hood?
We're not the hood.
I'm your homey, she is too.
We're the hood?
We're other people?
So, are you hot for him or not?
D'you wanna go out with him
or not?
D'you want to or not?
It's your decision.
Yes or no?
But Magali...
Magali's no excuse,
stop dodgin' the issue.
Go there and tell him yes or no.
We can't take a beatin' for you.
Think it's funny, bitch?
Fathi comes hasslin' me,
I get mugged 'cause of you...
Scared of Magali?
The hell I'm scared of her!
So?
She's hot for him.
You jus' want him gaspin' for you.
I'm not heartless.
Call that bitch Magali.
Let's get this settled right now.
- I'm outta credit...
- Jus' call her, please.
And get my cell back for me, slut.
- Shut up!
- Watch your mouth.
What's goin' on?
You givin' up on Krimo?
Why? What's up?
Krimo's not somethin'
you bought, okay?
He can be hot for another chick.
If he does, if she's straight,
you don't apply
the hassle and threats.
It ain't fuckin' right.
I don't make threats, okay!
I love Krimo and he loves me.
It'll always be that way.
Fuck, can't you see?
How often have we broken up?
What happens?
We get back together.
Who broke up? Was it him?
No, I broke up.
You'll get together?
Yeah, like always,
we always have done.
We didn't break up,
we're takin' a breather.
We give each other time to breathe,
then get back.
A permanent breather.
If he's hot for you,
why's he askin' her out?
He asked you?
Yeah, but I didn't answer.
You didn't answer...
What'll you tell him?
Actually, I dunno. We'll see.
What d'you mean?
We'll see.
I knew anyhow.
You knew what?
I knew, that's all.
Stop thinkin' I came on to him.
Sure.
I didn't, okay.
Maybe he wants to fuck her.
Save your crazy ideas, girl!
Hold on, his homey, Fathi,
came and beat me up.
He gave me all this crazy hassle.
He said my girl Lydia
isn't straight with Krimo,
she's makin' him crazy.
She has to give him
a fuckin' answer.
You say he's hot for you
but he asked her.
It stops here, it's over, curtains.
Give up, girl, stop.
He doesn't love you no more!
He doesn't want you.
Know what? Give him an answer.
Tell him what you want.
I don't give a toss anymore.
He can drop dead for all I care.
Dumb bitch!
Goddamn slut.
That girl gets my back up bad.
Leave her, she acts cool
but she's dead hot for him.
Sure...
Forget her.
Screw that.
- Come on.
- Where to?
Surprise.
- Where're we goin'?
- Surprise, okay.
- What is this shit?
- Don't worry.
What're they doin' here?
I told Lydia to be here.
To sort this thing out.
What?
- You did that?
- Chill.
You fucker!
- Chill, okay.
- Forget it!
- You'll get your answer.
- So what?
Fuck...
Come here, please.
- What do I do?
- I dunno.
- Don't drop me in this shit.
- We'll come too.
I don't know what to do.
Come on, move.
This whole thing's
startin' to piss me off.
Me too.
Know what? We'll go see a homey
and have a drink.
Meanwhile,
you sort things out with him.
Get in.
Okay, Krimo?
Only Lydia, I said.
What?
Only Lydia.
Hold on, I'm Lydia.
That's her.
That's me.
- You could've said.
- Did I know?
- Get out.
- Okay.
Bustin' my balls...
Violence straight off, no style.
Get in, we need to talk.
Get in the car.
We're gonna sort this out, okay.
Get out, please.
Get out!
Let them fuckin' talk!
- Let them discuss this.
- You get out too.
Fuck, give 'em time to talk.
You're here, so we're here too.
Give us a break.
Will you get out?
You won't?
Go on.
Okay, I'm gettin' out.
What's this girl shit?
Let these people talk together.
Loser!
What's up?
They're gettin' out, so am I.
Leave me be.
Hands off! What're you doin'?
They're gettin' out,
so let me out too.
You stay in the car, okay?
Get in, sort this thing out.
- Gently, asshole!
- Let her go!
Let me out!
You're hurtin' me.
Let 'em talk for fuck's sake!
You won't let other people talk?
You're fuckin' kids!
You're the kid, Mr. Violence.
You're crazy. Jus' who are you?
Get back in the car.
Stop bustin' their balls.
Leave 'em be, brother.
I thought you wanted an answer.
I'm not gettin' in alone.
Know what? You two get in
and we'll wait over there.
I'm not goin' with you.
C'mon, it's okay.
I'm stayin' with Lydia.
Cut it out!
C'mon, move.
What's this hassle you're givin' me?
I swear, I didn't know.
Here you go.
- What'll she say?
- My guess is yes.
She'd have said that ages ago.
I say no.
No, I know her.
Shut the fuck up, okay?
You can't wait
to hear the answer too.
- I don't give a toss.
- So why're you here?
- For my homey.
- Drop dead!
Have you done thinkin'?
Say somethin'...
You think I can think?
I can't think!
Look at all this!
Can I get my head straight?
Everyone's hasslin' me!
I've been gettin' this non-stop
since you asked.
Everyone's pissin' me off,
tryin' to get me to give an answer.
Do I get time to think?
I can't,
I'm under all this pressure!
Magali keeps pissin' me off.
She's always goin' on,
makin' out
I'm some kinda slut!
They all step up the pressure.
My homey says I'm not straight!
Know what I hear every day?
"Be straight. Answer him."
I'm fuckin' sick of it!
It's too much pressure.
I can't take it.
It's not over for her.
It's not over.
It's easy to say Magali's over
but she comes pissin' me off.
Until it's over, she'll keep on
causin' me hassle and all.
Do they piss you off?
They make me out to be a slut!
They say I came on to you.
She says my stage dress's neckline
is too low!
That you're actin' for me.
- She took his hand.
- No shit?
I need time to think, see.
I can't think like this.
It's no use?
Is it?
You must know if...
You must...
Please...
Fuck, the pigs.
Stay calm, okay.
I smell smoke.
The registration, please.
- The registration.
- We don't have it.
Get out!
Let's see your hands.
Raise your arms.
- It's not our car.
- See my colleague.
- Whose is it?
- Nobody's.
- Who asked you?
- I'm just explainin'.
- No dangerous items?
- It's not ours.
Your pockets.
- What were you doing?
- Talkin'.
You don't know?
- Your pockets...
- Can I explain?
- Is it stolen?
- No, we found it here.
Empty your pockets.
Come on, make it snappy.
We were all together, like...
and we were...
We were together, out walkin',
and we came by here...
We were hangin' out, like,
and at one point... we got here.
And since they wanted to talk...
- Who?
- Lydia.
Hands on the hood.
Talk about what?
A deal?
- Who?
- The blonde in the car.
Get her out.
Come here, you.
They wanted to talk.
What's her name?
She wanted to talk to him.
No dangerous items?
What about?
Somethin' private.
Empty your pockets out.
Romantic shit.
Somethin' personal.
Is this yours?
Is that it?
You just found it?
That's right.
That's it, ma'am.
All right.
I'm clean.
Just checking.
This isn't yours.
I dunno. It's not mine.
You're sure? Know what it is?
Hands on the hood.
I said it's not our car.
- Can I go on, sir?
- I'm listening.
- What then?
- Hurry it up!
We came down the street.
The car was unlocked.
I told them to get inside to talk
to get outta the cold.
That's everything?
I doubt it.
I knew it. What's this?
When I say empty them,
you empty them!
What's this here?
What is it?
What're you hiding in there?
I said empty your pockets, okay!
D'you understand what I say?
Answer me!
Hands on the hood!
Sir, we're not hoodlums.
Shut your mouth.
Hands on the hood.
Got anything left?
Don't move, you!
Keep your hands there.
Don't move!
Let go of me!
You're giving me orders?
Fuckin' calm down.
Watch your mouth, you.
Telling us what to do, fucker?
What is it now? Go on, talk.
It hurts, huh?
What're you going to do now, huh?
What'll you do?
Shut it, okay!
No one asked you, so shut it!
Shut your mouth, okay,
just keep it shut, you hear?
Your hands behind your back, I said!
Fucker!
Fucker? Gimme your hands!
We'll see who's the fucker now.
- What's that? Who's the fucker?
- You are.
You really want a beating?
You'll get it!
That hurts!
I don't give a shit!
- Want another?
- Shut your mouth!
Okay, tell me,
who's the fucker now?
You are, you little shit.
Let go of me!
- Let go of me, okay!
- It's okay.
Let go of me!
This one's wild.
All right, let's see those birds
beat their wings.
One day, all the birds in the world
came together
for a big conference.
Ray of Hope took the floor.
Dear birds, you do nothing
but quarrel and fight.
This cannot go on.
Listen to me, we have a king.
A king?
We've had many kings before.
Why do we need another?
Just a second.
The one I'm talking about
is the true king.
His name is Simorgue.
Let us seek him out.
Let us seek him out!
Hey, girls...
Is it packed?
Quiet, my little brother's on.
Wicked.
Guess who I jus' saw, the bitch.
- Incredible.
- Who?
- It's crazy.
- Tell us.
Magali in Omar's arms,
isn't that crazy shit?
- Magali?
- Yeah, at the back on the left.
- Sittin' there, kissin'.
- Which Omar?
Halima's brother, straight up.
- Cut it out!
- On my mother's life.
- That's crazy!
- On my grandmother's grave.
- No shit!
- She's in his arms.
They're watchin'.
C'mon, you're imaginin' it.
On the Koran!
She's still hot for Krimo...
It's true! You think I'm crazy?
See for yourselves.
- Let's see.
- Quiet, my little brother's on.
At the back on the left.
Quietly...
Let's return to our search.
The patient must be very patient.
- What do you seek?
- I seek my path.
I'm seeking everywhere
to find it one day.
Gently...
Gently with the wings.
Show us the path
for we have crossed the 7 valleys.
You have crossed nothing.
Those valleys were a dream.
We are still in the same place.
The birds lowered their heads.
Some died,
just a few reached their goal.
Abdelkrim!
We've made a long journey
just to reach ourselves.
I hope my voice won't shake.
Why take it upon yourself
to answer for my feelings?
I believed
your feelings were like
any other woman's.
Your father asks
if you are pleased to be married,
if it brings you joy.
I told him that yes,
it was obvious.
You must be the only woman alive
for whom "yes" is not true.
Refusal is not natural.
Refusal is not natural?
How naively silly!
Marriage holds
a certain charm for you.
There too, I answer, "Yes".
Be silent!
Take your impertinence elsewhere.
It is not for you
to judge my heart with yours.
My heart is made like any other.
If it were to dare,
it would call me original.
Tell me, who are you
to speak like this?
The son of a poor soldier.
I heartily wish you
a better situation than this one
and would like to help you.
Fate has mistreated you.
In truth, love has done more harm.
I would prefer
being granted your heart
to all the world's riches.
Is it mistreated, abandoned so?
For now, simply give it
your dainty hand
to amuse it a little.
Here, you little pest,
perhaps I'll find peace now.
Plaything of my soul...
This is as sweet as a fine wine.
How sad
I only have the dregs.
Come, come!
Stop that!
You're too skilled.
I wish merely to get by
while waiting to live.
Should we not show reason?
Reason? I have none!
Your crafty eyes
stole it away from me.
Can you possibly love me so?
I find it hard to believe.
I do not care if it's possible.
I love you like a lost soul.
Your mirror shows it.
My mirror heightens my disbelief.
Oh, sweet beauty.
Is your humility
a mere hypocrite?
Your dowry outweighed you once.
Now you put it to shame.
Come now, jump, marquis!
Published 28/02/2014
@ www.podnapisi.net