One of the key dynamics
propelling everybody forward
in season 2 is
"power abhors a vacuum".
Power resides where men believe it resides.
All these different kings
are vying for the throne
because they see in the wake
of Robert Baratheon's death,
a chance to seize power.
Joffrey, Renly, Robb Stark...
they'll bend the knee
or I'll destroy them.
Season 2 is really
building towards a massive battle.
Loose!
Sync by honeybunny
Script by honeybunny & chamallow
www.addic7ed.com
We're in a Council meeting
and then, out of nowhere,
comes her favorite brother,
Tyrion.
I come in with a note from Daddy,
that I'm being appointed
the Hand of the King in his absence.
- What do you know about warfare?
- Nothing.
But I know that our enemies hate each other
almost as much as they hate us.
In the throne room scene, Joffrey
prods to this,
into a certain curiosity that's been born
in my mind.
I heard a disgusting line about
Uncle Jaime and you.
What you just did,
is punishable by death.
She's got not an ounce
of control over her son
and that's horrifying to her.
King in the North.
In episode one, we have this nice little
scene between Robb and-and Jaime.
Stannis Baratheon sent ravens
towards the high lords of Westeros.
King Joffrey Baratheon is your bastard son.
That's the first time we see Jaime
a little worried.
At the beginning of season 2,
Catelyn is with Robb,
and Sansa and Arya she hopes are safe
in King's Landing.
You need to answer for your brother's
latest treasons.
This is a poor girl, whose father
was executed,
she's sort of been left alone
with this monster.
Joffrey does it very publicly.
He's not afraid to show
how he's treating Sansa.
But because he rules by fear,
no one's gonna speak out about it.
What is the meaning of this?
She's to be your queen.
Have you no regard for her honour?
Tyrion is the only one that speaks out
against Joffrey
because he kind of can.
I'm looking for a boy named Gendry.
We'll be back. With more men.
I'm with Yoren on our way to Night's Watch.
But hopefully, Yoren is gonna try
and drop me home on the way there.
What did the Gold Cloaks want with you?
No idea. I thought
they were after you. Why?
Did you kill someone or is it just
because you're a girl?
- I'm not a girl.
- You think I'm as stupid as the rest of them?
Bran and Rickon
are still at Winterfell with Maester Luwin.
Every night is the same.
Running through the Godswood,
sniffing the dirt, howling...
These are dreams, nothing more.
My dreams are different. Mine are true.
Dany is in a much more somber place
than where we left
in the end of season 1.
Does it ever end?
Everything ends, even the Red Waste.
So I took it upon myself to send
my Dothraki off to try and find a place
that we could try and survive.
The one Dothraki that did come back,
came back with
tales of a paradise
in the middle of the desert,
that was intrigued by the idea of dragons.
I will vouch for her, her people
and her dragons.
Welcome to Qarth, my lady.
Season 2 begins with Jon
travelling north of the wall.
He's travelling north with the other
members of the Night's Watch,
the Lord Commander, and his friends,
Sam and Grenn.
The Night's Watch stop at a rather
horrible man's house, called Craster.
He's a quite despicable character.
He marries his daughters
and they give him more daughters.
Sam does the one thing he shouldn't do,
which is to fall in love with one
of Craster's wives, Gilly.
I wanted to give you something.
It belonged to my mother.
Keep it safe for me,
till I come back.
One thing we definitely need
if we're going to take King's Landing,
is ships.
Robb thinks the best move
would be to send Theon back to his father.
Catelyn's always had
an issue with the Greyjoys.
You don't want Balon Greyjoy
for an ally.
I need his ships.
They say he has two hundred.
Theon goes off with these good intentions,
but when he gets back home,
he gets turned against me.
My fears have come true.
The Starks have made you theirs.
Robb sent Catelyn to Renly's camp
to persuade Renly to join Robb.
Renly and Stannis are both fighting
to be king.
The Iron Throne is mine!
No one wants you for their king.
Stannis is obviously next in line,
but Stannis is not
gonna join the side.
Melisandre is a character
who arrives in season 2.
She believes in other gods.
You must give yourself
to the Lord of Light.
I've said the words!
Events take a sudden turn,
when Catelyn is in the tent,
trying to talk to Renly.
He is stabbed by some form of evil spirit
which has been conjured up
by Melisandre.
Afraid that she is actually
going to get accused of this murder,
Catelyn flees with Brienne.
In the name of King Joffrey,
drop your weapons.
I don't think I will.
When Yoren goes down, that's
when everything starts to get a bit scary.
Sweet boy, help us!
She already knows that's something
a bit strange about Jaqen.
And she sees the axe and she gives him
the axe and just leaves them to get out.
Round up any survivors!
We take them back to Harrenhal.
They are just focusing on staying alive
and that's probably the worst place to be
if you wanted to stay alive.
Unknowingly,
Tywin Lannister sort of saves Arya.
Get these prisoners to work.
Bring the girl. I need a new cup bearer.
Look.
The Fist of the First Men is where
they're gonna meet Qhorin Halfhand,
who wants to go on a ranging mission,
to find out what the wildlings are doing.
I need to move fast, and silent.
There's wildlings up on the pass,
Qhorin wants to go and
find out what Mance Rayder
is planning to do.
He's left to kill one of the wildlings,
Ygritte, who he doesn't kill.
When Sam and Grenn are digging through
the snow at the Fist of the First Men,
they find dragonglass.
We're not quite sure what the significance
of dragonglass is,
but it's a curious thing to find
buried underneath the
Fist of the First Men.
The Wolf Pup has gone south.
The North is ripe for the taking.
Theon completely betrays me,
and not only me, but my whole family.
As any child, any boy would want,
he wants his father's approval.
They attack Winterfell
and they decimate it.
I've yielded Winterfell to Prince Theon.
Betray me and you will wish you hadn't.
Mother of Dragons.
It would be an honour to host you
at the House of the Undying.
The Qartheen people only wanted one thing,
and that was my dragons.
And that began the theme
throughout season 2 for Dany,
which is the fact
that she couldn't trust anyone.
It's a pretty horrific bloody scene
that I return to.
And the dragons are gone.
Where are my dragons?
The plan all along was,
Pyat Pree and Xaro Xhoan Daxos
would steal my dragons, and rule.
You have my dragons.
I will take you to the
House of the Undying,
where I have put them.
You let a halfwit escape with a cripple.
And Rickon too, the little one.
Theon basically turns his back,
completely on our family.
I told you what would happen
if you serve me loyally.
And what would happen if you did not.
No!
He's really stabbed me
in the back completely.
Got as far as the farm,
then doubled-back.
Must have been the farmer's boys.
Killed them, burned them, and passed
them off as the little lords.
Fate is giving us this chance to...
You've lost your mind! Get out!
The Lannisters are
desperate to get Jamie back.
So, Littlefinger deceives Catelyn.
Both girls are healthy and safe, for now.
He says to her, if you give us Jamie,
the Lannisters will return
your two girls to you.
He's been a captive for a long time.
He killed Lord Karstark's
son when he escaped.
Kingslayer won't last a night.
Come.
When he meets Brienne the first time,
he's never seen anyone like that.
Is that a woman?
It's kind of the beginning
of a remarkable relationship.
Catelyn frees him, and instructs
Brienne to get him to King's Landing.
Now he can't carry out his duties
as a king because
he'd have to kill his own mother,
and he's not going to do that,
so it makes him look weak.
You saved me, and the two I was with.
- Speak three names.
- I can name anyone, and you'll kill him?
She's a little bit skeptical about it.
But when the Tickler turns out to be
dead, that's when she's like...
this guy is a good sort of contact to have.
Stannis two days from the capital,
and the Wolf at my doorstep.
We'll ride at nightfall.
She asks Jaqen to kill Tywin.
- I need him dead right now.
- This a man cannot do.
Give a name. Any name.
She decides to turn it around
a little bit.
Jaqen H'ghar.
A girl gives a man his own name.
I'll unname you, if you help me
and my friends escape.
If he's not gonna kill Tywin,
then she's gonna make him kill more
than one person to help them escape.
I don't want to marry the Frey girl.
This woman has the potential
to break the vow
that Catelyn made to
Walder Frey.
I don't need to marry you.
Walder Frey is a man you do not mess with.
- I am hers and she is mine.
- I am his and he is mine.
We die today, brothers.
Aye!
They kill men that Theon grew up with.
Let's go home.
They destroy Winterfell.
They burned it down, everything.
What she doesn't know and she finds out it isn't,
her two youngest are still alive. (***)
They may come back. Go north, to the Wall,
to Jon.
What do you think they'll say
when they hear about you and me?
Nothing happened between you and me.
She's very wily,
Ygritte, she mocks him and
mocks him and mocks him.
And you think she's just doing
this for her own fun.
But actually, she's playing the long game.
You should have took me
while you had the chance.
When Jon becomes a captive
of the wildlings,
he discovers that Qhorin Halfhand
has been captured as well.
Halfhand realizes that the only good
that can come out of this
is one of them becoming a spy amongst
Mance Rayder's camp.
- They'll never trust me.
- They might.
- If you do what needs to be done.
- What?
Come along, Jon Snow.
Time to meet the King Beyond the Wall.
If my dragons are
in the House of the Undying,
then take me there.
That's what the warlock wants.
It's here that I walk into unknown magic.
- This magic is strong.
- And what of my magic?
And she is tested with everything
that means the most to her.
Khaleesi!
Stannis Baratheon is coming for us.
Sooner rather than later.
Tyrion and Cersei have a lot in common.
And I think that's why
they're at such odds with each other.
They are going to attack us.
We need to be ready.
The king is taking personal
charge of siege preparations.
If the wind holds,
we'll reach King's Landing in a day.
Will it hold?
I can't make promises for the wind,
Your Grace.
They say Stannis never smiles.
I'll give him a red smile.
The threat from Stannis is the
most terrifying for Joffrey.
And the most real I suppose.
Mud Gate. That's where he'll land.
If Stannis does attack the Mud Gate,
what is our plan?
There's all this wildfire down
in the basement's basement.
He gets together with this pyromancer
and figures out a way to stop them.
When Joffrey realizes that
the whole fleet hasn't been destroyed,
you see that
he's most certainly a coward.
They're coming ashore. They're too many.
The Hound goes out there, and he
realizes they're outnumbered.
Half the men that arrive on the shore
are burning.
That's the one fear of the Hound.
He doesn't do fire,
and all it takes is one burning man
running towards you.
When the Hound comes back in
from the fighting
he abandons the king.
And that is a massive blow to Joffrey.
He just bolts and leaves the
responsibility to Tyrion.
Those are brave men knocking at
our door. Let's go kill them!
I get pretty banged up.
It could have been worse though.
My squire, Podrick, saves me.
And then Father comes in. Saves the
day so he gets all the recognition.
The king won't give you any honours.
But we will not forget.
With the great aid
the Tyrells gave to the battle,
the deal was struck
to marry Margaery to Joffrey.
Cersei thinks she's won,
because she's gonna upset Sansa.
She couldn't be happier,
and then Littlefinger
kind of crushes her hopes.
If he's not marrying me...
He'll let you go home? Joffrey's not the
sort of boy who gives away his toys.
Welcome home, Daenerys Stormborn.
My home is across the sea,
where my people are waiting.
They'll be waiting a long time.
He thinks that he's got her, but of course,
the dragons, they'd learnt
how to breathe fire.
Dracarys!
Jon hasn't returned when he should
to the Fist of the First Men
and Sam's getting nervous.
It's Jon and the Halfhand. They're back!
At the end of season 2, we leave Sam
in a rather perilous situation.
Two blasts is wildlings.
And three horns
is White Walkers.
Run!
Sync by honeybunny
Script by honeybunny & chamallow
www.addic7ed.com