Not you know to where you are going.
Yes I know it.
Not you know where you are.
I mean, veto the devil.
Only enter to the car, you are not able to
to walk the whole route.
Was this your election?
Not it was my election mom.
You want to live with that old dog that neither
though you understand and I not even know.
If you love me outside of your life,
I will be outside of your life.
You are impossible.
It seems that in any way we will return
to have the life that we had.
I am fed up with this shit.
Is what you not want?
Then I am outside of your life.
Nobody is requesting that.
I am outside of your life.
Then please...
veto of my life
- I leave
How good, veto.
THE RULE DE GEORGIA
Hello.
who are you?
He/she hears I didn't make anything.
Calm down
Oh God, you belong to those perverts.
He/she looks, I didn't make anything.
Please help me
- Are you crazy?
-No.
I Am Rachel.
I Am Harlan Wilson.
I found you playing my breast.
That was not my intention.
Then, which was it?
To see if you were dead.
Problems with the car Harlan?
Oh, I like this.
it is new
can I manage?
do you know it?
I found it sleeping to the side of the track
ok goes!
their name is Rachel
ok
it seems that now it is safe
now it is all yours
I work again
he/she hears
thank you for the aventón
but good
it has been a strange form
of picking up me
how do you call yourself?
Simón
in fact I don't have destination
the same as me
to where?
to any place
he/she went alone
good I believe that no longer ,
you are very lucky
it would consider this way me,
if you were not here
good we go or we will stay here
I don't like to speak
perfect, I don't like to neither listen
you could lower your feet inside
of my car?
oh, you change the rules
in fact there are not rules
only it is not good that some part of l
body of somebody estéfuera of l car
then I can speak to you?
it lowers your feet
you didn't say " Simón says... "
Simón
I am going to Hull
oh in Idaho, is there to where I go
what luck!
and you will call to somebody or you will arrive him/her
of surprise?
good, it is supposed that my mom would call me
how boring!
don't make that
he/she had mentioned it to you
you cannot hide letters
neither to show them
everything and l world play this way
we can make it
then if all
they make any thing you
you accept it, only because
they say that it is correct
probably yes
me due him my leg
one hears it cannot leave
they hurt me my arthritis, I cannot remain
in this position for a lot of time
to leave? did I say to leave?
I won!
oh
mom!
he/she hears, you cannot leave, to go is bad
hello
you are not mom?
oh
seriously?
oh please happens
oh
we go, help me to stop
to her they hurt him/her the muscles and
we should understand him/her
where is Rachel?
I thought that this trip
it would be good for us,
and that we could speak
and at least to tolerate us
where is my nie ta?
he/she got off l car
you are very pretty anyway, Lili
I should bring it by plane
-  do you still smoke?
-no
did I ask you if you still tint yourself the hair?
I have drunk something, in case that
interest you to know it
good it is not my matter
clear
I brought you a present
oh is adorable
how do you know it?
for the quality of the label
how will he/she be? there is only
seen the house once in video
1 3 years ago, it is as
you were you
Rache l is enough located
he/she is when he/she needs...
why are there children in your house?
they are my friends
children come, I want to present them,
this it is Sam Ethan
a lot of pleasure
this he/she is my daughter
hello
he/she came managing from San Francisco, California
he liked to smoke but no longer him ago
ok mom, is enough
it is important that they listen to it ,
so that they avoid and l cancer
please go for the suitcases
oh, you know, it is not necessary ,
that they use key there,
now only a button is pressed
do you travel with suitcases that you don't use?
oh, a couple of minutes will only be
I have friends
they have asked me him to come
to the city to visit them
good friends?
at least we stay in contact
good, less load then
here I bring their handbags
I believe that it put stones in the suitcase
everything remains exactly
as before
except for the birds
it is a glass tray
glass bowl, is classic
it is for the shelves
take it then
it is a gift mother
it is that there are many in my shelf
good, he/she looks well because
I won't take it of return
thank you, it is adorable
pretty handbags
good, this is everything
leave me in the city
I am glad to have you well-known Simón
you don't know me girl
yes I know you
ah yes?
I am with short skirt and my
legs are exquisite
and neither he/she has looked at it neither once
then now you know me
you don't have ring of commitment
how old are you?
30 ? 40 ?
you are gay
good you descend!
I didn't ask you you to descend
now yes I tell it to you
what? of what do you speak?
you cannot tell me where to lower
yes and now
only descend
I don't want you to play again
I found it sleeping to the one
side of the track
-  will it be?
-it is a charming type
thank you for and l sandwich
you won't arrive to your friends,
it is already very late
don't worry that yes I will arrive
he/she looks, the accidents happen
in their majority at night
I will call you tomorrow
don't make a mistake
ok
have me trust
as your father he/she used to say
everybody feels superior
you never said anything regarding it
that he thought when it was alive
and if he/she had made it what would you have made?
he/she had not made anything
your granddaughter goes away but you/he/she doesn't escape
it is easy to find it, only
be you slope
if he/she doesn't appear in next hours,
you call me to the cellular one and I will look for it
thank you to take care of it
I hope he/she makes him/her well
to be with you
and to you he/she would not make you well?
you are same
maybe and l make-up
where is my mom?
he/she left home of Allison
ok
you told to my mom
that he/she stops to smoke, to drink and
to be hated to if same
Rachel
am I hungry you have something sweet?
you arrive late 5 hours
my mom threw away me to some 20 miles
of Idaho and I had to walk.
you have to wait to the breakfast
but there are some apples in the table
you can really know
what is happening?
so that you realize
of how they are the things
I would love it
my mother and stepfather make me the life difíci l
maybe because I live with and llos
anyway, you
it supposed that it should finish
my studies in January
then, he/she had that re alizar some trips
until the university begins
then they had to come undone of my
they sent me to one summer to pass in Idaho
and it sent me to the woman's of the house
that and lla cannot be close
hence I am here
he/she tries to straighten out abue the
veto the devil
there is not kiss of good night?
ok
the only picture that he/she had seen of you
it is when you loaded me to my and this dog
I bought it to you, so that not
be him/her afraid to the funeral of your father
you put him/her Grandfather
he/she had 4, any help that gave me
he/she would not make sense
yes he/she made sense for you
my stepfather promised me to buy me a
car to go to the university
if it is that I can survive here
and to remain calm
oh, then your time here
it won't be a complete one I waste
good, I miss my friends
the friends happen but
the family lasts
I brought 7 novels
to read them here calmly
every week that I will be here
oh what a God this is?
I don't want you to mention to the gentleman in
any act
as ago an instant that
Oh God said
you spend and l sugar
I won't tolerate you to blaspheme
and next time I hope you sleep up
I wonder why
they send me to the masmorras
up, it is the rule of Georgia
go if that are strange
I will wash your mouth the
next time
and I wondered why
my mom hated you
I am happy that you are here, Rachel
then, they have something here well
that Harlan Wilson
don't laugh that with him you will work
what?
from and l Monday, it is very close,
you will wake up to the 7 am
I won't work
a rule more
if you live here,
you will have to work
ok, I know that you made this with my mother,
and she maybe changed
but I am not her, and not
you can tell me what to make
Rachel says it
he/she washes your plates
do you request it to me or do you order?
you finished, he/she washes then
your plates
I have never washed a plate before
hello, how these?
I don't know if I can pay this
good, I will be about choosing some
another of there inside
hello
good morning
Mister Price
I believe that he/she needs a hand
good, I should make myself the idea that
if you can walk with
this car for the city
maybe yes
as I believe that not, be not annoying
I prefer you to tell me that I am only
how old are you?
enough
enough for what reason?
to bother you
are you not a dangerous girl?
it depends on what you consider dangerous
better if you stay far from my
you won't have to brush yourself later
of mounting me
I should leave
good day cowboy
if it is that you like the picnic,
on Saturday he/she brings to your family
- Mary of I tempted
-I equip high!
- who is that?
-I don't know it
it is not of for these homes
- let us go!
-ahead go
picnic for and l July 4, there will be music and picnic
bring to the children,
there will be country atmosphere
hello
hello, I came to tell you that I won't work here
oh, spoke to me of you
you are a very beautiful girl
hear!
give me an urging affection ,
put on next to the telephone
good, allow me to help her so that
arrive as
it is exactly here to where he/she goes
it is not we so easy
I tell it to you, you are not a loader
how is it that one says in their language?
to hear that beautiful language me
he/she makes feel well
especially when I am sad
but like I am their doctor I tell him/her
don't load, don't feed animals,
not more cows
I should load, I am Basque
it will be Basque but he/she has
a hernia
it cannot please load
not even their hat
hello, I am the new secretary
are you the daughter of Lili?
it is a pleasure to know you
I am Spagui Kitalexan
but you can call me Icy
well
and you?
I am Rachel from California
ah California, the place of the fruits
and of the nuts
-signing my exit
- I want to say it again, don't load
do you know Harlan?
clear, he/she works hard as a Basque
I gave him/her that if he likes the adventure,
it would really appreciate a mounted one
ok
I will make it!
I like to know you Rachel
Simón
slowly
you are the antichrist
Simón, looks we have and l pleasure of
to have it here
it is not beautiful?
clear
the same as Lili
- of course
- yes
does he treat people?
not officially
oh, is hour of leaving
how good that Simón is not alone
he is veterinary, it is not legal
that that him ago
they would remove him/her their license
what do you read?
it is some poetry
the hands of bloodstained l are darkened
but they never finish making it
that he/she is Rubén the poet
he/she was born here in Idaho
how good that have recognized it
I see you here the 1 er Tuesday of August
August?
Ethan and Sam, this he/she is Rachel,
it is my...
granddaughter
it is very pretty
what age does he/she have?
no, and forget it
he/she only asked a question
can you bring us a little?
the boys and I are also thirsty
do you want?
I should finish first with this
how's it going was the work?
I believe that something confused
I saw same people again and
all in the same day
he/she doesn't give you shame to let these children to make this
- allow me to make it
-I can make it
- I try to help you, allow me to make it
- yes I can make it
- leave me
-I will make it
he/she looks but...
take it out of above mine
hear stops!
don't fight
take out me it, I didn't begin
ok
now truth
we go Sam you rotate it
- well made
-oh God
oh God, you injured
he/she had noticed you on the things
of the gentleman in the breakfast
no, it was alone a fight, not
we need the firemen
it returns and hit him/her
put it in your mouth
put it there
you are sure,
he stopped in my leg
and I cannot mention and l name of l Mister
Rachel cannot use the gentleman's name
she tries to enter soap in the mouth
I won't eat that ,
give it to somebody more
if you want it ,
I invite them to him
good-bye
it was raised in California
no, don't make that children
the fingers cojen and l fork
and the fork puts it to the mouth
they are the rules of Georgia
are you happy?
dear Paula Richards this
he/she is Rachel Wilcox, my granddaughter
Georgia has been surprised a lot by your visit
how more abue the?
you can take it out of your mouth,
he/she brings a seat
thank you
hello
I already finished,
do they excuse me?
clear
could you bring something of ice cream somewhere around?
there is in that jar
Rachel is working for Simón
that heard, it is brilliant
is gay then or what?
Simón is Paula's brother
he lost their wife and son 3 years ago,
he/she takes time to overcome it
that he/she is my girl, good and silly
don't tell me that only
don't worry
ok, Rachel!
that scream makes me feel a little afraid
please remain silent
I have to make it, it will be well
in a couple of days
and I suggest him/her that he/she makes their activities
normal and go to the barbecue
the paper of small ended
every week
oh, leave to fix for
tomorrow's barbecue?
clear, I have some gauzes in the office
would you bring them to me?
clear, I sit down it
you have made it very up to now
are they there?
yes
did you find it?
he/she used to work hard...
which do I serve him/her?
which did he/she want?
I will prove that of pear
Mrs. Seymour, the music
is it very high for you?
does he/she want to spend more behind?
he/she looks at affection
good shot
I arrive a little late
go
Chipy was asking for you
to and he only likes lla because
I revise their dog
how good!
and what is there of music's teacher?
not and lla is my shepherdess,
he/she is not possible terme with my shepherdess
George sent him/her this
didn't it put him/her some poison?
he/she is playing Bach
he/she waited some music country
we are residents of a learned earth
I cannot say the same thing
of Harlan
in some days, he/she will leave mission
for the church
am not I bothering it?
not but yes you can
it is you the only one
my sister and nephew are
here
I only escaped a while
in Georgia?
not exactly
it is supposed that one should
to maintain their family values
people make the
that in the bottom they want
sometimes not
I am not for sure
Harlan is rebellious
we leave he/she doesn't preach,
I don't like it
or the envenaré
anyone can make any
sew any person
he/she cannot leave it if it begins him
he/she only survives
oh please
you have 17
you allow yourself to take for your instinct
you don't understand a little bit what is to survive
oh, and did you invent it not?
without a doubt you are a survivor
you are noticed in everything, eyes, it forms
of walking, face
he/she died your wife and son, and
I feel proud that are here
you know, when he/she had 12 my stepfather
it forced me to have sex with me
and I loved him, he/she went delicate to
to weigh of it
I also survived Simón
you don't only have to feel pain
Rachel hears to see ribbon
3, 2, 1,
good I throw Rachel
oh sits down it they ran out of
the peaches another thing?
my girl's name is June
what an uh? what did it happen?
their name was June
is ah, beautiful?
June was my life
I never planned to see this way it but until
we end up thinking of marrying
but good
Simón said that you will go to one
mission in the Mormons
yes
I want to make it
I don't make it to intersect the hair ,
I will have to make it per years for the mission
your hair will grow
and for how long will you go?
2 years
enough time
can they have sex in the mission?
no
not until we marry
then you are about telling me that
you never had before sex
are you virgin not?
and you?
comic sounds
do you like to look?
it excuses
he/she looks I believe that we should return
put on in the part of behind
at some time you did look?
clear in a magazine I suppose
leave the skin
do you want to see?
no, really not
what is what impedes you?
you can play it if you like
he/she plays me
I believe that we should stop
that is not exactly
I don't apologize for anything
ok
hello, he/she not waits
will you allow me to happen?
no
will we work tomorrow?
why not?
I don't know it,
I mean, due to what I said
on your wife and son
you were right, they are dead
and it is already made
I only love you that everything
what my father made I caused it
that is everything
was it this way?
yes, he/she needed a what a topic to converse
Rachel told to your grandmother
what you told me
why?
he/she didn't have option, that is very serious
you are a silly idiot
he/she waits
don't you know how to recognize the truth?
everybody knows that I lie
nobody believes me
I believe you
but you don't count
shit, I cannot believe that there are
fact that
you are a complete one silly
oh Rachel
I went to fish with Harlan ,
I will put this in and l refrigerator
I will ask it once
and I will know if you tell me the truth in
that instant because you are part of my
I don't understand you completely but
yes I understand each other to me
I will know it
I am really sleepy
Did Arnold play you?
if it was this way, he would be dead
you are grandiose
and you
you are the only one
we give ourselves the turn
you are a charm, to be with you is brilliant
if you have something important,
he/she leaves your message and I will call you
I can hang and to call again
damned it is
that it is not excuse
if t ienes something important he/she leaves
your message and I will call you
what?
what was that whole moving call?
- Harlan good morning
-Good morning Mrs. Randol
how's it going?
how are you?
their newspaper
thank you
is Rachel in her room?
I believe that it is very sleeping
if it allows me to wait for it it would appreciate it
he/she hears thank you for and fished l
does he/she believe that June is beautiful?
good, I prefer the autumn, your you know,
September, October
no, I refer to my girl
June Smith
oh
clear, yes I think that small Smith
they are nice
I don't eat Rachel
good, nobody is
as Rachel
Harlan?
pancakes?
no
I avenge to tell you that I will speak with her
and I want you to come with me
why?
it is the only way that you realize
that I leave home with her
what?
I have to be said it personally to June
and me what I have to see?
I believe that it is the only form in that he/she forgives me
oh Harlan, I only sucked you
the penis, was not even an appointment
I wait for you in the truck
thank you for the breakfast
Sra. Randoll
you know
anything is left without being
punished
I have to change myself
the meditation is the road to your interior energy
and instead of losing your energy
your you will overcome your problems
he/she usually takes something of time
and every day you will go filling your energ ía
to improve your health, to increase your energy,
to reduce the stress and to overcome the sadness
then taking deep respirations
relax you!
and it lets that the energy is recharged
and be renewed in you
he/she remembers, you are very blessed for
estresada to be
you are maybe only looking for
an excuse to not say
and I believe that it is this way
but you played me and you dressed
and that avoids you to make something
Harlan is supposed that you are religious
it is supposed that yes
if you only could
I have to be sorry
to be sorry of what?
if you could forgive me
Rachel everything...
ok, I forgive you
something more?
ok then already forgave you
Lili
she is a liar
did you manage so much to tell me that?
Rachel
it is outside with a friend
she was smoking crack
in that night
Pey and Former they were with that for the house,
do you realize what I speak?
I know that something is passing him/her
and he/she lies the whole time
he/she is a destructive liar
why are Lili here?
I listened all that, and I deny it ,
that never happened
he/she is paying me to have her
brought here
it is as simple as that
then why you are here?
I am here to tell you the truth
why do you think that I am here then?
where should it be then?
it was supposed that he/she would go to the university
in autumn
but who he/she knows if he/she will make it
because he/she lied in the shipment of the application
are you hungry?
then you don't drink, you consume drugs,
do you smoke or do you have sex?
not until I marry
for good luck
I don't understand
why you take such a strict life
and boring?
because it is the correct thing
how can you know if something is correct?
I chose to believe
it is question of faith
I didn't say that I have this way faith or things
but something knows
yes, I understand it
1, 2, 3
let us be maybe guessing
great idea
you know, there is not reason to feel that I hurt
your feelings because we don't marry
no, undoubtedly not
oh, is she?
Harlan
hello
surprise
of course, I only have
one minute and I should already return
hello
June wants you to know
to my friend, Rachel,
he/she works for the doctor
Wart, crossing the street
your you know the lady
Randoll, she is their granddaughter and
it is from California
Rachel Wilcox, and she will study in New York
- a lot of pleasure
-hello, I kissed Harlan
and of this it is in fact what is
in the mouth?
no, he/she would not make that
I am not this way
and what does that mean Harlan?
anything, is it that sini fica
he/she only wanted you to sit down that I am
1 00 honest% with you
he/she looks at the truth it is that I took advantage of him
ok, I made it, he/she didn't have anything to see
I kissed him and he wanted to be sure
anything will interfere between him and you
and it already happened and we are only friends
is all that happened?
clear, it is everything
Harlan?
she made me oral sex
he lies
but we don't kiss each other, June
Junepher,
what things
June returns
when dad died, you missed
some food especially?
something?
no
I took an alone time
I will light the radio
at least these on time, he/she enjoys
your food, I will wait Rachel
the life this full with surprises
still when he/she is falling everything
this it is not a surprise, mother,
this it is a damned lie
he/she hears we already arrive
then and l agreement is that I cannot see you
or to speak to you or to come closer to t i
I don't try to put on in one
cruel position
it is not exactly
now she will put more
attention to that makes
you are my only friend
ok is well
Rachel
good ok, good-bye
did you have a good time?
did you make it?
does what a mom make here?
where is the grandmother?
he/she went to fall asleep, I stayed to wait for you,
I take hours thinking how I will be able to
to forgive you
I sometimes think the same thing
regarding you
and then, I was happened to use
the only weapon that I left
instead of using all the other ones
and it is my love for you
you took it to this point
I love you
did you practice it in the mirror?
he/she waits
he leaves as their own one
daughter, that is it that not
I understand, he loves you
the question is if it is that he/she loves you
how does he/she love me?
I want the truth
the same one that I said
dilo
he should have you that said, for what reason to manage
10 hours to listen the same thing?
he said it and I believe him/her
I want to listen to it now of you
Rachel
I don't believe that you know more
the difference
of what is well or
what is bad
what a lie is and
what the truth is
and that it is my blame
only he/she didn't want to be as my mother
with all that of the good thing and
the bad thing and the rules
what is what you mean that?
that he never played you
he/she never played me
he never slipped their hands until
the superior part of my
it never put their hands in my waist
when their head looked at you
while we had dinner
never, it never put their mouth in my body
never mom, I said it
at this time not, grandmother
I am proud of you
uh, is a happy morning
uh played you the naricita
yes your naricita
when did it begin?
when he/she had 12
when did he/she stop?
when my friend tried to kill him
when he/she had 14
I went to mass and I outlined the
option of beginning again
and there I left it
Rachel, takes!
ham and cheese, one is
for Simón, he/she takes
that you have a good day
if you don't enter to have breakfast in 15 minutes,
you will have to wait to the lunch
it is they very already opened up
ok, you believe me, it is all yours
you can use the colors
thank you Rachel
of anything
your mom is here of turn
- good-bye
-good-bye pleasure of seeing you
thank you Dr.  Wilson
we see each other soon
of course
hello, they are 25 dollars
oh not, the doctor will send me
the invoice to my house
not you if one can because
he/she has to be charged today
where is Ethan?
it is on vacation, I don't really know
where it is
effective or check?
you know that it is not the form
in that were accustomed to
I am new
then
I will be paid him/her completely
in their receipts and I will give him/her this
as a reminder
these they are copies of their receipts
unpaid
when will Ethan return?
I don't have idea
I will send him/her weekly reminders
thank you
of anything
it is not so happy this end
that he/she has good day
astonishing
I have not been able to charge to Nicolás in 4 years
and you already took out him/her 25 dollars in 2 minutes
I am this way
I am happy of you young lady Wilcox
oh, I never saw him/her making that
oh from the school that I don't play ,
but this relaxes me a lot
did it go out with the shepherdess?
I not even thought it
you know, it used to go out with your mother
I know it
we were some lunatics
why didn't he/she marry her?
problems would not exist
the things didn't work in the way
in that we would have liked it
you know of and llo
it is strange, then you could be my dad
but your dad had a car and a cow
yes I ended up seeing and l car
the pizza is clever
at least answer him/her and tell him/her
that you don't want to speak to him/her
he/she answers and it cuts
you have something of this size but
more filudo?
one of these it should be
you know that this puts me hysterical
I call it prenatural
I will finish here, without anything and without
to live in a place
where I am not welcome
who does he/she say that you are not welcome?
your face
at least you will be in prison
I don't know if it is one of the better defenders
of criminals in California
but it is over there happy, smiling, laughing
and playing to the golf
take you this!
then you did know my true dad?
it is exactly with the one that you wanted
that your daughter marries
he/she had their character
and everybody until me
we respected it
average was not?
but he/she was good person
I know it
there
do you want to listen something strange?
probably not
when Arnold spoke to me, I began
to hate the sex
but then sometimes before only played me
I felt love for him
did he/she tell me how it can be this way?
the re lación that took was maybe good,
sure Rachel am not
but I know that everything the rest was lie
I will show you the cover of this game ,
to finish quick and go home
I won't see, I am not looking
how it is supposed that you will arm it
if you don't look at it?
it is as knowing how it is
that your life will finish
he/she makes that all that involved
fall
good, veto to house
I don't want to go home
you cannot stay here,
good night
hour of sleeping
I found this in the closet
I believed that it would be safe there
most of people guard
people's gifts that the visit
I don't like flowers inside the house
he/she is late mother, will sleep
oh goes
there was a time in that you pulled me of those
hair if you found me drinking
a long time ago, of your hair
it is good
this will go here
here he/she goes
they come here, allow me to take you to the bed, we go
no, don't attempt it, you don't come
to my life to tell me what to make
everybody should pay attention to the rule
I don't like your rules
I please ask you you to leave me calm
for your father, it is already enough
but you continue this way, you are drunk
it is not a lot like it stops
that you are alarmed
he/she was afraid ,
Arnold maintains us,
he helped me
- I want you to stay
-I want you to die
really not, only a little bit
why do you scream to the abue the?
because you slept with my husband
Rachel
mom!
grandmother!
I need help
ok there goes
a doctor maybe need
don't play me
mom why they began another time?
I can alone with her
you go once and for all
allow me to walk
be careful with the glasses,
can you stop?
uh is as new
we go to the bed
I will put you in your bed
and I will give you hna aspirin
I will make it
I go to...
good
I need to vomit I believe
not in the stairway
allow me to help
ok goes
ok
how good
he/she can make it almost alone
I am fishing
I am alone me and my dog
Rachel is not here and I am not
I please that spy
the doctor will see you, be you calm
good it seems that it is already better
apparently yes
suddenly he/she put on this way and
he/she started to run as crazy
it is not normal in pigs
does he/she believe that it is stress?
stress in pigs
silly!
sangrona!
go to work, pass it well
I don't seem him beautiful
he doesn't like I
no, he likes the problems and the adventure
where is Rachel?
where Simón
how good
I thought that you would not leave until
that you are well
to where do you go now?
I will give a turn
you are not dressed as to give a turn
I am thirsty, I die from thirst ,
and I can no longer remain inside
although you to I will go in bus
no
it was not a question
certainly that not
allow me to go, I don't care your regals
don't no longer continue
come unfastened
it is well, don't wet me
I called Arnold last night and
I requested him/her the divorce
do you find mom well?
you lost your...
my good sense
I will take the bus,
he/she enters to the house
thank you
what you have a good party Giorgia
thank you to allow me to stay here
tonight
good giorgia me the pidi or
the first source
I believe that a good ide went to
I tossed hn little of perfume in
your washbasin
I don't believe that it bothers you
I forgot that he/she had that perfume
this fence to your hygienic paper
every time that you pass somewhere around you see it
do you want to smell it?
non thank you
do you believe that you don't should?
poem that contains the
line.. " it lay under and l bust
of Athena on the door of l room "
which it is and l crow
correct
can I request you a favor?
in commercial
can you hug me?
to hug you?
to put on next to you
to feel that somebody is next to me
" which the wolf is "
correct
can I request you another favor?
what?
relax you!
I believe that leave to sleep
there are blankets and pillows
in the closet
ok
you should sometimes eat something
I will open the door
oh, you intersected the hair
it was amid my drunkenness
oh already memory
dad's hugs
he/she always smiled
for any thing
it was very pretty
clear
why you tried to move away it
of my?
me?
sometimes, you didn't like that
let us look at TV together
and you took it away from my
TV distracted you when
they should rest
you feared a lot that we came closer
a lot my dad and me?
how much did we attach?
you know, in most of the cases
he/she feared you to marry a fool
and to lose all that you had gotten
as it happened to me to my
I believe that it was for their alcoholism
and yours also
yes
you know what it is what I don't really understand
of all this
maybe guess
if he really loved me
oh is not silly
I refer to at some time, not
I include to the present talves
which you believe that they were
the rules then?
why it will lose and l time for
somebody that I didn't care?
I remember that gave it jiste
my parents never gave it jeron
and how do you know that they didn't make it?
I don't know it
hate
that you have bought me so many
do you think yourself to drink all?
no
how could not he/she love you?
Rachel
oh took the free day
he/she needs more exercise, to walk more
enough with that then
or not?
you have to behave well
it is very fat
fat are
you see what I told you, the doctor he/she mentioned it
I was not me
thank you
clear
you are pretty with the short hair
where is Rachel?
it is Saturday I gave him/her the free day
he/she left to fish with Harlan
I need to stop to drink
I am not here
how can I help?
it is pregnant also
I want to go to my office with her
I take a long time one second
ok
it is with the Californian fool
it was worthwhile to spy
I don't know it
it is risky that you ace my friend
good I was thinking a lot
and reaching conclusions
we can maybe be more than friends
you know, maybe can
to end up loving me
I kick the boys
seriously
it is something that loved you
I kick them
good but like I will be far
in this mission
I don't believe that you can paté ar for always
prome to overcome it
I believe that I leave, put
the raft fences to the bank
more cats
it seems that this town needs more cats
and that it was my last patient
does already nobody look the hour?
me yes and you
I made it yesterday
what is what puts back to a clock?
and that completely sounds a complete one
disorder
except you, you are not a disaster
anyway
I need to show up
that seems a good beginning
to overcome it
I am inside in re alidad
from already
I will make the arrangements and I warn you
thank you
is all that you need?
I will miss what I began to lose
people are busy
as busy as for not noticing
what your husband made to your daughter
yes because, I don't know eómo it happens that
you always tell me the truth, thank you
what was that?
I don't know it, I sit down it
no
thank you
I should leave
how long more we will follow them?
until it snows
ok makes it
Medy, lists
Harlan
I will give you a good clap
vamonos!
the car doesn't start up
volte to toward us
oh God, descend
run!
hello, I will show up,
I am Rachel Willcox
a lot of pleasure
Chris Cunning has
me...
how are you?
he/she looks I only came to tell you that Harlan and me
we are only friends
anything will spend another time
I promise it, for the honor scout
then they can go and to make their things
to have a good time
and tell to June that doesn't have
that to worry
and what has happened was already
and it is the end of it
ok
then why ho you leave home
and you leave us tranqui those
ok looks, intent to be kind
but I will say it in
other words
if you call me, or I see that they continue ,
at some time
if I see them to speak Harlan or to make things
regarding him
I will look for all their boyfriends of you
and I will throw them to me silly
ok?
did they understand me?
good thank you for their time
happy summer
I will make him/her easo
Harlan
hello I look for my wife
what an oh that is?
my stepfather is here
hello beautiful car
Rachel, I feel bad that you hate me,
I cannot live with this lie
I don't hate you
you are in private property
hello George t you, only give me an instant
I should not be of
I agree that come home
of somebody that you don't really know
I should take the time and
to be with you
what do you make here?
what do I make here?
yes
you called me to tell me that you left me
and you hung me
and do you want to know what I make here?
if it was not for my daughter it would not be here
or not?
we go affection, please, you know me
better than any person
he/she told it to me
what did he/she tell you? hey
that it used drugs when the
they found in and quarter l of Elestiano
that he/she stole you when we went to the store
or that he/she was drinking when
it collided and l car
what lies were they?
oh please, you are a lawyer
I am fighting for my life,
curse
don't speak this way to him/her
ok
thank you
it is something that I could not change
an accident, an illness ,
I accept it
she would not lie with something like that
and me?
I don't know it
affection, please
put on this in your mouth, enter to the car
and it drives
look Mrs. I love Rache l and
he/she would never make something that
what is he/she making?
I won't let you to use the gentleman's name in vain
don't come closer to small small
drive!
I won't move, ne will be here
I swear for heaven's sake that never
stay it for the trial
and if you don't put on that in your mouth,
I will make pieces your car
ok
I leave
I will be here
it is I gave fíci l when one comes from San AND rancisco
how's it going if it is innocent?
he/she deserved it anyway
Rachel
-  can I speak to you?
-no
can you speak to me?
Rache l
I am becoming crazy, it is
the only hotel in the city
we have a house
only listen please to me
Rachel will overcome this anger some day
but we will have damaged our re laci ón
I mean, what it will happen with
our life?
I don't want you to regret not to believe me
but I really need here you with me
I don't know to who to believe
you have to choose some
of those that you told him/her not at some time
it is ugly to be in your own limits
it is certain
can I offer them something?
no, thank you
anything?  some special plate?
will they only be sat down there?
yes, it is well, I will take myself charge, thank you
I will make any thing for
to demonstrate you how much I love you
and how so simple it is for my to forgive it
ok?
we will see the way to overcome this
and yes we can
Rachel, didn't know where you were,
was it concerned, are you well?
grandmother am well
I want you to stay in the house Simón
ok
and I believe that your mom will call
ok?
clear, we speak then
leave to prepare the dinner
I love you affection
hello
who is?
Lili
hello
I need a bathroom
is ok well?
yes
t ienes that volte ar to the left
here to the left
ok
I will bring water
here it is
me...
it is simpler to believe in that that
you need that in what you know
I need Arnold
it convinced me and you also me
you convinced
is a powerful type not?
help me to understand
I need to tell you what I sit down because
all that I saw is how much you loved him
and how much the he/she loved you
and how much he loves me
and I thought
what suertudos we are
only that I cannot conjugate
I cannot arrive to that that him ago
or what he/she always thought
I avenge to tell you that I believe you
I like your short hair
and that anything of this is your blame
anything is your blame
I really gave it je to have
a conversation topic
what?
Simón believed me
the grandmother believed me
mom only wants to know if you believe me
oh please
I began to lose the things with Desser
I began it to lose because he/she knew that
it would not return again home
and he/she wanted you to pay
my errors
you can give me of madwoman if you like
but tell him/her that I sit down it
he is not annoying with you ,
it is willing to forgive you
although I can take him/her some time
it was good, thank you
of anything
my mom could not cook
for and llo also shook hands him/her
what bcurre?
the same thing always
oh called your mom to tell you
good night
here I am at home
of the grandmother
do you come?
no
ok
good, then good night
please it returns to San Francisco
non mom, not at this time
Rachel cannot leave this way the things,
we need to speak
can you call me in the morning?
ok
good-bye
you need help Rache l
for that reason I am here
you know that you destroy your mother
with all this, you know it
I will pay you the therapy
how pretty
ok, I will tell you what I will make
I will leave you here my Ferrari
I will go in and your mother's l car
and we will go of return to San AND rancisco
and you can take mine, if
it is that you tell him/her the truth
I don't like you to ruin my relationship
ok, this it is the treatment
my mom returns with you to San Francisco
and he/she goes to sent to leave well
but I won't be there
is that the plan?
good, he/she decided that
it would be me the liar
then you owe me
to be due what?
not taking you in opinion
it would affect you a lot
to be in the newspapers
he/she wanted you to write him/her
a letter requesting me
an excuse for that made
is that?
and a check for 10 millions
oh, clear, that, certainly
I mean, always
you wanted to give the appearance,
of a good relationship father - daughter
that impressed me and for that
instant for my all was well
it is a great lie yours
I believe that better you give me 20 my llones
because if he/she decides that you are a shit,
then he/she will receive 10
ok
we see each other in trial
as I have the tape
of what do you speak?
you know, I hate this scent
do you remember to Tomy?
him that he/she threatened you with the gun
then you are above with cables or cameras?
he/she doesn't swim, with sincerity
ok, is already enough Rachel
and l matter is that I have it engraving ,
there is a video of us
oh yes
you, all sweaty one ,
entering she and I had 14
grandiose
he/she looks, as much as my mother it is happy, you will have everything
I won't make fairy against you,
- happy mantén to my mother ok?
-ok
were you thinking?
I have some saved money
and it would be happy of paying the
education of Rachel
it won't be that a problem
or maybe neither he/she needs it and you already have it
maybe with a mortgage you feel happier
mom, I leave in the morning with Arnold
thank you
veto to the sofa
I love you
please Simón
no
it is not like with your family
I will never have sex with you ,
never, not
I not even think it and
ent iende that not
you are good in it maybe
but the matter of the attraction for beauty
and demons take away from my
he/she doesn't have anything to do with him
him trat or of forcing the things toward my,
without necessity that you enter to my bed
as a friend, or a father
he/she has everything to do with him
this is to know it I gave ferencia of the correct thing
and the incorrect thing, of the truth and the ment anger
he made you before that
and if you cannot notice the difference,
you cannot trust nobody
and you won't be able to love then
how you make to be so
sure of yourself?
it is good that
count me of your wife,
describe me the
what do I describe you?
did you love her?
when he/she played it, it felt the best
it leaves of my being played
it is a different form of loving, Rachel
do you believe that vue lvas to love?
I don't know it
maybe, I don't know it
maybe
thank you to not say
where is your car?
to the turn of the corner, for
reasons of security
if he/she could close the doors and windows
and to maintain it far from t i, he/she would make it
he/she would wait for the insurance
you know that I know it
oh goes George t you
I believe Rache l, I know it
and you also know it
it is not displeasing to have that in your mind?
you are a criminal, not known here
but you will already fall
if my hi ja was not in love
of t i, would kill you
it seems that Rachel didn't arrive, but you/he/she seems
that it is busy
thank you
could you give him/her this to and lla?
since I don't see it
please
I don't want you to leave
I call you when arriving
I know that that glass will be seen
well in your shelf
clear, I will find the best place
thank you
small hey
they come to say goodbye to Lili
- adi ós,
-adi ós L i li
adi ós children
who is?
I already go
Rachel why ho you lifted the telephone?
newly I got up
Simón has just left for and l work
he/she was ahead
I thought that it could allow him/her to leave,
but I am not able to Rachel
him ment iste
I arm puzzle guiding me of the cover
look at me!
why?
you look at me, you should tell him/her the truth
Simón says that difference doesn't exist among
the truth and the lie
is he/she able to the lie to be correct?
no
and what does it happen if I tell the truth?
they will be imputed criminal positions
but he/she will take long steps
we go you leave to vest to go
but he/she looks I have to go to the kitchen
and to make some things
we will attempt this way it
Simón and Harlan t clever ienen the camione ta
and and lla gave me this to give you
no, will change
you can read it in and l road
hurry!
what does he/she make you think that he/she will believe me now?
we will make it, you and me
I should maybe manage
clear but I won't leave you hanejar
why are you so hurried?
will you send more to somebody for your car?
it is ridiculous
good, non sue him to make that, but
that he/she has been giving me problems
it is not good to leave it in a street
anyone of Idaho
quí tate!,  is the best thing that you know how to manage?
Rache l can take it if gives you to
Rache l?
yes
you adore to the car
you waited many months
for that car
don't worry about anything, only
he/she wanted that and lla takes it as my appreciation
let us go! move!
for!
what? what bcurre cont igo?
has something become bad?
you believe that your AND errari will be a good payment
for and did llo for that make?
what? it is not that of him
that it is
allow me to lower, for!
let us go affection, please!
for!
ok ok, I will make it
I am stopping
allow me to leave
devils! Lili!
speak to me!
please you could turn yourself?
turn you!
ok well, continues walking!
there your things are, of turn
in Idaho, with your mother
she seduced me
you are a damned one!
what did you hope he/she makes?
was it drugged?
and fortune-teller what?
she enjoyed it
no
do you want to take this in opinion?
it continues, for my well
you will go to the damned sick jail
gone damned pervert!
dear Rachel, my mother
he/she always told me the things
more difíci them of the life
in those which to trust
to have faith and to forgive
then I want you to know about my voice
that I forgive you because I love you
so simple and so complex
to forgive is to continue ahead,
to continue with everything, he/she loves you, your mom
mom!
lament that happened
oh affection
I love you
I regret it so much
yes
Mrs. Randoll
I believe that he/she already knows that I am
in love with their granddaughter
and when it returns of my mission,
I will marry her.
ok