Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Jarita.
- Hi, Omar.
- How are you?
- Doing well?
- Yes.
Hi.
Jara, how are you?
What time is it?
10:57 PM.
Did that hurt?
- A bit.
- Screw you.
- Did you sign the petition?
- Not yet.
Not yet...
Get with it, eh?
"THlS lS THE lMAGE
CUSTOMERS HAVE OF ME"
Hi.
- It's 11:00 already?
- Hi.
I left you a couple of pastries
in the bag.
Stop eating on the desk
with the monitor, use the table.
Okay... I'm going.
Be good. See you later.
They move like this.
Clockwise, see?
That's how they move.
So, how goes it?
What?
- What do you mean, what?
- It's an expression.
Monotheism.
- How you doing, Fidel?
- Shitty.
The menstrual flow
is a vaginal discharge,
which are very common,
most women have them.
There's different types
of discharges.
There's the normal menstrual flow
we all have each month...
It was around here, wait.
Now you're gonna see something.
There it is, look.
What do you say?
Let me get a close-up.
There you go.
I'm losing it.
Please.
Unbelievable.
Here you go, Kennedy.
Well...
Tell Rojas he's wanted
on the loading dock.
Thanks.
Mr. Rojas, you're wanted
on the loading dock.
Look me in the eye when I talk to you.
If it happens again, you're fired.
- See you Monday.
Coming.
I had to wait 45 minutes to be served.
I can't believe no one is there at noon.
And there was no one around
to settle the check.
It's stuffy in here.
I got chicken and potato salad,
there was no pickled tongue.
- Look, Uncle.
- Good.
Don't just stay inside
playing that game.
Tell him, no homework, no game.
She says no homework, no game.
Tell her I'll do it.
He'll do it.
- Did you buy bread?
- No, I didn't, here.
It's okay.
- Take it.
- I've got money.
- Here, take the money.
- Forget it.
Goal! Goal!
Didn't see it, eh?
C'mon, start.
I'm getting it in.
It hit the post.
Cocksucker!
- Come here!
- Easy, Pablo
- Easy, Pablo.
- Motherfucker!
Easy, Pablo.
Pablo, Pablo...
Hey, that's enough.
Are you okay?
Easy now.
- Pablo, stop it. Please...
- Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch!
- Can you hear okay?
- Yeah.
- Should we take you to the hospital?
- No, I'm okay.
Here's your money.
- And a bit more, it was busy.
- Okay, thanks.
Can we speed it up?
It's 7:30 AM.
What kind of pillow do you have?
I don't know, a pillow.
- What's it made of?
- I don't know, Omar. The usual.
Turn to your right
and look at your shoulder.
The other side.
- It feels tight?
- Yeah. Right there.
It's the trapezius.
I don't know.
- Better?
- Yeah, fantastic.
Jarita,
where'd you learn to do that?
On TV.
That's 16 pesos.
- Got change?
- No.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Excuse me.
- Hi.
- A machine?
- Yeah.
Take number 30, in the back.
Thanks.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
- Is this number 22?
- Yes.
- They said it was free.
- Yes, it is.
- Thanks.
- Sorry about that.
- Good afternoon.
- Hi.
May l?
ALL KNlTTlNG
- Is this the latest?
- Yes.
I have the previous one, too.
- No, don't bother.
- It's no trouble.
Let me see.
Here it is.
This is the previous one.
- If you want back issues...
- Thanks.
- I can get them in three or four days.
- Thanks, but...
I can get the first few issues.
It's more complicated,
but give me eight to 10 days,
and your phone number,
I'll call you when I get them.
No, it's fine, really.
The pin comes up to here,
so the pulley can work
on this side.
Excuse me.
Isn't it this long?
And this high?
Jara, hold your arm out a minute.
Here, like this, at this angle,
it rotates like this, see?
No, no.
If it's not straight,
it doesn't work.
Yes, it works.
It turns on its own axis.
What's up?
They don't like
the petition upstairs.
We'll have to have an assembly.
Did you ask for my permission?
No, I didn't.
Asshole.
How you doing?
What a jerk.
- Come here.
- Me?
Yes.
What?
You know what.
Go put it back.
- What?
- Keep your voice down.
I'm doing you a favor.
Keep it down.
Okay.
Some pasta or rice, go ahead.
But not this.
Yeah, okay.
I don't want any trouble,
get going.
It won't happen again...
Move it.
Hi.
Fucking kid!
- Big guy.
- Hi.
- You all right?
- Everything's fine.
- Did you see the game?
- No.
The country girl is hot, eh?
I've caught her stealing yogurt
a couple times.
Excuse me.
With that ass you don't need a pussy.
I'll split you in eight like a pizza.
- Hello.
- Big guy.
- So?
- Things are getting nasty, Jarita.
There'll be trouble.
- Got a light?
- No, I don't smoke.
You can't smoke here.
What do I care,
they'll fire me anyway.
- Why do you follow her?
- None of your business.
Let's go play PlayStation.
Stop bugging me.
Come on,
let's go home.
- Come on.
- I already told you.
- Come on, let's go.
- In a bit.
- Why?
- Just wait.
I don't want to.
Well, you have to.
Let's go!
Stop goofing around.
Move it!
- Go to hell!
- Move it!
- Go get that.
- I don't want to.
- Go get that, brat.
- Go to hell.
- You go to hell.
- Hello.
Come on, Matías.
- Come on, move it.
- Let go!
Stamp.
Did you get a stamp?
Get one.
- Hi, how you doing?
- Good.
Great. Look, we have 100 pesos,
can we both get in?
- No.
- No?
Move aside a bit. Stamp?
Okay, well...
we only have enough money
to buy drinks.
- Sure, but the cover is 80.
- Yeah...
I know it's 80,
but is there any chance?
Can I go out for a smoke?
- No.
- No?
There's no way
to work something out?
- No, no way.
- No?
Look...
Move aside a bit.
- 140 for both.
- 140 for both?
Yes, 140.
I'll talk with her and
maybe we'll come back.
Okay.
Stamp?
- Hello.
- Hello, how are you?
- Can you get by?
- Yeah.
Move it over a bit.
- Hi.
- Playing soccer tomorrow?
- No, I can't.
Can you pass the salt, Jara?
Can you put it down?
It's bad luck if you hand it to me.
Thanks.
- Hello.
- Can I help you?
- No, thanks, just looking.
- Let me know if you need anything.
- Thanks.
Bummer.
What the hell happened, Jara?
- I'll take care of it.
- And where was l, sleeping?
Hang on. I'll wash my face
and we'll figure it out.
I have no choice,
I have to suspend you.
There's a bathroom
in the control room, Jara.
Yes?
A pizza, mozzarella
and a fainá. And a beer.
No! No!
That wasn't a foul.
And now they yellow card him!
Larrionda is full of shit.
He's pissed off.
What a bastard.
It's no use.
Totally one-sided.
- Hey man, got any money?
- Huh?
- Just a coin.
- I have nothing.
Seriously.
I just came from work,
I don't have money.
Just a little money, man.
- Seriously. I don't have anything.
- Give us some money, man.
- Some money, I said.
- I just came from work.
Don't touch me,
I have nothing.
Take my cell phone.
Leave me alone.
- That's it.
- Give me some money.
Here, that's it.
Leave me alone.
Are you sure you don't want
to get your hand checked?
No, it's fine.
Really.
Where did you meet that girl?
Julia? Chatting, on the internet.
- Who won this game?
- No idea.
- Progreso won.
- Progreso, really?
Will you meet Julia again?
Rampla got robbed
three penalty kicks.
- Three penalty kicks?
- Yeah, they screwed them again.
What a rip-off.
I'm starving...
I didn't eat dinner.
This first date stuff makes me nervous.
Maybe it doesn't show, but...
I don't know...
- Have you ever done it?
- No.
I don't recommend it.
You imagine what it will be like,
and so does the other person.
You build it up,
and when you meet
it's totally different.
I was nervous all day.
I could barely work.
It's not the first time.
I've tried before,
and I can't get used to it.
I just can't.
Are you going out again?
Probably not.
I don't think she liked me.
They're looking
for someone perfect...
Are you sure?
- About what?
- That she didn't like you.
Yeah.
Maybe she's not my type either.
Why not?
She's kind of...
kind of weird, strange, you know?
She likes the beaches here.
Here, in Montevideo.
Now if you said Lagomar, Solymar...
Maybe because she's from the country.
Beaches here suck.
She's strange how?
From the little time we spent together,
she seems to be kind of...
she likes heavy metal bands.
Which bands?
Like Guns n' Roses...
She mentioned a Metallica CD...
I'm not against any kind of music,
I listen to everything, but...
heavy metal kind of gets on my nerves.
I'm going to the washroom,
be right back.
- Thanks, have a good day.
- Thanks.
- Hello.
- Hi.
18 pesos.
Thanks.
SMlLE,
WE'RE FlLMlNG.
Pretty smile.
Have a nice day.
- Hello.
- Hi.
...OUR CO-WORKERS
We have to call to try to get more food.
Hey, Big guy.
They fired eight people, Jara,
what a disaster.
- Want me to call?
- Could you send a text message?
Coming!
- Jarita...
- Open up.
Jara...
Hey! You take a holiday
and all hell breaks loose, eh?
They fired four from the warehouse
and one cleaner.
What are you doing?
What's with him?
Danilo, do you copy?
Hi.
What are you doing?
Stop, stop.
Stop, Jara!
- Big guy, listen.
- Stop it, kid.
- You'll get yourself fired.
- That's enough.
- God damn it!
- You'll get yourself fired.
Easy, kid, easy.
- Calm down.
- Take it easy.
- Come here.
Stop, stop!
- Stop, damn it. Stop!
- ldiot.
- Stop, stop!
- Calm down.
- That's enough.
- Easy, it's okay.
What the hell
were you thinking?
How long do you think
I can put up with your shit?
So?
He said to wait
until Jara leaves.
First of all, do you have a brain?
You don't have a damn thing.
If you want to smash things,
smash your head against the wall.
You think I can put up with this?
It's enough.
You understand?
Answer me.
Hey, man... it's the final stop.
- Yes?
- Hello.
I'm looking for Julia, please.
Julia's not here.
- Are you from work?
- Yes.
- Did you get fired too?
- Julia went to the beach.
- Ah, okay.
Tell her I got her
unemployment insurance arranged.
Sure, I'll tell her.
Thanks.
- Bye.
Julia?
Hi.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org