Welcome back
ladies and gentlemen,
to the big game.
This is it!
50 million viewers
all chasing up on.
Perhaps the
greatest football player
of all time.
We are now
in the final moments
of this historic game.
Seconds on the clock,
this is it.
This is for the gold!
The arena sold out
and a 100.000 strong.
But the big question
remains calm.
Are they putting the kid in?
Now! He is!
Oh trouble right there!
Trouble right there!
Trouble again.
He is right on the edge.
He is all over the field.
Look at the speed!
The yellow defences is really
going to have come on strong.
And here is
another challenge on the way.
But even
under such pressure
this kid has the tendency
to really come on
strong enough
in the final moments
of any game.
Believe me
he is only in the disaster.
Exploding through the defence!
Oh!
The kid almost went down!
He almost went downgrade.
Defender going crazy!
He is carrying
a lot of speed
across that field.
Down!
Look out!
He is in trouble!
That's a fair ref there!
This ref is as cool as
Hannibal Lecter.
Oh...
look at that.
It is a penalty kick!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
This is it!
It's all come down
to this one shot.
I would not want to be
under the pressure
this kid is
experiencing right now.
This is for the gold.
He is waiting.
And there... she is.
One of the most feared
goalies on the world's stand.
With an unprecedented
63 gold medals under her belt,
and 39 World Cup titles.
There is not
a more experienced
and respected goalie
on a planet.
And here is the kick!
GOAL!
He is done it!
He is done it
and he has gold!
We have just witnessed
the impossible.
He is taken the gold.
Pandemonium!
Pandemonium,
the crowd is gone ballistic.
Unbelievable!
They are taken home
the World Cup.
You have just witnessed
the single greatest moment
this sport has ever seen.
Just incredible!
But he is done it!
He has done it!
He has done the unthinkable!
Singlehandedly,
this kid has won
perhaps the greatest game
ever played and axed his name
into the history books.
Incredible!
Never and I mean never have I ever
witnessed such a performance.
This kid will go down
as perhaps the greatest.
And I mean the greatest
ever to play the game.
Johan Cruyff,
George Best,
Pele, Messi,
Ronaldo, Rooney.
We are moving over
gentlemen because there is
a new kid in town.
One can only imagine,
the endorsements,
all that bubblegum,
all that candy.
No more curfews.
This man can write his own
check at this:
his everybody’s Christmas.
Everybody’s Disneyland.
Sundays without care.
This boy has done
the absolute unthinkable!
There is not
a team on the planet
that will not pay very dearly
for the talents, the skill,
the shear genius
of this young man.
Finally the money
for a new bicycle.
He won’t have to go
to bed at 9 p.m.
You still have to mow the lawn,
but it will be in solid gold!
He is big and ugly
and get probably
in a child's house
through a wicker chair.
The End
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2448014
Goal! (2012) English for hearing-impaired.srt
and Goal! (2012) English.srt
FPS: 23.976
With special thanks to: "Youri, Paavo and Mikhail"
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) ALL DVD's to be subtitled.
2) ALL VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled.
3) ALL videos/DVD's used in lessons at school to be subtitled.
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV.
____           __            ___   __              ___        __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _   /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /    /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
- Bringing you free subtitles       /                  Online  /  Since 1993    - /
-  |Africa| |Asia| |Australia| |Europe| |North America| |South America|   -  /
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+                          A big Thank You to EVERYBODY                            +
+        involved in making [closed capture] srt files and supporting us       +
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/42cku
Help other users to choose the best subtitles