I'm just so brokenhearted.
I want my daughter to
find another husband.
If she married again there
would be a man in the house.
What about Thao?
The man of the house is right there.
Look at him washing dishes.
He does whatever his
sister orders him to do.
How could he ever become
the man of the house?
Be patient, once he's older,
he will be the man of the house.
No way.
Today is a blessed day,
for a child is born.
I offer food to nurture this child's body.
I offer clothing to protect this child's flesh.
The child is blessed with
a mother and father.
Oh, spirit of this child return
home and do not wander anymore.
Come home, spirit and soul, come home.
Live a good life and grow old.
Why does that old white man stay here?
All the Americans have moved
out of this neighborhood.
Why haven't you gone?
Why don't you strut away,
you dumb rooster?
Those punk-ass Mexicans
messing with you?
Please, it's important.
He went for his lighter
and they shot him.
He didn't even have a gun on him.
This time we have witnesses.
These guys will be locked up for a long time.