Honey, you haven't told me
one name that you liked yet.
Are we positive
it's a girl?
You can't tell anything
by the sonagram.
Yes, Paulie,
it's a girl.
If you would have came with
me to the doctor's today...
you would have seen her kicking
and moving on the monitor.
She was even
sucking her thumb.
Hey, what's the matter?
Nothing, just I'm late...
And cousin Mike is gonna
be here any minute.
So I just...
I know that look
on your face.
What's bothering you?
I do not have any
look on my face.
Yes, you do.
I'm nervous, too.
Okay, but we got to
talk about this...
or it's gonna get
real weird, real quick.
I know, I know, I'm just...
with the wedding
and everything...
I guess I'm just
distracted.
Have fun with your friends.
We'll be waitin'.
Yo.
Three days away, cuz.
You lucky bastard.
Lucky?
Yeah, lucky!
Beautiful girl,
baby on the way...
I'd say that's lucky, man.
That's real lucky.
You ran away and
left me, long time ago
Why are you playing
that song again?
It's a good song.
It's for someone that
left a long time ago.
Did you tell him yet?
No.
Tell me what?
Guess where Jimbo
is right now.
Eatin' a san dwich?
ookin' for a job?
Picking Tc up from
the train station.
What the fuck happened?
Tc's coming in?
Why the fuck is
Tc coming here?
Nobody likes Tc!
And... he's a groomsman.
Oh!
You don't make a guy
like that a groomsman!
He's a zero!
Plus you haven't seen the
guy for like 8 years, Paulie!
Do I see you every
day, anymore? No.
Are you still one
of my best friends.
Are you groomsman? Yes.
Am I cousin? Am I
a normal person...
that doesn't fuckin'
steal shit from you? Yeah!
No, forget about it, man!
ook, Mike, it's
in a few days...
all you gotta do is just
be cordial to him, okay?
You can't do that?
I can't do that.
Why not?
'cause I don't know
what cordial means.
Speak English, Paulie!
Fuckin' cordial...
what is that?
It means "be polite,"
you retard.
Just be polite to the kid.
Why didn't you say polite?
Mr. Shanty-lrish-Newspaper
Man, He's got to...
Be nice to him.
He'll be here in an hour.
I'll be cordial.
When he comes in,
I'll be real cordial.
Yo!
Thanks for showing up.
I thought I was supposed to pick
you up at the train station.
Yeah, about two
hours ago, man.
I gave up on you.
I'm walkin'.
I thought they
said six or eight.
What eight?
And you pick eight?
Shut the fuck up
and get in. come on.
You clown.
Pop the trunk, man.
You look good, man.
Yeah, you look good too, dog.
Shit, it's good
to see you, buddy.
Yeah, good to
see you too, man.
I take you by your
Dad's place or what?
No, not necessary.
Actually, I was hoping...
to crash with you and
Jules, what do you think?
Can I?
Shit, fine by me.
You good?
Hey!
I don't give a shit, if you can't
get over your differences...
and play in the band, I'll
just get a new drummer.
You can't get
another drummer...
it wouldn't be
the same band!
And you're not going
to use the old name...
if you got a new band.
No way!
Why are you
causing trouble?
It's your cousin's wedding...
And you're acting like
a little school girl.
I said I would be cordial
to the cocksucker, didn't I?
Didn't I say I would be
cordial to the cocksucker!
But I will not play in a
rock and roll band with him.
That's where I
draw the line, Dez.
Hey, Paulie, mind if I get
another drummer?
cousin Mike doesn't want
to play in the band.
Dez, we haven't played
together since High School.
Maybe it's not
such a good idea.
It's not a good idea.
It's a great fucking idea!
This is my wedding
present to you.
ook, you need to
rock one more time...
before you walk
down the aisle.
Man, are you hearing me?
I'm hearing ya, Dez.
We will rock, dude.
come on now.
It's good that
you're back, man.
It's too long you
neglected your friends.
I just couldn't believe
when Paulie tracks me down...
and tells me he's
getting married, man.
Yeah, Paulie of all
people, you know.
If you ask me, it's 'cause
he got her pregnant.
No shit.
Well, good for him.
Biggest mistake of his
life, he marries that bitch.
- Yo!
- Hey!
Hey, look who's here!
What is goin' on, fellas!
- How you doin'?
- Good!
Good!
How you doin', man?
Dig the goatee, man.
That's cool.
Hey, have shrunk?
Everybody's taller than me.
I heard the good
news from...
Yeah, baby on the way.
The wedding, too.
Obviously.
- Dillon's got that puffed rice...
- et's ahh...
see what's up
with cousin Mike.
Oh, yeah.
come on.
All right.
Now what kind of
friend would I be...
if I didn't try to
patch things up
between two old friends?
Hey, Mike, Tc's here, wants
to say something to you.
ook, first off I
just want to say...
I want to apologize
for what I did.
You owe me more than an
apology, you fuckin' prick.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
cousin Mike.
You said you were
gonna be cool, right?
Fuck this guy,
I'm bein g cool.
I'm being cordial.
Whatever you want to say.
But this guy fuckin'
disappears for eight years...
The guy fuckin'
steals from me...
An apology's
going to do it?
I should kick your
fuckin' ass on prin ciple.
Mike, you ain't
kickin' nobody's ass.
Mikey, it was just a card.
come on, man,
you're being ridiculous.
Why don't we just
get a fuckin' drink?
Look, Mike, you said you were
gonna accept his apology.
Just accept his
apology, all right?
It's a little crazy
to get worked up
over a fuckin' baseball card.
It's just a fuckin'
baseball card.
It's not just a
baseball card...
it's a Seaver Rookie,
I bought it with my
own fuckin' money...
when I was a child.
I was a fuckin' child
when I bought that card!
It's worth hundreds, maybe
thousands of fuckin' dollars.
and-and the meaning
it had to me...
the sentimental value!
I remember in the
second grade...
I don't know what
to say to you, man.
I just don't know what
to say, all right?
I didn't know it was
worth that much to you.
Okay? What more
to you want?
Well why did you
fuckin' steal it?
Mike, Mike, you're
being ridiculous.
Either accept my apology
or not, that's it, all right?
All right.
I accept your apology.
God damn, you
make me work, man.
What's wrong with you?
I got a let it off my chest.
Eight years is a long time.
I'm trying to
apologize to you, man.
- come on.
- I apologize to you.
You're a fuckin' animal!
What the Hell, Mike!
All right, fuck it!
Fuck it!
Go ahead!
Go ahead.
That's what you
want Mikey... fight!
- Kick his ass, Tc!
- What do you mean?
Fuck him up, TC!
Go for the mouth.
All right, fuck
it, all right...
I don't give a
shit. Fuck it!
Yoou wanna be a man?
Fuck it, come on.
I'm not afraid of
your ass. come on.
I forgive ya'. Fuck it.
You fuckin' believe this guy?
He was gonna hit me.
You should fuckin'
hit him anyway.
You forgive me?
You got problems.
You had it comin'.
You got problems
with rage.
Startin' that much trouble
your first day back.
Dez, what do you say you
get Tc a beer right away.
I'm on it.
It's good to see some
things don't change, huh?
Welcome home
brother, come on.
Shoot a little pool.
I don't understand
the New York Jets...
They always play
in Giants Stadium.
All right, here
we go boys.
Why don't they have
their own stadium?
My bar, listen up.
We finish the
bottle, we go home.
Hey, shut it!
Tc comin' home.
And the band gettin'
back together.
And Paulie,
Paulie!
Drink up, cuz.
Bad luck.
Is there more?
There you go.
Where's my car?
Jimbo, Jimbo, you're
not driving anywhere.
You don't need a car now,
you got a ride already!
Look at that!
Seriously, I'll drive!
You're not
driving anywhere!
Are you fuckin'
kidding me?
Come on, we'll walk.
It's just a couple of
blocks. No big deal.
I'm not walking
with you anywhere.
Whatever, Seaver.
Whatever.
I thought you made up.
Didn't you make up?
You made up right?
You made up.
Hey, that's my trash!
Hey, come on, put it back.
That's my trash, dude.
What's your problem?
The Olympic
sport of beer.
Hey, hey.
Maybe we got to
settle down, Jimbo.
ettin g derelicts
drink after hours!
They should shut
you down, Dez!
Fuck you, bitch.
Dez, Dez, Dez, seriously,
what are we going to do...
for the rehearsal dinner?
One song.
All right, I think if
we get that tight...
Why don't you wanna go
fishing? lt'll be fun.
You're not comin', Tc?
There's a fine line
between fishing...
and standing in the boat
looking like an idiot, all right?
come on, don't leave me
hangin', man, I feel like shit.
Jimmy, he just wants to
spend time with you.
It's the least you
could do as his brother.
Be nice to him, okay?
And remember, don't say
anything about Sue.
You promised.
come on, baby, have a
little faith in me, all right?
You know I purposely
didn't go fishin'...
'cause I know you
need to talk.
So talk.
What's going on?
come on, you've got some
sense of what's going on.
I'm tellin' you,
he's go this edge.
This ridiculous edge.
How long has he
been in this funk?
- It's been this way about a year.
- A year?
Did he tell you he got
fired again last week?
What do you mean, again?
Second job in ten months.
You knew him years ago...
was he the type of
guy that gets fired?
All right, look.
Just try being direct,
and saying
"Jimbo, what the fuck
is going on?"
come on, I've
tried everything.
I've tried couples
counseling...
I've tired his father.
Nothing... he won't
talk to anyone.
And he's getting fat, too.
Oh, yeah.
That I noticed.
He thinks it's funny that
he's let himself go.
He says now that he's
married, why bother.
That's what happens
when you get to 35.
You think you got
your head together...
and then all of sudden
your body falls apart.
Yeah, well his head
is hardly together.
I got to hand
it to you, bro'.
You figured it out, man.
You got a nice
house, great boat...
all the time to enjoy it.
Hey, look, I only fish
before or after work.
Today is an exception
because I wanted...
to spend time with
my big brother.
Wait a minute, you call
what you do, work?
Shit, if I had to type for a
couple of hours every day...
yeah, I'd have plenty
of energy to fish.
Wait, you're going
to try and tell me...
the reason you just go home
and watch TV every night...
is because you're too tired
from sellin' office supplies?
I'm not a salesman,
I'm the general manager.
Okay? There's
big difference.
I've got 1 5 people
underneath me.
Yeah, Jimbo.
I've seen that pack of
misfits that work under you.
Jesus christ, come
on, Paulie, seriously.
Do not compare what
you do for a living...
with what I do for a living,
'cause there's no comparison.
I do a man's work, okay,
I have to oversee
multiple locations.
I've got shipping,
inventory.
I've got trucks.
So when I get home,
I'm tired, all right?
I'm not doing what you do.
What do you do? You sit in
front of the computer...
for a half an hour, an hour.
So you have the free time
to jog and lift weights...
and fish and do
all that fun shit...
that you seem to
have all day to do.
All right, I see
what you're saying.
So you think the reason...
that you packed on a
couple of pounds lately...
is because you don't have the
time to work out anymore.
What other reason
would there be?
Maybe it's the twelve pack
of Budweiser a night...
I don't know.
Jesus christ, I
work a long day.
I don't have time to exercise,
but I enjoy a few cocktails.
Okay? If you knew
what I went through...
the pressures I was
under, the deadlines...
you wouldn't begrudge
me a fuckin' drink.
All right? I didn't
get lucky, man.
I did not marry
a rich girl.
Fuckin' I'll han d it to
you, you got lucky.
I didn't want to get into
it with you, Paulie.
I'm worried about
you, that's all.
What the Hell are
you worried about?
Getting married.
We've been livin g together
for a couple of years.
You know? I think it's
gonna be all right.
It's different when you
get married, trust me.
I just don't want to see
you making a mistake.
We got a baby comin'
in a couple of months.
It's a little too late to
worry about that, all right?
Hey look, I know, I know.
You don't have to get
married to someone...
just because you
got them pregnant.
It's not the '50s.
No one's puttin' a
gun to your head.
I'm marrying her,
because I love her.
Is that so hard
to believe?
No, of course, I
know you love her.
And you're a good guy.
You're the kind of guy who
has always done the right thing.
It's just not necessarily
the right thing...
to get married to someone
just because you got
them pregnant, that's all.
I just don't want to see you
making some huge mistake.
Hey, Dez!
Rehearsal, one hour!
In my garage!
That is the commitment
I like to see, cuz.
Yo!
Do you see me
unloading the minivan?
Dad, we're
going to Murph's.
We're gonna be late.
You're going to be more late
if you don't get your butt...
off the bike and help
me unload the minivan.
We have to be there in
five minutes, Dad.
Yoou got to be there in
five minutes, huh?
et me ask you a
real quick question.
Who likes the
delicious Fruit Loops?
Oh, you do?
How about the little
"fudgie-fudgie"?
You like these?
I guess if you're too busy to help
your dad unload the minivan...
you're too busy
to eat crap food.
Okay, okay!
We'll help you!
You're gonna help?
What a good idea!
Hey, there's
more out there.
Whoa, where's the fire?
So the band is
back together?
Yeah, rehearsal later on.
I can't believe they
actually agreed to it.
Why wouldn't
they agree to it?
Why wouldn't they
want to rock?
Because, sweetie,
maybe the band...
didn't mean as much
to them as it did to you.
What you drivin' at?
All I'm saying is, those
were your glory days...
were they not?
They were not
my glory days.
I've had plenty of
good days since then.
It was what, 1 7 years ago.
Oh, they were good
days, weren't they?
Yeah, baby, they
were pretty great.
We had broken up for
good, just an hour before
Now I'm staring at the bodies
as they dance across the floor
They don't ride
like that anymore
They just don't ride
it like that anymore
We've been livin g together
for a million years
come on.
Now it feels so strange
out in the atmospheres
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
You're way off.
You guys got way off.
That sucked.
Dude, we were...
Honestly, we were...
We started to rock.
Anyway, besides, Tc's
voice sounds like dog shit.
Bite me, man.
That's a great song, dude.
It's a stupid song, you
don't play a break-up song
for a guy's fiancé!
It's a dumb idea!
Where's Paulie, man?
I thought he was going
to come to rehearsal.
He's being a pussy.
ike mister hurt
feelin gs an d shit.
Hey, why don't we
play Jane's Addiction,
"Been caught stealin"'?
I bet Tc knows that one.
Shut the fuck up, dumb ass!
Why don't we do
"American Idiot"?
You can be yourself!
Stop, just stop!
All right?
Knock this shit off.
You know what we should
play? We should play...
We should play,
Eddie Money, "Shakin'."
That used to rock.
I ain't playin' shit 'til
you put a fuckin' shirt on.
This is old school.
You look retarded.
It's like Sid Vicious, man!
You're jokin', I
know it, come on.
It's on!
Let's go!
Rosanna's daddy had
a car she loved to drive
Stole the keys one night
and took me for a ride
Turned up the music just
as loud as it could go
Blew out the speakers
in her daddy's radio
She was shakin'
Snappin' her fingers
She was moving
round and round
That girl was shakin'
We started drinkin',
weren't thinkin' too straight
She was doin' 80 and she
slammed on the brakes
Got so high we had
to pull to the side
We did some shakin' 'til
the middle of the night
She was shakin'
Snappin' her fingers
She was moving
round and round
That girl was shakin'
Are you crazy?
Yoou look beautiful...
for a big, fat, pregnant girl.
Babe, is cousin
Mike bringing Jen...
or can I give that
seat to my niece?
I think you can
probably give it away.
Hello?
Dezzi-Dez.
Yeah... oh, would
you let Tina know...
I'm coming over later
for the high chair.
Okay, thank you.
Here you go, you too.
Desmond, yeah,
hold on a second...
I'll take it outside.
Excuse me.
Private matters?
Hey Dez...
What's up, man? Look, I'm
sorry I couldn't make it today.
Everyone else was there,
rockin' out Strong Island style.
Yeah, look, I know...
I had to help out Sue out with
some things here at the house.
Don't tell me you're
gettin' chicken shit on me.
I need you in this band.
No, no, not at all.
Look, I, um...
I got to ask your
advice about something.
I'm thinking about maybe not
making Jimbo the best man.
That's a big mistake, Paulie.
It's your brother.
That's the kind of thing
brothers don't recover from.
Yeah, well, he told me that
marrying Sue was a mistake.
ook, Paulie...
Your brother's always been
sort of a schmuck, right?
If he's such a schmuck...
why should I have him
be the best man, right?
'Cause he's your brother.
Not a good enough reason.
Is there any way
you're blowing this
thing out of proportion?
I remember how nervous I
was before I got married.
I was 21 years old, right?
Hey! Did I invite you
into this conversation?
Hold on a sec'.
Did I invite you? No!
Do your homework!
Sorry about that.
Look, think long and hard.
About this whole thing
before you make that call.
All right?
See you tomorrow.
Pop! What're you gettin' at?
All I'm sayin' is I
appreciate all your help.
ivin g here at
the house with me...
it's nice to
have your company...
watchin' the Met
games and all, but...
don't you think it's time?
Time for what?
You're a grown man,
still livin' at home.
It's not healthy.
I got to take care of you.
But I don't need you
to take care of me.
Yes you do, Pop.
You should start thinkin' about
startin' your own family, Son.
Takin' care of them.
Don't you want a family?
Of course I do.
So what are you waitin' for?
Don't you know any nice girls
who want to get married?
Nice ones, no.
Maybe you'll meet one at
your cousin's wedding.
Weddin's are
good for that.
I don't know.
No one like Jen.
It's like I told you,
only the lonely can play
Forget about it,
you look fantastic.
Yeah, it's him, I got it.
What are you doing here?
I thought it would be a
good time to come by
and get some of
my stuff back.
What stuff?
I thought we did
this already.
No, I had an extra box of
stuff in the back bedroom.
Oh, I threw it out, I
thought it was garbage.
You threw it out?
Jen come on, you
didn't throw it out.
There were two important
baseballs in there.
It couldn't have been too
important if you left them here.
No, they were important,
they were real important.
They were valuable
collectors items.
Collectibles.
Grow the fuck up, Mike.
I mean, don't you see
that's why we broke up.
You are a child.
What man in his
thirties, do you know
that cares about
baseballs and comics
an d all that other
adolescent shit
that you obsess over!
How... how you
been otherwise?
Go away, Mike.
You look really good...
Jen come on!
Did I tell you Paulie's
getting married this weekend?
Yeah Mike, you
told me that.
Yeah, it's exciting.
Really exciting.
I got a tux, it's nice.
I... I don't have
a date for that,
you should come,
you know all the guys.
You know my little brother
is back from college.
Yeah?
So?
So.
I think you should
stop, stopping by.
And if you don't, I think
I'll have him take care of it.
Who Top cat?
You're threatening me
with my little brother?
Yeah, he's not so
little anymore.
Wow, man, you know what?
You just want to throw
me under the bus,
toss me out
of your life
like we never had
anything, cool,
that's fine with me, Jen.
I don't give a shit,
you can do that.
Fine, whatever man...
All right, you know what?
Do me a favor, see if you
ever meet another guy,
like me, in
your whole life!
Ever, 'cause I got
news for you, Jen.
Guys like me, nice guys.
cordial guys.
Huh, Yeah...
that's me...
We're far an d
few between, Jen.
Far and few between,
so good luck,
go enjoy your lonely life.
'Cause I can't
do it anymore.
I'm done, fine!
I got your bike...
I got your bike
in my truck.
I've been driving
it around,
trying to figure out
when would be the right
time to bring it over.
The right time?
Yeah, the right time.
I got your bike.
It's in my truck.
There you go, I put all the
reflectors back on for you.
Thank you, Mike.
Give Paulie and
Sue my best.
You look great.
Jen, come on,
let's work it out.
Come on, talk...
Jen talk to me.
Talk to me Jen,
whatever I
did, I'm sorry.
I don't even know what
I did and I'm sorry!
Jen!
Jennifer come on, Jen!
What you yellin' for!
Mind your fuckin'
business!
That's what!
You're not even close.
I am close.
Hey, Jimbo, Jimbo, what was
that song you wrote for Jules
when you were trying to
woo her, in High School.
What was it?
Woo me, is that
what you call it?
He had ulterior motives
if I remember correctly.
Remember that song
you wrote for her,
back when you
were trying to...
You know what I mean.
Back in the day, remember?
You're talking
like 20 years ago?
Come on, come on,
don't be a prick.
He used to play
all the time...
come on, what was it...
How'd it go.
Hey Jules...
Don't you play
me for no fool...
Jesus christ,
that was back in
High School, man.
How am I supposed
to remember that?
Jimmy, you're
so full of shit,
you didn't
forget the song.
I don't remember the song.
Oh, you remember every
note to "Stairway to Heaven"
but you can't remember
three cords you wrote for me.
I haven't played "Stairway
to Heaven" for years,
Jesus, come on.
That's not the
fuckin' point!
Hey, why don't you just
grab the guitar and play it...
ook, I don't remember
the fuckin' son g.
If I remembered the song,
I would play the song.
Okay!
But I don't
remember, I'm sorry!
I'm having a tough
time, Paulie,
I don't know
what's going on.
You know what it is?
I get over come
with emotions.
Yoou know, I'm completely
flooded with emotion.
I start crying, my heart gets
all heavy, I can't drive,
cause every song I hear on
the radio reminds me of her.
Right.
And I know I shouldn't go
over there and see her,
but I can't
help myself,
I got to see her
with my own eyes.
Seriously, you got
to calm down, man.
I mean, there are
other women out there,
give yourself time, and
you'll meet somebody new.
But not that hot
Paulie, she's so hot.
And that ass,
God, Paulie...
Where am I going to
find somebody that hot,
that likes back, again.
That's a combo in
this life time.
Look, you know,
when I met Sue,
she was kinda
going through
what you're going
through now.
She was datin g this clown
from Staten Islan d,
when I was working
over there
and I'd see her on
the ferry occasionally.
And one night,
I'm coming back.
And I see her,
and she's crying.
So, I go over to
her, you know,
being the nice
cordial guy that I am.
I ask her how she's doin'.
And she tells me
the story about,
about how she just
found out her boyfriend
was cheating on her.
So I walked her home and
asked her, you know,
maybe when she's
feelin g better,
maybe she let
me take her out.
Maybe, ahh...
maybe let me make
something of her life.
Month later, she called.
Here we are.
Baby on the way.
I didn't know that's
how you guys met
on the ferry like that.
That's romantic, Paulie.
Yeah, yeah.
That's really romantic.
How come you never
told me that before?
I don't know, that kinda shit
just doesn't come up, does it?
What about Violet,
I like that.
That could be a good name.
No, no flowers.
And no virtuous
names either.
ike Hope, Faith
or Chastity.
She should have a regular
name like Liz, or Betty.
Liz or Betty.
Now you are aware that
those are the same names,
right, they're both
nicknames for Elizabeth.
You know what, I
didn't know that.
You know what
we should do,
we should do what
Dez and Tina did.
They waited until
their boys were born.
check out their
personalities,
an d then they name them.
Oh so, are you waiting to
check out her personality,
before you finish
painting her room?
I'm going to get to
the room, all right?
How about Betty?
You like Betty?
I like it.
Elizabeth it is then.
I like Elizabeth.
- Okay.
Where do you think
you're going?
I got an eight o'clock
tee time with Paulie
and the guys, I'm late for.
You're not doin' anything.
I going to work
and it's your turn to
take the kids to school.
8 o'clock tee time.
Desmond, you're the
adult, they're the kids.
Okay.
I'll see you tonight.
come on boys!
Let's look alive, Daddy's
taking you to school.
Love you.
You too babe.
Boys, let's go!
I'm gonna go
to work, okay?
I remember, when
we first met
You were, standing
by the pool
Smoking on a cigarette
You asked me to the
Sadie Hawken's dance
I spent all night, trying
to get into your...
Hey Jules
What we gonna do,
come September
and when you go
off to school
Hey Jules, you're just
hangin' with a fool
I'm not cheating on you
I'll never let
go of you
Nice shot, man.
Thank you Bro'.
That still doesn't explain
why you took his
baseball card though.
'cause I was mad at
Mike about something,
so I did it just
to piss him off,
you know stupid kid stuff.
Stupid kid stuff is the
fact that eight years later
he's still
pissed about it.
Wait 'til he finds out I
only got 40 bucks for it.
You're kidding me,
you only got 40?
Yeah.
can you believe that
jack ass thought
he was going to retire off that?
And why was it so urgent
to get out of town
and then why not call
anybody all this time.
Oh come on, Paulie,
if anybody was going
to get it, it would be you.
Bro', I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Well, the reason that I
left the way that I did,
was because...
Well, I accepted
something about myself
that I knew you
guys couldn't.
We're your best friends,
what wouldn't we
accept about you?
Paulie, I'm gay.
Hey you know, I'm honest
with myself, I probably...
probably crossed my
mind a couple of times.
You never really allowed yourself
to really believe it, right?
Yeah, yeah I guess.
Yoeah, well welcome to the
first 25 years of my life, man.
So... that's just
what you do now?
Or...
No dude, that's
who I am now.
Yeah, that's what I meant.
Just hit the
ball, come on.
Made ya' nervous,
didn't I?
ittle bit.
I'm tellin' ya, my dad
flipped when I told him.
I'm sure, what did he say?
You can imagine.
My dad's old school, like,
It was the hardest thing
I ever had to do, man.
I just really prepared
my announcement to him
and then, when
at dinner, I says to him,
"Dad, could you pass the
salt to a homosexual."
And my Dad just stayed
real quiet for a long time.
And then he says to me, "Are
you seeing a psychiatrist?"
ike I got some kin d of
sickness or somethin g.
And then he says to
me, with real disgust,
"Be safe."
And that was it,
man, that was it.
That was it.
Hey, Dez!
can we talk for a second
at what a stupid idea
it is to have a softball
game for a bachelor party.
come on.
What the hell is
that all about?
You know what we
should be doing.
Yeah, playin' basketball.
No man, we should
be gettin' a limo,
we should be packin'
it full of strippers
and we should all be gettin',
you know, on our way
down to Atlantic city.
Our wives would love that.
He wants to play softball,
we're playin' softball.
Oh, God, softball,
that's a lot of fun.
You all right?
He said, uh,
He says you were
judgmental yesterday.
Who did,
He did?
Paulie said I was
being judgmental?
Yeah.
He said that to you?
When?
The other day.
He said I was being
judgmental the other day?
To you?
He didn't say shit to me,
look, the other day, we talked
I was just telling him
what my feelings were,
you know what I mean,
he's my brother.
I can't give him advice.
Don't give him advice
unless he asks for it.
No, that's what a older
brother's supposed to do.
You know Paulie, he's not
going to ask for advice.
Just do every one
a favor, all right.
For the next couple days,
keep your opinions
about Sue to yourself.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's that mean?
Did he say, I said
something about Sue?
Jesus christ, I'm just
lookin' out for him, man.
I mean, seriously,
you think he's
doing this thing
because he loves this girl?
Or do you think he's doing
it because he knocked her up.
No, I think he's doing it
for all the right reasons.
He loves her.
I still don't understand
why you're letting his
asinine comments bother you.
Sue, how could
they not bother me.
Because they would only
bother you if they were true.
ook, he's my brother
an d my best man.
He's supposed to
be supportive.
Just think about what his
speech is going to be like.
To Paulie and Sue, I think
you're making a huge mistake.
But good luck, you're
gonna need it.
What do you think, Paulie.
You think we're
making a mistake.
What?
What are you
talking about.
No.
Well are you excited
to get married?
Sue, of course I'm
excited to get married.
ook, all I'm sayin g
is maybe Jimbo shouldn't
be the best man,
if he feels the
way he does.
I mean think about it, it
just doesn't feel right.
How do you feel, Paulie?
Would you still propose to
me if I weren't pregnant?
Of course.
But...
Iook...
It's an unfair question,
because you are pregnant.
And, I'm not going to put
myself into a hypothetical.
If you're doing this outta some
kind of obligation, Paulie,
then you can
forget about it.
I want to get
married to you.
'Cause I love you.
But if you don't feel
the same way about me,
then you can just
forget about it.
Sue, Sue,
Of course I feel
the same way.
You know, you're
being irrational.
Yes, I love you,
but can I say
that positively,
I'm ready to get
married and have kids?
I don't know.
Excuse me?
Then what are we
doing here, Paulie!
This is real life, okay.
These are the cards
we were dealt.
The cards we were dealt?
This is not a God
damn hand of poker
that's poppin' out
of my belly, Paulie!
Sue, this is crazy, we're
getting married in 3 days.
I just told you
what my brother said
'cause it pissed me off!
Oh, Jesus.
You know what I
was thinking,
You should get into
upper management.
I was in upper management.
No, I'm not
talking about work,
I'm talking about, your family.
Your wife.
You guys should
start a family.
It'd settle you down, man.
Get rid of all that
noise in your head.
Where's this coming from?
It's just...
You have a kid,
you walk in light.
It gives you a reason to
wake up in the morning.
Walk in the light?
Yeah.
What, Too much?
Too heavy?
Yo.
What the fuck?
What?
Where are you?
I'm gettin'
lunch with Dez.
Why?
You asked me if you could
work a couple days this week.
Don't you remember asking
me if you could work today?
Did we say today?
Yeah, we said today.
I fuckin' forgot, I was
gettin' tuxedo's with Dez.
Yeah.
I got mine this
morning, nice.
Cummerbun d.
Forget about it,
it's all over.
Man, I got Dez, we
can't do this tomorrow?
No, we can't do
it tomorrow.
Tomorrow's Paulie's
softball game.
Yo, Jimbo, you're really
kind of screwing me here,
I'm short a man.
I got a job to do.
come on, Mike, God damn it,
I'm going through
some shit in my life.
Real shit right now, and
you give me a hard time
about edgin g some
fuckin' lawn.
I'll talk to you later.
Wally chara, never
walked onto the mound.
So my little guy
is jumping up and
down on the bed, right.
And he says to me, say,
hey dad, pull my finger, right.
So I pull his finger,
but instead of farting,
the little guy,
he's in shorts and
he shits himself!
The little guy shits
himself right there.
What did you do?
I said, "Son, you're an
idiot, clean your shit up."
Well, that's really
understanding of you man.
If you shit yourself,
you got to pick it up.
I don't like that story at
all, it's kinda of sad.
You know cousin, Mike, you
have to tell the story
about the time you
pissed your pants.
Which time was that?
What time was that...
Sisters Dorothy's class.
I think you
were 1 1 th grade.
Sister Dorothy's
class was 4th grade.
You know what,
let Jimbo tell it.
'cause he was
in the class,
he sat right behind me.
6th grade.
What's the difference,
I pissed my pants,
who cares what
grade it was.
Okay, so we're in
Sister Dorothy's class
and Mikey's sitting two
seats up in front of me.
He says, raises his hand,
"can I go to the bathroom?"
She says, "No."
All right, so
ten minutes pass,
he raises his
hand again, says,
"can I go to the bathroom?"
And she says, "No," again.
And she knows
I'm suffering,
'cause she can see
the pain in my eyes.
And you know what,
she doesn't care,
because she's a nun.
And she likes to
see kids suffer.
Yeah, and this
is a big day.
We had these
special reports,
this book report.
You had done, uh...
you'd drawn this
picture of Tom Seaver.
Remember you spent
days doing it,
this really passionate...
It was awesome!
It had to be passionate.
It was about the '69 Mets.
Right?
Tom Seaver,
your favorite.
So I drew a picture
of Tom Terrific
on the mound.
Wham, with that fast ball,
inside-out cuttin' action.
Go ahead.
So, some other kid's
readin' his report.
And I hear whimpering.
And I look up, and it's
Mikey and he's shakin'.
Okay, and I wonder what
the Hell is going on.
Iook down and I notice
there's a big...
There's a pool of
piss in his seat.
And it's dripping down,
right on top of Tom Seaver.
Right on top of this
report this poor kid,
and then the other
kids are noticing.
And he starts to cry.
Okay, then Sister
Dorothy notices,
and you know
what she says.
She says, "Stop
being such a baby."
That's fucked up.
Yeah, but what does
my big brother do?
I mean, the protector
of all of us.
Jimbo, check this out,
comes over to my desk,
grabs me by my hand,
he says "come on,
we're leaving."
And he just walks me
through the class.
And he walks me
right up to the door,
and Sister Dorothy goes,
"Where do you two
think you're going?"
How the fuck have I
never heard this story?
You've heard this
story before.
I've never heard
this story, before.
You were probably too
busy worrying about
how to get the band together
or something like that.
You guys don't
want to rock?
I do want to rock.
I just don't want you
to keep asking me
what fuckin' dot we're on.
You're a bunch of dicks, I don't
know why I call you friends.
Come on, let Jimbo
finish his story.
And I said, "Get
out of our way."
No, that's not
what he said,
that's not what he said.
Jimbo looks at Sister
Dorothy and says,
I quote,
"Get the fuck
out of our way."
But here's the best part.
What's better than that?
Here's the best part,
She does.
She clears outta the way,
they walk right out
of the front door of
the school and go home.
That's the kind of
big brother I got.
To big Jim, huh.
My best man.
I'll toast to that!
Jimbo, that was
beautiful, man!
What about me I'm the one
that pissed my pants.
Paulie, would
you be pissed at me
if I didn't come
to your wedding,
'cause I'm startin' to
feel kin da weird about it.
Look, I know you're drunk,
so I'm not going to pay
too much attention to this,
but what the Hell are
you feelin' weird about?
I don't even have
a girlfriend,
I don't have a girlfriend,
I live in the same house
I grew up in, I
have the same job
I had when I was
in High School.
That'd be great if
I was 23 years old,
but I'm not 23 years old.
I'm 33 years old.
When am I goin g to have a
family, he's got a family,
he's got two
beautiful boys.
You're starting a family.
Where's my family.
What, when I'm an old man?
What's that got to do with
you not going to his wedding.
A lot!
I don't want everyone
asking me about Jen
and be answering questions
about Jen all night!
Who's going to be asking?
Who?
Listen to me, Michael.
You're my cousin, right?
You're coming to my wedding.
All right, Paulie.
Go to bed.
Get some sleep.
I'm gonna call her.
No, no, you're not going to
call anybody, all right.
You're going to go to
bed, we've got softball
first thin g in the mornin g.
Hey, see you tomorrow!
Hey, why don't you wake up
the whole neighborhood.
Smarten up!
Enough already!
My kids are sleeping.
I'm sorry, Dez.
Hey, Pop, let's go fish!
Ain't gettin' married
so much fun?
Oh yeah, lot of fun.
Lot of fun.
Every time a
guy gets married,
he gets divorced
from his friends.
And his buddies
are never going to be a hundred
percent supportive of that.
This has been
a weird week.
You know, I mean, like...
Jimbo all of a sudden
seemed like his
old-self tonight, right?
Yeah.
I should just keep
him as the best man,
but then I have
cousin Mike
telling me he doesn't want
to go to the fuckin' wedding.
What the Hell
is that about?
It's training
you for kids.
It's God's way of
training you for kids.
I mean, every
day you wake up,
they can have completely
different personalities.
Trust me.
Man I got to tell you
Dez, I'm freaking out
about that man.
I mean, how do you
the whole kids thing?
Honestly?
You have one kid,
you loose a little bit of
your life, little free time,
little bit of
your freedom.
You have two kids,
life is over, Joe-Joe.
So why do it, I mean...
Why did you and Tina
have another kid?
What do you do with
your free time?
Honestly, what do you do?
You watch TV.
You go and hang out with
these knuckle heads.
You jerk off, right.
isten to me,
Free time, it's not all
it's cracked up to be.
But at the end
of the night.
If I couldn't...
you know...
If I couldn't
go upstairs...
check in on
my little boys,
if I couldn't
look at them,
make sure they're okay.
My life...
My life would be empty,
is what it would be.
There are people
that know,
and there are people
that don't know.
And you my man, are about
to be a man that knows.
All right man.
- All right.
- All right, thank you.
- No fear.
- Sleep tight.
Paulie.
You know I'm doin' this
whole band thing for you,
so, you know, if you
don't wanna do it,
Just let me
know, all right.
Dez, I'm into
it, all right.
Nice.
That's good, hey,
if you could just
get the other guys
a little excited about
it, that would great.
It's important.
Really important
that we do this.
All right?
Paulie,
and just remember
when we rock out,
shirts are optional, baby.
Go to bed, Desmond.
Shh.
These guys are
in uniforms,
we're gonna get crushed.
All right, let's
bring it in here!
All right now, come
on, take a knee.
Get your hat off, Jimbo,
let's go, hats off.
I'm good,
I'm good.
Our father who art in
heaven, hallowed be thy name,
thy kingdom come,
thy will be done.
on Earth is it
is in Heaven.
Give us this day,
our daily bread.
Forgive us for
our trespasses,
as we forgive those who
trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from evil.
- Amen.
All right, bring it
in here real quick,
we do burned tongue on three.
One, two, three!
Burned tongue!
It's going
right out there!
Come on, Jimbo!
Come on!
All right Jimbo,
get ready to move!
Come on, Paulie,
do your thin g!
Come on, Paulie!
Paulie!
coney Island, huh?
What do you say
to that, hotdog!
Come on, big mouth!
Oh, Tc, you stink!
Nice rip, cuz'.
Good to see you've
been the cages.
Nice one, Mike!
Way to go,
I got it!
What the fuck is your
fuckin' problem!
What the fuck are
you talking about!
It was my ball,
you shouldn't even
tried to fuckin' get it.
They why didn't
you get it!
Because you fuckin'
called for it!
I didn't want to get
barreled over by you!
Fuck you!
isten, next time
I call for it,
clear the fuck out, I'm
the center fielder.
Hey, you know what
Jimbo, fuck you, man.
No, fuck you, man!
Go fuck yourself!
Fuck you!
You've been a fuckin'
prick every...
All right, break it up!
Get off!
Fuckin' prick!
Fuck you, Paulie!
I'll fuck you up!
Hey, hey, hey!
Knock it off!
Fuck man!
Paulie, come on.
You know what?
I'm fuckin'
done, all right!
I'm goin' home!
Good, you big
pussy go home!
Boohoo!
And you know,
another thing Jimbo,
how about this,
You're not going
to be my best man!
How about that,
you fuckin' prick!
What, because of this?
Yeah, because of this!
It's a fuckin'
softball game,
I'm your fuckin' brother!
Well then why don't you
fuckin' start actin g like one,
you fat fuck!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, Paulie,
I don't want to part
of your wedding anyway.
Fuck your fucking wedding.
Don't say anything you're
going to regret man.
Fuck you!
And I'm the fuckin'
center fielder, bitch!
can I talk to you
about something?
Jesus christ, baby, It's
not a good time, trust me.
Just hear me out, 'cause
I really need to talk to you.
Why does everyone fuckin'
need to talk to me right now?
Are you crying?
ike you give a shit.
Of course I give a shit, baby,
my brother just fuckin'
wigged out on me.
Just keep it
together, all right.
Yoou're a selfish
fuckin asshole!
You know that!
What do you want me to do!
Just go to Hell!
You want to talk!
Yeah, I want to talk!
All right, let's talk!
Right now!
- et's talk!
- Talk to me!
Fuck you, I can't
stan d your face!
Bullshit, I'm listening,
talk to me right now.
I'm fuckin' waiting,
I'm right here!
I'm going to
take a shower!
My fuckin brother...
Fuck!
Hello?
Hey Julianna,
it's Paulie,
Is Jimbo around?
Oh no, he just left.
lf, umm...
if you speak to him later,
could you have him call me.
We just had a stupid situation
at the softball game.
And I just don't like
the way I left things.
Fine Paulie, if I hear
from him, I'll tell him.
Hey, is everything
all right,
you soun d, you
soun d a little upset.
Everything's fine.
I'll pass along
the message, okay.
Boys, where you at!
We're in here, Dad!
Hey, grab your axes,
let's practice.
Dad, we practiced
all ready.
Yo, gentlemen, when I ask
you to do something,
I expect you to do it.
Let's go, chop-chop!
come on.
What you
talkin' about?
Blues is awesome.
Okay what were we
working on last week?
Dad, you know our
band is so lame.
What is it?
overboy,
somethin g like that.
Loverboy, '85,
the best of,
Let's go.
No.
Rock out.
Fine.
I'll slap a
headband on you.
Go.
No.
Grab your bass.
Just play.
That's it, listen
to each other.
I was born to run,
i was born to dream
The craziest boy
you've ever seen
I got to do it my way
Or no way at all
And I was here to please,
I'm even on my knees
Makin' love to
whoever I please
I got to do it my way
Or no way at all
Mike, don't you
even want to know
why I didn't call
you all these years.
I really don't give a
shit at this point, Tc.
come on, come on, don't
you think it would have
to be something really
heavy for me
to take off and not
tell you about it,
comeo on.
We shared everything,
man, when my mom died,
who did I go to first, Huh?
I went to you.
We shared everything.
Yeah, so I thought.
I also thought,
we were going
to go in together
on my Dad's
landscaping business.
Not me, We.
Both of us.
I know, I know.
No one knows how
to get hold of you.
Your father doesn't even
know where to reach you.
And then I'm left
holding the bag
on the landscaping
business.
I know I didn't
handle it right, okay.
Handle it?
You didn't
handle anything,
what the fuck
did you handle?
Mike, I'm gay.
What?
The reason I left, is
because I'm a homosexual.
You didn't talk to
me for eight years,
'cause you're a gay?
That doesn't even
make fuckin' sense.
It does make sense, 'cause
when I told my Dad about it,
he couldn't
deal with it,
so what made me
think my friends
could handle it
any better, huh?
Because we were
your friends!
And I was your
best friend, man!
Jesus christ, what
did you think,
I wasn't going to
talk to you again
for the rest of our lives?
That's what wound up
happening anyway,
why didn't you
gamble on me, man!
'cause I just didn't
think you'd understand.
So you take my Tom Seaver
fuckin' rookie card?
That was my favorite
card in the world!
That's the one you take?
No, do you want to know
why I stole your
Tom Seaver card?
Yeah.
You want to know why I
stole your Tom Seaver card.
I just said I
want to know,
what are we arguing about?
I was pissed at you
man, that's why.
can you imagine
being gay,
and having your best friend
making faggot jokes
24-7 every God
damn day of your life!
Don't be such a
"fudge-packer" this.
"Take it up the ass" that.
Can you imagine bein g me?
Be me for a
God damn day!
So, I took the one thing I
knew would piss you off!
You son of a bitch!
Dad!
Fuck you!
Yo!
What up B',
what are you
doing around here,
you going to see your Dad?
Naw, hell no.
Just walking around,
clearing my thoughts.
You know.
What about you, get over
your little tantrum?
I will after the drink
I'm about to have.
What is with you,
you're getting a drink,
you don't invite me, I
go away for 8 years
and all of a sudden
I'm an outcast?
Shut the fuck up, get in.
That's right.
come on, son.
Gary, get off my car.
How many times
do I to tell you.
Go join the Army
like your brother.
I got five messages from
you, what do you want?
What's up, twins.
et me get a crun ch.
I know why Tc took my
Tom Seaver rookie card.
He told me.
There's your crunch.
He took my Tom Seaver
rookie card because he's gay.
And he was mad at me
because I kept
making gay jokes
all through
high school.
He's a gay guy, our best
friend's a gay guy,
and we're all making gay
jokes, I felt terrible,
but you made gay
jokes too, right?
No, because I knew, I
knew before he did,
I knew back in high school.
How did you know
he was a gay?
I was with him down
by the shore and...
just you know.
I knew.
How would you know,
are you a gay?
No.
Only on the weekends,
but don't tell my wife,
pay for my crunch.
et me get a screwball.
come on, today.
You know you're parked
in front of my house,
this one's on the arm.
Now this,
this is where we should
have a bachelor party at.
What is this?
Oh man, come on.
You're a married guy,
what are you doing here?
You're not.
Yeah, I don't like
these joints, man.
Why, man, it's
fuckin g great!
I'll tell you
something buddy,
for the next hour,
I'm not married, you
know what I'm saying?
Gentlemen put your
hands together
for the PBaroness
of PBurlesque!
Chrystal!
Oh, and here he is, one
of our regulars, Jimbo.
Hi, Jimbo...
Two whiskey's up here.
Hey, chrystal, I didn't
know you worked Fridays.
charming place.
ooks all right to me.
Hey, Mr. B!
Hey Jimbo, what
do you say?
Who's your friend?
This is my friend Tc,
he's been my friend
since we were 3 years old
now he gives me a hard
time, just like you do.
What are you giving
Jimbo a hard time about?
I'm actually not, I'm just
trying to make sure he's okay,
that's all.
Yeah, I'm fine.
I can tell you,
he is not okay.
Look at him.
It's the middle
of the afternoon,
he's a married man
and he's in a titty bar.
If that's doin' okay,
the world
is upside down.
Don't you start
in on me. All right.
What do I tell this bum
every time I see him?
He's lucky.
He's lucky, he don't
know real hardship.
He's like all the
kids your age.
They're fuckin' babies,
crying all the time.
Cryin' all the time instead
of knowin' you's are lucky.
et me ask you
a question, TC.
Are you married?
Oh, Jesus christ.
I've heard this speech
before, excuse me,
I'm going to
be at the bar.
No, sit down,
Stay two seconds.
Learn something
for a change.
Are you married?
No sir, no I'm not.
- Any kids?
- No.
You ever been
in the service?
- No.
- See that figures,
Because if you had
gone into the service,
they would teach
you how to be a man.
Oh, really?
Instead, you stay home
with your mother,
living in the same house
you were born in for 25 years.
What happens?
She teaches you how
to be a cheerleader.
Definition of an adult
is a person that has
a job, is married,
has kids,
and owns a home.
Okay.
When I was growing up,
the average age of
an adult, by that definition,
was 24 years old.
Now how old are you?
I'm 35, sir.
Christ had already
died on the cross
for your sins by that age.
Why don't you have
a wife and kids?
'cause I'm gay, sir.
That's why.
Hey Jimbo, come
on, any day.
I think we should
get out of here.
come on.
I'm having a drink with
my friend chrystal.
I think we should go,
come on, let's go.
Dude, if you wanna go, go.
I just got here, man.
come on, I want to talk
to you over here.
If you wanna fuckin' go
Tc, just fuckin' go!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
everything all right here?
Yeah, it's fine.
Everything's okay?
Yoeah, he's a
frien d of mine.
Excuse me ma'am, can I talk
to him for a minute, please?
Tc, stop.
Fuck.
Think of Julianna,
come on.
Don't you dare fuckin'
bring that shit up.
Exactly, think about it.
This is not
going to fix it.
Tc, you are so fuckin'
close to gettin' slapped.
Just get the fuck
outta my face.
come on, I'm gonna
ask you one last time.
Please come with
me right now.
Okay, I tried man.
I tried.
Shut the fuck up.
Uh oh!
I hear thunder!
ook at the ol'
man, he's an animal!
Who's an animal!
Look if you want her,
don't be a wuss,
go and get her.
I'm not a wuss, Pop.
come on, she just don't
want to be bothered,
that's all.
Suit yourself.
All right, Pops,
come on, let's go!
Go get 'em, old man!
Use the jab,
Pop, use the jab!
Jenny!
Hey Jen!
Jennifer!
Come on out!
Jenny!
Mike, why are you here?
'Cause I love you, Jen.
All right, I
love you so much.
I can't get you
outta my life.
I need you.
Hey, hey.
You're scaring me.
I don't know any
other way to say this,
but I never want to
see you again.
Why am I scaring you Jen,
I just want to get
you back in my life.
That's all.
Okay, we're never getting
back together again, okay.
It's over.
I never want to
see you again.
I don't want to be
friends, you know,
I don't want anymore
of your visits.
I don't want
shit from you!
So please, leave me alone
and get on with your life.
- Jen...
- It's over.
What happened Jen, what?
What did you do
to her, Michael!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
He didn't do anything.
No, what are you
doing here, Mike,
why are you
upsetting my sister?
I'm not trying to upset
your sister, Top cat.
I'm just trying to
get back in my life,
that's all.
She doesn't want to get
back together with you.
She told you that already.
isten to me, I don't want
to see you aroun d here again.
Or I'm going to have to do
something you don't like.
What are you going
to do Top cat,
you're 1 9 years old.
You're 1 9!
Don't be stupid!
Listen to me,
don't you be stupid
and make Top cat angry.
Watch your hands.
Angry?
What about my
level of anger!
Is anybody here concerned
about how angry I am!
All right, I'm going
to give you 3 seconds.
Get in your truck and go.
One.
Two.
Dick.
Ugh!
Oh, you asshole!
You hit me!
Yeah.
I told you to get
out of here, man.
So you hit me when I
wasn't paying attention.
Yes, and I'm going
to hit you again
unless you get in
the truck and go.
You've changed, Top cat.
Hey, Jen, I got
news for you,
you'll never find a guy like
me again as long as you live.
I'm a good guy, Jen.
And you blew it.
How'd it go, son?
Not so good, Pop.
All right, why don't you
go into the living room,
lie down, put
on the Met game,
I'll make us a
meatloaf, how's that?
That sounds
really good, Pop.
Hey babe, the
crib is done.
And it looks terrific.
Good.
Do you think you'll finish
painting her room tomorrow?
can't the painting
wait a week?
I mean, we're getting
married this weekend, babe.
I don't want it to wait.
Why does it need
to be tomorrow?
Because her
room being done,
makes thin gs
feel real to me.
It's important.
So waiting until
after the weekend
is going to make
it feel less real?
Yes.
We said we'd have it
done by the wedding.
I'm gonna get a beer.
Tc?
Jimbo, this
isn't good, man.
What's up, man, I thought
you left hours ago.
This isn't good.
No, this is good.
And it's none of your
fuckin' business.
Miss, look, just
go back, okay.
He's a happily
married man.
Shut the fuck up.
We're going for a drink.
We're just goin g
for a fuckin' drink.
Look you...
Shut the fuck up, Tc!
isten, you know
Jimbo, I'll just...
Chrystal, come on,
don't listen to him.
we're just goin g
for a drink.
et her get inside, let
her go inside, she's fine.
God damn it, what the
fuck are you doin g, man!
Let her go, okay.
What the fuck
are you doin g!
Think about this,
just think about it.
Think about your wife.
Think about how it will ruin
your whole fuckin' marriage.
My fuckin' marriage
is shit anyway!
My marriage is fucked man!
Yoou want to know what's
fuckin' wron g with me?
You want to know
what's fuckin' wrong,
is that what it is?
Huh?
Is that what my
wife wants to know?
Did she send you?
She didn't send me.
Is that what my fuckin'
brother wants to know
and his perfect
little fuckin' wife?
What's wrong with
Jimbo, is that it?
Just relax, sit
down right here,
I'm gonna get
some coffee.
I don't want fuckin'
coffee, all right!
Look it's all
gonna work out.
It's not gonna work
out, it's fucked,
you know why?
Why?
You know why
Julianna hates me?
She doesn't hate you.
She should, and
you know why?
I can't have kids man.
What do you mean,
you can't have kids?
She wants babies,
she wants babies,
and for a year we
were fucking trying.
And it wasn't
happenin', man.
So a couple of
months ago,
I went to the doctor and
he told me I had some
hypothalamic pituitary, shit...
sperm shit...
I'm totally and
completely infertile man.
Man, I'm sorry.
No chance of havin' a kid.
I didn't know...
I can't have a kid,
you think she's going
to fuckin' stay with me
if I can't have a kid.
She's going to
understand...
No she's not going to
fuckin' understand.
Paulie's going
to have a kid.
to have a kid,
my little brother he's
going to have a kid.
That's what a
fuckin' man is.
Someone who
can have a kid.
My little brother's going to
have a fuckin' kid and I can't.
I can't even be
his best man,
what the fuck.
He was my best man!
Hey Sue, I'm thinkin'
about going to Dez's
for a couple of beers
tonight, if that's all right?
It's almost midnight.
Actually, it's only 1 1 1 5.
Actually, that's not the point.
Paulie, the point
is, is that I'm pregnant
and I'm gettin' scared
because and you're
so off in your own shit
an d your own feelin gs
an d here I am,
just sittin g here waitin g
for you to take care of me.
Sue, look, I mean I think
you're kind of over reacting...
I mean I did take
care of the crib today.
All right, I did
finish the crib.
Over-reacting?
It's been months, since
you've given me flowers.
How about a little
romance, Paulie?
You know what would
be nice, occasionally,
breakfast in bed.
Or-or...
better yet, how
about a foot massage?
Do you know-do you
know what it's like.
to be on your feet all day,
five an d a half
months pregnant,
planning a wedding
that your fiancee
has absolutely no interest in,
And working your ass off?
You know what,
Sue, I mean look,
I don't see you making
me breakfast in bed.
You are not fucking
pregnant, Paulie!
And I have to do everything!
And when you actually
do contribute,
it's like pulling teeth.
ike the God damn
crib for example.
'cause I'm not under
any pressure, right?
I'm runnin' around all week
trying to keep everybody happy.
But that's nothin'.
What about my happiness?
Oh, please, Sue, look.
I-I don't mean to
sound unsympathetic.
But why does it always
have to come back to you?
Why?
Paulie, I'm so sorry.
You have so many
outings to plan.
The softball games,
and the fishing trips,
and the golf outings.
Your stupid fuckin' band.
You know what,
that's a lot.
You know what, fine.
I'll just stay home, okay?
No, it's not about that.
I miss my friend.
I just want my friend back.
And I don't even
know if you want this,
if you want me?
If you want this
baby or any of this,
this whole life.
What?
Hey, it's me, Tc.
Look, I need a favor.
Well, then you called
the wrong guy, Tc!
Oh, come on, I don't
need this right now.
I got Jimbo right
here passed out.
He's in a bad way, he's
been drinking all day.
I just don't want
to bring him home.
Did you call Paulie?
Paulie doesn't need to deal
with this shit, right now.
Paulie!
Come on, relax.
All right, bring him over here.
But listen, Tc, listen
real close, okay?
Such an ass, man.
Un, dues, tres, quatorze.
Shut the Hell
up, that's awful!
I know it sounds awful!
That's why I'm practicing!
What the Hell is this?
It's Jimbo, Dad, he's all drunk.
You're a pack of idiots.
What did we do?
We're helpin' him out.
We got to get him some coffee.
What is this?
It's "Little House on the Prairie."
Get him on the couch.
How'd this happen?
How'd this happen, practice.
How else does it happen?
He's a drunk!
I'll talk to him in morning.
Son of a bitches, waking me
up the middle of the night.
You were up anyway,
watchin' porno.
What are you
arguing about?
Jimbo, cover yourself up.
Jimbo, look... hey!
Daddy, I was joking!
You got to be fuckin' kidding me.
You said, "don't see you
making me breakfast in bed."
Well, she was screaming
her head off at me.
You know, like
a crazy woman.
She's pregnant, she's
allowed to scream at you.
All the time?
Yeah, It's
called hormones.
Look, I know I'm supposed to
be excited for the wedding,
and for the most part I am.
The thing that
scares me
are those moments
when I'm not excited.
Like, tonight for
example, you know?
can I just say, I think
you're blowing it?
I mean, that's just her,
she's looking for something.
She's asking for help.
And you're sitting
here at this bar.
What are you doing?
You know what it is, Dez?
It's like... a
wedding is one thing...
There's all the insanity
that goes around that,
and preparing for that.
And everyone gets nervous
before they get married.
But... you know, we got a kid
coming in a couple of months.
A kid that we didn't plan for.
And I guess I'm just...
I don't know if I'm...
If I can be a good dad.
You know, I don't know if I can do it.
et me paint you this
little scenario, okay?
Sue gets done
with your indecision.
All right, she can't
deal with it anymore,
you guys break up.
And say down the road, like
three years down the road,
she meets this guy
and he's a great guy.
And he's not a coward.
And there's some night
you'll have visitation rights.
And this guy- this guy
he's reading
stories to your kid.
He is tucking
your kid into bed.
This other man is
loving your kid.
And at some point your,
you know, your boy
or your girl is going to
start calling this guy Daddy.
Fuck, I'm not sayin g I want
some other guy raise my kid.
I'm just saying...
ook, I love Sue an d
I want the baby I'm just...
Then there's no problem.
All right, listen,
there's no problem.
Go home.
Thank you, Desmond.
My gosh.
He's out like a
light in there.
Where did you guys go?
He took me someplace
call the F oxy Hunt,
something like that.
Apparently he's a
platinum member too.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Son, you don't
go there, do you?
No, Pop, I would
never go there.
- Good.
- Not Mikey.
All right, boys,
that's it for me.
You'll clean up,
won't you, son?
Yes, Pop.
Good to see you, Tony.
Yeah, good to see
you, Mister Sullivan.
My boy will forgive
you eventually.
He gets that stubborn
streak from his mother.
But she always
came around too.
- I love you, Pop.
- Love you too.
- Good night.
et me ask you a
question about bein g gay.
Off the record, all right?
- Uh-huh.
- Off the record.
Fine, fine.
Off the record.
Dating, that's got to
be kinda weird, right?
Mikey, what are
you getting at?
Okay, it's got to be easier
to date if your gay, right,
because with girls it's, you
got to know what she likes,
an d it's a whole deal.
But with guys, guys
are horny all the time,
you just meet two
guys and boom.
Actually it would just
be easier that way.
It's the same thing, man,
you want to meet somebody,
just hook up, get your
leather stretched, whatever.
That's easy, man.
But if you want to meet
somebody and make it special,
make it count, that's
tough too, man.
That's always tough,
no matter what you are.
You know what I mean?
I probably should have
thought this through
before we got into
all the particulars.
You asked.
I know I asked.
It's just...
I'm just trying
to be honest, man.
Uncle Liam.
Morning, James.
You feeling the pain?
Oh, yeah.
I hit it pretty
hard last night.
How did I get here?
Tc brought you over last night.
You passed out.
But don't worry,
we called Julianna.
she knows you're here.
Pops, did I do
anything really stupid?
come on inside, I'll
make you breakfast.
Good morning.
Morning.
Hmm.
Flowers.
Breakfast.
What is missing
in this picture?
What could possibly
be missing?
A foot massage.
You did really good, Paulie.
I like the bedroom.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
So you two have kissed
and made up, huh?
Yeah, we made up, but
there's no kissin' goin' on.
- Not yet.
- You're not my type.
You think Jimbo knows?
Not a chance.
Knows what?
How about you, Pops,
you know my secret?
I'm old, I'm not stupid.
What secret?
Guess.
Man, I'm way to fuckin' hung
over to guess anything, what?
Check it out, right, TC is gay.
Bullshit.
That's right, I got a
boyfriend to prove it.
He's got a boyfriend.
Good for you.
Yeah.
Jesus christ, Pop!
I can see your feet!
Paulie, hey listen...
Before you say anything,
I know I've-I've been a
prick all week and ahh...
Can we talk?
It's pretty important.
I didn't know how
to deal with it.
I still don't know if
I can deal with it.
You two can still
have kids, Jim.
You two can adopt.
Oh, God, come on, that's
what the Doctor said.
It's such bullshit, Paul.
It's not the same
thing and you know it.
It is the same thing.
Any asshole can get
a girl pregnant, all right?
That doesn't take any talent.
But to be a dad,
to be a good dad.
Doesn't seem to be too
many guys that can do that.
When I found out you
two were having a kid,
I just snapped.
I did, I mean, you're my
younger brother, okay?
An d you had your world together
an d my life's fallin g apart.
It's not supposed to be that way.
you were the punk kid
who was trying to hang out
with me and my friends.
Yeah, you liked it
better when you could
beat the shit out
of me everyday, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, I liked that a lot.
Seriously, umm...
I know I've been tough the last
couple of months to deal with.
I'm sorry.
Can you forgive me?
Of course, man, come
on, you're my brother.
Just talk to me next time,
don't let it get weird like this.
What about Julianna, you know?
I can't...
This shit is so hard for
me, this emotional stuff.
You just got to tell her
as straight as you can.
Just be honest.
I can't call her,
send her e-mail.
Can you do it for me?
Look man, you're
gonna be fine.
Just tell her the
same way you told me.
She's gonna to leave me.
She's not gonna leave
you, she loves you.
Why?
A year from now, you're
going to adopt a kid
and you're going to have a
big fat smile on your face.
My chinese and
Romanian kids can play
with your kid.
Well, is everything all right?
The guys called
me last night
in the middle of the
night and I woke up,
what the Hell is
wrong with you?
Listen.
There's something I got to
talk to you about, okay?
Okay.
Okay, I know I've been really
hard to be around for awhile.
Don't think I'm not
aware of that, okay?
But there's a reason,
it isn't just things
were bad at work...
A couple of months ago
I went to see a doctor, right?
It's okay, baby, what's wrong?
Okay, you're scaring me.
They did some tests.
He told me I
can't have kids.
I knew how bad
you wanted them.
I thought you were
gonna leave me.
You can't leave me.
It's okay.
I was so worried.
If you need to leave
me, I understand.
I just want you
to be okay.
Tc, you got to go,
it's your Father.
It's the right
thing to do.
I don't think it's a
good idea, I just don't.
It is.
He's your father.
If I can take it,
he can take it.
He loves you more
than anybody on Earth.
You're his son.
Go ahead. Good luck.
All right, thanks.
Sure you don't
want me to stay?
No, I'm good. Thanks, man.
Gay pride, woo hoo!
Dad?
Dad, it's me, Tc.
Look...
Perdóneme.
You look great, man.
Oh, I feel like crap.
I don't know, man.
come on, you know
you need to do this.
Why do I need to do it?
That's stupid that
I need to do this.
Come on, don't be a can dy ass,
You know what you
need to do, do it.
Look, he probably
didn't mean it.
He was probably just
caught up in the moment.
et's not make a whole
big thin g out of it.
For Christ's sake, why
don't you go by an d hug him?
You wonder why your
kids are juvenile delinquents.
Mike, he's not a good
guy, go get your revenge.
What she says.
She'll say anything you say.
Look what she does.
That's not true.
I have my own mind.
All right, come on, hurry up.
Top cat!
That's disgusting.
Really, really disgusting.
Hey, Sue!
Sue, you home?
Yeah.
Hey, come on.
I got a surprise for you.
You didn't need
to do this, Paulie.
This is beautiful, but...
unnecessary.
Yeah, well I absolutely
had to do this.
All right, give me...
Give me your
engagement ring.
- What?
- Give me your ring.
All right Sue, I know for
the last couple of weeks...
Maybe even the last
couple of months,
I haven't been the man
I'd promised you I'd be
when I first did this,
PBut I want you to know
from this moment forward
you have me fully, all right?
As your friend,
and as your husband,
And as the father to our baby.
And you know I want
that baby, Sue.
You know that, right?
Yes.
Will you marry me?
Yes, I will.