Today we bring together...
...another fine group, another
generation of men and women...
...into the ranks
of our armed forces.
Please raise your right hand
and repeat after me.
I do solemnly swear...
INDUCTEES: I do solemnly swear...
...that I will support
and defend...
...the Constitution
of the United States...
...against all enemies...
...foreign and domestic.
So help me, God.
Congratulations.
Let's hear it for
these fine young gentlemen.
New recruits
of the armed forces.
ROBERT ACOSTA: I live here
in Santa Ana, like...
...you know, I'm not going nowhere.
I'm not gonna do nothing.
You know, my friends
are getting locked up.
So it's just like,
what's the point?
I mean, what's the point
of staying here?
You might as well just leave,
and then they start...
I talked to a recruiter,
and he starts telling me...
"Okay, you could go here, and you could
go there, and you could do this and that."
So it sounded good.
It did. It sounded good.
I'd been encouraged to talk to a
recruiter for the National Guard...
...and so I thought that
it would be a good way...
...to get money for school...
...and also learn medical, some medical
skills. And I went in as a medic.
I didn't join the active duty.
I joined the National Guard...
...and my recruiter told me
I would be stateside.
He said, " National Guard
doesn't get deployed.
"You'll receive
the college benefits.
"The only thing that will happen is if
there's ever a riot or anything like that...
"you will be deployed
for that."
But he was like, "Other than
that, you won't get sent overseas."
I grew up in a family where my
father was drafted during Vietnam...
...my grandfather was drafted
during World War II
...and spent three years
in the South Pacific.
And they hated the military,
in large part...
...but they got a lot
out of their experiences.
So I felt like I had an
obligation to give something back.
Because I didn't have to go,
it didn't mean I shouldn't go.
MELISSA STOCKWELL:
Freshman year of college...
I would see them around campus
and I kind of thought...
...it's something I wanted to do.
I absolutely love our country. I think
it's the greatest place in the world.
And so sophomore year
I signed up.
I saw Top Gun when I was in
eighth grade and I just, I knew.
I knew what I wanted to do.
I knew what I wanted to be.
And then I saw Marine when I was in
high school and I was like, "That's it."
They're mean, they're tough. They
got cool uniforms and chicks dig them.
MALE NARRATOR: Ever wondered what
it's really like to be a soldier?
What do you got? I've received
word from Alpha Company.
DT ready to be verified.
Verify.
MALE NARRATOR: Put yourself in
the picture with this free video.
You'll see over 200 great jobs in the
Army and over 180 in the Army Reserve.
You'll also see what skills you'll
learn, how you can earn money for college...
...even what soldiers do
in their free time.
Put yourself in the picture...
...and see what it's really like
to become an army of one.
When you advertise cigarettes...
...you see that little Surgeon
General on the side, right?
But they used to advertise
cigarettes where it used to be cool.
You used to see the
billboards, it used to be cool.
They advertised cigarettes
on being cool.
Now you got the military.
You don't see
no Surgeon General sign on it...
...that you might die from
bomb shrapnel or whatever.
That we might go to war
and lose a limb.
You don't see that. They advertise
the military as being a man.
"Fight for value.
This is great for you."
They don't tell you the
consequences. You understand?
AIDAN DELGADO:
I was one of those people...
...who didn't think about the full picture
of what being in military service...
Because recruiters
and Army people...
...they soft-pedal all of the
objectionable parts of the military.
I mean, you never hear
recruiters say, like...
"Oh, well, you may get
a chance to shoot prisoners."
Or, " You may get a chance
to abuse Iraqi civilians."
Or, " You may get a chance to
see your friends getting killed."
The killing...
...and the bloody business of the
military, they downplay that...
...because parents don't wanna hear it,
and people don't wanna think about it.
Is this for
training purposes only?
SOLDIER 1: And that little red button
right there, you'll press that button.
Oh.
SOLDIER 2: Push it.
The closest thing to combat...
...without pulling the trigger,
is Marine Corps recruiting.
And I'm the type of person,
I love a challenge.
The system is not designed for
the individual recruiter to excel...
...if you have ethical or moral,
you know, dilemmas in your life.
It's a system
designed to fraud...
...and to manipulate, lie, cheat,
beg, borrow and steal.
If you're willing to do that, then you'll
be successful at Marine Corps recruiting.
ACOSTA: They know
what they're doing.
They know where to go.
They know what to say.
And it's sad because it's just, like,
all these guys thinking, you know...
"For once in my life, I'm gonna
leave and I'm not coming back."
They go straight to Iraq.
"Here's the big book of all the
opportunities we have in the Marine Corps.
"What do you want to do?"
Pushed it across the desk
at me.
I looked him in the eye, and I pushed
it back across the desk, you know.
And I said, "I wanna be a
grunt. I wanna go blow shit up.
"That's what I wanna do."
That's what I got to do.
I got to go blow shit up.
While you talk
about health care...
...and you talk about pay and
your benefits, and, you know...
...and all these things that are
positives, without a doubt.
Educational benefits. I mean,
all these things, they're great.
That's not what your purpose
is in the military.
I mean,
your purpose is to kill.
I mean, that is your primary,
especially as an infantryman.
I mean, make no mistake about it, that's
what your purpose is, is to take life.
Aye, sir! Aye, sir!
CHARLIE ANDERSON:
It starts in basic training.
They systemically
break you down.
When they bring you in...
...they make sure that everybody
shows up in the middle of the night.
They keep you up
through the night.
ALL: Yes, sir.
Your day starts at 2:30
in the morning...
...and that happens
for the first couple of weeks.
And actually, through basic
training we got up after 4:00 once...
...because they want
to keep you tired.
Because that puts everybody
on the same wavelength.
DRILL SERGEANT: You will stay
awake, you understand me? Yes, sir!
Aye, sir! Aye, sir!
Huh?
I'm just...
Get the frick away from me,
you fricking turd!
Come here, son. How about you?
You already order portholes?
Yes, sir.
So what the fuck you coming up
here for? The screw doesn't...
Huh? Huh?
Now get up and go!
SOLDIERS: Aye, sir!
Get! Move!
SOLDIERS: Kill!
Go get them!
SOLDIERS: Yes, sir!
Yes, sir!
One of the most rare
discharges from the Marine Corps...
...is an administrative discharge
for failure to adapt.
Fricking bridge, son.
Now get a bridge.
Go get your fricking boot lace
and do it right.
RECRUIT 1: Aye, sir.
What are we doing?
RECRUIT 2: This recruit can't
find his left moon boot, sir.
RECRUIT 3: This recruit
can't find his left moon boot.
Well, hello, idiot!
What do you think happened?
It's fucking mixed up.
No, sir!
Aye, sir.
Aye, sir!
HUZE: The training program
is so effective...
...that the vast majority of
individuals who go through it...
...emerge from it as a warrior.
Harder. War cry!
Kill, kill! Say it!
RECRUIT: Kill.
Louder.
Kill!
War cry!
DAVID GROSSMAN: You will read
a hundred military manuals...
...and you'll never see
that four-letter word "kill."
You will talk to military
psychiatrists and psychologists.
And they will never
use the word "kill"
...and they do not want
to talk about killing.
And that is a pathology.
That is dysfunctional.
HUZE: Taking someone's life is
not something that's abnormal.
It's taking it when you're
not in a state of rage.
That's abnormal.
Being able to have
a sustained desire...
...is what requires training.
Kill, kill. Say it!
RECRUIT: Kill! Go. Go.
Go. Go.
I mean, every human being,
at one time or another...
...has probably had an overwhelming
urge to kill somebody.
You want to strangle that guy.
You're enraged.
You're red with rage
but you didn't kill him. Why?
Because somewhere inside the midbrain
of most healthy members of our species...
...is a resistance
to killing their own kind.
We slammed head-on into that
in World War II.
We found out the vast majority
of people wouldn't kill.
And so, by Vietnam,
we had crafted a technique...
...that makes killing
a conditioned reflex.
We're having
realistic simulations...
...and you take realistic
simulations of the weapon...
...and you shoot the target
and the target drops.
You're shooting your man-sized
target and you figure...
"Oh, it's gonna be no big deal."
And you've seen enough movies.
You pull the trigger,
bullet hits, they drop. Done.
GROSSMAN: The hardware in enabling
killing hasn't changed much.
The pistol, the rifle,
hasn't changed that much.
The software
has changed phenomenally.
The psychological process began
months before we entered Iraq.
And there was all sorts of, like,
chanting and songs about, you know...
"Kill ragheads.
Kill Osama bin Laden."
And then, like, the little targets that
would pop up for the range training...
...they call them, you know, bin
Ladens or Taliban or other...
...you know, ethnic things.
As well as the dehumanization,
you know...
...the hajis, the ragheads,
those kind of terms.
Bomb the village
Kill the people...
Do it Throw some napalm in the square...
Do it on a Sunday morning...
Kill them
on their way to prayer...
Ring the bell
inside the schoolhouse...
Watch those kiddies
gather around...
Lock and load with your 240
Mow them
little motherfuckers down...
I mean, it...
And if you get a whole group
of people singing this thing...
...it gets kind of catchy.
It's a group dynamic.
DRILL SERGEANT: One, two!
SOLDIERS: Kill.
HUZE: This is what's
instilled in you.
I mean, our war cry
in training, you know...
...like when you're approaching the target
and firing and live fire was "Kill babies."
SOLDIERS: Kill!
DRILL SERGEANT: Fuck!
SOLDIERS: Kill! Kill!
Songs about, you know,
going to a schoolyard...
...and breaking out your K-boy
and killing the kids there.
Or going to a shopping mall and, you
know, killing the women that are shopping.
I mean, these are cadence that
you sing while you're jogging.
DOUGHERTY: They have you do all
these different chants and cadences...
...about killing and stabbing or,
you know, and I just thought...
"Oh, my God! I can't believe
that we're saying this"
...when I first went
into basic training.
And then, as the weeks kind of went
on, you just go with it and you say it...
...and you don't really
think about it anymore.
'Cause it's just... They're
just words, you know. But...
So I think we're killers.
I mean, we're not killers...
...or we're trained killers,
but I don't know.
Well, am I going to be able to
do this when it comes down to it?
You know,
when I'm getting shot at?
Am I gonna flip out?
Am I gonna cry? You know.
You have no idea of how you're
gonna react until it actually comes.
But I wanted to know.
DRILL SERGEANT: Amen!
SOLDIERS: Up!
Chaplain comes out, grabs
the mike. Let us... Bitch.
Let us pray!
Down!
Amen!
Up!
HUZE: Someone, you know, or a group of
people make very well-thought-out decisions...
...about cadence, about training...
...so that by the time you actually need
it for real, you know, in a combat zone...
...that you don't stop
and become paralyzed with it.
Because then you're dead.
Everything is associated
around killing. Everything.
And I mean, sooner or later
it's gonna sink in...
...and after a while
you actually wanna do it.
Because, you know, you're looking forward
to go do what you've been trained for.
Well, I think
that's the difference...
...because you actually
start wanting to do it.
I mean, I did it.
I wanted to do it.
I wanted that experience.
I wanted to know
what it was like.
Somebody gotta be there
when it gets ugly...
when it gets bloody...
Somebody gotta
get their hands dirty...
Yep, it's a fucked-up job
But somebody's gotta do it...
Somebody gotta come up
with a plan...
And be there
when the shit hits the fan...
I hope
y'all out there understand...
Look, man,
it's a fucked-up job...
But somebody gotta be there
when it gets ugly...
Somebody gotta be there
when it gets bloody...
Somebody gotta
get their hands dirty...
Yep, it's a fucked-up job
But somebody's gotta do it...
The thing you have
to understand about Iraq
...is that there are
no front lines and rear lines.
The moment you get off the
plane, you're in harm's way.
This is a new war and the
action's kind of everywhere.
REIBER: When I was over there,
we were on a constant advancement.
And so there was never a single time
that we weren't open to mortar attacks...
...we weren't open to an ambush, we
weren't open to whatever it was.
ROBERT SCAER: There is
no sanctuary in this war.
In this war,
you're in combat all the time.
Not only if you're a combatant...
...but if you're a support
personnel. You're in the war zone.
It's a street-by-street
battle, a town-by-town battle...
...and the combatants
are invisible.
They look
just like the people.
DOUGHERTY: The enemy could be
anyone that you see.
You don't know
where to focus your attention.
where to focus your anger.
The aggression and the hatred...
...that would be focused on a clear enemy
gets focused on every single Iraqi.
REIBER: It was just constant, you
know, surrounded by hundreds of people...
...hundreds of Iraqis.
The majority of them
have AK-47 s.
And you're getting hit by bricks
and they don't want you being there.
You're so compromised,
you know.
You drive on one block and
children are playing football...
...and they're laughing and they're
screaming, "America, America."
And then on the very next block
you'll get shot at, blown up, RPG.
They were telling us
little kids were running up...
...and stabbing the sides
of the doors.
So we had to get ammo boxes...
...and break them up and put them
in the sides of the doors.
I mean, they weren't
gonna stop bullets...
...but they'd stop little kids
trying to stab the doors.
We put sandbags in all of our
vehicles. The Army we had, we made it.
DENVER JONES: They show on TV
...all this high-tech equipment
that we would have and all.
I never seen any of it.
I mean, like I said,
I had a Vietnam-era flak vest...
...no armored vehicles...
...no intel...
...no real direction.
DELGADO: I used to ask guys,
"What are we here for?"
You know,
"What are we doing in Iraq?"
And by and large what they said was,
"We're here because of September 11."
There was a disconnect between the
facts, or, you know, the reported news...
...and their, like,
emotional justification.
Most soldiers felt that what they
were doing was related to terrorism...
...either revenge or prevention.
To us, there really was
no mission. It was just...
The mission was, you know, just
get this crap over with and go home.
MULLINS: I've been on
over 150 combat missions...
...and, on most of those
missions, it had no purpose.
I grew up in Brooklyn. I've
been in a lot of fistfights.
And the one thing that I know is that if
someone hits me first, I'm pretty much done...
...you know,
if they get a good hit in.
And that's basically
what it was like in Iraq.
You wait for someone to sucker
punch you so you can punch back.
SARRA: You take
a 19-year-old kid...
...give him a rifle and as much
ammunition as he can carry...
...or put him behind the wheel
of a tank and tell him...
"You wanna go back home to your
girlfriend and all your buddies...
"and drinking beer and MTV and
Internet? Go destroy that city.
"Go through those guys that are trying
to stop you and I'll let you go home."
"Sir, yes, sir.
Done deal. See you."
MULLINS: Initially it's "Hey, I must do my
job, " and then it becomes, "I love this job."
All right,
get the fuck in there.
MULLINS: Some people just love to
shoot. Trigger-happy. And they'll shoot...
...not even
when something is wrong...
...but when they just think
something is wrong.
And I didn't wanna
cross that line, you know.
SARRA: We had been in a firefight,
we had been in an engagement.
The engagement was over and I see
this woman walking out in all black.
She's got a bag on her arm,
she's wearing a burka...
...and she's walking out
towards the armored vehicle.
And the guys on the amtrac start yelling,
waving their hands and telling her to stop...
...and they're raising
their weapons.
And I went, "Okay, one of
two things is gonna happen.
"This woman is gonna
put up her hands and surrender...
"and start talking
to the Marines...
"or she's gonna walk up
to these guys and explode."
If she blows up, she's gonna
kill a bunch of those guys...
...or wound a bunch of them. I've got
a clear shot with nothing behind her.
And this was all, I mean... This
was split-second, like, you know...
It happens that fast.
Pulled up my rifle,
took two shots at her.
I know I probably missed the first shot.
The second shot I'm pretty sure I hit her.
And as soon as
that second shot went off...
...the guys in the other vehicle
opened up and they cut her down.
She fell to the dirt and as she
fell she had a white flag in her hand...
...that she had
pulled out of her bag.
At that moment, right there,
I lost it.
I threw my weapon down
on the deck of the vehicle.
I was crying. I was like, " Oh, my God,
what are we doing here? What's happening?"
I had a gunnery sergeant who'd been
in the first war, he said, "It happens.
"There's nothing you can do to bring her
back. It happens. We gotta keep going."
At first, you know, you
think to yourself, you know...
"Wow, what a horrible country where
little kids can step on mines, you know...
"and there's no treatment
for them."
And then you think, you know,
"I'm glad I'm here to help."
And then, as things go on
you start to wonder...
"Could it have been one of my
guys that did this?" You know.
"Could it have been a
cluster bomb that we dropped?"
You know, "Could this kid have
been caught in friendly fire?"
And then you start to feel
like you're just a mechanic...
...fixing the things
that your friends broke.
I remember that the first
mission that we had was...
...at a POW camp,
at a prisoner of war camp.
And there we abused people, to keep
them awake for long periods of time...
...we kept them
on sleep deprivation.
And this was the first mission
that we had in Iraq
...and from there
we moved on to firefights...
...and raids and curfews
and traffic control points.
And the killings of civilians
started to pile up...
...and it became really difficult
for me morally...
...to feel comfortable with
what I was doing as a soldier.
NOEL: If you're
killing another man...
...a soldier and a soldier and
you're killing that other soldier...
I don't think
it'd probably be so bad...
'cause you're in a war and
that's the consequences of war.
You got to kill this man
'cause he's trying to kill you.
You understand?
But this war's
a different war.
This is a war you're fighting
men, women and children.
When you know
you gotta run these kids over...
...when you know you gotta put a bullet in
this woman and this woman is pregnant...
...that's what messes with you.
When you're looking at these
kids laying on the floor dead...
...and you see your child's face
laying on that floor...
...that's what messes with you.
That's why is
this war's so different.
'Cause you're just not
killing another soldier...
...you're killing a family.
SOLDIER: Jesus!
You don't go to war
in a country...
...and not go to war
with its people.
So I was seeing all of these
starving kids...
I was seeing bodies
by the side of the road.
You would go through
these battle zones...
...and there would just be tons of
dead people laying out in the road.
Whether they were Iraqi soldiers or
Iraqi civilians wasn't necessarily clear.
Families would ask, "Can we
come in and try to find our son?
"We think
you killed him last night."
And I felt, I mean, I felt at
least somewhat responsible for that.
Just like I had no control over the
circumstances that put me in Iraq...
...they had no control
over the circumstances...
...that put them and me
on the same battlefield.
SOLDIER: Is that it or what?
In combat,
you're killing for survival.
You're backed into a corner.
You can't go home.
You're in another country
13,000 miles away from home...
...and someone's shooting at you
and your friend...
...and the guys you've known
for six, eight, ten months...
...a year, two years,
three years.
And they just shot
somebody you know.
It's not about killing at
that point, it's about revenge.
It's about, "We're gonna take
you guys out so we can go home."
Like you turn on the news
every day and you hear a number...
...like, you hear, like,
14 wounded and 10 dead.
I mean, all it is is a number
and that's absolutely ridiculous.
It's just all they see is,
you know...
...two soldiers injured today,
three soldiers injured...
...and they think, "Okay, he'll be all
right, you know. He's just injured."
But they don't realize
injured is, you know...
...missing both his hands
or both his legs or whatever.
The number one injury in Iraq
is from bullets and bombs.
The number two injury
is psychological.
The number three injury
is endemic disease.
ACOSTA: A grenade was thrown
in my vehicle.
I grabbed it,
tried to throw it back out.
And when I did that, it fell between
my legs down on the floorboard.
So when I reached down to grab it again,
I had it in my right hand and it detonated.
It went off.
It took my hand off. It...
I got some shrapnel in my
vest, my legs were shattered.
My left leg... Or my right leg was
broken, my left leg was shattered.
It was pretty much just,
like, destroyed.
And it kind of, like, just...
It didn't hurt at all.
It didn't hurt really at all.
But it just confused me,
you know.
I was just, like, " Whoa, what
just happened?" You know.
We got in-country
in April of 2003.
And then I got injured
in the end of April 2004.
I couldn't see
anything at all.
I didn't have any eyesight
for about five months.
My right eye, they said, "Possibly
you have to have a cornea transplant."
I see like 20l200
out of it, right now.
I was in a truck accident.
That's nothing heroic.
It was just...
I was riding with this young
soldier that was driving too fast...
...and hit a hole in the highway.
And caused me come up and jam my
head into the ceiling of the vehicle...
...and then come down
on my tail area...
...and then shattered my spine.
And I'm disabled for life.
STOCKWELL: I was in a Humvee.
Unfortunately, they didn't
have any doors on the Humvee.
An IED went off,
a roadside bomb...
...and the Humvee swerved,
hit a guardrail.
And I think... I believe
that's where my leg got caught.
It's a left leg,
above-the-knee amputation.
I walked for the first time
today, which was very exciting.
ROBINSON: Part of the reason
they're surviving is that...
...technology has given us some
body armor that protects the torso...
...but they haven't gotten to the point
where they can protect the extremities.
And so guys that normally would've
died in Vietnam are surviving...
...but with horrible injuries.
None of us remember anything.
We all... I don't remember
anything about the crash, anyway.
I had a epiphany, dream,
whatever you want to call it.
"Boom." That's all
any of us really remember.
That's it. We're just
flying along and "boom."
Eighteen people out of the two
helicopters died, four of us made it out.
I think the number of killed
needs to be reexamined.
The number of wounded
And I think the big question
is the number of injured.
People who aren't, who don't sustain injury
as a result of enemy contact directly.
I think those numbers are much higher
than anybody really knows right now.
ED ELLIS: They don't give
even the body count now.
They keep it quiet,
on both sides.
So they try to keep death
out of it.
This is so ironic, you know.
They have...
This is the most profound
killing machines...
...if you could say
profound is the word for it...
...but most expert killing
machines ever invented.
Yet the actual killing
is kept out of the equation.
SOLDIER:
Gun on that rooftop...
We've increased the hit rate...
...from around 20%
just a few decades ago...
...to around 90% today.
Now, that's about a six-fold
increase in the firing rate.
And those who are firing...
...are at least four times more likely
to hit what they're shooting at.
Because instead of a panic-stricken
spray-and-pray response...
...they're actually
hitting the target.
HUZE: We got into a lot of firefights.
We didn't lose a single Marine.
It was because,
in certain areas...
...everything was
considered hostile.
Taking fire
from that general direction...
...there are 50 fucking people there,
it's one guy is shooting at us.
You know, we can't find the one
guy, fucking kill everything.
You know, lay fire down over there.
Suppression fire, area target.
You know, you don't think...
"Oh, okay, there's a lady in a
pink dress, let's take her out.
"There's a kid, well, you
know, let's take him out."
No. We're taking fire from over
there, blanket the fucking area.
It works.
It's effective, you know.
You don't take fire
from that area anymore.
You know, threat's eliminated.
And you keep going.
ANDERSON: When we finally
got to Baghdad...
...and I spent some time with the infantry
company that was attached to us...
...those guys actually would
tease each other...
...if they didn't get a kill in
during the day.
And until you got a kill,
you'd be made fun of.
You want to be the coward? You want
to be the guy who doesn't do it?
You want everyone
to look back at you?
And it's shame.
I mean, in some... I mean, you'll
do it. You're just gonna do it.
Everyone, I mean... You know,
peer-pressure group killing.
I mean, you know.
And you go ahead
and you do it.
I don't think that
it's necessarily courage.
The killing and the abusing
and the dehumanizing of people...
...it doesn't really come in it
because that's the world. That's it.
Like it's taken and you're just trapped
in the bubble and that's what it is.
JONES: I've seen one of the soldiers slow
his truck down like he was gonna stop.
And he slowed down like he
was gonna stop for the child...
...and then he speeded
the truck up and ran over him.
But the Army told us
if we was...
If somebody got in front of
the truck, to run over them.
The person that was riding
with me was angry about it...
...but then again they said, "Well,
that's what the Army told us to do.
"Just gotta mark it up."
MASSEY: We were on
the outskirts of Baghdad...
...and we had set up
a checkpoint.
Well, this particular day
the car didn't stop...
...and we discharged our weapons
into the vehicle.
And they were rolling
on the side of the road...
...in pain and agony.
And the driver of the vehicle,
the one that, the survivor...
...he went over to his brother,
and I was watching him.
And he picked
his brother's head up...
...and he's crying and he's
weeping back and forth.
And I'm assuming
that his brother expired...
'cause he gets up and he
walks directly towards me.
And he gets about an arm's
length distance away from me...
...and he goes, "You did this."
He goes, "Why did you kill my
brother? We're not terrorists.
"We're not, you know,
we're not insurgents.
"We didn't do anything,
we didn't do anything wrong."
And it was that moment
that hit me.
I said, " Whoa,
what are we doing here?"
"You know, what's our purpose?
What's our mission?"
We just shot
three innocent Iraqis.
You know, they didn't have any...
They weren't doing anything wrong.
KEVIN LUCEY: He was told to,
"Pull the fucking trigger, Lucey."
And then he shot that man,
and then he shot the other man.
He looked at the man...
...and he could see the fear,
the terror in the man's eyes.
And Jeff said, you know, all
of a sudden he just wondered...
...was he there
because he had to be there...
...like Jeff was?
And then he just thought
about him being...
JOYCE LUCEY: His family. He said
he could see this boy's family.
That he must've had a mother or a father
or maybe a wife, children, whatever.
I mean, just quick things
that go through.
I mean, I'm sure it was a very
small space of time but just...
He said, just the quick things
that went through his head.
And he told his sister that his
gun was shaking as he was aiming it.
He told me he was a murderer.
He said, " Don't you understand
your brother's a murderer?"
JOYCE: "I'm the mother of
Corporal Jeffrey Michael Lucey.
"Yesterday would've been
his 24th birthday.
"I say 'would've been' because Jeff
died on June 22nd at the age of 23.
"His dad and I
have struggled every day...
"since my husband found Jeff hanging
by our garden hose in the basement.
"He chose to end his life
after struggling...
"with the demons of post-traumatic
stress for several months...
"after his return from Iraq.
"Some may say
Jeff returned unharmed...
"but the young man that came home
without obvious physical wounds...
"was destroyed
by the dark hidden pain...
"of the emotional cost
of this war."
Guns go snap...
Money goes snap...
Life goes snap...
Lights go snap...
Cannons go snap...
Mind goes snap...
Nerves go snap...
Necks go snap...
Live wire snap...
Life goes snap...
Tell me how does God choose?
Whose prayers does he refuse?
Who turns the wheel?
Who throws the dice...
...on the day after tomorrow?
STAN GOFF: Killing is just
one aspect of it.
I think what's important for people
to understand about an occupation is...
...the whole situation
is one of domination.
It's when you are obliged...
...by the nature of your job
to dominate people...
...so killing is just sort of, you know,
the icing on the cake, so to speak.
There's the day-to-day reality...
...of behaving abusively
toward people...
...of threatening people
with guns, of...
In the case of Iraq, a lot
of times rounding up people...
...against whom you have
no evidence of any crime.
SOLDIER: Turn your head. Turn your head.
Yes, yes, yes. All right. All right.
Turn your fucking head.
You fucking there. Okay.
Get your fucking head down!
Turn your head!
Yes, yes, yes.
Hold this.
You stay.
Yes.
All right. All right.
DELGADO: It's the way
the military operates.
And the way the government
and the military together...
...have indoctrinated soldiers
to think it's okay...
...to do this to Arabs, to do this to
Muslims, to do this to the enemy.
Here. Here's your cane.
Hey, sit down, you.
Hey, come on. SOLDIER 1:
Hey, cut the sob scene.
Put them all in this room.
Put them all in here.
Put all the women in here.
Christ. SOLDIER 1: No,
no, no, no. You two women.
Okay, you two.
You two.
SOLDIER 2: You, come here.
SOLDIER 1: You can stay
in there.
It'll probably take you an
hour for you to get back up.
DELGADO: There were similar type
abuses going on in Nasiriyah...
...you know, breaking bottles
over people's heads...
...or whipping children
with an antenna.
And these types of abuses
happened everywhere.
If you put anyone
in harsh enough circumstances...
...they become the person
who's capable of doing that.
And so in a way,
we're all subject to that.
We could all do that, given
the proper circumstances.
And some people have lower
breaking points than others.
We had one guy
that was brought in...
...who had been identified as like a
senior-ranking Al-Qaeda member, you know.
Or Taliban, you know. He
was brought in as a bad guy.
And he had been hung by his hands
for three days from a tree, you know.
And his hands were completely gangrenous
and we had to amputate both of them.
And they told us, "Watch out for
this guy, you know. He's really bad."
And then after a couple of weeks of him
being in our clinic, they let him go.
And they said, "Our mistake."
SOLDIER 1: You better stop!
My ass.
You run my goddamn checkpoint,
I'll fucking shoot you.
SOLDIER 2: Get out!
Get out of the goddamn car!
REIBER: We didn't call them
insurgents when we were over there.
We called them just hajis,
you know.
They weren't the Republican
Guard. They weren't civilians.
They're just the enemy.
And I engaged a vehicle with a.50-caliber
machine gun and blew it up, you know.
It was a pretty big explosion.
Found out that they had gasoline and
they were gonna take out the checkpoint.
But I remember laughing
after I blew it up.
And then driving by and seeing burning,
you know, the flesh dripping off, on fire.
And none of us
even talked about it.
After it happened it was gone.
It was done.
My Captain, he came walking
up to me and he said...
"What's the matter, Staff Sergeant?
You look a little under the weather."
And I said, " Well, sir,
today's been a bad day.
"We've killed
a lot of innocent civilians."
And he looked at me and he said,
" No, today has been a good day."
And he walked off.
And I thought to myself, "This isn't
the Marine Corps that I signed up for.
"This isn't the Marine Corps
that I want to belong to."
PILOT: I got numerous individuals on
the road. You want me to take those out?
MAN: Take them out. This
is not a good day for them.
Okay.
Ten seconds.
Roger.
Impact.
CO-PILOT: Oh, dude.
It's very hard to take somebody and
turn them into someone that can do that.
And then what they want you
to believe...
...is that they can do that and then
revert you back to a civilian.
And that's absolutely
as ridiculous as it sounds.
SHOOTER: Roger.
MAN: Hit him.
Got him.
Good.
Second one.
Hit the other one.
Movement right there.
Roger. He's wounded.
Hit him.
I'll hit the truck.
Get the truck and him.
Go forward of it and hit him.
Roger.
I am not fighting for justice...
I am not fighting for freedom...
I am fighting for my life...
And another day
in the world here...
I just do what I've been told...
We're just the gravel
on the road...
And only the lucky ones
come home...
On the day after tomorrow...
There he is.
Oh, my God.
Welcome home.
Daddy!
Oh, God, I missed you so much.
Look at this guy.
Glad to be home.
DELGADO: We got in the big room and
we got these little PDA Palm Pilots...
...and we had to fill out
a survey saying...
...were we thinking
of committing suicide.
Were we thinking of killing anyone,
were we thinking of abusing our spouse.
They offered us the chance
for psychological services.
They offered the choice
of going home...
...or staying at that Army base
to receive treatment.
And after serving for one year in
Iraq, nobody would willingly choose...
...to stay on an Army base for
months after to be treated.
SARRA: As these vets come back,
you're not gonna know who they are.
They kind of
ghost into society.
They might be the quiet kid
in the back of a college class.
They might be, you know, a kid
that's cleaning up at McDonald's.
It might be... You know, you
don't know. You have no idea.
It's not like we come back with a
sign, you know, that says, "Hey, vet."
There are some guys who just
don't wanna talk about it.
We all become
casualties of war.
Who we are when we leave
is not who we are when...
...and if we're lucky,
to physically return.
Because psychologically...
...you're completely
changed by it.
I was blessed that he was home
in one piece...
...and he wasn't home
in a body bag or a coffin.
But a part of him died over
there and I don't think...
I take that back. I know that he'll
never be that same person again.
HUZE: I'm now back
with my wife.
I get to be with them
and I get to be a daddy again...
...and I get to be
a husband again.
But I've got all this stuff.
And you don't...
For me, I didn't feel like
I could share that...
...to start with.
I mean, how could I?
My wife's so proud of me,
so how can I tell her...
...about seeing a bunch
of civilians that are dead?
How could I tell her about the dead kid
I saw laying on the side of the road?
How...
Then I go from being a hero to a
monster. And I felt like a monster.
My friends and my family were
scared to even be with me.
They... I'd find myself
outside and...
The girlfriend that I did
have, I was really aggressive...
...and grabbed her by the arm
and scared her almost to death.
And she didn't wanna have anything
to do with me from then on.
It was a mess.
I was a mess when I came back.
I was really impatient when I first...
'Cause I wanted my eyesight back...
...and they were like, "Well, you
know, we're gonna do an operation.
"Then we have to wait two to three
months, you know, and see how it looks."
The doctors left it up to her.
You know, if she could handle
it, well, then I could go home.
I had to play nurse with him.
He got to come home with me.
He was blind.
I took care of the kids...
...had to take care of the house,
had to take care of my husband.
Had to bathe him, had to do everything,
you know, and it's stressful.
It's... It...
I didn't know when it was gonna end. I
wanted it to just end. I wanted it over.
I wanted to be where we are now, back
then, because it was just... It was so hard.
He wouldn't talk. He looked so bad. I
couldn't cry because he could hear me.
You know, he might not have been
able to see me but he could hear.
I have my days.
You know, like I...
There's times where I'm glad
I'm alive, I'm glad I made it.
And then there's times where I wish it
would have killed me 'cause it's hard.
I mean, not only just the fact
that I lost my hand...
...and I have to deal with that every
single morning when I wake up...
...but I can't run.
I can't, you know,
there's things I can't do.
Like, my way of living just kind
of, like, didn't exist for a while.
It was just kind of like
just going.
Like, kind of lost, in a way.
It's, like, Sandy, she told
me last night, she was, like...
"You know, I'd like to go
dancing or something."
But I... We can't, you know. It's
just something that we can't do.
I'd like to feel comfortable
when I go out.
Just the other day this guy
asked me how'd I lose my hand?
And I told him, "I lost it in
the war." And he said, "What war?"
And I told him, "The war in Iraq."
And he said, "That's still going on?"
And I was just like, "Yeah,
dude, it's still going on."
When I went on convalescent
leave for 30 days...
I spent thousands of dollars
on alcohol.
I tried to drink myself,
you know, back to reality.
And it didn't work, and
then one day I just woke up...
...and I was like, "You know what?
Maybe I'm here for a reason.
"I'm here to make sure
their names never die...
"their memories never die,
and to make sure...
"that no other soldier has to go through
what I had to go through on their own."
I took all that anger
that I had in Iraq...
...and that feeling of not caring
about myself and then wanting to die...
...and I brought it home with me.
I didn't leave it in Iraq.
I didn't turn it in
with my duffle bags, you know...
I kept it with me.
REIBER: The worst thing
is that you don't fit.
You don't fit anywhere.
And there's no place for you
to fit in except by yourself.
And then, you know, you
don't like yourself anymore.
I'm not a person
that wants to kill myself...
...but if there was ever a time
that I didn't...
You know, that I felt
that way, it was then.
And that's horrible, you know, being
out of the military for the first day...
...and you can't go to sleep at
night because you hate yourself.
And you hate what you just
did. It's a horrible feeling.
It was difficult for me
to say, you know...
"Hey, we did something
horrible over there.
"And, you know,
I'm having nightmares about it...
"and I'm having flashbacks
about it."
You know, especially being
a Marine, because you're...
...you know, you're supposed
to be this superman.
Marines are the golden boys
of America, the supermen.
You know, we're not supposed
to come home...
...and have those feelings.
After the high of coming back
a war hero has gone down...
...then they begin to think, "Well,
maybe what I did wasn't so great...
"or wasn't so brave.
I'm not such a hero."
Even guys who hated the war in my unit
say sometimes they wish they could go back...
...so they could go back to that
feeling of having a purpose.
'Cause it's that silence, that
emptiness, being by yourself...
...that really forces that introspection
that's painful, and nobody wants to do that.
When you cross that line,
when you kill someone...
...how the hell...
Like, I could barely...
I had so much trouble
transitioning when I came home.
And I'm still, I still have
my depressed moments, you know...
...but it's not as dark
as it was.
And I can't imagine
where I would be if I did...
...have that memory of
shooting someone, you know.
Split-second decision that's
made, you pull a trigger...
...it triggers something else.
You can't take it back.
No matter what I do...
...if I go back to Iraq, if I,
you know, become a Muslim...
...you know, if I read the Koran every
day, I cannot bring back that woman.
And there's nothing
I can do about it.
ACOSTA: Just think about it, though,
like, you're ending somebody's life.
I mean, it doesn't bother you
then. I mean, my main concern...
I didn't care at the time
that people were dead.
Like, I looked the guy
in the eyes, you know.
Probably has a kid or a family
or a wife or something.
Somebody to go home to. He's
not gonna go home tonight.
It's just death, you know.
It's just death.
And it's survival...
...and it's just not
giving a shit, you know.
And I think, for me,
that that's...
For me, that's the thing that's so
tough to deal with and reconcile...
...is the loss of humanity...
I think, and that it's not
always easy to tap back into it.
I think one thing one has to do
is to make the soldier realize...
...that he's not suffering from
a psychological disability.
He's suffering from a change in
his brain function and structure...
...that's produced by a terrible,
life-threatening experience...
...and that everybody would have
done the same thing.
Post-traumatic
stress disorder...
...the number one thing is they're
reliving it some way or other.
It's like someone says, "What are
you doing with that? The war is over."
And there's one poet who said...
"Yes, the war is over and over and
over and over again in my mind."
And they can be in dreams,
it could be in flashbacks...
...which get a lot of press but I
think don't exist very frequently.
It could be in intrusive thoughts,
that's the most common one.
And there are people
who have intrusive thoughts...
...every day, almost all day.
HUZE: The things that are most difficult
for me are the images of the kids...
...dead children.
Images of women.
Images of men that...
I mean, I would venture,
were non-combatants.
When I see car wrecks
and when I hear...
...not even explosions
but cars backfiring...
I don't see what everyone
else sees, you know.
I see mental images in my mind
that have to do with the war.
And that's hard to deal with. I
mean, that still bothers me when I see...
...even a, you know, car wreck,
people laying in...
It has nothing to do... They
don't have military clothes.
And all of a sudden I'll see my
friend that's laying on the ground...
...with half of his head gone.
I don't know. It's just...
This whole thing sucks.
All this sucks.
I mean, like...
It's just messing up a lot of
things. I mean, like, even...
Like, God, I'm so glad
I have Sandy because, I mean...
...anybody else that wasn't
as strong as she is...
...would have probably left me
a long time ago.
And, you know, she said last night,
and it really made me feel good...
...she's like, " Well,
we're in this together."
You know, 'cause I told her,
"Look, I think I need therapy."
'Cause I'm, like,
not doing too good and...
I don't know,
I have a lot of just...
I don't know if... I don't know
what it is, I just have a lot of it.
Nobody calls these people up
and says...
"Hey, I wanna ask you a couple questions
and make sure you're doing okay.
"I wanna ask how you're doing.
How's your family doing?"
So usually, when they finally get
to the point of diagnosing PTSD
...or something else, it's after
there's been an episode...
...a marital problem or a crime
or a meltdown at work...
...or a serious fight
with a friend or a sibling.
And then they go, "Wow! I'm messed
up. I've got something to deal with."
And then, hopefully, they come
forward and seek help at the VA.
MASSEY: So I reported in...
...and I seen a psychologist,
and I explained to her...
I said, " You know, this is everything
that had happened while we were in Iraq.
"We killed a lot of innocent
civilians and that's my problem.
"That's what I'm having
a problem dealing with."
And she looked at me and she said,
" Staff Sergeant, I can't help you."
I said, " What do you mean,
you can't help me?
"You know, you're a psychologist.
That's what I'm here for."
She goes, " I don't deal
with conscientious objectors."
I lost it. I said...
"What? You're gonna label me
as a conscientious objector...
"for not wanting
to kill innocent civilians?"
I said, " You're nuts
so there's no way, you know...
"you can label me
as a conscientious objector."
I killed people. I killed
innocent people for this country...
...in the defense of whatever
the reason why we were in Iraq.
JACKIE MASSEY: It really hit home
one day when I went to the gym...
...to go work out, you know,
and he was fine.
He was taking a nap
on the couch.
And when I came home,
he had smashed a desk...
...that was sitting
in our living room.
And he had kicked it
with his feet...
...he had hit it with his fist.
And I guess that was the part that
really kind of struck home to me that...
...you know, " Wow, I'm married to...
"someone who has been to war...
"who has seen a lot of death
and a lot of destruction...
"and this is
what it's doing to him."
We still have that ball
in our gut, of adrenaline...
...and still the mentality
of operating in a combat zone.
We can't... You can't just
turn that off, you know...
'cause we were taught how
to do that for three years...
...or however long
that you're in for...
...and you can't just
turn it off.
And so when you get out, I expected
that I should act the same way.
I was driving on the freeway in
the Bronx, on the Major Deegan...
...and someone
cut me off one day.
And I got so pissed off,
I followed him off his exit...
I got out of the car, wrapped
my T-shirt around my hand...
...and I went
to punch his window in.
And then I realized that there was
nothing restraining me when I came home.
I just held that frustration
inside. I brought that home with me.
I didn't associate it
with Iraq.
with frustration...
...my past frustration,
my past experiences.
I just felt, at that moment,
I was angry...
...and this is gonna be my
appropriate reaction to his actions.
Whatever the normal
response is...
...they were taught in basic
training to respond even faster.
And their life depended on it,
their buddy's life depended on it.
And so they come back and
then it's not appropriate here.
There's an old saying that...
...if you're a good soldier,
you'll be a bad civilian.
And this is part of it.
You've been taught to be angry,
you've been taught to kill...
...and it was necessary, maybe,
for your salvation and survival.
It's not adaptive now.
It has a lot more to do...
...with having one's
worldview shattered...
...and feeling like
there's no safe place anymore.
And it's one thing to sort of trade
your worldview in for another one...
...than to have it just shattered
with nothing to replace it.
It leaves people at odds...
...and it leads to situations where
you're trying to deal with this.
And a lot of times people tend
to become very fragmented.
ACOSTA: Well, there's times where
I think it's going away, like...
...and I'll, like, go weeks at
a time without anything and...
Just last night, like,
I couldn't sleep at all...
'cause I don't know, like, I thought
somebody was in the house or something.
And I swore up and down there
was somebody on the roof.
And then you know that feeling you
get when you don't wanna move at all.
And then...
I don't know, I was really paranoid.
I sleep with a gun under my bed.
And, like, you know, like...
Just really bothers me sometimes. Like,
any little thing, I'll go investigate.
I started carrying around
a gun with me wherever I went...
...because I felt
a lot safer doing that.
And, you know, it was just a part of
me that I didn't let go from the Army.
And one night I was,
I drank, like, 175 of whisky...
...and went to a party,
and a guy pissed me off.
And so I pulled it out and I loaded it,
put it to his head, pulled the trigger...
...and it didn't go off,
and so I pistol-whipped him.
And from there I...
They called the cops,
you know. I pointed...
I was really drunk
so I, you know...
...pointed it at everybody,
told them to get away.
The cops came in. I got
rid of the weapon, actually.
They didn't even catch me
with it...
...but I fought the cops off
for a while.
Fought two of them off me
and tried to get away...
...and then got beat up
pretty good by the police.
And was thrown in jail, charged with
felony, assault with a deadly weapon.
I had, like, seven felonies.
You know, of course, they were
trying to slam me with everything.
But sitting in jail...
...in a jail cell, you know,
full of dirtbags, pretty much...
...it was just a huge reality
check of, "What am I doing?"
One minute, you know,
everyone was...
Everyone in my family
was proud of me, you know.
Got quite a few medals
in Iraq and Afghanistan...
...did really well as a soldier.
Everyone was proud of me
because I did that...
...and now I'm sitting in a jail cell
facing 5 to 10 years in prison.
Luckily, I just got
break after break.
Instead of going to five years in
prison, I went to a PTSD program.
That's been the most, probably,
positive thing that's happened to me...
...because it made me think,
you know.
"What am I doing?
What am I so angry about?"
JOYCE: The emotional scars that these
troops are bringing back with them...
...we don't understand it,
we don't see it.
It's not a physical thing that you can look
at and say, "Well, this boy was wounded."
And our son hid this for a
long time from a lot of people.
Even his unit didn't see it.
Nobody saw it coming.
All of a sudden it exploded,
and it exploded months later.
And it caught us
off guard.
And, you know, regretfully, we had
conditioned ourselves in a way that...
"Okay, Jeff is having
a bad day."
We never knew...
...the depth of the torture, the depth
of the hell he was going through.
I was seeing a psychologist at
the VA, when I was depressed...
...but I stopped.
And I wasn't doing anything.
And I know that that was the
end of the road for me, you know.
I knew
where I was going from there.
And I made a conscious
decision to go there, you know.
I knew that I would...
That ultimately I would
probably just kill myself.
I wanted to die but I
didn't wanna kill myself.
Like, I would think that
I was gonna die anyway.
Like, I'd just walk outside
and get hit by a bus, you know.
Just 'cause I've been through
so much shit, it can't be...
Death can't be that far away.
NICKIE: A good friend of ours
had been in Iraq
...for about eight months,
nine months. Came home.
Had been trying to get custody
of his little girl.
Finally got custody of her.
Three weeks after he's had
her, he's at his friend's house.
And he's got a babysitter
for her.
And he called up the babysitter and
nobody, I mean, nobody talked about it.
Called up the babysitter and said,
" Hey, can I talk to my little girl?"
She said, " No, she's asleep
already." And he just said...
"Okay, well, just tell her that
her daddy loves her very much."
Hung up the phone
and killed himself, you know.
And when everybody was talking about it,
and when they found him and they were...
"Oh, well, was he drinking?
Was he doing drugs?"
I mean, they thought of
everything that they could think of...
...as an excuse why he did this
except the biggest one.
Nobody stopped to realize that
this man had just been in a war zone...
...for nine months, a year,
and nobody talked about that.
I read the other day, there were
suicides that are occurring in Iraq...
...and one of the public
relations people said...
"Those people probably would
have killed themselves anyway."
And I found that hard to believe,
that that would be their position.
But they take the position
that wartime experiences...
...have no bearing on suicides.
I'll just start unloading them
right here.
ACOSTA: I'm 22 years old
and I'm all...
I'm all messed up
and my legs...
Shit.
Messed up. And it's hard
to wake up in the morning.
My hand's gone.
My hips are all messed up
now 'cause...
Just walking all weird,
my knees hurt.
Like, I had goals
in the military, you know.
Like, never before had I had
goals and that was all taken away.
SANDY RESTREPO: Every day he wakes up, it's
kind of like a different person, you know.
And it's just like what, you know,
today is it gonna be happy Robert...
...or distant Robert or, you know, and
it varies throughout the day as well...
...but it's just hard because sometimes,
you know, it hits him harder.
He'll have a rough night and then
that'll continue on throughout the day.
You don't really take the world of
violence that you experienced in Iraq
...and then replace it
with the world of being home...
...you know,
the less violent world.
You don't really replace it
because what happens is...
...that you come home and
you're not the same person.
So your world is gone and you
have to start from scratch, really...
'cause you're
a totally different person.
So the world is shattered.
And it's kind of...
A lot of soldiers don't realize
the position that they're in.
We've got our demons
to wrestle with now, and...
It's easy. I try to stay so
busy, I think, sometimes where...
And worrying about others
and the politics of it...
...and the justifications for the war not
being there and this, that and the other...
...so that I don't ever have
to stop and, like, and feel.
So I don't have to deal
with my own demons.
I think...
...he doesn't understand
or realize that...
...he probably most definitely has PTSD
and, you know, some of these things.
And he's trying to help all
these other guys and talk to them.
And I think
he needs to look at...
"Hey, these are possibly
my traits...
"and, you know,
what I have from this war."
The common feeling is, you know,
you come home from the battlefield...
...and, you know, this loved one
that's waited for you...
...you know, you're just totally
disconnected with them.
And I found myself totally disconnected
with Jackie when I first came home.
But fortunately
Jackie was able to read up...
...and was able to understand
about the effects of PTSD
...and, you know, what it does to a human,
you know, what it does to a human being.
I kept a journal
for a long time...
...trying to find a pattern
of what would set him off.
You know,
was it something that I said?
Was it something that I did? Was
it something that he saw on TV?
Was it something, you know,
just didn't go his way?
And it's not one thing
in particular.
It's all those things
and more.
RESTREPO: While you're
in the military, you're taught...
...to know that
they're gonna take care of you...
...as long as
you take care of them.
As soon as they get out
and they start questioning...
"Well, why is this institution
doing these things to me?
"Why aren't they returning my phone
calls? Why aren't they filing my claims?"
A lot of them have had
their wives divorce them.
Their kids have been born
while they're gone.
They've got a multitude
of issues to deal with.
And then there's
the paperwork nightmare.
You've got guys at Walter Reed
who've lost limbs...
...and have to, you know, literally
wheel themselves around the campus...
...to get their pay straightened out or
to get their compensation benefits.
It's just, the amount of aggravation
that these guys have to deal with...
...to get their life in order,
is ridiculous.
JONES: They took a statement
from the unit I was attached to.
And that statement alone, I
suppose, was enough for them to say...
...that my PTSD is...
...as far as the Army goes,
is not related...
...and they're not gonna put it on my
medical, on my physical evaluation board.
Yeah, 120 days seemed to be
the only thing they knew about.
I gave them the records in their hand.
They called me five times and said...
"Can we just do this over the
phone?" And everything like that.
I said, " No, no,
I have my medical information.
"I'll bring it
and give it to you."
I took the information down
there, put it in their hands...
...and filled out
the paperwork and everything.
And they said, "Okay, well good.
We'll call you in 120 days."
I thought,
"What's up with these people?"
You're gonna get better
in 120 days...
...or maybe you'll go back to Iraq and we
won't have to deal with you in 120 days.
120 days
is absolutely ridiculous.
It's a good thing that
we didn't tell this country...
Every soldier in this country, when
we got the call to deploy, didn't say...
"Well, do you know what? Give me
120 days and I'll get back at you...
"before we go make sure
that freedom's not paid for."
What we are seeing is...
...a Department of Defense that,
when the soldier comes back...
...if they have a psychological injury
or combat stress injury from war...
...they are not
diagnosing that illness.
What they are doing is calling
it a personality disorder...
...or a bipolar disorder...
...or some other kind of disorder
that has nothing to do with combat.
They tried to label me
with a personality disorder.
I was like, " Okay, you know...
"I did three years of infantry
instructor at Parris Island...
"three years of recruiting,
I'm a combat veteran...
"and you're fucking telling me now
that I got a personality disorder?
"Bullshit."
But that's what's happening.
They use the personality
disorder as a tool.
It's just a tool that they can label you
with and then they're not held responsible.
ELLIS: You know, these guys
that just got back...
...they came through and
we're talking to them today...
...and they were
a great source of information.
They said they were asked
when they were leaving Iraq...
"Are you suffering from PTSD,
post-traumatic stress disorder?"
If you answered yes,
yes, you stayed in-country.
You didn't go home.
And, you know, I talked to this
friend who's a veteran counselor...
...that they really tightened up
on the medical benefits.
You've got two years to
declare all your problems...
...after you get
out of the service.
If anything comes back,
you know, they don't want it.
And we put everything that we are and
everything we ever will be on the line...
...when our country asked us
to do so.
And you don't expect
to be betrayed for that.
You expect them to fulfill
their commitment to you...
...just like you don't hesitate
to fulfill it to them.
The military is trying a new
policy, right now in this war...
...where rather than evacuating
psychologically injured people...
...if they can treat them
there in Iraq...
...and keep them with their unit,
they don't send them back.
So we don't even know how many
psychologically injured there are.
But the nature of war and
all the confounding factors...
I believe, much as Vietnam
was Agent Orange...
...this war will be the
psychological injury of war.
ACOSTA: This is my home.
I grew up here and when
somebody welcomes me back...
...it's just like, "Welcome
home," and you're just, like...
"I am home."
You know, it's cool.
Like, it feels good
when somebody says that.
I'd rather have somebody say,
"Welcome home," than, "Thank you."
If Americans actually listened to the
veterans that they claim to respect so much...
...their attitude would change.
But the thing is, Americans wanna honor
the veterans in, like, a very cursory way.
You know, putting
a yellow sticker on their car...
...having a little parade
or welcome back.
But they don't wanna honor
the veterans by really, like...
...listening to
what they have to say.
I imagine that you have been kind
of inundated with all the talk...
...about the body armor story that
was in the New York Times this week.
We found out yesterday that there's
more information that's been revealed...
...and now that the Department of
Defense took 167 days just to get...
...the bulletproof vests ordered.
MADDOW: Right.
Just to get them started, it took 167
days, and our allies, they took 12 days.
Because they just called
the factory and ordered.
Exactly, exactly. And that 167
days was during the insurgency.
It was a time when people
were getting wounded...
...and people
were getting killed.
And body armor
could have saved lives.
If you sat with me
and five guys in my squad...
I could have told you about this
problem a year-and-a-half ago.
It didn't need
congressional testimony...
...it didn't need a New
York Times investigation.
But all too often they listen
to the bureaucrats...
...and they listen
to the four-star generals...
...and the general comes and gives
them the thumbs-up and says...
"Well, sir,
everything's great."
I think that the only conduct
unbecoming for a non-commissioned officer...
...in the United States
Marine Corps...
...is if I identified
failed leadership...
I identified misguided policy...
...that resulted in the loss
of my Marines' lives...
...and I didn't speak out
about it.
That would be unbecoming.
WOMAN: Hello? Hi, could I
speak with William, please?
He's not in.
Can I take a message?
Yes. Could you tell him
Chad called...
...from the National Veterans
Foundation?
All right, I sure will.
Thank you very much.
The Army discharged him
while he was in jail.
Brought his discharge papers
for him to sign in jail.
Did absolutely nothing
to help him. Nothing.
And now he's still getting
no help whatsoever.
He has a bad conduct discharge...
...even though it had nothing
to do with his military.
And so he can't
receive benefits from the VA.
Guys like me are gonna have to be the ones
that come out and start talking about it...
...or nothing's gonna happen.
You know, there's gonna be...
Everybody is gonna be sitting
in their rooms...
...afraid to come out
and get help.
Part of healing
is to take action.
So we encourage people to talk
about the problems that they see...
...that they're experiencing, that
they see their friends experience...
...and then to get involved.
You know, people don't expect veterans
to be out there speaking out against war...
...even though it turns out,
you know, that we're sometimes...
...the most effective people out there to
talk about what really happens with war.
I came home on leave halfway
through my tour in Iraq
...and I decided that I couldn't
participate in the war.
This was the first case
of any combat veteran...
...to come back and go public
with his criticism about the war...
...and the government
and the policies.
So it became a political case and
the military responded politically...
...and gave me a sentence
of one year in prison...
...and a demotion to the lowest
rank and a bad conduct discharge.
I ended up
doing nine months in jail.
I got out three months early
because of good conduct...
...and ever since then
I have been an activist.
'Cause it's strange go
from soldier to activist.
Well, I mean, it's not
typical. I'll put it that way.
And what I hope to do
is become a teacher.
I think that might be some redemption
for me to be able to change...
...to try to change
the next generation.
O'BRIEN: Whenever I talk about
war, even in a theoretical way...
...you know, I think, you know,
children with missing limbs...
...you know, and there's a powerful
emotional connection that I have.
I guess nothing's purely academic
for me anymore after being overseas.
DOUGHERTY: Our men and women are
coming back and being abandoned...
...by the same government that
says it's supporting the troops.
And people are waiting months,
people are waiting over a year...
...for necessary mental and physical care
that because of the things they did...
...the things they saw in Iraq.
GOFF: For the Vietnam veterans who
are in this movement, the Iraq veterans...
...are our children.
Those are our kids.
And that's exactly
how we feel about them.
I mean, you know,
we're just in love with them.
And the commitment they show
to one another is very moving.
I think we feel this responsibility
that, like, we're speaking...
...not only for ourselves, but for the
people who are still in the military...
...who don't necessarily have
that freedom of speech.
And I think that the opinion is
turning. I mean, the opinion polls...
...are showing that
three-quarters of the troops...
...want to return
within the year.
Those are troops in Iraq.
So they can no longer use this
rhetoric of "Support the troops."
Because what the troops are telling you,
both in Iraq and those who've returned...
...is that they don't want any part
of this. They want to come home.
MEJIA: It's amazing to come to New
Orleans and see the similarity between...
...the level of devastation here
and in Iraq.
The way that the government and
the corporations are behaving...
...with total disregard for
human life and human interest.
A lot of the things that are
happening in Iraq are happening here.
ALL: You're right!
When I came home and I realized
that I had to speak out...
I also realized that...
...having been to Iraq and
having been a part of that war...
...gave me a platform
that I didn't have before.
MULLINS: I'll never make
myself feel better...
...about conforming
when I was in Iraq...
...conforming when I was
in the military.
But what I can do,
is do my part now.
I wanted to go to college
so bad...
...that I chose to put my life on
the line to join the military...
...just to get that money,
those benefits.
When I think about the deaths
of my comrades...
...while I was in-country,
in Iraq...
I tried to think...
I tried to tell myself...
...well, I did at one point try to tell
myself that they died for a reason.
But I couldn't find that reason.
I couldn't justify it in my mind.
And that's why I'm here,
speaking out.
I'm speaking out
because they can't speak out.
I'm speaking out because
their voices are silenced.
A lot of military service
is about duty.
And I think, you know, there's a
sense of responsibility to fight...
...that they instill in you
in the military.
And we've kept that with us, you know,
and I think many of us are realizing...
...that the military,
that wasn't our duty at all.
That fight wasn't our fight.
This is now.
There was no, nothing
honorable about what we did.
And that's what
I always thought...
...going to war and being a soldier,
you're some kind of a hero.
And there was some stuff
that I did that was not...
...even close to being a hero.
You know, there's stuff
that I did, that was...
Or that I saw...
...you know, whatever it was, that
had nothing to do with honor...
...you know, being honorable.
Nothing to do with it.
And that broke my heart, yeah.
When I was living
in Camp Lejeune...
...my minister was
a really phenomenal man...
...and he gave a sermon
on hope once.
And he said that...
...science has proven that you can live
approximately 72 hours without water...
...around two weeks without food...
...and spiritually we've proven you can
only live a few minutes without hope.
If I didn't have hope that
this was going to end somehow...
...that we were
going to be successful...
...then I probably would have let myself
out of this life a long time ago.
I don't know that I can let go of it
or if I can let myself off the hook.
I know that to an extent that
that guilt fuels my fire right now.
That it... When they come at
me, when they try to quiet me...
...it makes me rage that much
louder, it reinforces my resolve.
And maybe I shouldn't be
let off the hook, you know.
And maybe that's not the point of this
is for me to ever let myself off the hook.
The point is to be wiser
and to learn from it.
To the people, I just want
to say that I'm really sorry.
I'm really sorry for all the damage
and I am really sorry for my cowardice...
...for not opposing the war...
...for not speaking out sooner, for
not disobeying more orders in Iraq.
I'm sorry.
And to the troops I want to
say that there is a way out.
You know, we sign a contract
and, you know...
...we swore
to protect the Constitution...
...and to fight for freedom and democracy,
but that's not what we're doing in Iraq.
And if it means jail, or if
it means disgrace or shame...
...then that's what it's going to take, you
know, but there is a way out, you know.
And I also wanna tell people
that after being in jail...
...that there is
no higher freedom...
...that can be achieved than
the freedom we achieve when we...
...follow our conscience.
And that's something that you
can live by and never regret.