The ancient book say...
That in the beginning...
There was no light in our world.
It took a super strong man...
To bring the sun down
to our little planet.
The guardian of the sun...
Regulates the seasons, looks
after land and stuff like that.
As for the moon...
It was brought over from
the world of dreams...
By the first guardian of the moon.
Actually,
he is someone who brought
dreams into our world as well.
And that's...
How the balance was created...
Between day and night.
Sohone!
Hye, girls.
How you doin'?
Tomorrow is the big day.
Guess who is about to become the
next "guardian of the sun".
Sohone!
Damn right.
Glim!
I know what you're upto and I
forbid you to even think about it.
You are not going to that ridiculous show.
If you say, dad.
It's not your business and
it was too dangerous.
I told you a million times,
but, no no no no no!
Why should you listen
to an old candle, han.
Well, young lady
because this old candle knows better.
You know you can't go out in the sun.
Last time you snucked out your
arms melted down your feet...
Yep!
I'm not good to spend my
life resculpturing you.
Of course!
You want to end up like your mother.
She also wanted to see the world.
Oh, Ursula, my poor precious darling!
Why did you have to go out for big carrots in
a terrible heat flame at 3 in the afternoon.
I told you the fields weren't safe.
Nightfall!
Quick! Get to bed
and find something else to dream about.
If I catch you trying to go tomorrow...
You are gonna be in big trouble...
Young lady.
You making me boil and the
melting's giving me wrinkles
end of a conver...
Sa...
Tion.
My, friends.
As you all know
tomorrow I shall be named...
The new "guardians of the moon".
It will be a historic moment...
For all, people
of the night.
Miss me!
You can catch me, come on.
And I will be will...
Mune can't you be responsible for once.
You've embarrassed me in front of leeyoon.
I forbid you to go to
the ceremony tomorrow.
You can come out when you are
ready to make yourself useful.
But I am useless.
Ya!
Today is the day.
Everyone to the arena.
Oh poor daddy, still frozen!
This day is going to go
down in historic, dad.
I can't miss it.
Don't worry, I'll stay in the shade.
I promise.
Love you.
I'll be back for lunch.
People of the day!
Give you applause...
For the mench...
The mighty...
The legendary...
Guardian of the sun.
Master xolal.
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you...
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you my dear krrrack!
You have the sweetest heart of stone.
People of the day.
I've been in charge of the sun's past...
For 350 years now.
It's time for me to step down.
I call upon my disciple
to come forward
ya!
Ya!
Sohone!
As long as the sun shines brightly
the moon will glow humbly.
I am yule, the guardian of the moon.
I call upon my disciple
to step forward
oh, sun!
I present to you, my disciple
he has a heart of fire.
And I believe him worthy of you.
I acknowledge him!
We're all gonna die!
Help me.
The sun recognizes its new guardian
I name
sohone!
Yes, sohone!
Thank you! Thank you! Hello darling!
Sohone!
Kukku!
Oh, moon.
I present to you my disciple...
He has a heart...
Oh goody!
And I believe him...
Of you.
But, only one creature on the planet
can be the judge of this.
The purest creature of all.
The moon...
Recognizes...
What is this?
Mune! Get out of there, right now!
Mune!
Who do you think you are.
I...
You are ruining my ceremony.
Go!
Get out of here!
Stay!
Stay still!
What's your name, little creature?
Mune!
Well then
mune!
You are the new guardian of the moon.
What! Him?
But, you said this whole
ritual was a formality.
Well,
the moon felt otherwise.
There can be no day without night.
The same goes for the guardians.
The harmony of the planet
now rests in your hands.
Prove yourselves worthy.
You double crossed leeyoon
you little blue rat!
But I never wanted this.
The big one is as arrogant as you were.
The small one is as naive as you were.
It was an honor to serve
as guardian with you.
Come here, old chap!
Necross!
Xolal's reign is over.
The old lizard is on his way out out.
Spleen, get your butt over here, quick.
Come on. Chill out, mox.
All this negative energy stressing me out.
What? You wanna fight.
I will mess you up!
Silence!!!
I have been burning with desire to hear
that delightful news for centuries!
Now the time has come
to steal back the sun!
The boss is on fire.
We are gonna so chaos
and misery everywhere!
Yepi.
My precious one's!!!!
What are those?
These are evil corruptors.
They find darkness in
even the purest of souls.
Here! Here! Make me evil!
Make me evil!
Please...
Well.
Whatever!
Soon, that the sun will be mine
years of training.
I was going to be the perfect guardian.
Moon was meant for me,
no one else.
Obviously, the moon was meant for you.
Right, me!
Precisely, no one else.
Certainly not that...
Ridiculous little blue rat.
That thing, a guardian!
Exactly, give me a break!
Clearly the old guardian's...
Made an absurd choice.
Necross agrees with you.
Necross?
Mune stole your place.
Really.
What does necross think
I should do about it?
Take back whats rightfully yours.
Meaning?
The sun for him
the moon for you.
Come on, leeyoon!
You know you deserve the moon.
Ya!
I do.
Well, mune.
This is your home now.
I felt the same way, the first time.
Whats that for?
Well, to steer the temple, of course.
And what's this?
You know where the moon
comes from, don't you.
No.
It comes from the world of dream.
The first guardian carved the moon...
And brought it into our
world through this trap door.
And now it's your turn to watch over it.
But I don't know what I am supposed to do?
The role of guardian of the
moon is extra complexity...
And all this made
this extremely careful.
You should never put dire consequences.
Goodbye!
Look, I really think there's been a mistake
I'm scared of the dark, the
stars, all look the same to me.
I get dawn and dusk mixed up.
I'm a terrible singer, so...
Guardian of the moon!
Master yule?
Master yule, are you okay?
It's...
I got no words, it is just...
It's just...
Am I right?
My bad.
Don't worry, I'm used to it.
And yes, it's just...
Man! This dude was cool.
Can you imagine!
That guy harpooned the sun and
brought it to our planet.
So, let's get down to business.
Where are the harpoons, han?
We hardly ever used them.
Being guardian of the sun
has become more complex...
Since the discovery of astronomy,
astrophysics, quantum physics.
But harpooning is what I trained for.
Well, there are other skills that you
need to learn other than harpooning star.
Season calibration, photosynthesis,
proper solstice management.
You are paying tribute to master xolal.
Like all his predecessors, he has
transformed into a majestic statue.
It is an honor serving you. Master xolal.
And now it's time for fearless guardians...
To embark upon their thrilling
cosmic adventures and...
Hello.
Hey! Come back here!
No.
Glim!
Where are the kill cupboards?
Same place as usual, dad!
I am guardian...
Of the moooon!
I'm pretty sure this thing can go faster.
No!
No! No! No! No! No! No!
Wrong note.
This, this chord?
Maybe...
No! No! No! No! No! No!
Give me that, this chord!
No!
Or this one!
Hello, my fine feathered friend.
Would you like to rest on my broad
and perfectly tend shoulder.
Master sohone!
This much heat could damage the crops.
It's time to raise the sun.
Listen krrrack! Times are changing.
People want the sun that shines you around.
Shines like me.
What the heck is he doing there?
Stop!
Stop, you are wrecking everything.
Sorry!
What's mune doing with the night?
Please, stop!
This is a nightmare.
Night time?
At this hour?
The temple's gone off course.
Its latitude is all wrong.
Don't worry, everything is under control.
Where are you going?
Stay here!
Nooooooo!
Oh, man.
That little fuz ball is messing
up my first day on the job.
I have come to pay my
respects to an old friend.
You have my "congratulations".
Oh, leeyoon!
I'm about sorry what happened to you.
But, as you can see I have got a
situation with the night here and...
Yes, I can see that.
Yule made a terrible mistake
choosing that fraud.
Lucky for us, I have got day under control.
Mune's not only hurting the night, sohone.
He is threatening the harmony of our planet.
You will have to deal the
consequences of his failures.
That is so not cool!
You must set things right.
You and me... as guardians.
Master sohone, where are you going?
To get rid of that poser.
I am not gonna let him
jeopardize my career.
But you can't leave the temple
its your duty as a guardian to
to do what?
Have you seen the size of this thing!
Or you worried?
Someone's gonna steal it by guard!
Oh no!
The moon is drifting.
I have an idea.
I don't think I have a
back bone in my body.
Well, I don't have any
bones in my body, really.
But, I just feel like I am a lousy daemon.
I'm bad and...
Hush!
I think I'm doomed.
It's just... I love nature, you know.
Well, nature doesn't love you back.
Get used to it.
Now, let's bust this thing.
What's that fool doing?
Stay here, let me handle this.
Come on, take it.
The moon's fine. Just
put it back in the sky.
And let's forget about the whole thing.
Come on! Maybe no one noticed.
It will be our little secret.
With this wind velocity and
this pressure gradient,
the moon should hit the
lower troposphere and...
What was that?
You come on!!
What are you doing over there?!
I'm carrying this entire thing.
Working pretty hard, back here.
Getting sweaty.
The sun!
No!
And, where do you think!!
You are you going?
Two little devils are stealing the sun.
Its none of your business, let
the guardians handle this.
But I need to tell them
you need do as I say.
Dad!
Give me back my hand.
Sweetheart. You're just too fragile.
All I want is to protect you from danger.
You have to trust me, daddy.
Glim, get back here.
You are made of the same
wax as your mother.
Just like all your night friends.
Creeping and crawling and
when you come into the light
its a disaster.
Its not my fault.
Its a responsibility.
Its an honor to be a guardian.
Its an honor I never wanted.
Sohone!
A girl?
Ladies first.
I'll will finish with you later.
A fan.
You came here to see your
hero in action, ay doll?
The sun!
Somebody stole the sun!
What?!
I'll be right back.
No! No! No! No! No! No!
This can't be happening!
It can't be!
The sun!
This is my fault.
Night?
At this time of day?
That's weird!
It probably just an eclipse!
Well! Well!
You are mine once again!
For years I've been watching you.
I spread your light to run the planet.
I spread life.
Still they took you back.
The took your light away from me.
And then plunged me into darkness.
Fine...
Then..
Bring on darkness!
Oh ya!
Have you seen how slap happy the boss is?
Nothing like a little chaos and
destruction to make him smile.
Put the sun somewhere safe!
Where I can watch its heart grow cold.
And die
you are an idiot.
But its not my fault, I...
No!
That wasn't you riding the
temple of the moon like
a wild goroon!
The temple of the moon!
Every guardian has their own style.
Mine, well its a work in progress.
A work in progress?
Oh boy!
You have obviously never
studied the ancient books
or any celestial laws.
And you claim to be a guardian?
Seriously.
You're right.
I'm just a regular kid from the forest.
All I'm good at is calming down
babies who have nightmares.
But yule put me in charge
right?
It must be for a good reason?
So I made one
small mistake, but
you!
I am gonna...
Hey!
Get back here so I can hit you.
I'm a laughing staff because of you.
You're gonna pay for this.
First the moon, now the sun!
I am the one who has to clean up your mess!
But...
You're gonna have the shortest
career of any guardian ever!
Hey! Hands off!
Necross was the thief.
How could only be him.
He must've been plotting his revenge.
Tonight mune gave him the
opportunity to take it.
Okay, let's set a few things straight.
Here! You're the real guardian.
Mune, you are just not up to it.
Hurry, sohone.
Without the sun's light,
the moon will wane and could soon go out.
Don't worry, I'm on it.
I've to get that sun back.
Wait, I'm coming with you.
You are warm.
And if you get too far away I'll freeze.
Listen sweetheart...
You're not gonna leave me here?
Alone...
In the dark...
In the forest.
Unprotected!
Oh no!
What have I done?
You destroyed what was most sacred to us.
My friends!
I'm sorry, I never meant to cause any harm.
But you did.
You are not the moon.
I was trying to get it back.
I almost did, but...
Don't you realize the
consequences of what you've done?
You don't belong here anymore.
No!
No! Don't leave.
I can still fix it, I...
Dad.
I'm sorry.
I promise I'll find a
way to make this right!
Glim!
Gliiimmm!
Where is that girl?
Seriously?
See, harpoons are way more
complex than they look.
If you want good results,
you gotta handle them
with care and attention.
Just like the ladies.
You're right.
Can I get a hand here?
I'm stuck!
Stuck with me?
Lucky girl!
Check me out.
Can't find biceps like
these on night guys, han!
By the way
are you from night or day?
I am mixed!
I am from dawn and dusk.
Do you have any problem with that?
You are not prejudice, are you?
What? No, of course not?
I mean is just that night guys...
They're, different.
They scare kids.
Wait a minute.
The fourth star of the zebra
constellation indicates north.
Which means we're heading east!
We're going round in circles!
Noooo!
No, I know exactly where we're going.
I know my stars, sohone.
I'll take the lead from here.
Really?
No need to swoon over
three blinking insects!
I'm coming to look for the sun with you.
No, can't do, bug boy.
I'm on my way down to the underworld.
Like you could ever handled that.
I wanna fix the damage I did.
That's cute.
And what do you gonna do to necross, han!
Sing him a lullaby!
You won't make it through the forest alone.
You need me.
Finding the sun is serious
business, small fry!
You guys keep arguing that
about who is man enough
I'm going.
Alright, you can guide
me out of the forest.
But after that you're out of the picture.
You are not strong enough
for what's waiting for us.
Hurry!
I'm freezing here!
I am...
Guardian of the moooonnn!
Chu chu chu chu moon moon!
Didn't see you there!
Now...
Rise and go forth into the night!
What?
But, but...
Why won't you stay up?
Sohone!
Aren't you afraid of the lightning monster?
The who?
Well...
You know, the ancient book say that
in order to get to the underworld,
you have to dive into a giant blue hole
and face the terrifying, bloodsucking,
bone crushing lightning monster
guarding the entrance.
No one even knows what it looks like.
Because no one has ever
survived the journey.
Ever!
I don't read books, but
I can throw a harpoon.
You're safe as long as you stay with me.
What about necross?
The ancient books say he became
a gigantic lava monster who...
I told you I don't read it!
Leeyoon?
Whats happening with the moon?
My powers, they're gone!
Never fear, good people of the night
I'm in charge now.
We better hurry!
Don't panic!
Not to worry.
The giant blue hole!
Its exactly how the books described it.
Amazing.
Right!
And how do we get down there?
Disguise ourselves as sardines?
This algae is filled with oxygen.
It will provide enough
air under water for...
Ya, ya, I get it!
OK!
Not too, bitter for you?
Nope.
Delicious.
What?
Strange! I mean
helium algae is known
for being quite bitter.
You've did...
Come here you little...
This over here is oxygen algae.
You see.
Glim.
Here's one for you.
I won't need any.
But...
You should, this stuff
is extra pretty good.
The water is too cold for me.
I might freeze and break.
Why, you thought adventure
was all riding unicorns
and dancing with elves?
Bad news honey!
We are not living in a fairy tale!
Its gonna be okay.
I'll take you with me.
Hot!
Don't let me sink, okay!
You'll be safe.
Just, let yourself go.
I won't let you down.
I promise.
Man, you are really bad with the ladies.
What?
Nothing.
You!
Help me!
The moon is dying.
Hurry! I'm talking to you!
Do something!
No!
Oh no!
Its the big black house!
Its the end of the world!
Darkness is spreading all over the planet.
Chaos! Chaos! Chaos! Chaos!
Stop talking about chaos.
I'm gonna have nightmares again.
Chaos! Chaos! Chaos!
A chaos hou! A chaos hou!
Glimmmm!
Hey! Unhand the lady!
Glim!
Glim, I'm coming!
I am here!
Let her go!
Glim!
Sohone!
Sohone, do something!
I'm trying!
Up there you go!
You got him!
The lightning monster!
He's gonna rip us apart!
Swim for your life, mune!
Who're you calling monster!
Snort fish.
Hey!
I am the guardian of the sun.
Show some respect.
And I'm...
Phospho!
Are you the guardian of the underworld?
I used to be guardian of the moon, boko!
For that with one I wish you holding spray.
Come on, spiky, get the girl back now.
Atta boy!
A cute little chick.
Ignore to chat here, han.
We need to get to the underworld.
Necross has stolen the sun.
So why didn't you stop him?
I thought you are the guardian?
He sent two little devils.
Wait.
You got aborted by two little minions?
No, but...
Well its his fault.
Quit.
Its giving me a headache.
Master phospho!
I was picked by accident.
But you...
You are a real guardian.
We need your help.
I haven't heard that in a while.
So tell me.
Why try to take the sun back?
To impress the ladies.
Now you are talking?
Impress the ladies!
Brilliant!
Here we are.
On the road to the underworld.
Come on, it got a long
and gloomy decade once.
What about glim?
We can't leave her like this.
Oh right.
The chatty one.
Move aside.
And let the artist work.
Hands off!
Is that any way to thank your savior?
I strengthened your wax, girl!
You should be more flexible for a change.
Or a little kissy will do.
Can I do that too?
Every guardian develops his own gift.
Here's clear
you're screwing everything off.
Who is that guy?
He says he was the guardian of the moon.
Phospho, something!
Phospho!
But the ancient books say...
Come on!
This way!
Mune!
Thank you.
For watching over for me.
Glim.
You can hold on to me
if you feeling scared.
May I hold on to you too
if I'm feeling that we
have been frightened?
No.
Master phospho.
I've read all the history books about him.
But you were actually there.
Could you tell us what really
happened with necross?
Necross
well, a traitor, he is simply
a great guardian of the sun.
But he is not.
He tried to keep the sun all for himself.
Luckily xolal stooped him.
Xolal?
That dried old prune?
Ya my friend, but then...
He was the most powerful
warrior on the planet.
So, there was a clash of titans.
A nasty one.
He smashed necross...
Pulled away down, into the underworld.
And the underworld's...
Whats waiting for you at
the bottom of this casam.
But I don't understand why
xolal had to step in.
As guardian of the moon,
weren't you supposed to watch
over the harmony of the planet?
Yes, and I did.
I watched over the moon.
But then why would you
into exile after that?
Chapter 35 of the book 4 says...
Somebody's gonna research, han?
Well, if you know so much
I guess you won't need my help.
That's not what she meant. We
good luck, kiddos.
Nice job.
What? I was just asking.
The temple!
Whats it doing here?
The moon?
No.
The moon is gone.
The temple has gone insane.
I have to stop it.
We don't have time for that.
The sun is dying.
It might be too late already.
You take care of the sun.
I have to save the moon.
No, mune, remember, the
guardians are linked.
The ancient book said...
You really gotta stop
reading those books, babe?
Come on.
Get lost, marble head!
Goroun!
What are you doing here?
Come here boy!
Quick!
We have to catch him.
Okay, now lets stop that temple!
We have a planet to save.
Go!
Careful!
Don't worry.
This I know how to do.
Hang on!
Mune, don't leave me! Mune!!!!
Oh no, no, no, noooooo.
I don't know how to steer this thing!
Calm down!
Easy boy!
I'm here.
Its working!
Calm...
Down!
That was amazing!
Mune!
Did you see that?
My dust worked on him!
Well, look at that.
The legend I got the temple to settle.
He's got guts!
Maybe more than I ever had it.
Who is this?
It looks like the guardian of the sun!
I am the guardian of the sun!
Is that the moron who lost the sun?
Hey!
What a loser!
Mune is the real hero.
You just cleanup.
You are just a loser.
Useless!
Whats he doing now?
He wants to get by?
Moron!
What a pathetic hope!
You're the worst guardian of the sun ever.
Pathetic!
Is that really one you gosh, sheron!
Mother!
Leeyoon!
Leeyoon, where're you?
Leeyoon.
What are you doing?
Leeyoon!
Come on!
Wake up!
Where is the moon?
It died!
I became a guardian and it died!
Everything went wrong.
Why me?
So this is the end!
Its not fair.
How could necross betray me?
I did everything he asked.
Those lying snakes!
Those lying liars!
Always picking on me.
I'm in pretty quite love
of already get to know me.
Go then yourselves...
I will get a new moon
from the world of dreams.
Who do you think you are?
A God?
You can't just create a moon.
The first guardian did.
We're all doomed!
Doomed, I tell you!
Come on glim.
Let's go!
Hey, wait for me.
Hello!
What's that?
Are we in the world of dreams?
Nightmares... nightmare everywhere.
Stop!
You did it again!
Ya.
I have got powers!
Maybe the moon was right after all.
Okay!
Now I'm gonna show these ugly monsters
who the real master of dreams is.
Enough with the nightmares.
Lets have some dream!
The moon core!
I thought that was a legend!
By the mighty power of the guardians,
I command a new moon to appear.
Mune!
I saw him!
He carved a new moon!
Who cares!
The sun is dying.
And the moon is as good as dead
this is ridiculous!
This is embarrassing!
They call him the guardian of the sun?
Give me a break.
Stop it!
I'll fight you.
Yes!
Such anger!
So hatred!
Whats happening to me?
You are darker than necross!
Daemon!
You forked tongues mindless worms.
I know you're nearby, necross
you've spread your chaos once.
I won't get away with it again.
Phospho!
That useless fraud is your backup!
I'm surprised to see you
here, my old friend.
I thought you beclouding somewhere...
Behind the rock!
Don't listen to these snakes, boko!
They're trained to make evil
just like they did with necross.
Shut up, mop.
I've enough of your old drooling face.
I'll crush you into dust.
Respect the mop, kiddo!
Back on your feet!
Its too late!
How're you doing that?
I don't know.
I just am.
I like dreaming with you.
I...
I had a funny dream!
Ya!
Me too.
Mune!
I misjudged you.
Forgive me.
You really are the guardian of the moon.
Well...
I better put this back in the sky then.
The moon can't shine
without the sun's light.
They're connected.
Like the guardians, remember?
No time to lose then.
Lets find sohone.
Calm down, kiddo.
Deep breath!
Here,
take my energy!
You look
much better when you shine.
Phospho!
Phospho, what're you doing?
I'm going out in style.
For the ladies, right!
No! Nooo!
Thank you phospho!
Now that was a great explosion!
You're going to have to
try a little harder.
Spleen!
You bunch of evil sloshing imbecile!
I'll have to take care of this myself!
Sohone!
Glim!
Mune!
I think I was never gonna see you again.
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
We missed you too, my friend.
Well!
Shall we.
Welcome guardians.
Necross!
The sun and the moon in the underworld?!
What a treat!
Hang on.
Sohone, watch out!
Get the sun.
I'll take care of lava pan.
You shall know come for
them for such a failure.
You brought disgrace in the
guardians of the sun's honor.
I'm gonna enjoy crushing you.
Quick, we gotta go.
You're mine, sucker
and right now your girlfriend is in
the clutches of my evil accomplice.
Yellow flowers are nice,
but they're more fragile, right?
Right... and...
That's why I gotta go.
Gotta water them.
Of course.
Bye then!
You thought you can spread
darkness on my planet?
Then get away with it.
Not on my watch.
You're too late.
The sun is dead.
There's nothing you can do
to save you planet now.
Oh yaa?
Take this!
You bite like a mosquito.
That hurts!
Glim!
Don't go any closer.
Got ya now.
Its chaos time!
Glim!
She is gonna make a nice candle.
Get your stinking breath out of my face.
Glim!
I saved the sun!
Ya.
You did.
You have to help sohone.
No!
No, I need to save you.
No.
It's too late for me.
But, you can defeat necross!
I have seen your power.
Go!
My sandman.
You think you can light the
sun just by puffing it.
I'll blow it down quicker than
it took your girlfriend to melt
you're trapped, little blue rat.
Sohone!
Quick, mune
get out of here!
I can't hold it for long.
I have enough of you. Die
insects.
What's going on?
I can feel it too.
Let's show him what we're made of.
Yah, lets finish him off.
I got him.
Nighty night!
What?
What've you done to me?
You're taking a nap, big guy.
I put you to sleep.
You dirty little blue rat!
I am the master of dreams.
There's nothing you can you do to me here.
You're gonna pay.
You really need a cook.
Hold still, dummy.
This snake has been squeezing
your heart for too long.
Mune!
You pulled out the fires of the underworld.
That was epic!
I never thought I'd say this, but...
Bro!
You really are the most
powerful guardian of all time.
You okay, mox?
I bloomed.
We're gonna be fine here.
That's mune!
The guardian of the moon.
Ya, I always knew he would make it.
What?
Glim!
This is gonna be good!
Sohone!
Glim!
Glim! Glim! I'm over here!
Daddy loves you!
Sweetheart! Glim look around.
I'm on the left.
My baby kid...
I love happy endings!
My bad!