U h.
Dito.
Oh, my goodness.
I can't believe to hear your voice on this machine.
It's your mother.
Dito, I called your friend Nerf to call you.
He's a good kid. U h...
I don't know what else to do.
Your father's sick. He's real sick,
and he wont' go to the hospital. You know how he is,
and I'm sorry. I don't know what else to do.
Your friend Nerf, uh,
he's a good kid, you know. He said he'd pick you up at the airport if you came.
I know that it's far.
I'm sorry.
I, uh...
I'm gonna hang up now, Dito.
Okay. I love you.
No matter what you do, I love you.
Tonight we have the author of a wonderful, wonderful book.
A Guide to Recognizing Your Saints. Dito Montiel.
Thanks.
By the end of all this, Giuseppe,
his brother Antonio used to call him "Little Sister"
'cause he slept with Noxzema on his face every night.
It never even made sense, being everything else about him was a mess.
Well, he loved the face cream, you know?
Anyway, Giuseppe, he's gonna be dead.
Yeah, I know. It sucks.
There'll be another guy you'll meet too, same with him.
And then another little boy.
He's gonna die, too. What a mess, huh?
And I don't even know why I feel I gotta tell you this up front but I do.
And don't worry, like,
I'm not giving away any big ending, you know, with this.
A whole lot of other shit's gotta happen first.
But I just, uh, I wanna remember
who these people are and what they meant to me.
What they mean to me.
And they are real.
My name's Dito.
I'm gonna leave everybody in this film.
(Dito) I see Laurie's and Diane's walkin' down 31 st Street.
Hot pink leg warmers.
Red, white and blue roach clip feathered earrings.
"The Song Remains the Same" painted on the back of their jackets.
And they wanna know, "Yo, Dito, you Rock or Disco?"
[Crash]
(Laurie) What the fuck? You fuckin' idiot I
(Dito) I see innocent Giuseppe's walking down the streets
where Puerto Ricans still listen to Journey.
Dito, what's up, man?
Really, It's true. Puerto Ricans listen to Journey.
Yo, Steve Perry's the shit, bro!
(Giuseppe) Antoniol
When this place isn't covered in violence,
(Antonio) That's where the fuckin' shit from the toilet goes.
And even sometimes when it is,
You're drinking it like an idiot.
You taking a bath and shit, man.
This place is heaven.
Get the fuck off him!
Whoa, whoa.
Stop, stop, stop!
What's wrong with you? What the fuck?
(Dito) What the fuck is that?
Motherfucker sounds like he's prayin' and shit.
Yes. Praying and shit, huh?
[Guys laugh]
Oh, ladies.
U h, which one of you wanna suck, suck me off first?
You? You?
You ain't got shit!
What about that?
It's cute. I like it.
You got it.
Hey, clean this shit up, too.
Hey yo, check it out. I wrote "Bruce Lee" up there.
(Antonio) Nerf, you climbed all the way up there?
What are you, a fuckin' stupid, man?
What the fuck is the matter with you?
Yo, that's fucked up. Somebody wrote some shit on your house, man.
(Nerf) Reaper, he's from Queensbridge.
They wrote Satan and shit all over the church, too.
Hey, Dito.
It's so hot outside. You got out, yet?
Tell him it's hot because it's summer, you know.
Antonio, come in. Look at you guys. You're filthy.
(Dito) You want juice?
Yeah, give me a juice. Hey, look who's here.
Antonio, what's going on?
Are you fixin'- - What are you doing?
Could you keep it down down there?
Hello! Oould you please...
Do you want me to say somethin' to 'em?
No, it's okay. No. It's alright.
Oome on in.
Giuseppe, sit down. Good to see you. Antonio, where you been lately?
What do you mean? I've been around.
I haven't seen you at the handball courts.
You guys getting tired of getting beat, huh?
Dito didn't tell you we been at the Boys club, boxing?
They got the Golden Gloves coming up.
The only thing you'll ever box is oranges.
Dad, this is serious. They got bags and everything.
It's cheap. $1 O.
$1 O. Where you guys gonna get $1 O from?
It's just $1 O.
You guys wanna be Golden Gloves? You learn from the best.
U p from the waist, down from the chin. That's Golden Gloves.
Okay. Stop it already. Seriously.
You're serious? Oome here.
Shake my hand.
I'm glad to meet you. Serious.
That's a funny joke if I was five years old. Stop it.
The joke is five years old.
Antonio, how old is this guy?
He's serious. I don't know how old he is.
What happened to your nose? It's bleeding.
It's my father. He's stupid. Whatever.
Don't say that about your father.
Hand him a dish rag. Wipe his nose there. What's the matter with him?
Are you alright? Are you getting a job?
What are you doing with your life?
Yeah, for sure. I'm doing...
Yeah, you're not doing anything.
You wanna be boxers. Forget about these Golden Gloves.
You wanna learn? You come to me, 'cause I'm the king.
And the king sits right here.
Monty's throne, right? Monty's throne.
I'm the king.
I'm gonna get up. I'm gonna show you...
Are gonna get up? What?
I'm gonna show him. I'm going to show you the left hook.
I'm gonna show you that left hook.
Bye, Mom. Antonio, come on. Antonio!
Alright, man. Oome on.
Antonio, come on I
Where you going? What's the matter with him?
What's the matter? Where you going?
He wants to go. Giuseppe, come on, man.
Say good bye.
Thank you very much. I appreciate it very much.
It was a pleasure talking to you.
Thank you very much.
That kid doesn't say two words. It scares me that kid.
Antonio? Tonight I want you to come back.
I want you to have dinner with Dito and the family, alright?
You take care of that nose kid.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
They're alright.
[Door closes]
Good dancing.
Look who we got here.
Oh, shit! Friggin' pistachio dick.
Look at these girls.
It curves like a banana, right?
No, like a pistachio.
Do you want some? You.
It's as hot as a fuckin' oven in here.
[Both murmur]
Get the fuck off me! It's like 25O degrees. Get off me.
I feel like a piece of roast beef.
But look at me. I'm fuckin' sticky. Look at me.
So?
Fuckin' landlord's got the fuckin' radiators on in the summer.
You better not fuckin' cum in me.
No!
Don't fuck.
You better not fuckin' cum in me.
[Laughs]
[Screams in pain] Fuck!
What the fuck?
Fuckin' radiator burned me and shit!
Fuck me.
Oome here.
You want me to come over there and give you a hug or some shit?
I don't want you to fuckin' hug me.
Look what we got here. You guys are two naughty fuckers.
Who the fuck is this guy?
My little retarded sister.
You're the bitch who works at the pool with Diane.
I just got done fuckin' her.
Get the fuck out of here.
I'm virile and I'm virile and I'm virile, and I'm ready to do that shit.
I just stole this dildo from M rs. Duran's,
and I was wondering you go into that shit, baby? Two on one action?
All I'm saying, if I was an ugly bitch
and two hot studs like this wanted to fuck me, I'd be into it.
I'm taking a shit and I'm out.
What are you thinking about?
I don't know.
You're really beautiful, you know.
Thank you.
Are you pushing?
Do you wanna kiss me?
For sure. Kiss you.
Fuck you.
I'm sorry. I just, just wanna fuck you, you know.
Alright.
Alright?
No. You're bugging, man.
I don't know why I said that. I wanna fuck you, you know.
I wanna fuck you, too.
I do. I really do.
For real?
For real.
Class, this is Michael O'Shea. He's a new student.
He just moved here this winter from I reland.
And besides making music, M ichael wants to be a writer just like his father.
On his first day here, he wants to read a poem about America.
Here you go.
[Scottish accent] My name's M ichael O'Shea, and I'm from Scotland.
U h. My father says poems don't always have to rhyme.
This one doesn't.
My New friend. I know he likes me, but I think he needs me.
I definitely need him, too. This is a scary place sometimes.
But my new friend, he needs me
because together we're not like everybody else.
That was very nice, Michael. Thank you.
Okay, class, let's turn to page 64, please. Thank you.
It's hot as shit out here.
What the fuck you looking at?
Don't even fuckin' try that shit.
Want some gum?
(Antonio) Yo, did you really take a shit in there?
What is wrong with you?
You smell like open ass, man.
[Retches]
Hey I Hey, old bitch.
Hey, hey. Hey, put your ass here.
Go ahead.
N ice dress. Fuckin' looking like a cheetah.
(drunken man) Clean that shit upl
What? Fucker!
What the fuck is wrong with you, man?
Olean your shit up and tell him to fuck off!
Police'll be here in five minutes.
Antonio, come on.
No, no, no, no.
Wait, wait.
Open the door, man. Hey, come on, open the fuckin' door!
Yo, meet me at the park, alright?
Meet me at the park.
You fucker. You better fuckin' flinch.
You're the new kid from my class, right? From I reland.
Scotland.
We came and lived in Manhattan for a bit but now, yeah.
Fucking crazy there, right?
I'm Dito.
I'm, uh, I'm Dito.
Mick. U hm, Mike.
M ick. U hm, M ike.
And then Giuseppe was the kid climbing on the window. The church, the roof.
My friend, he was running naked on the... you remember that? On the roof?
He was funny.
Where you going?
J ust got bored, you know?
Kind of ride the subway around.
Back and forth, and back and forth.
And back and forth. Back and forth.
Stupid thing.
J ust back and forth?
Yeah.
I was gonna ride it to Coney Island or something.
Go there and I don't know, ride back.
I was thinking about going to Ooney Island, you know.
(Dito) Yeah, 'cause I've never been.
You've never been?
No. I went to the zoo once but that was like in the Bronx or something.
It's not really...
That's not traveling.
It sucks, too. There's nothing really there.
What are you looking at?
That dot.
Close one eye like this.
Fly right over it.
Oh, shit. I got it.
(Monty) You want China?
That's what they got Chinatown for.
You want Italy? You go to Georgie. Where's the Italians they go?
M ulberry Street.
Little Italy.
Wanna go to Puerto Rico? Go uptown. There's Puerto Ricans everywhere.
You know what Antonio just told me?
That there's wild dogs in Italy, right? Who needs that?
Not me.
I don't wanna be there.
[All talk at the same time]
How are you? N ice seeing you.
U ncle George, how you doing?
I'm just boiling.
(Monty) It's summertime. That's why you're boiling.
You want some juice?
Where you been?
I was in Coney Island.
(Monty) What were you doing there?
I was on the train. I meet up with this guy from school.
This Mike kid. He's from I reland. Like from the country I reland.
He was telling me about how he wants to do some music, like a band or something.
You just went to Ooney Island.
Is it just me or it's 1 OO degrees in this house?
It's summer. That's why it's hot. Right, Antonio?
Yeah. It's summer.
It's, summer, baby. It's hot.
What can I tell you?
Will you just stop teasing? The heat's unbearable. We gotta get a fan, Monty.
We gotta get a fan.
(George) Maria, you still there?
(Maria) I have to attach this machine.
(Monty) She's gonna set this place on firel
Can I see what's going on?
I brought the tape. I brought the machine to show you, Monty.
I don't care about that machine.
You can play things from the television.
So it's that machine.
(George) Rewind that. Let's see that again.
Dito, where you going? It's show time over here. [Telephone rings]
Are you expecting a date with that girl? That swimmer?
We heard from your friend you have a girlfriend now, huh? She's a swimmer?
A Swimmer? Who, Laurie? She sells food at the pool.
Yeah, she sells food at the pool.
(Monty) That swimmer girl? Right, Antonio?
(Antonio) The swimmer girl.
U ncle George, she's not a swimmer. She sells food at the pool.
That's what she does.
What does she do? Like races or marathons?
Maybe it was the guy from Ooney Island. The I rish guy.
The guy who wants the band. Right, Monty?
(Monty) She's a swimmer.
What's she doing at the pool if she don't swim?
[Answering machine] You have seven new messages.
U h, Dito, this is Nerf.
Your old friend Nerf.
Monty's not, not doing too good, man.
I know Antonio called you and, uh,
you... you're father's real sick, man.
Your mom called me
and... she really wants you to come home, you know.
So you should.
(fruit man) Hey, come back.
Fuck you!
I hate those fucks!
What are you doing?
Pay, thank.
Oh, my God.
Ohinese motherfucker always staring me down!
(fruit man) You pay.
Why does your dad calls us swimmers?
'Cause you work at a pool.
But I'm not a swimmer.
You better tell Antonio and his fucking brother not to come around my house.
I don't like that asshole.
Diane, don't worry about it.
He's a controlling little fuck! I could tell just by looking at him.
You're making it bigger.
Stop being crazy, alright?
Is it just me or does that nigger seem retarded?
What the fuck are you doing? That's my friend's mother's store.
That's the shit they wrote on your housel
What the fuck are you doing?
You got a problem?
Get off him right now. I'm not playing.
What the fuck? Are you crazy? Fucking bitch I
That's right, asshole.
I don't have a problem. Laurie, go get Antonio.
You need a bitch to go get your man?
I should fuckin' kill you! I should fuckin' kill you.
I'm gonna get you. I got you, baby. You stupid fuckin' bitch!
You nappy motherfucker.
I got you!
(Monty) Explain this to me.
You and this swimmer got into some trouble?
M r. Montiel, I don't even swim.
You don't swim. Look at that eye.
We collect tickets where the food is at the swimming pool.
I'm thinking of quitting. Maybe working at the supermarket.
It's just like too many kids.
Yeah, we care.
Fuck you, okay?
Put this on your eye, alright?
I'm not putting meat on my eye.
Get out of here. I'm not putting that on my face.
People used to do that 1 OO years ago.
I just want to know what's going on. Tell me what happened.
Nothing's going on. It's very simple.
What happened to your eye?
I'm telling you, nothing happened, okay?
Some jerk was acting like a wise guy.
Daddy, some jerk was acting like a wise guy. That's it.
That's it, okay?
(Antonio) You got cut a little bit.
He grabbed him by the face and cut him.
Who grabbed him by the face? A Puerto Rican?
The one that spray painted all the graffiti outside.
A Puerto Rican did this? Was it the Reaper guy?
Please, stop it.
Don't ask me to stop it. This guy better worry now. And I know where he is.
Nerf told me where they stay down by Queensbridge.
Remember what I said. Two shots. Six inches, they go right down.
Two shots? Shit.
Shut the fuck up. I'm sorry, Monty. I don't mean to be cursing.
That's enough, okay? Hey!
God gave me this mouth so I can use it and that's what I'm doing.
Am I gonna have to smack this girl?
She's just talking.
Get the fuck out of my way!
(Antonio) Yo, Yo, get the fuck out I
Hey, fuckin', Nerf, where the fuck did you get a car?
My mother let me take it out to practice for my license.
How'd your mother get a car?
I gotta practice for my license.
Hey, get off the car! Get the fuck off my car!
What the fuck?
(Antonio) Get in, get in. Let's go.
(Nerf) No, don't get in.
I'm coming back. I'm coming back.
You're gonna leave me, then?
This thing is huge!
I'm coming back.
(Dito) We're gonna go around the block.
What happened to your face?
They hit him in the face with a bottle.
Your graffiti friends hit him with a bottle. They fucked up your mom's store.
Dito.
(Nerf) I don't know what you're talking about.
Take us down to Queensbridge.
I gotta take the car back.
Take me down to Queensbridge right now.
No, I can't.
Fuck it. I'll drive.
Alright.
Shut up!
Are you gonna call me? I'm gonna be on this corner. You better call me, Dito.
Your graffiti friends hit him in the face with a bottle.
What, are you fuckin' stupid?
What did you say?
He's my brother.
You know the guy that writes graffiti around here?
[Speaking in Spanish] No hablo ingles.
[Antonio speaks in Spanish] No habla fuckin' I ngles.
What the fuck you doing out so late, man?
So you know the kids that write graffiti and shit, right?
How you know them?
Because one of, one of the members are my brother.
Is your brother?
Your bro... brother?
Reaper.
Reaper?
You see my friend right there?
He's cut, right?
Your brother did that.
Yeah, he cut Dito. Can you say that? Can you say his name?
He cut Dito.
You can tell him Antonio came by? Yeah?
(Nerf) He's a little kid, man.
You can remember to tell him that for me? He cut Dito.
I like this kid. I like this kid. I like him.
This kid's good. Alright, I like this kid. [Kicks trash can]
Are you fuckin' stupid? What's wrong with you? Let's get out of here!
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
I sent a little fuckin' message.
Your father's not stupid.
(Antonio) I swear your father's a good guy, man.
If anybody ever fucked with him, forget it.
(Flori) Antonio's not a well kid.
He shouldn't be hanging out with him.
He's a good kid.
No!
I was any different? Oome on, stop it.
You were so much different. You are a great father.
Not this guy's dad. He beats him to a pulp.
(Antonio) He's a good guy, you know? He's a good guy.
(Dito) That's right, motherfuckerl That's the song?
[Shouting] That's right, motherfuckerl
Man, I'm telling you, your band's gonna be fuckin' hardcore, man.
Yo, Radioman, what's up, my man?
Who the fuck is that guy?
He's cool. Your band has to be cool.
We need to be like Black Flag, Bad Brains, U rban Waste, Major Oonflict, all of them.
Those bands rule. That's fuckin' music.
Our band needs to be cool. We need a good name.
For what?
The band. This is it.
Right here?
This is Frank?
What's the deal with this Frank? We can do the job together.
Definitely. He's going to go on about Job.
You know, the guy from the Bible. J ust say you know.
Which one's the job?
He's got like everything going on, man. He's cool.
I told him you don't have to be a fag to talk like a fag.
Therefore you don't have to be a fag to have your dogs walked by a fag.
Watch the little one. I gotta go, Raul.
I gotta call this pain in the ass before it gets too late.
Yeah.
Oh, unbelievable. [Telephone rings]
Frank, this is Dito.
H i.
Okay.
M ikey, there's $1 O I owe you in dimes. It's on the floor.
Take it for train fares, okay? [Telephone rings]
Yes?
M iss Levitt, I was just gonna call you.
I would never take little Bobo onto the subway. Please!
George, come here. Oome here!
No, I'm serious.
You gotta tell me who would say things like that about me.
No. Wha...
I got somebody here. Let me ask. Listen, Hey!
You know the video of, uh, Lionel Richie with the blind lady?
Hello.
Hello. Yes.
She heard you. I love that song, too.
Yes.
Yes, 9: OO
Thank you!
Oh! N ightmare!
Okay. Let's go. Oome on.
I got Shakespeare. Let's go, guys. Come one.
Let's go. Oome on, come on!
Oome on. Did you take the dimes for the train fare?
Okay, let's go. Oome on. And close the door.
You see, they're insects. Fuckin' horseflies like animals in this place.
I don't want them getting out. Get George.
Let's go. That's it, come on. Let's go, come on.
[Dogs bark]
My good friend here says your name is Titi or Ohiti or Rodito.
Dito.
And you guys are gonna do a band?
Dito's gonna sing.
Oh, how gay. I mean, great. [Laughs]
Is this gonna be like Lionel Richie or you guys rock out?
No, Frank. We're gonna be hardcore like Black Flag.
One of my clients, Bobby, he has the Pomeranian.
He's an entertainment manager, like music or something.
I'll have you guys walk his dog. You never know, right?
Hello there, Abigail.
Taking the dog out for a drag again, I see.
She's too cheap to pay the six bucks for me to walk that thing.
I mean, come on, they're older than dirt.
Frank, what's the job about?
M iss Abigail needs some hot young action, right lovely?
Oome here. George.
She can't hear worth shit.
You walk dogs for half an hour or until they crap.
I charge them $6. I give you $4.
I thought we get $3.
This is one honest young man, this boy. Like Job from the Bible.
You know who Job is, Oondito?
Yeah. I already told him, Frank.
You just got a raise then, for the band.
'Cause we walk dogs, you know? You walk dogs.
Whole wide world walks fuckin' dogs.
[Dogs bark]
Always carry paper. Pretend you pick up the crap.
[Car engine revs]
Ay I
How loud is this freaking city.
[Sirens wailing]
(Dito laughing) Nerf.
Oh, my God.
It's good to see you, man. Really.
Thanks for picking me up.
Hey, no problem, man. I couldn't believe it when you called, dude.
I still can't fucking' believe it, but you're here, man. It's fucked up, right?
It's been a long time, and it's great to see you.
You bugged out when Antonio called, huh?
I still can't believe it, you know. That's all.
Guess who I saw the other day?
Fuckin' Laurie. Your old fuckin' girl, right?
Still up on Ditmars. She's got a kid now. Kid's a fuckin' rat.
She's got a kid? Who with?
I don't fuckin' know.
Not that Guido who used to hit on her?
Guido Tony I No, no. Fuckin' no.
That motherfucker went to the army or some shit.
Maybe he invented something. I don't really know.
Hey, remember this place? Greek Pancyprian Club.
Yo!
U h, this place rock or disco? [Laughs]
I hate that shit.
Fuckers.
U h, it's a full-on Yuppie club now, man. U nbelievable.
Better that way, though. People always dress up and shit.
It looks a little bit better around here, you know.
Your mom's still here, huh?
Yeah.
But she's sleeping.
I mean, everybody says I should get my own place, but...
I ain't got to pay rent. You get free food. For now, you know.
Thanks for letting me stay. I can get a hotel if you want.
Hotel?
Hell, man. My mom's got the room all cleaned out.
She's all excited. She thinks you know all the movie stars in Oalifornia.
[Laughs]
Wait a minute. Let's just, uh...
Let's just hang here a minute, okay?
I mean, damn.
I didn't think I was ever gonna see you again, you know.
U pstairs we can't really talk.
You want some?
U h, no, no. That's cool.
I just take a little.
Yeah, sure.
We just... We should go to Monty's right now.
Nah, it's late. It's late.
What time is it?
We'll go in the morning, then.
I hate to... I hate seeing him like he is, man.
He's fucked up.
And your mom, she...
She didn't think you'd come back.
She told me that, uh...
She tells everybody about your book.
It's like your friend, remember? That, that kid, fuckin' I rish.
How are you?
[Chuckles] How am I?
Are you alright?
I'm alright. Ah!
I don't know how to answer that, man.
J ust like my fuckin' mom. Like I told you.
I told you how she's so excited to see you, and then with me, you know, it's like...
When l...
She sees me on the street, she hides.
And she's so fat, you know. And she tries to hide behind these skinny little poles.
Poles like that right there. [Laughs]
Even she hides from me and she's my fuckin' mom.
They're not supposed to do that.
I know. Things will...
Things will pick up and get better.
No, man.
Things don't get better here. You tell me that they fuckin' do, but...
It's really, it's fuckin' good to seen you, man.
That's the truth.
Is that true?
(Antonio) Shit I
[laughs]
(Antonio) Oh, shit.
(Dito) They got this thing over the Empire State Building
which is like Ripley's Believe it or Not.
M ike was telling me about this guy he saw. He's humongous.
It's a 10-foot tall statue of this real guy and a bunch of other shit.
That's where the niggers stay at, right?
No. That's 42nd Street.
Oh, Yeah. Needledick was saying they got triple X movie over there.
Like fuckin' people fuckin' pigs and shit.
People fuckin' pigs? Get the fuck out of herel
This guy is like 10 feet tall. He's fuckin' huge, man.
There's loads of cool shit there.
Check this guy out.
What do you wanna see, some fuckin' titties or a giant?
Yeah, I wanna see a pig get fucked.
Exactly.
Mike, huh? Dito says that you guys work for some faggot, right?
Think he can give me a job?
I'll see.
Yeah?
Yeah, man. I'll check out.
(Nerf) Yo, this weed is bogus.
I know a guy from school. He's got great weed. That shit will fuck you up.
He's cool as well. Guy is cool.
Wow I
You can get weed, huh? This guy's pretty fuckin' cool.
He can get fuckin' pot.
That's pretty fuckin'... yeah. This guy's pretty cool.
You can understand what he says?
'Cause I can't fuckin' understand him.
Yo, Dito, I'm going to take off, man.
Where you going? Where you going?
What's your problem, man?
Antonio, I don't want any trouble.
I just wanna hang out. If you got a problem with me, I'll go.
No, man. I ain't got no problem.
You can hang out as much as you want.
You can show us where the giants are and all that.
I like this guy. He's, he's fun. He's a good guy.
(Nerf) We're getting something to eat,
and she wants to go go White Castle. [Laughs]
(Diane) Why don't you shut up?
Why you got to do this?
What'd you say?
Why you got to do that shit?
Don't you fuckin' move, Diane.
Out the fuckin' shit, alright?
Do what?
You know what. It's just played out.
What's played out?
She moved.
What the fuck. I'm fucking serious. That shit is not funny!
(Nerf) Giuseppe, that's enough.
I'm getting the fuck out of here.
Yeah? Go ahead. Bye.
Could you do something about your fucking crazy brother?
Fuck you, Giuseppe, alright?
You fuckin' piece of shit I Fuck you.
(Dito) Lauriel
She wants to go to White Oastle, alright?
This bitch loves going to White Oastle. To White Oastle.
(Dito) Laurie? Come on.
(Nerf) Where you going?
Fuck them. It's played out here.
Laurie. Laurie, can you stop for a sec? Laurie, come on I
Did you really see what that fucker did?
I know.
You think that's funny?
I know it's not funny. I don't think it's funny.
Hold on a second!
I'm sorry. I don't fuckin' like that, either.
Yeah, right. You do.
I'm coming. I'll be right there, alright?
I am sorry.
Whatever.
~ Trouble ~
~ Oh, trouble Set me free ~
~ I have seen your face ~
~ And it's too much Too much for me ~
~ Trouble ~
~ Oh, trouble Can't you see ~
~ You're eating My heart away ~
~ And there's nothing M uch left of me ~
~ I've drunk your wine ~
~ And you have made Your world mine ~
~ So won't you be fair ~
Hey, my name is Diane. I like to fuck.
My name is Jenny.
And everybody in this place is a fuckin' joke.
My name is Nerf.
And this shit sucks.
I'm Giuseppe, Antonio's brother.
I'm Laurie.
And everybody's gonna leave me.
I know they are.
I'm a fuckin' piece of shit.
And that's who I am.
~ Trouble Can't you see ~
~ You have made me a wreck ~
~ Now won't you leave me I n my misery ~
~ I've seen your eyes ~
~ And I can see Death's disguise Hanging on me ~
~ Hanging on me ~
~ I'm beat I'm torn ~
~ Shattered and tossed And worn ~
~ Too shocking to see ~
Hey, listen, Antonio. I'm sorry about this played out shit.
Don't worry about it.
No, that's fucked up!
Now, that's fucked up.
I'm going to go in.
Do you want me to come?
No.
Don't worry.
I'm good. I'll call you tomorrow.
Monty said he wanted to play some handball tomorrow. So I'm gonna come by.
That's fucked up.
[FIori's muffled voice] He's my Goddamned son, too.
They run around like a pack of wolvesl
Do you even have any concern? Do you?
Nol
What's wrong? You okay, mom?
I'm okay.
It's okay. It's nothing.
Dito.
She, you know, she got excited, you know.
I was just, uh... Your mother, she... you know, went for a walk.
She gets excited.
You okay?
Fine.
I'm good.
What happened with you and Antonio? He was here.
He said you were mad at him. You had a fight or something?
It's alright.
How'd get that? What's this on your face?
You okay?
Yeah.
What happened to you? What is this?
It's nothing.
Hey, come on. You know me.
Rock of Gibraltar, right?
Yeah.
You been taking your Dilantin?
What, are you writing a book, huh?
No, it's just...
I'm fine, okay?
You were on one of your journeys
with that kid M ike in Manhattan. Antonio was telling me.
I wasn't with Mike.
What if I did go? What if I went to Manhattan or I went somewhere else
like, uh, I don't know?
Oome on. You're not going anywhere, Dito.
Oome here.
How are you, Dito, huh?
Since when are you here at this time?
Put on the TV. Give your old man a break, huh?
Forget it.
Are you scared?
I would be.
If a guy wrote on my house "I was dead", he's already fucked you up.
I'd be having a fuckin' heart attack.
They just write shit.
Locker room disinfectant stuff, right?
Check this shit out.
"Do not inhale, breathe. Avoid skin-eye contact.
I rritant. Skin irritant. U nsafe.
Eye irritant. Skin irritant. U nsafe.
Keep away from all body parts."
Wanna try it?
What, do you drink it?
Sniff it.
Mike, I'm sorry Antonio's a fuckin' asshole, man.
He's not always like that. It's just when he gets around people and shit.
Fuck him.
You're always fuckin' afraid of him. Give me that shit, man.
No, I'm not afraid.
He's a dick.
Fuck him.
I'm scared, M ike. It's just...
I'm sorry. I don't even fuckin' know what I'm saying when smoking.
What the fuck are you sorry for, M ike?
If some guys were after me like that, I would be shitting myself.
Oalifornia's probably the best, right?
I always think about that place.
Well, let's go, then.
What do you mean?
Let's just fucking go.
I saw this, uh, TV commercial, right?
You can take like a, a bus, right?
It's $39.
$39?
That's crazy.
Hey, is your fuckin' head going like boom, boom, boom? Like hard.
[Clank]
Laurie.
Laurie?
You're so stupid.
U h?
Hey, stupid, I'm not talking to you.
I'm still not gonna talk to you.
Come on.
I'm not talking. Why are you here?
Why are you even here?
'Cause I wanna be here.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What's wrong? Why are you still mad?
You forgot, right? You let Giuseppe throw knives at me and Diane.
You still mad about that?
Like, I'm not even mad. I just feel like the whole shit was stupid, you know?
Hello? Shit.
You're drunk.
No.
Oh, shit.
You're stoned. Yeah, you are.
No, I'm not.
You are.
You know what I'm gonna do if you let me in?
No. What you gonna do?
I'm not even gonna fuck you.
Wow! You're not gonna even fuck me!
Not even if I let you in?
I'm just gonna lick your pussy:
Oh, my God.
My mother's like right there. She can hear you right now.
You know why?
No, why?
Why what?
What are you talking about?
I don't know... I don't know why you're gonna lick my pussy.
That's what you wanted me to say.
Because, uhm,
I'm gonna lick your pussy because me and M ike we're going to Oalifornia
with our band and shit.
I want you to come, you know, because I love you.
Because the fuckin' Mets won.
What? What did you say?
You said you love me.
What?
You said you love me, right?
I'm serious. That shit means a lot to me, you know.
I love you. I don't why. I love you.
' Oause I love you. 'Cause...
I can't.
Stupid.
(Antonio) Hey, yo. Hey, yo,
I stole us a Spalding from Fishbein's.
I swear that fuckin' Oharlie his getting blind as he can be.
I can't wait to get that motherfucker.
I would play. I just gotta go back.
I gotta go to the city right now.
What do you wanna go to Manhattan for? Monty wanted to play handball.
You okay? What happened?
It was my fuckin' father. You wanna go first to the park?
No, I gotta fu... I gotta go fuckin' with the dogs.
M ike with the dogs? Oome on. Hey!
Maybe you could see if I can get a job there, man.
Tell your friend I ain't gonna fuck with him, right?
Maybe we can hang out later.
Look who's here.
Sorry. I got lost changing trains.
Take little Geronimo here. You got to go through the teeth over here.
Look at Young Geronimo. Oareful, motherfucker. The teeth are lethal.
Take Bobo and Lulu too, because M iss Levitt will have a fuckin' heart attack.
You gotta go through here. Merry-go-round.
Oould they make it a little more heat in this city or what?
Sorry, he's blind. Poor kid.
So this guy has a Pomeranian. Marilyn.
You gotta walk the thing sometimes for like an hour before it craps.
On 2nd Avenue. Bobby, the owner, he can be a real pain in the ass.
He'll check the dog's ass. Make sure it just does it. Okay?
Thank you, ma'am. They're okay.
Those things always end up with you going to hell.
So, remember he's like an entertainment manager,
or like he owns a store or something. Fish and lizards.
But music, too. Whatever.
I told him about you guys and the music,
and that maybe he should do something. You never know, okay?
I gotta head downtown. M ikey, you have the address. You can walk from here.
And break the leg. That's what they say in the big time.
Oheerio, Frank.
Your mothers must be really proud of you.
I could jump from one side to the other like this.
Jesse Owens would've. You're not a track star, man.
I'm sorry. I hate to tell you this. You're not making it.
What you think, you cute Giuseppe?
I'm not cute. I'm handsome.
Who the fuck told you that?
Girls.
Go get my ball, man.
Go get my... Go get my ball.
Hey, Bobby.
This is Dito.
Hey, there. I'll bring him right back.
Thanks.
Let's go.
No, don't fuck with that. Oome on, man.
Touch it with your finger. With your finger.
What the fuck are you doing, man?
I heard if you put both feet on it at the same time, nothing happens.
You like conduct electricity and shit.
What are you Einstein? You sound like an idiot.
You're worried about me, Antonio, aren't you?
Am I fuckin' worried about you?
The fuckin' train is coming. I don't give a fuck about you. Get my ball, man.
You don't give a shit?
Now how about giving a shit?
The fuckin' train is coming. You don't see it?
Tell me you're worried about me.
I don't give a fuck about you. If you wanna die, go ahead. Go ahead.
You're not gonna tell me you're worried about me?
What the fuck? Oome on, man. Get the fuck up here.
What the fuck are you doing? The train's coming right at you.
You're my brother.
The fuckin' train. It's right there.
You're gonna be retarded and just sit down? I don't give a fuck.
Get the fuck out already. Get he fuck out!
Gol Get the fuck out I
I was calling. You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
When I call you, you always call me back. I got worried.
This is messed up, huh?
It's fucked up. It's just fucked up.
I'm getting out of here. Me and M ike we're leaving. We're going to Oalifornia.
I know. Remember you told me? You wanted me to go with you.
Yeah.
What? You don't want me to go with you?
Is that what you're saying?
I want to talk to Antonio.
I'm just going to talk.
Why can't you even look at me right now? You're not looking at me.
How do you mean? How else can I look at you?
You said that you loved me, right? Did you mean that?
Laurie, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm gonna talk to Antonio.
You better not. You better talk to me right now.
You okay? You okay?
Don't worry about it. What are you going to do? It's fucked up.
He's, he's fucking... He's stupid.
It's just fuckin'- - Now he's dead and he's stupid.
You know Giuseppe. He's fuckin' he's an idiot.
I found out where the fuckin' Reaper guy is.
I found him for sure this time. I know where they hang out.
Don't worry about that, either. I'm gonna kill his ass.
I'm here for Giuseppe. Antonio, you're here for your brother.
That's your brother in a box.
That's your brother.
Is that all you think about, the Reaper guy? It's your brother's funeral.
What the fuck do you mean, "Is that all I ever fuckin' think about?
What do you mean?
What do you mean by that?
What'd I say?
All I ever think about is you? Is that what you're saying? I think about you?
I'm asking you a fuckin' question. What did you mean by that?
I didn't mean anything by it.
Get the fuck out! I don't even fuckin' care about you!
I don't fuckin' even care. Do you hear me? I don't give a fuck.
(Monty) Antoniol
I'm sorry, Monty.
Fuck! Fuck!
You alright?
Hey.
Do you know this used to be a candy store here? Oan you believe it?
[Piano music covers voice]
What does the Stop mean? Do you see the hand?
Stop!
It means you don't cross the street. You stop.
Go.
Yo! Don't be making no transactions on my corner here, alright?
(Laurie) Yo.
Fuckin' Hector. Little kids here, man.
I'm serious. I'm serious, Hector.
Fuckin' television. Yo, that works?
Hey, is that's flat screen?
(Laurie) Yo, I'm serious. That works?
(Dito) You used to be a swimmer?
Oh, you used to be a swimmer, right?
Hey.
Who's that?
Shit. This is Joey. Look.
Joseph. M r. Joey.
Joey, like Giuseppe?
Like Joseph.
It's his father's name. Joseph.
Mommy, who's that man?
He's gone now. He wants to know who you are.
I've known your mother since she was, like, she was this big.
She can't be this big, you know.
[Laughs]
Your mom said you were coming into town.
Yeah, I'm gonna see my father.
Yeah, Nerf told me, you know, you'd be here in your corner.
My corner. Nerf.
Wow.
Laurie, you look beautiful.
You know, I'm in my bests.
I'm looking really good. My best slippers.
You should see them actually. Manolo's.
You're staying at your mother's, right?
Nerf's.
Nerf's mother's. Alright.
Yeah. Alright.
I'll be around, you know. Maybe later I'll come back or you wanna come down.
You wanna come down and play.
It was really nice to see you. I gotta make dinner now.
It's good to see you.
Alright. See you, M r. Joey.
Antonio. Yo!
Antonio.
Yo, Antonio.
Yo, Dito, what's up, man?
Oome on. I'm sorry.
What's up, Dito? Where the fuck you been?
I know where he's been, since he's all I have to think about.
He's all I have to think about.
I'm fuckin' working.
What are you always fuckin' pissed off for?
I'm not pissed off. You know your father had a seizure?
This guy don't even know his fuckin' father had a seizure.
He's acting like there's nothing wrong.
You're in fuckin' N iggerville.
Nerf's dad is black. What happened to my father?
My father's Dominican.
Nerf's fuckin' Nerf, man.
You're never around anymore. Where the fuck were you?
Where the fuck are you? Nowhere!
This fuckin' guy. Oome on, let's go.
I don't fuckin' know you anymore!
Yo, tell me who the fuck...
Look, yo, you don't think I'd fuck you up?
Ohill out, Antonio.
You have no idea how fuckin' close you are. Nerf, let's just fuckin' go.
Antoniol
Nerf. Nerf!
What's up, motherfucker? Think you can hide from me?
Think you can fuck with my family?
Think you can fuck with my family, nigger?
[Dito shouts in pain]
Don't fuck with me 'cause I know your family.
I know your father. I know where you live.
Don't fuck with TS S! Next time I'll kill you. That's my word.
I know your family. I know you live right here. Don't ever fuck with me!
H urry up.
[Men laugh]
You're scared.
(Antonio) Yol What the fuck, man?
Yo! Yo, yo, yo yo.
J ust... just fuckin' lay there for a second.
Yo, come here. Oome here. Look at me.
Oh, fuck. He fucked up.
Don't be mad, okay?
No, no. Nerf, get your mother's car.
Go get your mother's car right now.
You're fucked up. That fuckin' It's...
[yelling] Oh, fuckl
[soft music covers voice]
Every day something's different with you guys. I don't know what it is.
Every day is something, huh? Right, Antonio? Every day is something.
Yeah.
So what happened this time? A dog bite you? H uh?
I told you I fell off a park fence.
Oh, you fell off a fence?
Never mind about that, okay? J ust tell me what happened.
H i.
It's 2: OO in the morning.
(Laurie) I just wanted to see what happened.
Sorry.
What happened?
There, now you see. Now go.
I said I just want to know what happened.
The freaking graffiti guys. You know, the Reaper. Your fuckin' race.
They whacked him with a bat.
It's not my race.
(Flori) Monty? What are you doing out there?
U h, don't worry, Flori. I'm talking to Dito and Antonio, okay?
It's so latel
These guys, they knew who you were, too.
The Reaper guy. The bat man.
But don't worry about it. We'll take care of it. J ust trust me.
Why do they care who I am?
They care who you are. These guys are crazy, M r. Montiel.
Daddy, me and M ike are planning a trip to go to Oalifornia for a month.
Listen to Antonio, okay? What do you mean you wanna go somewhere?
You wanna go to Ohina, go to Ohina Town.
You don't even listen to anything.
I'm sorry. I just feel you're not listening to what he's saying.
Sorry, daddy. I'm serious.
You said to me that if I were to leave,
that you wouldn't talk to me anymore.
And if I were to go, would you not talk to me?
That's what you said you were gonna do.
But you're not going anywhere, Dito.
You're not going anywhere. You stay right here at home with us, okay?
Daddy, can you be my fuckin' father for a second?
I wanna go somewhere. I wanna do something for once. I can't be here anymore.
It's a nightmare here.
(Flori) What's going on out there?
Flori, wait a minute. Everything's gonna be alright.
Who do you think you are talking to me like that?
He's your son.
J ust mind your business. I told you to mind your business.
Alright. You wanna go, then go!
Is that what you wanna hear? Then go.
Don't you ever talk to me like that again.
Antonio is gonna make everything right. Right, Antonio?
He's gonna make it right. Yes! He's gonna make it right!
He's gonna take care, okay?
Why don't you shut the fuck up? Listen to him. Why don't you leave my fuckin house?
Listen to me. Antonio, you are going to make it right?
You're gonna make it right, right?
[Dito and Laurie argue] He's not going nowhere.
Get he fuck out of my house! Get the fuck out of my house.
Hey, hey. Hey! What are you doing?
Get the fuck out. I hate you!
What the hell are you saying to me? You hate your father?
Hey, fuck, relaxl
Monty?
Hold his head!
(Antonio) Dito, where are you going?
What is happening?
You'll be alright. You'll be alright.
You'll be alright.
[Whispers] Dito.
H i.
Dito.
Oome here.
[Whispers] Look at you.
You're beautiful.
Momma, you do.
Monty?
Monty. Look who's here.
Hey. Look at you.
Long time no see.
Daddy.
Antonio and Nerf called. Said you were sick.
Me? Rock of Gibraltar, man.
You don't look so good.
He came all this way to tell me I don't look so good, Flori?
No.
He's here to take you to the hospital because you're sick, right?
Well... thanks for coming. You take care, okay?
Take care?
When I came all the way here to see you?
Dito, it's nice to see you again.
You came and everything. Now you take care.
I see what he's doing.
Nice. I see what you're doing.
That's because you're a very smart guy.
Well, I'm your son. You know that, right?
You're my son?
Yeah, I'm your son. Remember?
You're my son? You're not my son.
I'm not gonna fight.
You want me to leave?
Big shot comes here.
Comes 15, comes 3, 000 miles.
From co... Comes 3, 000 miles in 15 years.
You go back to California like the rat you are.
You leave me, your mother.
You don't see your friend Antonio.
Monty.
Not oncel Oncel
You can go. You take care.
Used to be Antonio's house.
House of horrors. The poor kid.
Look how nice it is now.
It's nice, huh?
I wasn't upset when he went to prison. Not a bit.
That's where me and you father are different.
You know, if you hooked your father up to a lie detector test
and asked if he was the best father whoever lived ever,
he'd pass with flying colors.
That's because he loved you with everything he had.
Every last bit. He loved you.
He loved coming up here with you.
You know, people used to think he was your grandfather.
He thought that was funny.
You know, one generation can be funny, I guess. But two?
We were too old to have such a young boy.
We needed you probably more than you needed us. Or, you know.
Your father was so crazy about you.
I never saw nothing like it.
You were more his buddy than a son.
He couldn't wait for you to come out and play.
I'm sorry, Ma.
You can't come back with hatred for your father. You can't.
How could you love him so much in that book and not see him for so long?
I know you have your reasons.
We all missed you here.
You're my son, too.
Look at you.
You're a man now.
It's good to see you again.
To say your name to you.
I thought of this every day, and now it's here.
Every day.
[Indistinct talking of girls]
You asked your dad, right?
How can we afford Oalifornia?
Frank.
Remember the commercial you told me about? You told me about that.
I saw it. The $39-buses.
We get the money from Frank and we can go.
Hey, Ronnie, give her her shirt back.
I just wanna get the fuck out of here.
I'm not gonna go without you. And we're going, right?
Yeah.
I want my fuckin' shirt back.
Oan you give her back her frigging shirt?
I'm serious, Ronnie. I'm serious. Ronniel
Ronnie! Give her the fuckin' shirt back.
Why you do this every time? Fuckin' little pervert.
Here.
I gave you your shirt. Tell your friend to talk to me.
Your friend has a mind of her own.
Tell your mind to talk to me.
My mind is not gonna talk to you. I don't wanna talk to you.
You don't think I'm not gonna get in there now?
You're not gonna get in.
You didn't think I was gonna get in?
H uh?
I'm sorry, Laurie. At my fuckin' house I didn't mean to...
I didn't mean to.
You were so mean to me. You were really mean to me.
I was pissed off.
I was pissed off. I lost it, you know. I fuckin'- -
What is that?
Is that a bruise? I did that to you?
Yeah.
Don't worry. I bruise easily. It's fine.
When I grabbed you?
Yo, Dito.
The Reaper's over there. Let's go. Get up out of the pool.
Antonio found the dude that hit you with the bat. He's waiting for you.
Oome on!
You going over there is so fuckin' stupid.
Let's go! Dito, come on, man.
You don't need that fuckin' asshole. He is the fuckin' worst!
Where are you going? You're so full of shit, man.
You wanna get out of here, but you're running after Antonio.
The guy's a fuckin' dick, Dito. It's because of him you're fucked up.
Fuckin' go then! Go!
I'll be right back.
You're not coming back!
What's up, Dito?
The fuckin' spic is right there, man.
Nerf told you, right?
Yeah.
That's our motherfucker right there.
He's in there playing Asteroids.
Yo, get down. Get down.
Yeah, let him go. Let him go.
[Both laugh]
He'll be there all alone.
I'm gonna show this fucker what's up.
(Dito) Frank?
Frank?
Oh, shit.
What's up? Is it Saturday?
It ain't Saturday, Frank.
Sit down. Sit down.
Frank, we need our money. Remember I was telling you...
You guys know this shit's no good. H uh?
You like this song? You can hear it, right?
Listen, listen, listen.
Oh, fuck! Did you hear that?
Did you hear that?
It's like... Oh, I love it.
Right?
And these things like fuckin' ultrasonic.
They're like walkie talkie shit. But in your head.
Like, it sounds there but it's in here, too. You know what I mean?
It sounds there but it's in here, too. You know what I mean?
Walkie talkie shit, I'm telling ya.
Out there, in here. Out there, in here. It's amazing.
Frank, you ain't paid us for three weeks.
Damn. This shit is impossiblel You hear that?
[Sniffs]
Oome on, Frank. We know the fuckin' money's in the fridge.
Fucking great song. I love this song.
I love this song.
Frank, enough shit already. The fuckin' money's in the fridge.
Either you get it for us or we're gonna take it.
What are you gonna do?
Wait.
M ikey, you came here to rob me?
Frank, we're friends, man.
I didn't come to rob you.
Frank, we didn't come here to rob you.
We just want to get paid, you know.
You haven't paid us for three fuckin' weeks.
Three weeks? I haven't paid you in three weeks?
[Sniffs]
Okay.
I mean, it's cool. It's cool. I owe you money.
I mean, you know,
[closes fridge door]
I got a gun in here too, you know.
And if you rob me, you know,
I would've had to have used it.
But I wouldn't. I would never. I'm sorry.
How much do I owe you?
[Sniffs]
Three hundred for both.
Three hundred.
[Sniffs] You know what?
Take it all, M ike. Take it all.
It's only $3OO, Frank. All we want is what we're owed. We're not asking...
Like Job. Remember from the Bible?
Like him. You're so good, M ikey. You're so good.
But here is no good anymore. Here is no good.
You're always talking about the music, or Oalifornia.
Here's no good anymore, okay?
Here's no good anymore. Take it! J ust take the money, please.
Take the money.
It's time to go. Listen to Ditol
He knows when it's time to go!
It's time to go.
Mikey... it's time to go.
Take it.
Take it all.
It's time to go.
(Puerto Rican kid) Yeah, yeah. That's me.
Yeah.
No conscience. No conscience. These motherfuckers.
Do what they want. Do exactly what they want.
You show them what's up. What's right.
You go, boy. You go.
Pow I
I was afraid maybe you drowned in here or something.
Listen, Dito.
U hm, you know, this thing with Antonio, you know,
you know, don't worry.
You're kids.
I spoke to the guy, the guy with the suit.
He said everything is gonna be okay.
It's gonna be good. He's gonna take care of it.
I'm not worried about it. Okay?
I'm sorry I ran away when you had the seizure, dad. [Sniffs]
Don't worry.
Monday, instead of going to school,
you take your I D card. You go to Riker's Island, you see Antonio.
Take your friend M ike. He's a good kid.
Daddy, I wanted to tell you that...
I know. I just want you to understand everything.
I like Antonio. Yeah.
Why don't you ever listen to anything I ever say?
I'm listening to you. Listen to me.
It's gonna be okay. Alright?
Don't fuckin' touch me.
Listen to me.
Get the fuck off me! Don't touch me. Don't fuckin' touch me.
[Shouting] Don't you talk to me like that I
Don't you raise your voice to me!
Your my son. Oome on. Dito.
Get the fuck off me!
What's the matter with you? It's gonna be alright. Do you hear what I'm saying?
It's gonna be okay. It will be okay.
My friend M ike just died, dad. He just got fuckin' shot. You don't know whats happening.
What are you talking about? What happened?
My friend M ike is dead.
Oome here.
Don't fuckin' touch me! Please, get the fuck off me!
What is the matter with you?
You don't raise your hands to your father!
You don't raise your hands to your father. I love you.
I'm asking you not to fuckin' touch me!
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Don't you fuckin' do it!
Don't you raise your hands to me again!
I'm your father.
You're not supposed to hate your father.
When are you my father?
When are you my father? [Sobs]
(Laurie) You know, I, uh,
I waited around for a year at my window when you left.
I bought Oalifornia maps.
Any time I heard anything about it, I would think of you.
Embarrassing.
Dumb little girl.
Listen, I'm not heartbroken about it, alright? I'm over that shit.
I was just a dumb girl. We were fuckin' kids. Whatever.
But you need to take your father to the hospital.
I mean, your mother...
I'm serious.
I got a little boy. He's a good kid.
And he's gonna look after me when we're older.
So you look after your mother. You take care of your father. You take care of your mother.
It's real simple. 'Cause she's a good woman.
It's not a fuckin' stretch.
I know what you're saying. Alright?
Thanks for coming. I should go.
Wow.
Monty's son.
You know what? You're Flori's son as well.
And that's why you're all fucked up.
Yeah, I'm all fucked up.
You think you're going? You're gonna fuckin' leave? Go ahead, fuckin' go.
You're not gonna go.
You didn't fuckin' come all the way over so you could leave again.
You don't know.
You don't know what it was like in the house, okay?
Listen. You want it straight?
'Cause I'm the only one who's gonna tell you for some fuckin' reason.
You killed him. You killed your father when you left.
Are you hearing me? You fuckin' killed him.
You left a trail of blood when you left.
So forget me. Forget all this shit. Forget it, alright?
You killed your mother and you killed your father.
And for the past fuckin' 2O years he's been dying,
just waiting for you to come home.
Say daddy, you're fucked up. I hate your guts.
Whatever you need to get out of your angsty little fuckin' head.
Touch my head one more fuckin' time and I'm gonna go nuts.
Go ahead. Go fuckin' nuts.
Go fuckin' nuts. Let it out! Stop fuckin' running away.
You think you're a man? That's just a fuckin' tail between your legs.
Go home and take care of your mother.
Go home and take care of your father.
That's gonna make you a fuckin' man.
That's all you've got left.
'Cause if you don't do that shit, it's too fuckin' late.
Okay, bye.
Yeah.
You're going to hospital.
Where's Ma?
Ma? Where is she?
Why don't you get out?
Get out of the house.
Did you love me? Ever?
I said go.
Dad, did you love me or not?
Daddy, I gotta know.
Lie to me and tell me you did. Let me feel like the piece of shit I am.
Did you love me or not?
[Shouting] Answer me!
A father always...
Not a father! You!
Of course I did.
I told you I loved you the last time I saw you.
I love you, Dito. Alright?
You're my son. I'm very proud of you.
Now, Antonio,
he doesn't have anybody to tell him something like this.
Listen, Monday you don't have to go to school.
Monday you take your I D.
You go to Riker's.
You see Antonio.
Take your friend Mike with you.
I like that kid.
You take the bus there with your friend.
You go see Antonio.
Yeah, man.
Have fun.
You're just kids, Dito.
J ust kids.
But your friend Antonio, he needs you now.
'Cause he don't have anybody to tell him what I just told you.
Oome here.
(guard) Okay, enough.
Thank you for coming.
I know I'm in the middle of no place, right?
No, no. L... I should've come, you know, a long time go.
It's alright.
Damn, Dito.
I got so much I wanna say to you.
I just don't know what to say.
(Dito) I don't know what I was expecting to happen.
Antonio exists.
Crazy, huh?
I n the end, just like I said,
I left everything and everyone,
but no one.
No one has ever left me.
Poor Antonio.
He's in for life.
(interviewer) Maybe he'll get out.
Yeah, but he's got a bad temper.
With a bad temper you can't be out of here.
He's a good guy, though. He's a good guy, though.
Oh, yeah. I like him.
But good guys don't get out of here.
They won't change. Not to worry, you know.