[Miley vocalizing]
OK, again.
- Ow!
- [chuckling]
- [man] Go, take it!
- [Miley laughs]
[continues vocalizing]
Hold on, huh.
- [cracks]
- Ah. [laughs]
- That crack, I think it's good.
- Hey, watch this.
- [cracks loudly]
- Ah!
[♪ Hannah Montana:
We Got The Party]
♪ Come on guys tell me
what we're doing ♪
♪ We're hangin' around when we
could be all over the place ♪
♪ The sun is shinin'
just the way we like it ♪
♪ Let's get out of this hallway
Show the world our face ♪
♪ It's Friday
but there's nowhere to go ♪
♪ Anywhere is cool
but we're not going home ♪
♪ And we can do anything
we wanna do ♪
♪ It's all up to me
and you ♪
♪ Turn this park
into a club ♪
♪ The stars are lights and the
moon is the vibe from above ♪
♪ Skateboards here's our ride
so pull on up ♪
♪ Oh look everyone
is waiting for us ♪
♪ So anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows
We got the party with us ♪
♪ Anywhere we
are Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows
We got the party with us ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh oh oh
Oh oh oh oh oh oh ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh oh oh
We got the party with us ♪♪
[crowd screaming]
Hannah! Hannah!
[cymbals sounding]
[♪Rock Star]
[woman] Are you ready
for Hannah Montana?
♪ Sometimes I walk a little
faster in the school hallway ♪
♪ Just to get next to you ♪
♪ Some days I spend
a little extra time ♪
♪ In the morning
Dress to impress you ♪
♪ Guess you don't notice
Guess you don't need this ♪
♪ Sad you're not seein'
what you're missin' ♪
♪ On the outside shyin' away ♪
♪ On the inside dyin' to say ♪
♪ I'm unusual
Not so typical ♪
♪ Way too smart to
be waiting around ♪
♪ Tai chi practicin'
Snowboard champion ♪
♪ I could fix the flat
on your car ♪
♪ I might even
be a rock star ♪
♪ Sometimes I wish
when the phone rings ♪
♪ That it would be you
Saying "Let's hang out" ♪
♪ Then you confess that there's
something special between us ♪
♪ Why don't we find out ♪
♪ You don't even know me
Guess you don't need me ♪
♪ Why you're not seein'
what you're missin' ♪
♪ On the outside shyin' away ♪
♪ On the inside dyin' to say ♪
♪ I'm unusual
Not so typical ♪
♪ Way too smart
to be waiting around ♪
♪ Tai chi practicin'
Snowboard champion ♪
I could fix the flat on your car
♪ I might even be a rock star ♪
♪ Rock star ♪
♪ If you only knew
who the real me ♪
♪ I might even be a rock star ♪
♪ I'm telling you
that we are meant to be ♪
♪ That wouldn't it be nice
if you could see ♪
♪ That I really
am a rock star ♪
♪ Yeah Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, I really am a rockstar ♪
Hey Hey Hey!
A rockstar!
♪ I'm unusual
Not so typical ♪
♪ Way too smart
to be waiting around ♪
♪ Tai chi practicin'
Snowboard champion ♪
♪ I could fix the
flat on your car ♪
♪ Rockin' it
wherever we are ♪
♪ Yeah yeah, 'cause I really
am a rock star ♪
♪ 'Cause I really
am a rockstar ♪
♪ I am a rock star ♪
♪ Oh-oh oh-oh ♪♪
[car starts]
- [Billy] To the studio, James.
- [Miley] His name is Kenny.
I know, but I always
wanted to say that.
You are so lucky to have such
a great band. You know that?
- I know.
- I mean, everybody in that band
is a A-time
superstar musician.
That's coming from a guy
that plays every Indian casino
between the Atlantic
and the Pacific.
- Candice, this is my dad.
- How's it going? Jaime.
- Nice to see you.
- Nice to see you again.
- I'm Candice.
- How are you?
- She makes me sound good, dad.
- I'm Jaco.
- Hey, I know you.
- How's it going?
- Your dad was fantastic.
- Cool!
This is my bass player!
This ain't your bass player.
This is my bass player.
Dude, you're matching
my shoes today.
This is beginning of rehearsals
and there's a whole lot of work
to be done.
But this is the way you build
a band and the way you build
a tour,
and you just got to take
the time to get prepared.
- What if we start it
just with you?
- OK.
Just something that just brings
the stuff out of the ceiling
as it's coming down.
Maybe, four bars of that.
And then...
Then go into the...
[♪ Hannah Montana:
Pumpin' Up The Party]
♪ Get up, get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
- Are you ready
to meet Miley Cyrus?!
- [man] One, two, three, four!
And the girls doing a...
♪ Hey Miley you're so fine ♪
♪ You're so fine
you blow my mind ♪
♪ Hey Miley ♪
- That is killer.
- Yeah?
Ow!
You're stepping and shift your
left. You're gonna just step
your right over.
- Change.
- Yep.
[bass strums]
I think they overlap
each other a bit.
If you keep singing that,
I'll have time to do that.
She'll probably have on a trench
coat, sunglasses and a cool hat.
And she's underneath the stage
making her transition,
and we're gonna have some
illusional fun with the audience
keeping Hannah alive
for as long as we can
- while grabbing
important seconds.
- That's a good idea.
- James Brown stuff
you got going.
- Remember...
- Don't hit myself in the face.
- More like that.
Right here. OK.
- So good!
- Whoo!
♪ I am getting a blister ♪
[♪ Hannah Montana:
I got nerve]
[Jones] I wanted to make sure
the band was tight on everything
before Miley came in. We'll
get her for a little while,
and she'll have to go and do
school or go do the dance
or go do her TV show.
So she's working a lot harder
than we are. I'll tell you
that much.
Whoo!
Raise your hands in the air.
I'm a good driver.
- [shatters]
- [laughing]
[♪Let's Dance]
Now it's about the production.
We're tying up the whole show,
band, dancers, lights, video,
pyro, the whole deal.
So this will be our
first real run-through
before we leave
for St. Louis.
Put the line in front, here,
as opposed to here.
- Kick... and then down.
- Yeah, so you go...
Kick.
Go up on your toes. Go.
Kick, up. Here.
Boom.
We're doing a cheat sheet. This
is all the stuff we have to do.
[imitating an electric guitar]
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
The raver part.
- Right.
All right. Nice.
The place goes crazy. The Jonas
Brothers are gonna walk onto
the stage,
and at that moment the band's
gonna move in and we'd start
We Got The Party.
- You good?
- We're good.
- Thank you.
Ears, please. Thank you.
- ...for making it easy.
- You guys playing tonight?
- Yeah, we just got here like...
[♪We Got The Party]
I totally do this for you.
- You taught him that?
I hate you.
- No, uh...
- Mom!
- And Miley, relax.
Dancers, relax.
And we're gonna come back
in about ten minutes
with you and your dad
having a little rehearsal
for your duet, OK?
[♪Ready, Set, Don't Go]
♪ She's gotta do
what she's gotta do ♪
♪ And I've gotta
like it or not ♪
♪ She's got dreams
too big for this town ♪
♪ And she needs
to give 'em a shot ♪
♪ Whatever they are ♪
♪ Looks like
I'm all ready to leave ♪
♪ Nothing left to pack... ♪
- Actually, push there.
- OK.
- Feel that?
- Right, yeah.
I can really give you a spin
if you get me like, uh, uh...
- ♪ Hold on tight ♪
- [chuckles]
And just strut...
We pack up everything today
at 6:00 and we ship out.
[crowd cheering]
[cheering]
- [man] Thank you, everybody.
- [man 2] Yeah!
- [man] Miley Cyrus!
- Whoo!
Pop off!
[man] Just walking
to the stage right now.
Bye, loser.
OK, I'm not hearing
any static.
- You hearing anything at all?
- No.
[man] 'Cause of
the concrete walls.
OK. I shouldn't
hear static at all.
No, you'll hear it
around the corner.
[crowd screaming]
[crowd cheering loudly]
Are you guys ready
to rock tonight?
- All right, let's do it!
- [man] One, two, three, four!
[♪Life's What You Make It]
Everyone,
put your hands together!
♪ Aye aye aye oh aye ♪
♪ Aye aye aye ♪
♪ Don't let
no small frustration ♪
♪ Ever bring you down
No no no no ♪
♪ Just take a situation ♪
♪ And turn it all around ♪
♪ With a new attitude
everything can change ♪
♪ Make it how
you want it to be ♪
♪ Stayin' mad, why do that?
Give yourself a break ♪
♪ Laugh about it
and you'll see ♪
♪ Life's what you make it ♪
♪ So let's make it rock ♪
♪ So come on
Come on ♪
♪ Everybody now ♪
- ♪ Aye aye aye oh aye aye ♪
- I can't hear you guys!
♪ Aye aye aye ♪
♪ Why be sad,
broken hearted? ♪
♪ There's so much to do ♪
♪ Yeah yeah yeah yeah ♪
♪ Life is hard
or it's a party ♪
♪ The choice is up to you ♪
♪ With a new attitude
everything can change ♪
♪ Make it how
you want it to be ♪
♪ Stayin' sad, why do that?
Give yourself a break ♪
♪ I know you wanna
party with me ♪
♪ Life's what you make it ♪
♪ So let's make it rock ♪
♪ So come on
Come on ♪
♪ Everybody now ♪
♪ Let's celebrate it ♪
♪ Join in everyone ♪
♪ You decide ♪
♪ 'Cause life's
what you make it ♪
♪ Things are looking up
Any time you want ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is realize that ♪
♪ It's under your control ♪
♪ So let the good times
rock and roll ♪
♪ Ow! ♪
♪ Da da da do it now ♪
♪ Aaaaaaaaaaaaaah ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ Yeah yeah yeah ♪
♪ Yeah yeah ♪
♪ Life's what you make it ♪
♪ So let's make it rock ♪
♪ So come on
Come on ♪
♪ Everybody now ♪
♪ Let's celebrate it ♪
♪ Join in everyone ♪
♪ You decide ♪
♪ 'Cause life's
what you make it ♪
♪ Life is what you make it ♪♪
Thank you.
Thank you guys
for being here tonight.
I'm so excited to see you guys.
I've got some friends in the
audience.
Hey to all you guys,
I'm not sure where you are.
It's good to see you all.
[gasps] I hope you have
a great time tonight.
We do have a couple rules.
I never want to look out
and see anyone sitting.
Get up on your feet! Be singing
and dancing along with me!
Come on!
[drumsticks tapping]
[♪Just Like You]
[chorus] ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ So what you see
Is only half the story ♪
♪ There's another side of me ♪
♪ I'm the girl you know
but I'm someone else too ♪
♪ If you only knew ♪
♪ It's a crazy life ♪
♪ But I'm alright ♪
♪ I got everything
I've always wanted ♪
♪ Living the dream ♪
♪ So yeah,
everything I've always wanted ♪
♪ Isn't always what it seems ♪
♪ I'm a lucky girl ♪
♪ Whose dreams came true ♪
♪ But underneath it all
I'm just like you ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Don't wanna be
treated differently ♪
♪ I wanna keep it all inside ♪
♪ Half the time
I've got my name in lights ♪
♪ The other
half I'm by your side ♪
♪ It's a crazy life ♪
♪ But I'm just fine ♪
♪ I got everything
I've always wanted ♪
♪ Living the dream ♪
♪ So yeah,
everything I've always wanted ♪
♪ Isn't always what it seems ♪
♪ I'm a lucky girl ♪
♪ Whose dreams came true ♪
♪ But underneath it all ♪
♪ I'm just like you ♪
♪ Yeah-ee yeah ♪
♪ Can't you see
I'm just an ordinary girl ♪
♪ Living in an
extra-ordinary world ♪
♪ Whoo oh oh ♪
♪ Trying to live ♪
♪ Trying to learn ♪
♪ Trying to just be who I am ♪
♪ Who I am ♪
♪ I got everything
I've always wanted ♪
- ♪ Living the dream ♪
- ♪ So yeah,
everything I've always wanted ♪
- ♪ Always wanted ♪
♪ Isn't always what it seems ♪
♪ I'm a lucky girl ♪
♪ Whose dreams came true ♪
♪ But underneath it all ♪
♪ I'm just like you ♪
♪ I got everything
I've always wanted ♪
- ♪ Living the dream ♪
- ♪ Livin' the dream ♪
♪ So yeah,
everything I've always wanted ♪
♪ Isn't always what it seems ♪
♪ I'm a lucky girl ♪
♪ Whose dreams came true ♪
♪ But underneath it all ♪
♪ I'm just like you ♪♪
[crowd cheering]
Thank you, guys!
I'll be right back.
- I think she's pretty.
- She's pretty.
She's funny, she's smart.
She's a great role model.
She's a great singer.
[girl] Whoo!
[crowd cheering]
My favorite
Hannah Montana song is...
♪ Life's what you make it ♪
♪ So let's make it rock
Make it rock ♪
♪ Nobody's perfect! ♪
♪ I gotta work it! ♪
♪ Again and again ♪
♪ 'Til I get it right ♪
♪ Mix it all together ♪
♪ And you know that... ♪
The Best Of Both Worlds
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ I say, I say
That I know I can ♪
♪ Who said, who said... ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
I don't know
any of her songs.
You know, I didn't expect
so much screaming.
[screaming]
It's like standing behind a jet
when it revs up. Actually worse.
How many of you think you could
be some of the biggest Hannah
Montana fans?
I can't hear you,
what'd you say?
Think you could be the biggest
Hannah Montana fans?
You have to wait and see.
Gonna test you out with
this next song.
I'm hoping you guys know every
word. This song is called,
Nobody's Perfect.
Hannah! Hannah!
[♪Nobody's Perfect]
Everybody makes mistakes.
Everybody has those days.
One, two, three, four.
♪ Everybody makes mistakes
Everybody has those days ♪
♪ Everybody knows what
what I'm talkin' 'bout ♪
- ♪ Everybody gets that way ♪
- That's right.
♪ Everybody makes mistakes
Everybody has those days ♪
♪ Everybody knows what
what I'm talkin' 'bout ♪
♪ Everybody gets that way
Yeah! ♪
♪ Sometimes I'm in a jam
I've gotta make a plan ♪
♪ It might be crazy
I do it anyway ♪
♪ No way to know for sure
I'll figure out a cure ♪
♪ I'm patchin' up the holes
But then it overflows ♪
♪ If I'm not doin' too well ♪
♪ Why be so hard on myself? ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect
I gotta work it ♪
♪ Again and again
'til I get it right ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect
You live and you learn it ♪
♪ And if I
mess it up sometimes ♪
♪ Nobody's perfect ♪
♪ Sometimes I work a scheme
But then it flips on me ♪
♪ Doesn't turn out
how I planned
♪ Get stuck in quick sand ♪
♪ No problem, can't be solved
Once I get involved ♪
♪ I try to be delicate
Then crash right into it ♪
♪ My intentions are good ♪
♪ Yeah yeah yeah ♪
♪ Sometimes
just misunderstood ♪
♪ Nobody's perfect
I gotta work it ♪
♪ Again and again
'til I get it right ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect
Ya live and ya learn it ♪
♪ And if I
mess it up sometimes ♪
♪ Nobody's perfect
I gotta work it ♪
♪ I know in time
I'll find a way ♪
♪ Nobody's perfect ♪
♪ Sometimes I fix things up ♪
♪ And they fall apart again ♪
♪ Nobody's perfect ♪
♪ I might mix things up ♪
♪ But I always get it right
in the end ♪
♪ You know I do ♪
Next time you feel like
it's just one of those days
when you just
can't seem to win,
if things don't turn out
the way you plan,
Figure something else out.
Don't stay down!
Try again! Yeah!
♪ Everybody makes mistakes
Everybody has those days ♪
♪ Everybody knows what
what I'm talkin' 'bout
Everybody gets that way ♪
♪ Everybody makes mistakes
Everybody has those days ♪
♪ Everybody knows what
what I'm talkin'
Everybody gets that way ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect ♪
- ♪ I gotta work it ♪
- Work it!
♪ Again and again
'til I get it right ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect ♪
♪ Ya live and ya learn it ♪
♪ And if I
mess it up sometimes ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect
I gotta work it ♪
♪ I know in time
I'll find a way ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect ♪
♪ Ya live and ya learn it ♪
♪ 'Cause everybody
makes mistakes ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect
No no ♪
♪ Nobody's Perfect ♪♪
Thank you, guys!
You all sound great out there.
How many of you guys out there
are ready to party?
Me too. But if I'm gonna
party with you guys,
I gotta change into my party
dress. I'll be back. Say "hello"
to the dancers.
[♪Pumpin' Up The Party]
Who is ready
to party tonight?
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ It's the same old
same grind ♪
♪ But we don't feel
we're wasting time ♪
♪ Not so bored that
we can't find a better way ♪
♪ My friends, my kind
No one's gettin' left behind ♪
♪ If they did it'd be a crime
That's why we say ♪
♪ Let the music
start a revolution ♪
♪ Revolution ♪
♪ No time to play it safe ♪
Come on!
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ They can't
We can ♪
♪ Parents might
not understand ♪
♪ Having fun without a plan
But that's what we do ♪
- ♪ We're all here ♪
- [chorus] ♪ Let's go! ♪
♪ Gotta make this party grow ♪
♪ Together we can make it blow
right through the roof ♪
♪ The music's gonna
start a revolution ♪
♪ Revolution ♪
♪ Too late
to play it safe ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ We don't have
to paint by numbers ♪
♪ Let our voice
come out from under ♪
♪ Hear it rise
Feel the thunder ♪
♪ It's time to lose control ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Pumpin' up the party now
Party now, party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪
♪ Hey
Get up ♪
♪ Get loud ♪
♪ Start pumpin' up
the party now ♪♪
- I didn't tell you...
Were you in Utah?
- No.
- I got dropped.
- You did?
- I got totally dropped.
- How?
You know in I Got Nerve when
I had the stunt? I got dropped.
- [Miley] It was terrible.
- Hurt yourself?
[Miley]
No, but it was terrible.
[♪I Got Nerve]
[Ortega] We worked on it. Gonna
put you in a better position.
You've got two spotters now.
There's no way anything like
last night'll ever happen again.
This flip is gonna be gone
after tonight.
- Why?
- I hate it.
- It's great.
- No.
- It's rock and roll.
- Mommy!
He's saying we have to
keep the lift after tonight.
- Baby, you're fine.
- [Miley] Woman!
Think back to cheerleading.
It's fine.
And his hand is never
gonna let go of your butt.
- Your butt.
- It will constantly be there.
- He's cute.
- I know.
- [chuckles]
- It's all right.
We're gonna go five,
six, seven.
- [Ortega] Spotters?
- Ready?
Five, six, seven.
I got nerve.
- Look at that!
You almost went down!
- [laughs] You almost went down.
[woman] You have to know...
He's gonna catch you.
Absolutely catch you. So here we
go. Five, six, seven. I got
nerve.
[Ortega] Boom.
It's fine.
But you have to trust them.
- You have to trust them.
- [Ortega] Solar plex.
- Good.
- Cross your legs.
- And...
- [woman] Here we go. Ready?
- Here we go.
- [woman] Five, six, seven.
I got nerve.
See? They always have their
hands on you now. You're never
airborne.
[♪I've Got Nerve]
♪ We haven't met
And that's OK ♪
♪ 'Cause you will be
asking for me one day ♪
♪ Don't want to wait
in line ♪
♪ The moment is mine
Believe me ♪
♪ Don't close your eyes ♪
♪ 'Cause it's a chance
worth takin' ♪
♪ And I think
that I can shake you ♪
♪ I know where I stand
I know who I am ♪
♪ I would never run away
when life gets bad, it's ♪
♪ Everything I see
Every part of me ♪
♪ Gonna get what I deserve ♪
♪ I got nerve ♪
♪ I got I got I got ♪
♪ Electrified ♪
♪ I'm on a wire ♪
♪ Getting together
we're on fire ♪
♪ What I said
You heard ♪
♪ Now I got you spinning ♪
♪ Don't close your mind ♪
♪ The words I use are open ♪
♪ And I think
that I can show you ♪
♪ I know where I stand
I know who I am ♪
♪ I would never run away
when life gets bad, it's ♪
♪ Everything I see
Every part of me ♪
♪ I know I can change
the world, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I know what you like I know
what you think ♪
♪ Not afraid to stare you down
until you blink, it's ♪
♪ Everything I see
Every part of me ♪
♪ Gonna get what I deserve ♪
♪ I got nerve ♪
- ♪ And you ♪
- ♪ You ♪
- ♪ You need to discover ♪
- [chorus] ♪ To discover ♪
♪ Who can make you feel free ♪
♪ Yeah, and I ♪
♪ I need to uncover ♪
♪ The part of you
that's reaching out for me ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ I know where I stand
I know who I am ♪
♪ I would never run away
when life gets bad ♪
♪ It's everything I see
Every part of me ♪
♪ I know I can change
the world, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I know what you like
I know what you think ♪
♪ Not afraid to stare you down
until you blink, it's ♪
♪ Everything I see
Every part of me ♪
♪ Gonna get what I deserve ♪
♪ I got nerve ♪
♪ [chorus]
I know what you like ♪
- ♪ Yeah yeah yeah ♪
- [chorus]
♪ I know what you think ♪
♪ I know what you like ♪
♪ I know what you like
I know what you think ♪
♪ Not afraid to stare you down
until you blink, it's ♪
♪ Everything I see
Every part of me ♪
♪ Gonna get what I deserve ♪
♪ I got
I got nerve ♪♪
How many of you guys'd
like to see the Jonas Brothers?
I'm gonna need
you guy's help.
How about everyone stand up
and yell, "Jonas Brothers"?
Let me hear ya!
Jonas! Jonas! Jonas! Jonas!
Thanks!
This next song is called,We Got
the Party With Us. Come on!
[mouths] I'm tired.
[♪We Got The Party]
♪ C'mon guys
Tell me what we're doin' ♪
♪ We're hangin' around when we
could be all over the place ♪
♪ The sun is shinin'
just the way we like it ♪
♪ Let's get outta
this hallway ♪
♪ Show the world our face ♪
♪ It's Friday
and there's no where to go ♪
♪ Anywhere is cool
but we're not goin' home ♪
♪ We can do anything
we wanna do ♪
♪ It's all up to me and you ♪
♪ Turn this park into a club
The stars are lights ♪
♪ And the moon
is the vibe from above ♪
♪ Skateboards here's our ride
so pull on up ♪
♪ Everyone is waiting for us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are, anywhere
we go, everybody knows ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are, anywhere
we go, everybody knows ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
- ♪ Oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh ♪
- We can't hear you!
♪ Oh oh oh oh ohh ohh ♪
- ♪ Oh oh oh oh oh ohh oh ♪
- ♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Radio, let me be the DJ ♪
♪ I'll turn you up, keep us
moving till we're on a roll ♪
♪ Everyone is dancing
to their own beat ♪
♪ And letting go
Everybody here's got a soul ♪
♪ It's Friday
and there's nowhere to be ♪
♪ We're kickin' it together
it's so good to be free ♪
♪ We got each other
and that's all we need ♪
♪ The rest is up
to you and me ♪
♪ Turn this park into a club
The stars are lights ♪
♪ And the moon is the vibe
from above ♪
♪ Skateboards here's our ride
so pull on up ♪
♪ Everyone is waiting for us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows
We got the party with us ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ We got the party
We got the party ♪
♪ Life is for dreamers ♪
♪ And I'm a believer ♪
♪ That nothing
can stand in our way ♪
♪ Today let's find
a place to play ♪
♪ Turn this park into a club ♪
♪ The stars are lights and the
moon is the vibe from above ♪
♪ Skateboards here's
our ride so pull on up ♪
♪ Everyone is waiting for us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Turn this park into a club
The stars are lights ♪
♪ And the moon is the vibe
from above ♪
♪ Skateboards here's our ride
so pull on up ♪
♪ Everyone is waiting for us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows
We got the party with us ♪
♪ Anywhere we are
Anywhere we go ♪
♪ Everybody knows ♪
♪ We got the party with us ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh
Oh oh oh oh ♪
- ♪ Oh oh oh oh ohh ohh ♪
- ♪ We got the party with us ♪
- ♪ Oh oh oh oh oh ohh oh ♪
- ♪ We got the party with us ♪♪
[crowd cheering]
Whoo!
Are you guys having fun?
Hannah is going backstage right
now to turn into Miley Cyrus.
And is it all right with you
guys if we play some more
Jonas Brothers songs?
[crowd cheering]
All right, then.
This is for all the ladies
in the house tonight.
[♪When You Look Me
In The Eyes]
♪ Ooh hoo, yeah ♪
♪ Ahh ahh ♪
♪ If the heart
is always searching ♪
♪ Can you ever
find a home? ♪
♪ I've been looking
for that someone ♪
♪ I'll never make it
on my own ♪
♪ Dreams can't
take the place ♪
♪ Of loving you ♪
♪ There's gotta be
a million reasons ♪
♪ Why it's true ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ And tell me
that you love me ♪
♪ Everything's alright ♪
♪ When you're right
here by my side ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ I catch a glimpse of heaven ♪
♪ I find my paradise ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ How long
will I be waiting ♪
♪ To be with you again? ♪
♪ Gonna tell you
that I love you ♪
♪ In the best way
that I can ♪
♪ I can't take a day ♪
♪ Without you here ♪
♪ You're the light that
makes my darkness disappear ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ And tell me
that you love me ♪
♪ Everything's alright ♪
♪ When you're right here
by my side ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ I catch a glimpse
of heaven ♪
♪ I find my paradise ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ More and more ♪
♪ I start to realize ♪
♪ I can reach my tomorrow ♪
♪ I can hold my head high ♪
♪ And it's all because
you're by my side ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ And tell me
that you love me ♪
♪ Everything's alright ♪
♪ When you're right here
by my side ♪
♪ When I hold you
in my arms ♪
♪ I know that it's forever ♪
♪ I just gotta
let you know ♪
♪ I never wanna
let you go ♪
♪ Cause when you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ And tell me
that you love me ♪
♪ Everything's alright ♪
♪ When you're right here
by my side ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ I catch a glimpse
of heaven ♪
♪ I find my paradise ♪
♪ When you look me
in the eyes ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Ohhh ♪
♪ Bu-yeah ♪♪
Thank you very much.
Once again, we are
the Jonas Brothers.
We couldn't leave you tonight
without taking you...
[drumsticks tapping]
[♪Year 3,000]
...to theYear 3,000!
[mouths] Ready? Go.
♪ One day when I came home
at lunchtime ♪
♪ I heard a funny noise ♪
♪ Went out to the back yard ♪
♪ To find out if it was
one of those rowdy boys ♪
♪ Stood there with my neighbor
called Peter ♪
♪ And a Flux Capacitor ♪
♪ He told me he built
a time machine ♪
♪ Like one in a film
I've seen ♪
♪ Yeah, he said ♪
♪ "I've been to the year 3000 ♪
♪ Not much has changed
but they lived under water ♪
Sing it now!
♪ And your great great
great grand daughter ♪
♪ Is doing fine ♪
♪ Is doing fine" ♪
♪ He took me to the future
in the flux thing and I
saw everything ♪
♪ Boy bands, and another one
and another one ♪
♪ And another one ♪
♪ Girls there with round
hair like Star Wars ♪
♪ Float above the floor ♪
♪ He told me he built
a time machine ♪
♪ Like the one
in the film I've seen ♪
That's right! Come on!
♪ He said, "I've been
to the year 3000 ♪
♪ Not much has changed but
they lived under water ♪
♪ And your great great
great grand daughter ♪
♪ Is doing fine ♪
♪ Doing fine" ♪
Here we go!
♪ I took a trip
to the year 3000 ♪
♪ This song had gone
multi-platinum ♪
♪ Everybody bought
our 7th album ♪
♪ It had outsold
Kelly Clarkson ♪
♪ I took a trip
to the year 3000 ♪
♪ This song had gone
multi-platinum ♪
♪ Everybody bought
our 7th album ♪
That's right!
♪ He told me he built
a time machine ♪
♪ Like the one
in a film I've seen ♪
♪ Yeah, come on ♪
♪ He said, "I've been
to the year 3000 ♪
♪ Not much has changed
but they lived under water ♪
That's right,
where are my ladies at?
♪ And your great great great
grand daughter ♪
♪ Is doing fine ♪
♪ Doing fine" ♪
Are you ready?
Go!
♪ He said, "I've
been to the year 3000 ♪
♪ Not much has changed
but they lived under water ♪
♪ And your great great great
grand daughter ♪
- ♪ Is doing fine ♪
- ♪ Doing fine ♪
♪ Doing fine" ♪
♪ He said, "I've been
to the year 3000 ♪
♪ Not much has changed
but they lived under water ♪
Sing it out!
♪ And your great great great
grand daughter ♪
♪ Is doing fine ♪
♪ Doing fine" ♪
♪ He said, "I've
been to the year 3000 ♪
That's right!
♪ Not much has changed
but they lived under water ♪
♪ And your great great great
grand daughter ♪
♪ Is doing fine ♪
♪ Doing fine" ♪♪
Ha!
- Thank you!
- Thank you very much!
[Tish] This tour, because it's
her own show, and she's got such
long sets,
it's more like I worry about
her. I'm totally proud.
She's an amazing performer.
Still, as a mom, it's just
so nerve-racking.
This year, so that doesn't
happen, they kind of put me
to work.
Actually, every time
she changes clothes,
I'm the one backstage
changing her clothes.
[timer sounding]
It's crazy.
There are three of us.
They're pretty timid with her
because they don't know her.
I'm, like, ripping her clothes
off, and it's so funny.
She's, like, "Mom"! We, of
course, banter back and forth.
It's funny. There's one change
I have to get her changed in,
what, 30 seconds?
Thirty-seven seconds, I think,
is... It has to be choreographed
to where we know
what we take off first.
[Miley] Like left foot, right
foot in, skirt out first.
[Tish] We have hair and makeup
people who, while we're changing
her,
they're trying to do a little
bit with her hair. But that's
crazy.
[timer dings]
Are you ready
to meet Miley Cyrus?
[drumsticks tapping]
[♪Start All Over]
[crowd]
Miley, Miley, Miley!
♪ I have to wonder ♪
♪ If this
wave's too big to ride ♪
♪ Commit or not commit
in such a crazy tide ♪
♪ It's sooner than I thought ♪
♪ But you called me out ♪
♪ I've lost control
and there's no doubt ♪
♪ I'm gonna start all over ♪
♪ Out of the fire
and into the fire again ♪
♪ You make me
want to forget ♪
♪ And start all over ♪
♪ Here I come straight out
of my mind or worse ♪
♪ Another chance
to get burned and ♪
♪ Start all over ♪
♪ I'm gonna start
all over ♪
♪ Fantastic and romantic ♪
- ♪ All a big surprise ♪
- [chorus] ♪ Big surprise ♪
♪ You've got the warning ♪
♪ hesitation pushed aside ♪
♪ It's sooner than I want ♪
♪ But you caught my heart ♪
♪ I guess I'm ready
now to start ♪
♪ Start all over ♪
♪ Out of the fire
and into the fire again ♪
♪ You make me want
to forget ♪
♪ And start all over ♪
♪ Here I come straight out
of my mind or worse ♪
♪ Another chance
to get burned and ♪
♪ Start all over ♪
♪ I'm gonna start
all over ♪
♪ It's so easy
You disrupt me ♪
♪ Can't complain ♪
♪ It's so easy
You disrupt me ♪
♪ Can't complain ♪
♪ It's so easy
You disrupt me ♪
♪ Can't complain ♪
♪ It's so easy ♪
♪ I'm gonna start
all over ♪
♪ Start all over
Start all over ♪
♪ Out of the fire
and into the fire again ♪
♪ You make me want
to forget ♪
♪ And start all over ♪
♪ Here I come straight out
of my mind or worse ♪
♪ Another chance
to get burned and ♪
♪ Start all over ♪
♪ Out of the fire
and into the fire again ♪
♪ You make me want
to forget ♪
♪ And start all over ♪
♪ Here I come straight out
of my mind or worse ♪
♪ Another chance
to get burned ♪
♪ And start all over ♪
♪ I'm gonna start all over ♪♪
[Miley] Thank you, guys!
[drumsticks tapping]
[♪See You Again]
[laughing]
♪ I got my sight set on you ♪
♪ And I'm ready to aim ♪
♪ I have a heart
that will ♪
♪ Never be tamed ♪
♪ I knew you were
something special ♪
♪ When you spoke my name ♪
♪ Now I can't wait
to see you again ♪
♪ I've got a way of knowing ♪
♪ When something is right ♪
♪ I feel like
I must have known you ♪
♪ In another life ♪
♪ 'Cause I felt
this deep connection ♪
♪ When you looked
in my eyes ♪
♪ Now I can't wait
To see you again ♪
♪ The last time I freaked out
I just kept looking down ♪
♪ I stu-stu-stuttered
when you asked me
what I'm thinkin' 'bout ♪
♪ Felt like I couldn't breathe
You asked what's wrong
with me ♪
♪ My best friend Leslie said
"She's just being' Miley." ♪
♪ Then next time we hang out,
I will redeem myself ♪
♪ My heart can rest till then
Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ I, I can't wait
to see you again ♪
♪ I got this crazy feeling
Deep inside ♪
♪ When you called
and asked to see me ♪
♪ Tomorrow night ♪
♪ I'm not a mind reader ♪
♪ But I'm reading the signs ♪
♪ That you can't wait
to see me again ♪
Come on!
♪ The last time I freaked out
I just kept lookin' down ♪
♪ I stu-stu-stuttered
when you asked me what
I'm thinkin' 'bout ♪
♪ Felt like I couldn't breathe
You asked what's wrong
with me ♪
♪ My best friend Leslie said
"She's just bein' Miley" ♪
♪ And next time we hang out
I will redeem myself ♪
♪ My heart can rest till then
whoa, whoa ♪
♪ I, I can't wait ♪
♪ To see you again ♪
♪ I got my sight set on you ♪
♪ And I'm ready to aim ♪
Let me hear ya!
♪ The last time I freaked out
I just kept lookin' down ♪
♪ I stu-stu-stuttered
when you asked me
what I'm thinkin' 'bout ♪
♪ Felt like I couldn't breathe
You asked what's wrong
with me ♪
♪ My best friend Leslie said
"She's just bein' Miley" ♪
♪ And next time we hang out
I will redeem myself ♪
♪ My heart, can rest till then
Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ I, I can't wait ♪
♪ To see you again
See you again ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, I
I can't wait ♪
♪ To see you again ♪♪
[female DJ] Parents are gonna do
whatever they can for their
kids.
You've got this girl looking
at you with her eyes,
"Daddy, this is gonna
change my life.
I will never ask you for
any other toy or anything
ever again".
What are you gonna do?
[♪Rock Star]
[male DJ] Gonna be a huge day.
The high heel derby for Hannah
Montana tickets.
Dads are running in high heels.
It happens at noon.
The winner gets four tickets
to see Hannah Montana.
Sold out show.
High heel derby
for Hannah Montana tickets.
- Go!
- [whistle sounds]
♪ I'm unusual
Not so typical ♪
♪ Way too smart
to be waiting around ♪
♪ Tai chi practicin' ♪
[announcer] Ladies and
gentlemen, this is it.
[whistle sounds]
♪ Rockin' it
wherever we are ♪
♪ Yeah Yeah, 'cause I really
am a rock star... ♪
Here's our winner,
ladies and gentlemen.
Four tickets to see Hannah
Montana at Scottrade Center
tomorrow,
and four backstage passes.
Matt Austin, ladies and
gentlemen. Winner!
Hannah Montana, baby.
Hannah Montana.
[♪Let's Dance]
♪ The weekends almost done ♪
♪ The moon is low in the sky ♪
♪ I feel like goin' out ♪
♪ Before the night passes by ♪
♪ I won't just sit around ♪
♪ When life becomes a drag ♪
♪ I dance ♪
♪ I like the bass ♪
♪ Turn it up turn it up
turn it up ♪
♪ I like the boom ♪
♪ Turn it up turn it up
Turn it up ♪
♪ I need guitar ♪
♪ Turn it up,
turn it up, turn it up ♪
♪ I like that drum
when it goes ♪
♪ Let's dance, for the weekend
What the night is all about ♪
♪ Let's dance, grab your
girlfriends, grab your
boyfriends, sweat it out ♪
♪ Let's dance
move your whole body
Let's start the party ♪
[rapping] ♪ To a number
one girl, can make
a girl go crazy ♪
♪ I need someone
to dance with me baby, dance ♪
♪ The music's on ♪
♪ Turn it up Turn it up
Turn it up ♪
My favorite song
♪ Turn it up
Turn it up, turn it up ♪
♪ The beat is strong ♪
♪ Turn it up
Turn it up, turn it up ♪
♪ We'll dance ♪
[Miley] Come on!
♪ Let's dance For the weekend
What the night is all about ♪
♪ Let's dance Grab
your girlfriends Grab your
boyfriends Sweat it out ♪
♪ Let's dance ♪
♪ Move your whole body
Let's start the party ♪
[rapping] ♪ To a number
one girl, can make
a girl go crazy ♪
♪ I need someone
to dance with me baby ♪
♪ Dance ♪
Back it up!
♪ When the night says hello
Yeah get ready to go ♪
♪ Turn it up
Turn it loose ♪
♪ Yeah you got no excuse ♪
♪ Just take a chance ♪
♪ Get out on the floor
and dance ♪
♪ Let's dance, for the weekend
What the night is all about ♪
♪ Let's dance
Grab your girlfriends ♪
♪ Grab your boyfriends
Sweat it out ♪
♪ Let's dance ♪
[chorus singing]
♪ Let's dance
For the weekend ♪
♪ What the night is
all about. let's dance ♪
♪ Grab your girlfriends
Grab your boyfriends
Sweat it out ♪
♪ Let's dance
Move your whole body ♪
♪ Let's start the party ♪
[rapping] ♪ As soon
as my album goes number one ♪
♪ We'll be livin' like a roller
with 40 diamond, Ha! ♪♪
Thank you, guys.
Are you guys having
a good time so far?
You guys aren't ready
to go home yet, are you?
Well, I got to tell you.
The reason that you guys
are having fun and I'm getting
a chance
to live my dream, is not all
because of what you see up here.
There's a lot of stuff that goes
on backstage that everyone
doesn't have
a chance to come out
and tell you what they do
and everything that makes
them part of the show.
But I can tell you that their
jobs can be a lot harder than
mine
and they put this whole thing
on, allowing me to live my
dream.
So this next song, I'd like
to dedicate to everyone here
tonight.
Thank you.
[♪Right Here]
♪ La de da de da ♪
Put your hands together.
♪ I'll be right here
where you need me ♪
♪ Anytime just keep believing ♪
♪ And I'll be ♪
♪ Right here ♪
♪ If you ever need a friend
♪ Someone to care
and understand ♪
♪ I'll be ♪
♪ Right here ♪
Off your feet!
♪ All you have to do
is call my name ♪
♪ No matter how close
or far away ♪
♪ Ask me once and I'll come ♪
♪ I'll come runnin' ♪
♪ And when I can't be with you
dream me near ♪
♪ Keep me in your heart
and I'll appear ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is turn around ♪
♪ Close your eyes
Look inside ♪
♪ I'm right here ♪
♪ Isn't it great
that you know ♪
♪ That I'm ready to go
wherever you're at ♪
♪ Anywhere ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪
♪ All you have to do
is call my name ♪
♪ No matter how close
or far away ♪
♪ Ask me once and I'll come ♪
♪ I'll come runnin' ♪
♪ And when I can't be with you
dream me near ♪
♪ Keep me in your heart
and I'll appear ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is turn around ♪
Close your eyes
Look inside ♪
♪ I'm right here ♪
♪ Whenever you need me ♪
♪ There's no need to worry ♪
♪ You know that I'm gonna be ♪
♪ Right here ♪
♪ Ask me once and I'll come ♪
♪ I'll come runnin' ♪
♪ And when I can't be with you
dream me near ♪
♪ Keep me in your heart
and I'll appear ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is turn around ♪
♪ Close your eyes
Look inside ♪
♪ I'm right here ♪
♪ Oh yeah yeah ♪
♪ I'm right here ♪♪
What Miley writes about is what
is real to her and what she
lives.
When you hear the things she
writes, you hear the honesty
of Miley's heart.
I mean, it's...
The music is real
and the songs that she writes
about is what she lives.
That's what, you know...
That's what I love about her
music, is that it's real.
This song was written for my
granddad who passed away
a few years ago,
but he's never gone to me and my
family. He's here with me every
night on stage.
This is a song
that I wrote just for him.
So this one goes to my
guardian angel, my pappy.
[♪I Miss You]
♪ Sha la la la ♪
♪ You used to call me
your angel ♪
♪ Said I was sent straight
down from heaven ♪
♪ And you'd hold me close
in your arms ♪
♪ I loved the way
you felt so strong ♪
♪ I never wanted you to leave ♪
♪ I wanted you to stay
here holding me ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ I miss your smile ♪
♪ And I still shed a tear ♪
♪ Every once in a while ♪
♪ And even though
it's different now ♪
♪ You're still here somehow ♪
♪ My heart will let you go ♪
♪ And I need you to know ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ Sha la la ♪
♪ I miss you... ♪
The cool thing about this song
is it can go either way.
But me and my family
know what it's really about.
So it could be about a
relationship you're having,
about your parents.
Anyone. Um, going away from
home. It can be about anything.
But why it's really important
to me is because it's about
my granddad.
♪ Everything that's happening
for me ♪
♪ I'm thinking back
on the past ♪
♪ It's true that time
is flying by too fast ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ I miss your smile ♪
♪ And I still shed a tear ♪
♪ Every once in a while ♪
♪ And even though
it's different now ♪
♪ You're still here somehow ♪
♪ My heart will let you go ♪
♪ And I need you to know ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ Sha la la ♪
♪ I miss you... ♪
- She's teaching me the song.
- I've never done that.
♪ I know you're in
a better place, yeah ♪
♪ But I wish that I could
see your face, oh ♪
♪ I know you're
where you need to be ♪
♪ Even though
it's not here with me, yeah ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ I miss your smile ♪
♪ And I still shed a tear ♪
♪ Every once in a while ♪
♪ And even though
it's different now ♪
♪ You're still here somehow ♪
♪ My heart will let you go ♪
♪ And I need you to know ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ Sha la la ♪
♪ I miss your smile ♪
♪ And I still shed a tear ♪
♪ Every once in a while ♪
♪ And even though
it's different now ♪
♪ You're still here somehow ♪
♪ My heart will let you go ♪
♪ And I need you to know ♪
♪ I miss you ♪
♪ Sha la la ♪
♪ I miss you ♪♪
[crowd cheering]
Thank you, guys.
[acoustic guitars play]
A minor.
A.
- OK.
- Wanna try it?
Yeah.
♪ You used to call me
your angel...♪
- She stand here?
- [man] Yeah.
Folks at home,
this is Miley's double.
This is her stunt double.
Currently enjoying
the new wind machine.
We really don't know why he got
hired. That's why. Look at that
face.
- The Superman wave.
- That hair.
- You're doing
a really good job too.
- It's been a long morning.
How many girls do we got
out there tonight?
[crowd cheering]
All right, I need all you guys
to get out of your seat,
throw your hands up in the air
because this is a girl's night
out!
[♪Girl's Night Out]
♪ Don't call me
Leave me alone ♪
♪ Not gonna answer my phone ♪
♪ Cause I don't
No, I won't ♪
♪ See you ♪
♪ I'm out to have a good time ♪
♪ To get you off of my mind ♪
♪ 'Cause I don't
and I won't ♪
♪ Need you ♪
[chorus] ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ Send out a 911 ♪
- [chorus] ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ We're gonna have some fun ♪
- ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
♪ Hey boy, you know
you better run ♪
♪ 'Cause it's a girl's night ♪
♪ It's alright without you ♪
♪ I'm gonna stay out
and play out ♪
♪ Without you ♪
♪ You'd better hold tight ♪
♪ 'Cause girl's night's
without you ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ Let's go GNO ♪
- ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
♪ Let's go GNO ♪
♪ Let's go GNO let's go ♪
♪ It's a girl's night ♪
I can't hear you, ladies,
come on!
♪ I'll dance
with somebody new ♪
♪ Won't have
to think about you ♪
♪ And who knows what let go ♪
♪ Will lead to ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ You'll hear from everyone ♪
- ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ You'll get the 411 ♪
♪ Hey boy you knew
this day would come ♪
♪ 'Cause it's a girl's night ♪
♪ It's alright Without you ♪
♪ I'm gonna stay out ♪
♪ And play out without you ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ Let's go GNO ♪
- Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ Let's go GNO
- ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
♪ Let's go GNO
Let's go ♪
♪ Hey boy don't you wish
you could've been a good boy? ♪
♪ Try to find another girl
like me boy ♪
♪ Feel me
when I tell ya I'm fine ♪
♪ And it's time for me
to draw the line, I say ♪
♪ Hey boy don't you wish
you could've been a good boy? ♪
♪ Try to find another girl
like me boy ♪
♪ Feel me
when I tell ya I'm fine ♪
♪ And it's time for me
to draw the line ♪
♪ ' Cause it's a girl's night ♪
♪ It's alright without you ♪
♪ I'm gonna stay out
and play out ♪
♪ Without you ♪
♪ You'd better hold tight ♪
- ♪ Cause girl's night
without you ♪
- ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- ♪ Let's go GNO ♪
♪ Let's go GNO
Let's go ♪
♪ It's a girl's night ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪
- Come on, girls!
- ♪ Hoo hoo ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪♪
Did you girls have fun?
[loud screams]
Thank you guys so much.
This is the end
of the night,
but you guys cannot sit down
and stop screaming and dancing
quite yet.
'Cause this next song, I have
the feeling you're gonna know
the words.
[loud screams]
Come on, you guys,
let me hear ya!
- [screaming]
- All the way up top, come on!
All right, you guys,
this last song is called...
...Best Of Both Worlds.
[tapping]
[♪Best Of Both Worlds]
[Miley] I wanna
hear you sing along!
♪ Oh yeah
Come on ♪
♪ You get the limo out front ♪
♪ Ooh oh ♪
♪ Hottest styles
every shoe, every color ♪
♪ Yeah, when you're
famous it can be kinda fun ♪
♪ It's really you
but no one ever discovers ♪
♪ In some ways you're just
like all your friends ♪
♪ But on stage you're a star ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Chill it out
take it slow ♪
♪ Then you rock out the show ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Mix it all together
and you know that it's
the best of both worlds ♪
♪ The best of both worlds ♪
♪ You go to movie premiers ♪
Is that Hannah Montana?
♪ Hear your songs
on the radio ♪
♪ Livin' two lives
is a little weird, yeah ♪
♪ But school's cool
'cause nobody knows ♪
♪ Yeah you get to be
a small town girl ♪
♪ But big time
when you play your guitar ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Chillin' out take it slow
Then you rock out the show ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Mix it all together
and you know that it's
the best of both ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Pictures and autographs ♪
♪ You get your face
in all the magazines ♪
Hey, Miley !
♪ The best part's that ♪
♪ You get to be
whoever you wanna be ♪
♪ Best! Best! ♪
♪ I have the best of both ♪
♪ You've got the best of both ♪
♪ Best! Best! ♪
♪ Come on, the best of both ♪
♪ Who would of thought
that a girl like me ♪
♪ Would double as a superstar ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Chillin' out, take it slow
Then you rock out the show ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds ♪
♪ Mix it all together and you
know that it's the best ♪
♪ You get the best
of both worlds♪
♪ Without the shades and
the hair You can go anywhere ♪
♪ You get the best
of both girls ♪
♪ Mix it all together ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ It's so much better
'cause you know ♪
♪ You've got the best
of both worlds ♪♪
[band plays We Got The Party]
Goodbye!
Thank you! I'll see you guys
real soon! Goodnight!
[crowd cheering]
Thank you guys
for coming out tonight.
See y'all soon.
[♪ Hannah Montana:
If We Were A Movie]
♪ Uh oh ♪
♪ There you go again
Talkin' cinematic ♪
♪ Yeah you ♪
♪ You're charming
You got everybody starstruck ♪
♪ I know,
how you always seem to go ♪
♪ For the obvious
instead of me ♪
♪ But get a ticket
and you'll see ♪
♪ If we were a movie ♪
♪ You'd be the right guy ♪
♪ And I'd be the best friend ♪
♪ That you'd fall
in love with ♪
♪ In the end
we'd be laughin' ♪
♪ Watchin' the sunset
fade to black ♪
♪ Show the names
Play the happy song ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah yeah ♪
♪ When you call me
I can hear it in your voice ♪
♪ Oh sure ♪
♪ Wanna see me
and tell me all about her ♪
♪ La, La, I'll be actin'
through my tears ♪
♪ Guess you'll never know
that I should win ♪
♪ An Oscar
for this scene I'm in ♪
♪ If we were a movie ♪
♪ You'd be the right guy ♪
♪ And I'd be
the best friend ♪
♪ That you'd fall
in love with ♪
♪ In the end we'd be laughin' ♪
♪ Watchin' the sunset
fade to black ♪
♪ Show the names
Play that happy song ♪
♪ Wish I could tell
you there's a twist ♪
♪ Some kind of hero
in disguise ♪
♪ And were together
It's for real ♪
♪ Now playin' ♪
♪ Wish I could tell you
there's a kiss ♪
♪ Like somethin' more
than in my mind ♪
♪ I see it could be amazing ♪
- ♪ Could be amazing ♪
♪ If we were a movie ♪
- ♪ You'd be the right guy
- ♪ Guy ♪
♪ And I'd be the best friend ♪
♪ That you'd fall
in love with ♪
♪ In the end we'd be laughin' ♪
♪ Watchin' the sunset
fade to black ♪
♪ Show the names
Play the happy song ♪
- ♪ If we were ♪
- ♪ If we were a movie ♪
♪ You'd be the right guy ♪
♪ And I'd be the best friend ♪
♪ That you'd fall
in love with ♪
♪ In the end we'd be laughin' ♪
♪ Watchin' the sunset
fade to black ♪
♪ Show the names
Play the happy song
♪ If we were a movie ♪
♪ You'd be the right guy ♪
♪ And I'd be the best friend ♪
♪ That you'd fall
in love with ♪
♪ In the end
we'd be laughin'... ♪