Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Harry Potter and the
Order of the Phoenix
It's just too hot today isn't it?
And it's going to get even worse.
temperatures up in the mid 30s Celsius.
And at night should go
up even, and perhaps...
Alright, lets go home.
What a lovely day.
Do we have to? We do.
Hey big D. Beat up another 10 year old?
This one deserved
it. - Ya. - Ya.
5 against 1, very brave.
Well you're the one to talk?
moaning in your sleep every night.
At least I'm not afraid of my pillow.
Don't kill Cedric.
Who's Cedric? Your boyfriend? Shut up.
He's going to kill me, mom.
Where is your mom?
Where is your mom, Potter?
Is she dead?
Is she dead?!
Is she dead...
What's going on?
What's going on here?
What are you doing?
I'm not doing anything.
Dudley, come on!
Run!
Dudley, run!
Expecto Patronum!
Mrs. Figg.
Took for the riddle wand,
Harry. They might come back.
Dementors in little
Winchik. What's next?
Whole world's in top sterny.
I don't understand. How did you know...
Dumbledore asked me
to keep an eye on you.
Dumbledore? You know Dumbledore?
- yea.
After You-Know-Who killed that
poor Diggory boy last year.
Did you expect him to let
you go wandering around alone?
Good Lord, they told
me you're intelligent.
Now, get inside and stay there.
Soon someone will be in touch with you.
Whatever happens, don't freak out.
It is hot. That's it, too hot.
The heat is suffocating...
Dudley?
Is that you?
Vernon, come quick!
We need to take him to a hospital.
Who did that with you, son?
Happy, are we now?
You finally done it. You
finally driven Dudley.
Vernon, don't you say that.
Just look at him, Petunia.
Our boy has gone yumpie.
I've reach my limit, you hear?
This is the last I'm gonna
take you and your losses.
Dear Mr. Potter
The Ministry has received intelligence.
That at 6:23 this evening...
You performed the Petrunas Charm
in the presence of a muggle.
As a clear violation of the decree...
for the reasonable restriction
of Underage Sorcery,
you are hereby expelled
from Hogwarts School.
Hope that you are well, Mafilda Hopker.
Justice.
Sorry, Hedwig.
Hygienist, these muggles.
Tonks, for God's sake.
Professor Moody, what're you doing here?
To rescue you of course.
Where are we going? That I'm
just expelled from school.
Not yet.
Kingsley, you take front.
But the letter said...
Dumbledore has persuaded
the Minister to suspend it.
It's about your formal hearing.
A hearing?
Don't worry, Harry.
We'll explain everything when
we get back to headquarters.
Shh, not here, Nymphadora.
Don't call me Nymphadora.
Stay in formation everyone.
Don't digress if one of us was killed.
Come on.
In you go, son.
It is time to enter in action.
It is the first sorcerer's thought.
He thinks with your return...
Talk a little lower
He grew stronger by the
minute. We have to act now.
- Harry!
- Mrs. Weasley!
Thank God, you're alright.
Bit pity. I'm afraid, dinner, we're gonna
have to wait after the meeting finish.
Look. No time to explain.
Straight upstairs.
First door on the left.
Yeah.
What kind of scum would
let it in to her house.
why my mistress, what
would he tell the creature?
What a shame
Do not worry, madame.
The creature is here.
Harry.
You alright? We've heard
of the Dementors attack.
You must tell us everything.
Let him breath, Hermione.
And this hearing at the
Ministry, it's just outrageous.
They can't expel you.
It's completely unfair.
Yeah. That's a lot
going around these days.
So what is this place?
It's headquarters.
The Order of The Phoenix.
It's a secret society.
Dumbledore formed it back
in the first, You-Know-Who.
You couldn't write any of
this in your letter I suppose?
Whole summer without a scrap of news.
We thought to write, really, I did.
Dumbledore made us swear
not to tell you anything.
Dumbledore said that?
But why he want to keep me
in the dark? Maybe I can help.
Afterall, I'm the one who
saw Voldermort returned.
I'm the one he fought with.
I'm the one who saw
Cedric Diggory get killed.
Harry.
Don't be so uptight.
Let it out.
Anyway, we heard the chatting.
Only had something more interesting.
Harry has the right to know.
If it wasn't him, no one know he's back.
He's hardly a child, Molly.
But not an adult either.
He's not James, Sirius.
He's not your son.
I'm good at it.
No one else he's got.
He's got me.
Potter will grow up into a criminal.
Just like his Godfather.
Stay out of this, Severus.
Why don't you tell him?
Hermione, I hate your cat.
We'll be eating down in the kitchen.
Just because you're
allowed to use magic now,
does not mean you have to whip
your wands out for everything.
Hi, mom.
You hungry, Harry?
You sure you're alright, Harry?
Harry Potter.
Sirius.
It is very peculiar. It seems that your
hearing at the Ministry...
is to be before the entire Withem.
I don't understand why is the
Ministry of Magic go against me.
Show him.
He'd find out soon enough.
"The Boy Who Lies?"
He's been attacking Dumbledore as well.
"Fudge: All Is Well"
Fudge is using all his power.
Including his influence
at the Daily Prophet.
Smear anyone who claims the Dark Lord
has returned. - Why?
The Minister thinks
Dumbledore's after his job.
But that's insane. No one in the right
mind would believe that Dumbledore...
Excatly the point. Fudge
isn't in his right mind.
He's been twisted and walked by fear.
Fear makes people do a lot of things.
The last time Voldermort gain power...
He almost destroyed
everything we hold on stand.
Now he has returned, I'm afraid the
Minister will do almost anything...
to avoid facing the terrifying truth.
We think Voldermort wants
to build up his army again.
14 years ago he had huge
armies in his command.
Not just witches to wizards
But a lot of dark creatures.
He's been recruiting, we've
been attempted to do the same.
But gathering followers isn't
the only thing he's interested.
We believe Voldermort
may be after something.
Sirius.
Something he didn't have last time.
You mean, like a weapon?
No, that's enough. He's just a boy!
You say much more, you might as
well inducting him to the Order.
Good. I want to join.
If Voldermort's recruiting
the army then I want to fight.
Harry.
You are hereby expelled.
Before the whole Withom.
The trains. Underground.
Genius of the muggles.
Here we are.
I've never use this entrance before.
It should be fun.
I'll just get my money.
"Dubledore
- Deaf or Dangerous?"
Good morning, Arthur.
Morning, Bob.
Inter Department Memos.
Used to use owls.
Thank you, Kingsley.
- They changed schedule of your audience.
- When is it?
In 5 minutes.
Mysteries department.
Minister, you is going to
do what is right, is not it?
Yes, the dream oughts to...
Mind you, in the audience only
talks when they talk to you.
Keep calm
It did nothing wrong.
As they say at bundles:
"The truth is going to appear".
Yes?
Fear that can't come in.
Good luck, Harry.
Diciplinary Hearing of 12th August,
into offences commited
by Harry James Potter...
resident at no. 4,
Privet drive, Winshik,
solicitor Cornelius Fudge...
Witness for Defense.
Albus Persidol Wilfred...
Brown Dumbledore.
You got our message that
the time and place...
of the hearing has
been changed, did you?
I must have missed it.
But by mistake, I arrived at
the Ministry 3 hours early.
Charges?
The charges against the
accused are as follows...
that he did knowingly,
and in full aware this
legality of his action...
but use the Petrunas Charm
in the presence of a muggle.
Do you deny producing said Petrun?
And you were aware that you're
forbidden from using magic...
outside school while
under the age of 17?
Yes, of course, but...
Dear witches and wizards
I was only doing it
because of the Dementors.
Dementors? In Little Winchik?
That's very clever.
Muggles can't see
Dementors, can they, boy?
I'm not lying. There were
2 of them. If I hadn't...
Enough!
I'm sorry to interrupt what have
showed in a very well heard story.
But since you can produce
not witnesses of the event...
I admit, Minister. Where
as it happens, we can.
Please describe the attack.
What did they look like?
One of them was very large,
and the other one was skinny.
Not the boys. The Dementors.
Alright. They are big.
Clothed.
Then... everything went cold.
Like all of the happiness
had gone from the world.
Now, look here.
Dementors don't just wander
into a muggle suburban.
Happen to cross with a wizard.
The odds are termolecule.
I don't think anyone would've believe...
that the Dementors were there
by coincidence, minister.
I'm sure I must've
misunderstood you, professor
Dementors are after all, under
the control of Ministry of Magics.
So silly but it sounded,
for moment as though,
you're suggesting that the Ministry
had ordered the attack on this boy.
That would be disturbing
indeed, Madam Under-Secretary.
Which claim for the Ministry
to put a full scale enquiry...
into why the 2 Dementors were
surveiling far from Azkaban...
and why they attack
without the authorization?
Of course there is someone
who might be behind the attack.
Cornelius, I employ you to see wiz.
The evidence the Dark Lord have
returned is incontrovertible.
He's not back!
In the matter of Harry Potter
The Law say in this states,
that magic may be used before
muggles in life threatening situation.
Laws can be changed if
necessary, Dubledore.
Really? To bring up tight
older folk criminal trial...
to deal with a simple
matter of Underage Magic?
Raise, in favor of conviction.
Those in favor of clearing
the accuse of all charges.
Clear up all charges.
Professor!
Badfoot, are you barking mad?
It is going to deteriorate
all the operation.
Sirius, what are you doing
here? If someone sees you...
I had to see you off tonight.
What's life without a little risk?
I don't want to see you get
trapped back into Azkaban.
Don't worry about me.
Anyway, I wanted you to have this.
Orginal Order of the Phoenix.
Marlene McKenine.
She was killed 2 weeks
after this was taken.
Voldermort wiped out her entire family.
Franklin and Ellis Longbottom.
Neville's parents.
They suffered a foughtless death.
It's been 14 years.
There isn't a day goes
by I don't miss your dad.
Do you really think there's
gonna be a war, Sirius?
It feels like it did before.
You keep it.
Anyway, I suppose you're
the young ones now.
Bye...
Hi, Harry Potter.
I suppose the Ministry don't
let you walk out free, Potter.
You better enjoy while you can.
Or else a prison in Azkaban
will have your name on it.
what I talked you
- Completely crazy.
- Stay far from me!
It is Malfoy.
what it waited?
Hi guys.
Hi, Neville.
What is it?
That. Pulling the carriage.
Nothing's pulling the carriage, Harry.
It's moving itself, like always.
You are not mad.
I can see them too.
You're just the sane as I am.
Everyone, this is Lunanut...
Luna Lovegood.
Interesting necklace.
It's a charm actually.
Keeps away the Naragos.
I'm hungry. I hope there's a pudding.
What's a Naragos?
No idea.
Good evening, children.
Now we have 2 changes
in staff this year.
Please welcome back
Professor Grubbly-Plank.
Who'd be taking care
of magical creatures,
while Professor Hagrid
is on temporary leaves.
We're also pleased to welcome our
new Defense Against Dark Arts teacher,
Professor Dolores Umbridge.
I'm sure you all will join me in
wishing the professor good luck.
I assume as care taken of
Mr. Filch is to remind you...
She was at my hearing.
She works for Fudge.
Thank you, headmaster for
those kind words of welcome.
And how lovely to see all
your bright, happy faces...
smiling up to me.
I'm sure we'll all going
to be very good friends.
That's likely. -That's likely.
The Ministry of Magic,
has always considered...
the education of young
witches and wizards...
to be a vital importance.
Although each headmaster
has brought something new...
to this historic school.
Progress of the seek of
progress must be dicovered.
Let us preserve what must be preserved.
Perfect what can't be perfected...
And proove actism, in
order to beat pro-imitate.
Thank you, Professor Umbridge.
That really was constant minimizing.
Minimizing? What?
What does it mean?
Means the Ministry interfering Hogwarts.
Dean, Seamus, good holiday?
Better than Seamus' actually.
My mom didn't want me
to come back this year.
Why not?
Let me see, because of you.
The Daily Prophet has been saying
a lot of things about you, Harry.
And about Dumbledore.
Your mom believes them?
Well, nobody was there
the night Cedric died.
Well, I guess you should read the
Prophet like your stupid mother.
I'll tell you everything
you need to know.
Don't you dare tell me.
I'll never let go anyone
that calls me a liar.
What's going on?
He is what's going on.
Do you believe him?
Yeah, I do.
Does anyone else got
a problem with Harry?
You alright?
Fine.
Seamus was backout there.
He'll go through it. We'll see.
I said I'm fine, Ron.
Alright. I just leave
you to your thought, huh?
Harry...
Come on, Seamus, go on, get it
Good morning, children
Ordinary Wizarding Level Examinations
Well, commonly known as... OWLS
Study hard and you'll be awarded
Failed to do so, and the
consequences maybe... severe
Your previous instruction subjects
have been disturbingly uneven
But please to know from now on...
You'll be following
a carefully structured
Ministry approved
course of defensive magic
Yes?
.. there isn't something about
using the defensive spells
Using spells?
Why would you need
spells in my classroom?
We aren't using magics
You'll be learning about defensive
spells in a secure, risks-free way
We're gonna be attacked,
it won't be risks-free
Do raise their hands
when speak in my class
It's the view of the ministry
That a theoretical
knowledge'll be sufficient...
To get you thru your
examinations, which after all...
Is what schools are all about
And how's theories supposed
to prepare us for out there?
There's nothing out there, dear
Who do you imagine'd attack
children like yourselves?
I don't know, maybe Lord Voldermort
Noe let's don't make this quiet plan
very clear.
You've been told...
That a certain dark wizard
is at large once again
This's a lie
This isn't a lie, I saw him, I
fought.. -Detention, Mr Potter
So, according to your say,
Diggory dropped of his own?
Then second you, Cedrico
Diggory fell dead why he wanted.
Cedric Diggory's death
was a tragic accident
He was murdered, Voldermort
killed him, you must know that
Enough... enough!
See me later, Mr Potter... my office
Come in
Good evening, Mr Potter
Sit
You're gonna be doing some
lines for me today, Mr Potter
No, not with your quill
Cause you're gonna be using
a rather special 1 of mine
Now...
I want you to write:
"I should not tell lies".
How many times?
See...
the enough for the message penetrate.
You haven't given me any ink
You won't need any inks
"I should not tell lies".
Well?
Nothing
That's rite
Because you know deep down
You deserved to be punished
Don't you, Mr Potter?
Go on
Diving snack box
It'll get you outta class
Let's take hours of
pleasures outta school boredom
You want for another?
I'm not asking you to write for me
I'm just busy studying this stupid exams
I'll do the introductions for you
Hermione, you're the most
wonderful person I've ever known
I'll never be rude to you again
Only I bet you will
What's wrong with your hand?
Nothing
The other hand
You've gotta tell Dumbledore
No, Dumbledore's got
enough in his mind rite now
Anyway I won't get
Umbridge's satisfaction
Bloody hell she was torturing you
If your parents know about this...
Yeah, I haven't got any parents, have I?
Harry, you've gotta report this
- It's very simple...
- No, is not.
Hermione, be what it
may is not that simple.
You don't understand.
But I want to understand.
Dear Malfoot, I hope you're allright
It's getting cooler here
Winter's definitely on the way
Despite I've been back to Hogwarts,
I feel more alone than ever
I know you but all
people will understand
Hello Harry Potter
Your feet, aren't you cold?
A bit
Unfortunately of my shoes
of mystery have disappeared
Suspect who Narguilйs
be for trбs of this.
What are they?
The Carl Pastro
They're gentle really, but...
People avoid them
because, they've been...
Different
Why can't the others see?
They can only been by
people who's in death
So you know someone who's gone?
My mum
She was quiet an extraordinary witch
She did a lot of experiments though
One day 1 of her spells went badly wrong
I was 9
I'm sorry
It wasn't that hard
I do feel very sad about it sometimes
But I have a dad
By the way my dad and i believe you
And you fought him
Everything's extremely tough for
you consipring against Dumbledore
Thanks, seems that
you're the only who does
I don't think that's true
But I suppose that's the way
he wants you if you feel.
What do you mean?
If I were the other one
I don't want you to feel
crowd from anyone else
Because if it's just you alone...
you aren't much as a threat
Would you ever stop eating?
I'm hungry
Harry
Can I join you?
Prof, what exactly are you insinuating?
And you requesting when
I punished my students
You conformed to prescribe
disciplinary practices
Seems silly but certain...
That you're questioning my
authority in my own classroom
Minerva
Not at all, Dolores
Just their medieval methods.
I'm sorry, dear
But to question my practices
is to question the ministry
And by extension, the minister himself
I'm a tolerant woman
But the 1 thing I won't
stand for is disloyalty
It is disloyalty.
Disloyalty?
Things at Hogwarts are
far worse than I feared
.. will take immediate actions
What happened to Dumbledore?
Umbridge revolutionised
the teaching of defence
To repress the seriously falling
standards of Hagwarts school
Just 1 question
You've been in this post
for how long exactly?
It registered before for the position in
the Defense against Arts of the Darkness.
Is that correct?
Yes
But you were unsuccessful
Obviously
Would you predict
something, please?
I'm sorry
Move their mouths.
1 tiny apocalypse?
Pity
No, wait... I think
1 do see something, yes
I saw something dark
You're in a great danger
Good
Cho, what's going on?
It's professor, Trelawney
16 years I've been here to teach
Hogwarts is my home
You can't do this
Actually I can
Minerva
Something you'd like to say, dear?
Oh there're several
things I'd like to say
Dear... calm.
Prof McGonagall
May I ask you to escort
Sybil back inside?
Sybil, come here
Thank you, Dumbledore
Dumbledore, may I remind you
Under the tone of educational decree
#23 as it acted by the minister
You've the right to dismiss my teacher
But you don't have the authority
to banish them from the garden
That power remained with the headmaster
For now
Don't you have studying to do?
Professor?
Professor Dumbledore? Professor?
Professor Dumbledore?
That cursed gargul.
We aren't learning
how to defend ourselves
We aren't learning how to pass our OWLS
She's taking over the entire school
Security's and will remian
the ministry's top priority
Furthermore, we've convincing evidence
That these disappearances
are the work of...
The notorious mass
murderer, Sirius Black...
Harry
Sirius
What are you doing here?
Return your letter
You said you're worried about Umbridge
What's she doing? Trying to
train you to kill the half-breed?
She isn't letting us to use magic at all
I'm not surprised
The latest intelligence says that
Fudge doesn't wanna train in combat
Combat?
He afraid we're forming
some sort of wizard army?
This's exactly what he thinks
That Dumbledore is assembling his
own forces to take on the ministry
He's becoming more crack on the edge
The others wouldn't want
me to tell you this, Harry
Things aren't going well at all, the order
Fudge's blocking the truth
These disappearances are the
same, that's how it started before
Voldermort is on the move
What do we do?
Someone is coming, I'm
sorry I can't be more help
But for now, it looks
like you're on your own
He's out there isn't he?
We've gotta be able to defend ourselves
If Umbridge refuses to teach
us how we need someone who'll
Harry
This is mad, who wants
me teach anything?
I'm a nut, remember?
You can't be any worse than her, anyway
Thanks, Ron
Anything, mate
Who supposed to make this?
Just we're
Not as bad
Well, at least safer than being tracked
Hey come back here
Hi.
So...
We know why we're here
We need a teacher
Proper teacher
One has really experienced to
defend himself against the dark arts
Why? -Why?
Because You-knows-who
it came back, idiot.
So as Harry says
So Dumbledore says before Harry said?
The point is where's the proof?
Perhaps Harry could tell us
more about Diggory got killed
I'm not gonna talk about Cedric
That isn't why you're
here, or we can clear up now
Come on Hermione, let's go,
these are some sorts freaks
Is that true you can teach us chant?
Yes.
I've seen it
I don't know you can do that?
He killed a Basalese...
With a sword in Dumbledore's office
And last year he really
did fight who went to flash
Wait
Those sound great when you
say it like that, but...
In fact, I was just lucky
I didn't know what I was
doing half of the time
I nearly always had help
He's just being modest
- No, Hermione, I'm not
Facing these stuff in real
life isn't like in school
It isn't like you made a mistake
you can try just try again tomorrow
But out there
When you're a second
away from being murdered
Or watching a friend
die rite before your eyes
You don't know how it's like
You're rite, Harry, we don't
That's why we need your help
Because the one we try of beating...
Voldermort
He's coming back?
"Dumbledore Army"
1st we need to find a place
where Umbridge won't find out
That's too small
- The prohibited forest?
- It is not going to come out right
Harry, what happened if
Umbridge does find out?
Who cares? I mean...
it"s exciting, isn't it?
Breaking the rules
Who are you and what did
with Hermione Granger?
Finally, at least know a thing
certainly of this meeting.
Which?
For the next few days we should...
All come to this place and practise
We gotta make sure Umbridge
won't find out this place
All student organisations disbanded
Watch way you're going
You've done it
It where is going Longbottom?
You got Neville.
You found the Room Needs.
Which room?
This's also called
come-and-go-room
The room only appears when
a person's immediate needs
And always is equiped
with that it is needed
So, you really needed a toilet?
Charming really
But yes.
It is this the idea.
It's great
Just like Hogwarts wants to fight back
Expelliarm...
You're just flourishing your
stick too much, try like this
Expelliarmus!
Would you please copy
your whole text 4 times
To ensure maximum attention
You don't need to talk
I think it's more like it
Expelliarmus.
Ron, awake
Stunning is one of the sorceries
more useful in your arsenal.
It is an essential artifice
for the sorcerer, so...
Run on, Nigel.
Give it your best shot.
Expelliarmus!
Not to bad.
Good, not bad... at all
Don't worry about,
Hermione, we'll go lightly
Thanks, Ron
- Come on Ron.
Come on Ron.
She was already, Ron.
Thank you -Shut up
I let her do that
She wouldn't be bothered.
It's really my intention
"All students will
submit to questioning"
"about activities illicit suspicions".
Come on, do you want a cup of tea?
Focus on the fixed point, try again
Expelliarmus!
Very good, keep the concentration.
Right.
a little higher
I'm ok...
The ones that they want to join
to the Brigade Inquisitorial
for extra credit,
it owes if register
in the High Magic room.
Reducio!
Working hard is important, there's
something be out this even more...
Believing in yourself
Expelliarmus.
Think of this, every
great wizard in history
Started out...
Nothing more than what
we're now... students
If they can do it, why not us?
Expelliarmus.
Fantastic, well done, mate
So, that's it for this lesson
We aren't gonna be meeting
again until after the holidays
So just keep practising
on your own best you can
And well done, everyone,
great great work
We see us in the communal room, Harry.
- Thank you very much, Harry.
- Not at all
Merry Christmas
- Thank you very much
- It was not anything.
Merry Christmas
Thanks. Merry Christmas
We was thinking, Harry.
We could place some vomitilhas
in the Umbridge's Tea.
Or Febricolate. You say
with some full furuncles..
Sounds great, guys, would you excuse me?
Are you all right?
I heard Umbridge gave you
a hard time the other day
Yeah, I'm ok
It's worth it
Just... learning all these
Made me wonder maybe he would...
Cedric... gave me all these stuff
He was really good
It was just Voldermort was better
You're a really good teacher, Harry
I've never been interested
in any of these before
A visgo.
It probably is full of Narguilйs.
what Sгo Narguilйs?
I do not have idea.
Well, how was it?
I mean she was sorta crying
Not that bad, are you?
I'm sure Harry's kisisng's
more than satisfactory
Cho's been half of the
time crying these days
I bet a longer kiss will cheer her up
You don't know how she must be feeling?
It stands to reason that
she is in sad by the Cedrico.
Confused to like Harry, it
feels blamed by tк him kissed.
In conflict with Umbridge who wants
fire her mother of the Ministry.
And afraid of do not pass in the NOMS
for being so worried about everything.
A person can not feel all this
She would explode.
That is because your emotional side
it belongs to the size of a teaspoon
Voldemort ought to be behind something.
Something that he did not
get the last time
Harry!
In the dream, where you standing
next to the victim?
- Or looking down at the scene?
- Neighter one.
It was as...
Professor, can you tell what's
happening?
Everardo.
Arthur is the watchman tonight
I assured him who are
the right people.
- Sir..
- Please!
Go to your portrait in Grimmauld Place.
Tell them that Arthur
Weasley is seriously wounded.
And that his sons are going to
arrive there soon, at portal key.
they are already theTarget.
It was close but they
think it's going to survive.
Once again the Lord of the Darkness
i did not acquire it.
Look at me!
what is happening to with me?
It wish to see me, director?
I'm afraight it can't wait.
Not untill the morning.
Otherwise, we will be vulnerable.
It seems that there is a connection in
the mind of the Lord of the Darkness
Whaether he is aware of the
connection, i don't know
Lets Pray that he continue not to know
It means, if he knows about her...
he will be able to read my mind?
Read. Control.
Go mad.
It formerly was common
the Lord of the Darkness,
have the pleasure invading
the mind of her victims.
Creating projected images for
torturб them until the madness.
Only after extracting the last
sanity drop.
Only when it did them implore
by the death, he finally killed
Used right Oclumкncia's Power,
it can protegк him of
access or influence.
Nestas classes I will attempt
to penetrate your mind.
And you will attempt to resist.
Prepare yourself.
Legilimens!
It is your curse.
Concentrate, Potter!
Concentration.
Merry Christmas
There go we!
Daddy came back.
Thanks.
Sit down, everybody, sit
down, now's time for presents
An artistic box for Ron.
A great box for you.
And...
They will go, Abram.
I want to see their the guy.
- Try.
- Thank you, mother, is perfect.
- It was what you wanted, actually
- It is.
- Well that, mother.
It was good.
We go personal, we will do this way.
Harry, Harry.
There you are.
Happy Christmas -Thanks
- It seizes that.
- Thanks.
Now the daddy. what is the of the daddy?
- Did all of them win?
- A toast!
- Fred, George,
- Hermione sees if...
- A Christmas toast!
To Mr. Harry Potter.
Without him, I wouln't be here
- Harry!
Harry!
That is delicious.
- I am going to want more of this.
- But daddy, no...
I don't understand why
he didn't wanna wear that
Because I keep seeming
an idiot, because of this
Not more than the usual.
arrogant brat stopped
there is courageous.
Harry Potter, the boy
who stopped the dark lord
Friend of Muggle, traitor of friends...
- If my poor loves
- Monster!
reager enough of your vile!
Away with you.
Okay, boss.
Monster lives to serve the
noble house of Black.
Sorry about that
He never was very pleasing.
Even when I was boy.
at least, not with me.
The what? Were you created here?
This is my parents' house.
For Dumbledore's
Headquarters for the order
Maybe the only useful
place I've been able to do
This's the Black's family tree
My cousin
I hated too much.
My parents pure blood
My mother tried another way
charming woman.
I was 16
Where did you go?
Close to my dads.
I always was welcome at Potters.
I've seen so much of you, Harry
You and i are so pretty much alike.
I'm not that sure.
Sirius, when I was...
When I saw Mr Weasley attacked,
I wasn't just watching
I was the snake.
And afterwards at Dumbledore's office
There was a moment
when I... I wanted to...
This connection between
me and Voldermort
The reason for it... is that
I'm the coming one like him
I just feel so angry all the time
The whole time.
And what if everything
that I've been thru
something gave wrong within me?
Inside me what if I'm becoming bad?
I want you to listen to
me very carefully, Harry
You aren't a bad person
You're a good person
that bad things happen to
Do you understand?
The world isn't spliting
to good people and deaths
People got both bright and dark inside
What matters is about choose the right1
That is what we really are.
Harry, we got to get going.
When all these are over,
we'll be a proper family
You are going to see.
It did same?
Harry!
Harry... Hagrid's back
I'm sorry.
I am going to talk that by last time
I order you to tell
me where have you been?
I told you, I've been away for my health
- Your health?
- Yes.
A bid of fresh air, you know?
Oh yes, as game keeper
Fresh air must be difficult to come by
If I were you, I shouldn't get
too used to being back in fact...
I might not be unpacking at all
That is top secret, right?
Dumbledore sending me
to party with the giants
Giant?
Did you find them
Well, they aren't that hard
to be found, to be honest
They are so great, are not they?
I talked to them to join the class
But I wasn't the only one
who tried to win them over
- Guests of the death.
- Yes.
Trying to persuade them
to join you know whom
I gave him Dumbledore's mesage
Supposed someone'll remember
he was great to, I supposed
- And did they do that to you
- Not exactly.
Go on, you have it, Dolvy dog
It's strange out there,
just like last time
There is a storm coming, Harry.
We all must be ready when it does
We confirm that 10 prisoners
extremely dangerous,
at the beginning of
night yesterday's escaped.
Of course the Prime minister
bundle was warned of the danger.
We have a great suspicion,
We strongly suspect the
breakout was planed
By a man who's experience in Azkaban
Notorious mass murderer, Sirius Black
He is cousin of the
fugitive, Belatrix Lestrange.
"Mass breakout from Azkaban"
Dumbledore warned Fudge of this
was going to happen
He is going to finish killing
for not facing the truth.
Harry.
I... I wanna apologize
Now until my mother tells that
the Prophet is not so right.
So, what I'm really
trying to say is that...
I believe in you.
Neville?
14 years ago
A death eater named Bellatric Lestrange
Used to excruciate my parents
She tortured them, trying to get info
they did not say anything.
I'm very proud of being son.
But I'm not sure I'm ready
for anyone to notice yet
We will make them proud, Neville.
That is a promise.
Make it a part of your memory, to be
the happiest thing to remember
Keep trying, Simas.
Right, it's your time now.
Expecto Patronum!
A fully proto is the
most difficult to achieve
A shield form's also been equally used
Fantastic Gina.
Just remember, it can protect
you as long as you're focus
Just concentrate Luna.
- Think of happy things.
- Expecto Patronum.
I'm trying - I know, you're doing good
This is a very advanced sorcery people,
and you all are doing fine
I'll make short work of it
Hello Potter
Maxim bombard!
Get them
I've been watching them for weeks.
Assembling Dumbledore's Army
Proved, that's what I've been
telling you right from the beginning
All your fear's coming back, you
know who, this isnt just all of it
We saw your lies for what they where.
A smoke screen for your attempt
to seek control of the Ministry.
Naturally - No Professor
He had nothing to do with that,
it was me
Most noble of you Harry trying to
suit me
As it's pointed out,
the name clearly says:
Dumbledores army,
not Potters.
I instructed Harry to
form this organization.
And I, i alone i'm responsible
for the activities.
Send an owl to the Daily Prophet.
If we hurry we'll still make
the morning edition.
Dolores, Saveboat, you'll
escort Dumbledore...
To Azkaban.
To await trial for
conspiracy and seducing.
Ahh.. I thought it might
hit this little snag
You seem to be laboring under the
illusion, that i'll be going to...
What is the frase?
Come Quietly,
Well i can tell you this...
I've no intention of going to Azkaban
You'll...!
Get him!
You may not like this minister,
but you can't deny...
Dumbledore's got style
Dolores UMBRIDGE SUBSTITTUl
TARGET DUMBLEDORE...
LIKE DIRECTOR OF THE SCHOOL OF HOGWARTS.
Boys and girls can't get closer
then 8 inches of each other
The ones that want to join me in
the Brigade Inquisitorial...
Should repress several illicit activities.
Watch out!
Please
Harry.
You did all you could.
Nobody could go against the
old hag.
Even Dumbledore didn't see it coming
Harry, if it's anyone's faults it's ours
Yea you would say that.
But I agreed.
I tried so hard to help but managed
to make things worse.
Well It don't matter anymore.
Because I don't want to play
anymore i cared too much.
The more you care the more you lose.
- Maybe this is better.
- Then what?
It goes alone.
Hagrid.
what is he doing?
where are you taking us?
Hagrid, why can't you just tell us?
I never seen the centaurs so worried
They're dangerous enough
when they sit tight
If the ministry restricts
their territories once more...
they're going to have a full uprising
on there hands.
Hagrid, what's going on?
I'm sorry to be so mysterious
I won't be bothering
you at all with that...
With Dumbledore gone...
And getting the sack any day now
Well I just couldn't leave
without telling somebody about it
Grope!
Down here, you great baboon
Grope.
I brought you some company.
I couldn't just leave him because...
because he is my brother.
Wow!
Half brother realy
He is completely harmless as i said
I thought it to him!
Grope that's not polite - Please do something
We talked about this,
you don't just grab?
She's your new friend,
Hermione
Grope!
Put me down
Now!
You're allright?
Fine, he just has a firm hand, that's all
I think you've got an admirer
You just stay away from her, all right?
He gets his own food and all
It's company he needs when I'm gone
You'll look after him, wont you?
I'm the only family he's got.
Feeling sentimental?
That's privat
Not to me and not to the dark lord
if you don't improve
Every memory he has access to
is what he wants and he'll use it
As a weapon against you, you wont
last 2 seconds if he invates your mind
Youre just like your father.
Lazy, arrogant
Don't say a word against my father
- You're weak!
- I'm not weak!
Then prove it
Control your emotions,
discipline your mind
Legilimens.
Harry.
Sirius!
Touching.
Stop it.
Is this what you call, control?
We've been practising for
hours, can we just rest?
The dark lord isn't resting
You're just like him, you're 2 of a kind
Sentimental children,
do a little whining...
About how bitterly unfair
your lives have been
It may have escaped
unnoticed, but life isn't fair
Your pleased father knew that
in fact he frequently...
- My father was a great man.
- Your father was a swine.
- Legil...
- I protect!
Let's go, Rabicho.
Snape!
Expelliarmus.
- Good, Tiago.
- Good, Tiago, continues!
Father.
Offside.
- Snotty!
Right.
Who it wants to see me take
the pants of the Snotty.
Enough!
Your lesson has gone to an end
It's not...
Get out!
- What is your name?
- Michael.
Your hand is going to be good.
The ink is not as bad as it seems.
See? it is already vanishing.
Hardly can see ours
And the pain stops after a time.
As I told you once before Mr. Potter,
Naughty children
deserve to be punished.
You know Jorge...
I've always thought a
picture outside the world
Fred, I think exactly the same
"OWL Examinations"
REGULATION 572 OF THE MAGIC
USE. ONLY NAVY BLUE INK
There it goes!
I'm ready when you are
I need that prophecy.
You're gonna've to kill me
I will
But 1st you have to help me
Sirius.
Harry, are you sure? - I saw it
It was like with Mr. Weasley.
It's the same door I've
been dreaming about...
I just couldn't remember
where I've seen it before
Sirius said Voldermort
asked for something
Something he didn't know how to ask
- And it is in the Mysteries Department.
- Harry, please listen.
What if Voldermort made you see this?
He's using Sirius because
he's trying to get you
What if he is? I'm supposed
to just let him die?
Hermione, he's the only
family I've got left
what we will do?
We will use Flu's Chain.
But Umbridge is watching
all the chimneys.
Not all.
It's unlocked.
Warn the others
You pirou? We go with you.
It's to dangerous.
When are you gonna get it through
your head?
I Bet you are.
Potter's trying to
help the Weasley girl.
You were going to
Dumbledore, weren't you?
Liar!
You sent for me director?
Snape, yes.
The time has come for him to answers
whether he wants to or not.
You bring the serum of truth?
I'm afraid you've used i all up
on the rest of students.
The last of it on Miss Chang.
Unless you wish to poison
him, I assure you...
I would have the greatest
sympathy if you did.
I can't help you.
He caught Petfoot.
He has Petfoot at the
place where he's hiding.
Petfoot? Who is Petfoot?
What is it? What is he
talking about, Snape?
Nore do i.
Very well
Oh, you got no choice, Potter.
As this is an issue
of Ministry Security,
you leave me with no alternative.
The Cruciatas Curse will
be used on your tongue.
That's illegal.
What Fudge doesn't know won't hurt him.
Tell her Harry!
tell me the what?
Well, if you're not telling
her where it is, I will.
Where what is?
Dumbledore's secret weapon.
- How much further?
- Not far
Had to be, so students
wouldn't find it in anyway.
- what you doing?
- Improvising.
Well?
Where is this weapon?
There is no weapon, is there?
You tried to trick me
Just you know...
I hate children.
You have no Business here, Centaur
This is a Ministry matter.
Lower your weapons, I warn you.
Under the law, as creatures
of mere human intelligence...
How dare you, filthy crossbreed
Incarcerous!
Please Stop, please
Please
Not enough!
I will have order!
Stop, it is not his fault!
He don't understand.
Potter, do something
Talk for them who I
did not do for hardly!
I'm sorry, Professor.
I must not tell lies.
what are doing?
I am Under-Secretary Dolores Umbridge.
Let me go
Thanks, Grope.
Hermione, Hermione, Sirius.
How did you get away?
The puking pastille. It wasn't pretty.
I told them I was hungry
and wanted some sweets.
Of course they tell me to bug off.
Very smart, Rony.
- Sometimes I am.
- It was brilliant!
He was brilliant. So,
how're we getting to London?
Look, it's not I don't
appreciate everything you've done.
But, I got you into
enough trouble as it is.
Dumbledore's army is supposed
to be doing something real.
Or were they just words for you?
Maybe you don't have to
do this all by yourself.
So how are we going to get to London?
Flying it is clear.
Mysteries department.
This is it.
92, 93, 94, 95.
It should be here.
Harry.
This has your name on it.
The one with the power marches
to vanish the Dark Lord.
And the Dark Lord shall
name him the same.
But he'll show him the
power of the Dark Lord.
Neither one could live
or the other one survives.
Harry!
Where is Sirius?
You better wish you could
tell the difference...
between dreams... and reality.
You saw only what the Dark
Lord wanted you to see.
Now give me to Prophecy.
If you're ready to toss, I'll break it.
He knows how to play.
Itty bitty baby... Potter.
It is Belatrix Lestrange.
It is Neville Longbottom, he?
- How will be their parents?
- Better now that will be avenged.
Everybody just calm down, can we?
All we want is that prophecy.
Why did Voldermort made
me to come and get this?
You dare speak his name.
You filthy halfbreed.
It's all right. He's
just a curious child.
Prophecy can only be retrieved
by those who know it.
Which is lucky for you, really.
Already we asked these questions
What was the riesen of the connection
between you and the Dark Lord?
Why he was unable to kill
you when you're just infant?
Don't you want to know
the secret of your scar?
All the answers are there,
Potter, in your hand.
All you have to do is give it to me.
I can show you everything.
I've waited 14 years.
I know.
I think I can wait a little more.
Now!
- Estupefaзa!
*
Petrificus Totalus.
Very good, Neville.
Estupefaзa!
- Estupefaзa!
Reducto!
We will come back for the door!
Mysteries department.
They chose the right name, it?
Voices...
They understand what they are telling?
No one's heard any voices,
Harry. Let's get out of here.
I also hear them
Harry, that's just an empty walkway.
Please, Harry!
Get behind me!
Did you actually believe...
that you're brave enough and..
You children stand a chance against us?
I'll make this simple for you, Potter.
Give me the Prophecy now.
Or watch your friends... die!
Do not give it to him, Harry!
Get away from my Godson.
Listen to me, you just
get everyone out of here.
Do what? No. I'm going to stay with you.
Harry, you turned out beautifully.
Lets take care of it for now.
Expelliarmus!
Very good, Tiago!
Avra Kadavra!
I killed Sirius Black!
Did you come to catch me
Crucio!
You want me, Harry.
She killed him. She deserves it.
You know the sorcery, Harry.
Do!
So weak.
It was foolish of you to
come here tonight, Tom.
aurores are already on way.
When they arrive, I
already will have party.
And you...
I will be dead.
You lost, gaffer.
Harry.
So weak.
So vulnerable.
Look at me.
Harry, it isn't who you were like.
It's who you are not.
Harry.
You're the one who's weak.
You can't understand love or friendship.
I feel sorry for you.
You are a fool, Harry Potter.
And now you will lose everything.
He's back.
"Dumbledore, Potter Vindicated"
"Umbridge Suspended
Pending Investigation"
Hogwarts Headmaster Reinstated
I know how you feel, Harry.
No you don't
It's my fault.
No the fault is mine
I knew it was only a matter of time...
before Voldermort made
a connection between you.
I thought making a distance
for myself from you,
like I had all year, he'll be less tempted,
and therefor you be more protected
The Prophecy said:
Neither one could live
or the other one survives.
It means, one of us i's gonna
kill the other at the end.
Yes.
why didn't he tell me
The same reason why
you tryed to save Sirius.
Same as your friends helping to
save you.
After all these years,
after all you've suffered,
I didn't wanna cause you anymore pain.
I worry too much about you.
Why aren't you at the party? *****
I lost all my things.
Probably people have been hiding them.
That is horrible.
It's only a joke.
But since this is the last night,
I really do need them back.
You want me to help search?
I'm sorry about your Godfather, Harry.
You sure you don't
want any help looking?
All right
Anyway, my mom always said...
Things we lose have a way
coming back to us in the end.
Not always in the way we expect.
I think I am going to eat pudding.
I've been thinking about
what Dumbledore said to me.
What's that?
The thing about fighting battles,
We've got one thing
Voldermort doesn't have.
Yea?
Something worth fighting for.