I won't let anyone come
between us anymore...
Are they recording?
Help!
Cigarette?
Light?
I don't believe the dream I just had.
I was in a forest, running barefoot.
I was hurt, and I was being followed
by somebody, and, well...
the more I ran, the more
I could sense him coming closer.
Who was the guy stalking you?
It wasn't a guy. It was me.
That's the weirdest part.
It was me running after me.
Can't you have normal dreams
like everyone else?
No.
Being like everyone else
is an awful bore!
We should've stayed home
and not gone out last night.
I'm exhausted.
Take a rest.
I'll wake you when we get there.
- Yeah, very funny!
- I'll drive, if you like.
I'll drive, if you like.
Come on. It was late, and I felt tired.
Felt tired, huh?
You were dead drunk!
Well, it was your fault for dumping me
for three hours
and disappearing with God knows who!
I hope at least that he was worth it.
I'll say! Unbelievable!
- Bitch!
- Bastard!
Maneater!
- Bad lay!
- Anybody's!
Cheap hooker!
Are there any cool places to go
in the country?
Well, there's a town hall,
but that's about it.
If I had to live here all year round,
I think I'd shoot myself.
It's another kind of rhythm.
It's different.
Besides, we didn't come here
to go partying.
We're here to study. Remember?
- Hey, we're not deaf!
- Chill out Marie, will you!
C'mon Hendrix, run!
C'mon, faster Hendrix, faster!
Don't be so lazy.
C'mon... that's it.
- C'mon, faster! Hurry up, Hendrix!
- Tom...
stop shouting for a minute.
You're giving me a head ache!
How long do we have to wait for Alex?
She'll be here
after you've had your bath.
No, because Alex has never seen
this cowboy suit.
Tom, go and have your bath,
and then you can put your cowboy
suit back on again. Okay?
Come on, Hendrix...
Yeah, like that.
Go on, yeah. Keep going.
Yeah, faster. Don't stop!
Keep going!
Look at me! Look at me!
Marie, watch the road, will you!
You've still got some makeup on, y'know.
Are you sure it's this way?
Of course I'm sure. In fifty meters,
you go right at the corn field.
There it is. Turn right,
and then go straight for four kilometers.
You really have to know your way around.
Nobody takes this road except
for tractors.
Four kilometers of this,
and it's good-bye car.
No, we're both used to it.
You can't act that way
when ever a guy tries to talk to you.
- I don't act that way with everyone.
- Come off it, Marie.
It's always the same story,
and you know it.
- Stop!
- What's wrong?
I saw someone!
That's not funny, Alex!
No, I'm not kidding.
I saw someone. I swear.
Stop screwing around like that,
will you!
Alex, come back here, please!
Alex!
Damn it!
If this is a joke,
I'll make you regret it!
Alex, where are you?
Alex,
where are you?
I'll get you for this, damn it!
If you think you're being funny,
you've got another thing coming!
Alex! Stop, you bitch,
Alex!
Come back bitch, right now!
Come back!
Come on!
I'm sick of your little game!
Enough is enough!
God damn you!
What if I had left you out here?
Yeah, very funny!
You scared the hell out of me!
Go on, laugh your head off!
- Very funny!
- Where's your sense of humor, Marie?
Here we are.
Okay, now I know why you passed
your exams so easily.
If you spend all your weekends up here,
there's not much
else to do except study!
Men det är lungt och skönt. Man kan
höra tågen som går förbi, det är det.
Easy Hendrix,
- How are you?
- Hello dad.
Don't worry. He doesn't bite.
You talking about me or the dog?
Marie, this is my father. Pop, Marie.
Nice to meet you.
So, I finally see you in person
and not just in a photo.
- Photo?
- You know, the one I took in Spain.
Yes, it's on the fireplace.
You're already part of the furniture.
And this is Tom. Hi cowboy.
- Are you happy to see me, pardner?
- That's all he's been talking about.
He insisted on staying up
and waiting for you.
And your mother's been worrying
all day, of course.
Mom always worries for nothing.
I think she left you something
in the oven.
But I told her we'd manage
and not to bother.
She didn't know if you'd have time
to eat on the way.
Oh, that's mom!
I'll put Tom Thumb to bed
and show Marie her room.
Right. I'll leave you then.
I have some work to finish.
- G'night. Sleep well.
- See you tomorrow.
- Good night, sir.
- Sweet dreams.
Did your dad build this place?
Not really. It was an old farm
that he renovated.
There are lots of them in the region.
Most of them are ruins.
It's a pity.
They've lived here for five years now.
Did they have problems
with the neighbours?
With the local yokels?
Well, at first, they took my folks
for a couple of hippies
who came to make goat cheese,
but now it's fine.
Well, that's my room. There.
This way now.
My parents' room's on the right.
Tom's room is there.
I'll put him to bed first.
There. You're all tucked in.
Mommy?
Alexis, is that you?
That's my mother.
Go on. I'll be right up.
Hi mom.
Is your friend all settled in?
Show her where the blankets are.
If she needs towels,
there are clean ones in the closet.
Don't worry.
She has everything she needs.
Good night, darling.
'Night mom.
Your own private bathroom.
Great, huh?
The heating is electric.
Should I turn it on?
No, I can do it if I get cold.
Well, what do you think?
It's like a doll's house... very pretty.
The problem is he's got a girl friend
he doesn't seem
to want to split up with.
Why are you so interested then?
Someone who's taken can't be
all that bad.
I'm always suspicious of guys
who are free.
Here.
- Want some more?
- No thanks.
Well, I think it's too easy to be
a womanizer
when you're already taken.
Well, you may be right. I don't know.
Maybe I'm just trying to convince myself.
Maybe he doesn't like me at all.
- What's his girlfriend like?
- She's Brazilian.
They've been together for three months.
What's he doing with a Brazilian woman?
What, is he into exoticism or something.
Anyway, I've gotta get a suntan fast
and firm up my ass a little too!
You should see the way she's built!
If you do salsa, I'll go with you.
Don't get them excited
or they'll keep us up all night chirping!
Hey, what about you?
When are you finally gonna
try your luck?
Don't start with that.
You're gonna end up an old maid, Marie.
I'm not hot enough to trot like you.
No, you're scared, that's all.
Well, I'm gonna have a smoke outside.
How about you?
No, I'm going to bed. I'm wiped out.
Don't stay up too late.
I'll wake you at nine, ok?
What's the game plan?
We'll start with international law.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Good night Alex.
- Good night.
Hey Alex...
I'm glad that I finally met your family.
C'mon Hendrix.
Come on, come on, come on Hendrix.
That's it, come on.
G'night Hendrix.
Okay, I'm coming.
Who can that be?
Hendrix, quiet down.
Who is it?
What do you want?
What's the matter, mommy?
Nothing darling.
Go back to your room, dear.
But what was that noise?
Tom, do as I say right now.
Go on, go back to your room.
Daniel?
Daniel? ...Daniel?
Shit, it's the TV plug!
What am I?
What am I gonna do?
Why? Why? Why?
Alex...
Wait a second!
It won't come off!
Wait!
Mommy!
Mommy! Mommy!
Try to calm down, Alex.
If he wanted to kill you,
he'd have done it already. Right?
Now listen to me, Alex, listen.
Listen to me.
Listen to me Alex, for Christ's sake!
Tell me where I can find a telephone!
In the kitchen?
Answer me, Alex!
I can't do anything alone!
I need you!
I'll be back. I'll be back, Alex.
I'll be back.
I have to see
if someone is in the house.
I don't believe it!
The phone's been cut.
I'm gonna get you out of here!
You'll see... you'll see...
Not so loud! He'll hear us!
Don't ruin our only chance. Come on.
Alex...
we're gonna get out of this.
I promise you.
Even if we have to fight it out,
we're gonna make it!
The others were alone!
There are TWO of us!
It's gonna work! It's got to!
Just a little more...
Alex, I got it open!
We're in a gas station.
This could be our only chance.
The knife...
This is for if I don't come back.
- Miss, what is it?
- Call the police! It's an emergency!
What?
Miss, wait!
Hey Jimmy...
- How are ya?
- Fine.
All alone tonight?
Uh weekends are slow around here.
Yeah, I'm all alone.
So then, everyone took off
and left the shop to you, huh?
Yeah, that's about it.
This place isn't bad for bringing a girl
at night, huh Jimmy?
Don't tell me you never did it.
My boss wouldn't keep me on
for two minutes
if I brought someone here.
I'll bet you've got all kinds
of real fancy ladies stopping here
and I'll also bet they ask you
for a little service while they're here.
You get 'em all excited.
Ain't that right, Jimmy?
Well, yeah, I guess so.
What do ya think, Jimmy? Y'like 'em?
Well, they look real good on you.
- They protect you?
- From what?
From the sun, Jimmy... from the sun.
Yeah, well, they're sunglasses so
they protect your eyes, sure.
What do I owe ya?
Just for the gas,
that makes twenty eight.
- Y'want the glasses?
- No,
I'm not convinced,
but what I could use is some booze,
so how about selling me
a bottle of J and B?
- I'd rather have a bottle of Campbell's.
- Sure.
Actually, I'm not allowed
to sell alcohol at this hour.
You promise not to tell the boss?
I promise.
What were you lookin' at, huh Jimmy?
What were you lookin' at?
Oh, somebody answer for Christ's sakes!
Answer!
State Police here.
Hello? Hello, police?
Oh I beg of you, help me!
Okay, calm down and tell me
what the problem is.
The Sorals, they have a farm
near Puyanne.
I'm a friend of their daughter, Alexis.
This guy broke in during the night.
He broke in and he murdered everyone!
He took my friend away in a pickup truck,
and I'm really afraid for her.
He just killed the gas station guy.
- Gas station?
- Yes.
- You're in a gas station?
Which gas station?
Hold on. I'll have a look.
I don't know what station.
I was in his pickup truck.
All I know is it's a very old pickup,
brown, old and rusty.
Did you get the vehicle's plate number?
How could I get the number?
I told you I was inside the truck!
Do you realize how many pickup trucks
there are on the road?
Without a plate number...
Jesus, an old pickup truck on a country
road at this time of night
shouldn't be that hard to spot, huh?!
Calm down please, ma'm,
and tell me where you are.
Listen, this son of a bitch
just took off with her.
If you don't send someone right now,
she'll never make it!
I understand, but we can't help you
if we don't know where you are.
And d'you think if I burn this god
damn gas station down,
maybe you can locate it, huh?!
The keys... they keys...
Where does the murdering son
of a bitch live?
Shit!
Damn it. Where did you go?
Why do ya care so much about Alex?
She turns you on, huh?
She does the same thing to me.
She turns me on too.
The lights are all out.
It looks shut down for the night.
Better have a look.
Go around the back, Fred.
- And be careful, huh?
- Right, Captain.
Captain, the back door is locked.
We've gotta...
You better call headquarters.
This is patrol car two-fourteen calling.
We've got a murder victim here.
Patrol car two-fourteen here,
headquarters.
We've got ourselves a murder victim.
Oh my God!
It's me, Alex. It's me.
It's all over.
Ok.
There... there.
Don't touch me, you hear?
Don't touch me I said!
It's all over. He's dead, Alex.
He's dead. It's over.
What are you saying?
- He's dead.
- You don't make any sense!
- Get away!
- It's all over,
- Alex, all over. Alex...
- Get out!
It's over, Alex. I killed him. Don't you.
Alex...
...please calm down. He's...
- Get away from me!
Don't come near me!
Come on Alex, come. It's all over now.
He can never do anything to
you again. Come...
You mad bitch!
- I'm gonna cut your head into pieces!
- It's me,
It's me, Marie, your friend.
I'm on your side!
I killed him, Alex.
It's finished. He's dead.
You murdered my whole family!
You don't know what you're saying.
There was nothing
I could do to save them.
There was just you...
Alex, everything is gonna be okay
from now on.
Please, you've got to trust me, Alex.
Easy no...
You'll pay for this, you little bitch,
you hear?!!
I'm gonna take care of you, Alex!
Help me... help me... help me!
Go on, go! Hurry!
- What's going on?
- Hurry up! Go go!
Go on! Go on!
- Hurry, hurry! Faster!
- What the hell is...
Faster, faster, faster!
Come on.
I'll tear your head off!
See what I got...
So, you wanna drive me crazy,
you god damn bitch, huh?
Do ya love me?
You don't love me, do ya?
Y'don't love me, huh?
You don't love me?
- You don't love me?
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes I love you!
Yes, I do love you! I love you!
Nobody will come
between us ever again, Alex!
Never again.
I won't let anyone come
between us anymore...
Are you sure she can't see me?