It's 4:15 on a Saturday morning
in El Paso town.
This is Uncle Bruce here going on
with the farm and market report...
on the station
all El Paso listens to.
My mother told me
never to do this.
Bless you.
My name's Jim Halsey.
John Ryder.
So you want me
to drop you off somewhere?
I'm getting your car wet.
Oh, this isn't my car.
It's a drive-away.
The owner's in San Diego.
So where you headed?
- You got a smoke?
- Yeah, sure.
You gonna tell me
where you're going?
Yeah, sure.
What are you looking
at me like that for?
Just looking.
What are you doing?
What'd you do that for?
I asked you a question.
Scare you?
Look, I think you better
get out now.
The ride's over.
Good-bye.
I'm gonna sit here...
and you're gonna drive.
Excuse me.
- What's wrong with that car back there?
- Why?
Thought I saw something,
that's all.
- I ran out of gas.
- So you need a gas station?
Would help.
Okay.
Gas stations have cigarettes.
What about gas?
I don't need gas.
What do you want?
What's so funny?
That's what the other guy said.
Who's the other guy?
The guy who was driving that car back
there. Picked me up before you did.
- Was that him in the car?
- I'm sure it was.
He couldn't have walked very far.
Why is that?
Because I cut off his legs...
and his arms...
and his head.
And I'm gonna do
the same to you.
Don't.
What part of Illinois you from?
- What?
- Your license plate.
Tell the man.
Chicago.
My wife's from Rockford.
You got a cigarette?
All right, the road's clear now.
Come on. Get going, sweethearts.
Drive.
You want to know what happens
to an eyeball when it gets punctured?
You got any idea how much blood jets out
of a guy's neck...
when his throat's been slit?
What do you want?
I want you to stop me.
You got the knife.
You'll stick me with it
before I can do anything.
That's right. So what have you
got to lose? Stop me.
Crying isn't gonna help.
Keep driving!
Please. I'll do anything.
Say four words:
Say...
"I want to die."
Say what?
Say it.
- I don't know if I can say that.
- Sure you can.
Repeat after me.
"I...
want...
to...
die."
I don't want to die!
Fuck you, buddy!
Jesus Christ!
Hey! Pull over!
Pull over! The guy
in your car's a nut!
Shoot him.
That guy's a fucking nut
in your car! Pull over!
- Kill him.
- That guy will kill you!
That guy, get him
out of your car!
Where do you think you're going?
Come back!
Oh, fuck.
Come on, you son of a bitch.
Hey, stop! Stop!
Wait!
- Okay, see you at 4:00.
- Bye-bye.
Shit.
We're closed. We don't open
for another 45 minutes.
Please, I need to use a phone!
Sorry. I can't let you in.
We're closed.
No! Listen.
- Please, I have to call the cops.
- What happened?
I can't explain right now.
I just need to use the phone.
If Jack saw me doing this,
he'd kick my butt.
Phone's around the corner. Go on.
You stink of gasoline.
Were you in an accident?
Hello, police? My name's Jim Halsey.
I know who killed those people in...
I picked this guy up hitchhiking...
Same guy blew up the gas station.
Jim Halsey. H-A-L-S-E-Y.
I'm at the Longhorn Restaurant.
You do?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. I won't go anywhere.
Jesus.
If you think the cops are gonna arrive
soon, you got another thing coming.
A guy got shot in the corner
a couple months ago.
It took them 45 minutes to get here
with the ambulance.
By that time
the poor guy was dead.
Specialty of the house.
Actually the cook's not here yet.
It's the only thing I know how to make.
Thanks.
That's real nice of you.
Everything gonna be okay?
I hope so.
You sure look
a whole lot better.
Guess it's safe for me
to smoke now, huh?
Sorry I gave you
such a hard time, but...
you'd be surprised the kind of trash
that passes through here.
- How is it?
- Real good. Thanks.
My name's Nash.
I really appreciate this.
- Where you from?
- Chicago.
- Where you headed?
- California.
How'd you know that?
That's where everyone's going.
Hollywood?
No. San Diego.
I thought about moving
to California.
Jeremy, who owns this place...
he's my cousin.
And Uncle Jack does the cooking.
Like that, see?
We're all kind of interrelated.
It's kind of hard
to just pick up and leave.
But you never know.
My brother Bill is from Mars.
Actually we're all from Mars here.
We keep our spaceship out back.
So, what planet are you from?
What?
You haven't heard a word
I said, have you?
Yes, I have.
That's okay. Go on.
Eat your cheeseburger.
I gotta get some stuff
out of the freezer anyway.
Stay where you are! Put your hands
in the air. Get down on the ground!
Wait a minute!
He's in there!
Get your ass on the cement,
or we open fire!
I'm not gonna tell you again!
Put your hands
behind your back slow.
- My wallet's in my pocket.
- Shut up!
We know how to do it.
Jesus!
Oh, my God! He put that there!
Now shut up.
Don't move.
What's going on?
What'd you do to him?
- You keep to yourself.
- Why you arresting him?
Pick up that stuff.
Do you know this guy?
Not really.
Then what the hell
is he doing inside?
Half the cops in the state
are looking for this creep.
Let's get this sack of shit
out of here.
Where's your driver's license,
your I.D.?
Where are your credit cards?
The guy I've been telling you about
took my wallet and planted the knife.
My license was in my wallet.
I don't have any credit cards.
I suppose he took
your vehicle registration too?
What's a young kid like you driving
such a fancy car? You steal it?
The car doesn't belong to me.
It's a drive-away.
I'm supposed to be delivering it
to California.
The guy's in San Diego.
What's his name?
I don't remember.
But I know the number of the drive-away
company. Why don't you call them?
Hell, son. You better start calling
somebody 'cause you're in deep shit.
It's 312-399-2090.
I know the number so well
because I called them so many times.
I was on their waiting list
for a month.
I wanted a car going
to California.
That's why it took so long.
Thank you for calling
Midwest Drive-away.
Our Chicago office hours are
9:00 to 5:00, Monday through Friday.
Closed Saturday and...
Well, now what are we gonna do?
You got one more call.
Call my brother, for God's sakes!
He'll be home.
It's 312-905-9044.
Maybe you didn't let it
ring long enough.
Do I look like a killer to you?
Folks coming in from Austin tomorrow
gonna be interested in talking to you.
I'm gonna give you a chance
to get some rest.
Get him locked up.
Get him out of my sight.
Let's go.
Jack?
That kid isn't a killer.
Any fool could see that.
Okay, face front.
Hold real still.
Now turn to your right.
Steady.
Make it your left.
Oh, those are real good.
Your mama's gonna like those.
Let's go.
You behave yourself now.
Hello?
Go! I'm right behind you.
Come on!
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Stop!
- Take her easy!
- Tell me about it.
Get over by the car.
Those cuffs on your belt...
take them off and lock
your partner's hands behind his back.
- You mean me?
- I mean you.
You! Yes, you!
Okay. We're gonna go
for a little ride now.
You two get in the front.
I'll get in the back.
- One of you open the door.
- Open the door, Jack.
Get in the car!
You and me, we're gonna
get in together, okay?
Ready...
steady...
go.
- Can I close the door?
- Shut the door.
Start the car.
Head for the highway.
Can you call out on that thing and get
me connected with somebody in charge?
I'll try to get through
to Captain Esteridge.
Do it. But don't tell anybody
where we are.
- Central, this is car number...
- I said don't tell them anything.
Central, this is one of your cars
and we've been hijacked by suspect.
He wishes to speak
to Captain Esteridge directly. Over.
Esteridge 10-11.
We'll try to locate. Standby.
10-12, El Paso. Clear.
This is Captain Esteridge.
Do you read? Over.
Captain, this is Jim Halsey.
You gotta listen to me, Captain.
I swear I didn't kill those people.
I got framed by this guy
I picked up hitchhiking.
What do you suggest
we do, son?
Come on, man. You tell me.
Why don't you
stop things right now...
let my men go
and give yourself up?
I don't have identification.
I don't have anybody to call
for you to check me out.
Are you willing to lay down
your arms and surrender?
I promise I'll do everything in my power
to see to it you're treated fairly.
I'm putting my trust in you, Captain.
Take us in.
Bang.
Well, I know
you caught something...
because you're probably
the best dang fisherman around here.
But if that's the best
you can eat...
I don't know what you're
gonna be able to do.
That'll tide us over until...
Looks to me like you best go.
- Better get on the road.
- Yeah, I'll see you.
Bye, Alice.
Well, what happened to you?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Nothing happened.
- I need some coffee.
- It's brewing.
- Bring it to me at one of the booths.
- You okay, kid?
How do you like Shitsville?
Don't you move.
You stay seated
right where you are...
or I'll blow your brains
through your ass.
The gun is empty.
You never checked it,
did you?
So help me,
I'll blow you in half.
All right.
Squeeze the trigger.
I will.
- Please.
- Oh, I will.
'Cause you can sure as shit bet
I'm gonna squeeze mine.
Bam!
Why are you doing this to me?
Come here.
You're a smart kid.
Figure it out.
I didn't do it.
I didn't do any of it.
I'm not gonna shoot anybody.
I'm not a killer.
This morning this guy
tried to kill me.
He's been following me
ever since.
I don't know why.
Do you believe me?
Sure.
No, you don't.
I wouldn't either.
Let's go sit down.
What are you gonna do?
Give up.
I have no choice.
Nice and easy. Come on.
Step down.
All right, step down.
I'm turning myself in.
Get out from behind the door!
Step away from the bus. Get down!
Move!
Move your ass now!
I'm giving up
and I'm not guilty.
You just wasted
two of my friends.
- You spit on my wrist.
- What?
I said, "You spit on my wrist."
Wipe it off.
You can see I'm unarmed.
Wipe it off!
- Come on, Lyle. Go easy.
- Shut up!
- Let's get him back to the station.
- I said, "Shut up!"
Wipe it off!
Put the gun down.
Goddamn you.
Drop your guns! Don't turn around.
Just drop them.
I can't believe you were gonna do
what you were gonna do.
Don't you know who he is?
You got the wrong man, Lyle.
Like hell we do.
Now just settle down and...
- Don't come any closer.
- Hand me that gun.
Just empty them.
You're in enough trouble already.
You just threw your life
down the toilet, girl.
When the truth comes down,
I'll be just fine.
I'm taking him to
the sheriff's office in Riley.
You stay put.
Let's go.
- Now what?
- We're going to Riley.
- Do you know how to use the radio?
- I better let you out here.
No. If I'm in the car with you,
they're not gonna hurt you.
- We can talk to them by radio.
- What are you gonna say?
We're gonna turn ourselves in.
Buckle your seat belt.
Do mine.
Hello? Can you read me?
We want to turn ourselves in.
We're turning ourselves in.
Can you read me? Over.
Listen to me this time.
We are turning ourselves in.
We just want to turn ourselves in!
Do you read me?
Hello!
The bastard's on his way.
Hold it there.
That's a good speed.
Shit.
Get the gun! Use it!
- No, I'm not gonna shoot anybody!
- Aim for the tire.
- Oh, God!
- They're gonna kill us!
- Use it! Shoot 'em!
- No!
I got you.
Jesus Christ! Use the gun!
Shoot back!
You got him. Watch it.
She's got a gun.
Watch it. Get down.
You got him.
I dropped the gun.
You what?
Get the shotgun!
Be careful, now.
There you go.
Hold on!
Holy shit!
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm okay.
1073, 221, are you okay?
Let's go, you son of a bitch!
Oh, God.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
- Why didn't he kill us?
- Let's go.
Why didn't he kill us?
Let's go.
Are you okay?
Why'd you pick him up?
I wanted to help him...
and I was tired.
I thought he'd
help me stay awake.
Can I sit by you?
- What are you doing?
- I want to call my father.
- No. No calls.
- It's only my father.
I said, no calls.
Not until we figure out
what we're gonna do.
I can explain it.
It's not that simple.
I already tried.
I'm scared.
Me too.
Thanks.
Nash?
Are you awake?
Let's head 'em out!
No, I'm okay. Don't...
I'm okay.
I just want you
to know where I am.
Everybody's
got this whole thing wrong.
No, I sound funny,
but I'm okay.
The Apostle Paul told us
to look within ourselves...
for the very spirit of faith.
You must look to nature where
the spirit is replenished daily.
I'm Reverend Hollis Maxwell inviting you
to visit a church this Sunday.
This is Channel 3,
KCIK Television, in Texas...
licensed by the F.C.C.
in Washington, D. C...
ending its broadcast day.
We invite you to join us
tomorrow at 6:00 A.M.
All right.
Don't hurt him, Ed.
You take it easy now.
Are you Jim Halsey?
- Who are you?
- I'm Captain Esteridge.
We spoke on the radio.
Where is she?
You come along with us now.
We're gonna need your help.
Hostage situation.
Hold your fire.
Hold it!
Please, don't!
Why don't you do something?
Fuckin' do something!
We can't!
Hold it!
- No!
- Do something!
If we shoot him, his foot will come off
that clutch, and that truck will roll.
Please!
Now, you get in there
and you see what you can do.
Please, do something!
Please, help!
She's sweet.
The gun is loaded.
Go for it.
Go ahead. Pick it up.
Tell you what... I'll let you hold
the gun on me before I do anything.
They'll catch you.
Please!
Yeah. Sure.
So what?
Pick up the gun.
Do something!
Put it in my face.
Right there.
That's good.
You know what to do.
Now do it.
Squeeze the trigger.
She'll die.
Oh, God.
You useless...
waste.
I can't tell you
how sorry I am for you, son.
Anything I can do for you?
When you're finished here,
you should go see a real doctor...
and get a complete checkup.
We all know there
was nothing you could do.
- Who is he?
- We don't know.
No prison record,
no driver's license...
no birth certificate.
We ran his prints
through the computers...
and we came up with nothin'.
I know we'll find something, but
right now, I don't even know his name.
How do you feel?
Tired.
He can't see us or hear us.
I want to talk to him.
What's your name?
Come on.
Do you have a name?
John Ryder.
What'd you say?
His name is John Ryder.
Do you have a police record?
Where are you from?
Disneyland.
How long do we
have to play this game?
Y'all give me a minute?
Come on.
All right, that's enough of that.
It was a bad idea in the first place.
Captain Esteridge,
is it true that...
No comment.
All right, son.
Get in the car.
Are you okay?
You'll never hold him.
All right, you listen up now,
and you listen good, son.
There's something strange between you.
I don't want to know what it is.
But I'm telling you,
he is in our hands now...
and whatever happens to him,
it won't be decided by you.
It doesn't have anything
to do with you anymore.
Okay?
Can I have one of your cigarettes?
Sure.
Stop the car.
You're not gonna use that thing.
Stop the car,
and don't do anything stupid.
All right.
What's on your mind?
Get out.
You're gonna get yourself killed.
And if you don't, you're gonna be
in a whole lot of trouble.
I'm sorry, sir.
- It's something I gotta do.
- You don't know what you're doin'.
Yeah...
I do.
Hi, kid.
Come on.
Come on!
Subtitles By
Captions, Inc. Los Angeles