- Fuck!
- It's not there.
It's in the kitchen where you left it.
How'd you get in?
You have a nice family.
They're fine. Alive.
Asleep.
- Are you gonna kill me?
- If I was, I'd have done it
when you walked to the car this morning and
been gone by the time you hit the sidewalk.
- Then why are you here?
- To talk.
But, Mike, if you make me kill you,
you will not go alone.
Sit.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
- I think.
- And yet you've killed men.
- Yes.
- I'm gonna ask you a question.
How you answer it
will determine how this night ends.
How does a good man decide when to kill?
The man you've been chasing
is a killer, a ghost.
Rumour has it that he works for a group
known only as The organisation.
It's so secret no one knows it exists.
It takes no sides,
yet it has ties to every government.
Its sole purpose is the training
and conditioning of professional killers.
These men are selected at birth -
rejects, orphans.
All of them unwanted and disposable.
They are made experts in every aspect of
combat and programmed for one purpose -
to kill.
The man you have been chasing
for the last three years, Inspector,
is the very best of them.
Put him there.
You shouldn't have stolen from me, brother.
Now you must pay.
Where is the document?
- Say it!
- I'm sorry...
- What happened to his voice?
- He made me swallow...
- What did you do to his voice?
- Nothing, ovie. Exactly as he was delivered.
Delivered?
- You didn't find him?
- No. A contractor. An American.
Swallow what?
Run!
We have all heard your theories, Inspector.
This isn't a theory. This is our guy.
No motive, no forensic evidence,
no witnesses. He's... he's a ghost.
- How long have you chased this "ghost"?
- Three years.
Well, thank goodness you have Interpol
to finance your persistence, huh?
Despite being the anus of the Third World, we
are in attempt of competent police work here,
and it is our belief that
Bwana ovie was killed by his own brother.
oh, so he choked down a pound of C4
and knocked on ovie's door?
Probably.
General, this man truly is the best
at what he does.
He is likely responsible
for over one hundred deaths.
Let me show you what I mean.
This is ovie.
And these are just the ones we know about.
Are you beginning to get the picture?
They might kill you for that.
For what you're doing to that whisky -
brutalising it with ice.
Never more than two cubes.
It waters down the Scotch.
I'm sorry. Aftermath
of my pretentious ex-husband, I'm afraid.
No.
I'm June. And you are?
This is where you tell me your name.
Excuse me.
Africa job complete. The money
has been wired to your account. Nice work.
Regrettably, the next target date
has been moved up at the client's request.
And the client wishes it to be public.
I've planned something more subtle.
I've made preparations.
Incumbent Russian president
Mikhail Belicoff's recent political shift
is in direct conflict with our client's interests,
and threatens their control
of the Russian government.
The client needs it to be public.
Do you accept the new parameters?
Yes.
We appreciate
you breaking normal protocol.
The specifics are being uploaded.
I, for one, will not let cowardice deter me.
Mr Belicoff?
In light of your political positions,
will the hardliners
continue to support your re-election?
one only needs to be...
We have a problem.
There was a witness in St Petersburg.
- How reliable are your sources?
- Impeccable, as always.
Interpol has arranged the pickup.
Will you intercept?
- Yes.
- Uploading data.
How much?
I can't be sure.
He never works again so quickly.
But the Russians say that Belicoff was grazed
by a single bullet from over 4km away.
But it definitely sounds like him.
Yes, sir.
Well, what bothers me is that he missed.
Yes, sir. I know what
this investigation has cost. I...
I understand. I just need a little more time.
- Sir, you need to see this.
- Sorry, sir. I'm gonna have to call you back.
oK. He shoots the bodyguard
to get a clean shot at Belicoff.
He splits these two civilians
by inches. Keep watching.
Keep an eye on the bodyguard. See that?
Back it up. Back it up again.
- An awful lot of arterial spray for a miss.
- Sir. You have a call.
- Whittier.
- They found Belicoff's shooter.
- They found him?
- Tip from a hotel concierge.
- Concierge where?
- Grand Hotel. He recognised his picture.
A picture?
Where the hell did they get a picture?
- I don't know, sir.
- All right. I'm on my way.
They found him.
Contact the Russian Secret Police,
tell them Interpol has jurisdiction.
They are to keep him under surveillance only.
No one moves until we get there. No one!
Was the target not at the location?
The girl was there, but she was no witness.
She'd never seen me before.
We will be unable to transmit payment
for the Belicoff assignment
as the task was not completed.
No. He took a direct hit
through the nasal cavity. I watched it myself.
Please wait. Uploading live news feed.
.. so afraid of my message
that cowardly violence is their only response.
That was the scene outside...
Who was the client?
Answer me!
Who ordered the hit on Belicoff?
If you set me up, I will find you and I will
burn that building to the ground around you.
Mike Whittier, Interpol.
What's the status of my suspect?
I was told you were coming, Inspector. I am
Captain Gudnayev, St Petersburg Militsiya.
Please make yourself comfortable.
- My men are almost in position.
- For what?
We were informed the suspect intends to flee.
My orders are...
Whoa, whoa. orders from who?
Interpol has jurisdiction here.
Militsiya's only responsible for the extraction.
Gudnayev is not directing the operation, I am.
I'm Chief Agent Yuri Marklov of the FSB.
The FSB? Why the hell is
the Russian secret police involved in this?
- Sir, they're going in.
- Get your men out.
- You have no idea who you're dealing with.
- These men are capable of handling this.
Shoot on sight.
Do not give that order!
47, it's Diana. I could be retired
for contacting you directly.
The client was... Belicoff.
Your location has been compromised.
Come on.
Stay here, cover the elevator.
Call me on my cell and tell me where it stops.
- Yeah?
- Five dead in the lift. None of them our boy.
He's on the third floor. He must've
opened the doors from inside the shaft.
Freeze!
Get down.
Don't move.
Fuck!
Sir!
We had him.
- How many men did you lose?
- 16 dead.
No! No, no! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Don't touch that!
- Where'd you get your fucking licence?
- I need the room, Captain.
- Where does he get all this stuff?
- Can you make it work?
Probably. Why?
I've been looking for you, Inspector.
I think we started off on the wrong foot.
Who informed you
of the whereabouts of my guy?
I believe it's time we had a chat, you and I.
Jenkins.
Yes, sir.
This assassin...
My associates tell me
you believe him to be freelance.
Your associates tell you that?
You do not believe he is connected
with Central Intelligence Agency?
- Why do you ask?
- No reason. It just seems a bit naive.
Well, it's a theory.
Yes, a theory.
But a theory shared by Moscow.
In accordance with Article 1764.3
of the EU Charter,
any state matters
which deal directly with intelligence
shall be the sole jurisdiction
of the host country.
Ah, and the light bulb comes on.
Took me a minute. Must be the jet lag.
- You're telling me to fuck off?
- No, no, of course not.
You are a good man, Michael.
one of Interpol's best.
But leave this intelligence work to the FSB.
And Belicoff?
I'm sorry?
There's two things wrong with this photo.
one: the footage has been tampered with.
Someone inserted that civilian
to cover up what actually happened.
- And the second thing?
- My boy doesn't miss.
- Delivery.
- You're supposed to leave this at the desk.
Mr Belicoff sent them.
Make a sound, I'll end your life. Understand?
Who else is inside?
I know you, from the street earlier today.
- You're coming with me.
- I can't.
oK, oK! I'll get my coat.
- Where are you taking me?
- Somewhere safe.
- Get in.
- Fuck you! I'm not getting in there!
There's a dead man in there!
Get me out of this car!
Are you going to kill me?
I'm gonna ask you some questions.
Before today on the street,
have you ever seen me?
- Why were you there?
- My boyfriend.
- He told me to meet his driver on the corner.
- Belicoff?
How, after I put a bullet through his head, was
he able to give that speech this afternoon?
Then you're of no use to me.
Wait! Wait! There is something.
Doubles. Mikhail has doubles,
just like Saddam Hussein.
The man I shot was not an impostor.
Belicoff is dead.
Why'd you tattoo your face?
Because it's the only place
I knew Belicoff wouldn't hit.
Tell me about Udre Belicoff.
Mikhail's brother?
He runs slave girls, drugs, weapons.
Both the CIA and FSB want him dead.
Mikhail's been protecting him.
Get up. Get up. You're coming with me.
I can't. He'll kill me
if he finds out I left the apartment.
Belicoff hired me to kill him,
used you to set me up.
The dead man in the trunk was your driver.
He was gonna use it on you.
You're as good as dead without me.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna finish the job I was hired to do
and find out who's behind this.
I need to talk to you.
I need coffee. Follow me.
We have three roadblocks - here, here, here.
We completely shut down
international airport.
All border security has been tripled.
He cannot get out of city.
- Train stations?
- Temporarily closed.
- And St Petersburg Station?
- No trains leave Russia from this station.
only commuter trains
headed towards interior.
What makes you think
he go further into Russia?
Because I know him better than anyone.
Thanks for the coffee.
Go to the last platform and wait.
- Why?
- Now.
- Jenkins, anything?
- Nothing.
Stay sharp.
I don't know, sir.
It seems odd for him to come here.
Trust me. This is where he'll be.
Jenkins, bench. Shaved head.
Got him, boss.
Fuck!
Jenkins.
I'm still on him, boss.
Platform... number nine.
Boss?
You've gotten slow.
Tell me why.
Why is there a hit on me?
Stay here.
How about dying with a little dignity?
You think it's done? It's just beginning.
I told you to wait.
I know.
I'm sorry.
I... I know...
Freeze!
You're the one who's been tracking me.
The Russian Militsiya
have got the terminal locked down.
You need a hostage, take me.
Come on.
He hasn't seen your face.
He doesn't have to die.
Take me instead.
Please...
stop.
She saved your life.
He said your ribs are broken. Unlucky.
- You seem awfully calm, considering.
- Your assassin is dead.
Why are you covering this up?
You know that's not our killer.
I told you before, Inspector.
This is no longer your affair.
Now, there are two ways we may proceed.
one: my men accompany you to the hospital,
and when you and your associate can travel,
they will escort you to the airport.
Then I will write a report
extolling Interpol for its help.
- Medals will probably be involved.
- or?
I report your incompetence and disregard
for my nation's laws to your superiors.
This will find its way
to the state prosecutor in Moscow.
So how do you think
we should proceed, huh?
How about...
go fuck yourself.
- I was running out of oxygen!
- Don't be dramatic.
- Dramatic!
- I got rid of the body!
- I've been there for hours!
- I brought you breakfast.
I'd thank you if I wasn't so mad at you.
Look at me.
Back at the station, you interfered.
I'm sorry. I can't allow that.
- I swear I'll never...
- Stop talking.
If you're looking for a reason not to kill me,
I don't really have one.
I'm not a whore by choice.
Belicoff owns me. I'm his property.
Would you like to know
how much he paid for me? 300. American.
I've tried to escape. The last time...
It is a strange thing to wish to die.
So are you?
Going to kill me?
No.
You don't want to fuck me
and you don't want to kill me.
I've never felt so much indifference
in my entire life.
If you ever again interfere with me like that...
I won't.
- Are we clear?
- Yeah.
Eat your sandwich.
I need to get some sleep.
- You know...
- Nika?
- Yes?
- Stop talking or I'll put you back in the trunk.
This was a royal fucking mess.
Get me a secure line.
Wait outside.
Are we on a secure line?
Yes, Comrade.
I heard you lost him at the station again.
If you're trying to make me nervous,
it is working.
Keep it low profile
while we track him down.
Don't appear in public
and he won't be able to reach you.
Comrade Yuri. All of those bodies you buried
and yet a single man eludes you.
The operation will not be a success
until he and that whore are dead.
I gotta give it to you, sir. Pretty slick.
Go fuck yourself.
It was a pretty stupid idea, actually.
If we get caught, we'll be making snow cones
in Siberia for the next 20 years.
Yet here we sit...
If I don't appear in public, you fuck,
how am I supposed to be re-elected?
Belicoff?
Shit! Hide that thing.
We came to see Chief Agent Yuri. What's up?
He is very busy man.
He asks you to go directly to the airport.
We will escort you there immediately.
oK.
It's for you.
- After all these years, I'd think you'd trust me.
- Tell me what you know.
officially, nothing.
Unofficially, it appears your employer
is throwing you to the wolves.
- Why?
- Belicoff's softening political stance
and his refusal to cooperate with hardliners
upset a lot of people.
So they ordered the hit and replaced him.
Seems you and your friend are the only ones
who know Belicoff is a double.
What's the CIA's position?
Company usually likes to be
on the side of whoever wins.
Take the envelope from the girl.
Ah, Udre Belicoff,
Mikhail's younger brother.
- Rumour is you'd like him to disappear.
- That is the rumour.
- I'd like to help.
- How's killing Udre Belicoff gonna help you?
Let me worry about that.
- What do you want for your trouble?
- Small favour.
This is a small favour?
I can't do this, not in your time frame.
- Keep reading.
- Jesus Christ. Tell me it isn't what I think it is.
oK. It's not what you think it is.
But I'd expect the last thing you'd want
is for me to be arrested with that file.
oK. I'll try.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, you're welcome.
We know Udre's been planning something
with a German arms dealer named Price.
The two have never met.
That's your way in.
Intercept Price and you get a shot at Udre.
I'll get you his file.
They're meeting in Istanbul in two days.
Good morning.
Have you slept at all?
Some.
You know, you can sleep in the bed.
I won't bite you.
Unless you pay me.
It's not polite to stare.
So when are you gonna tell me your name?
- Get dressed.
- What for?
We're going to dinner.
We need to buy you a new dress.
You're really quite charming
when you aren't killing people.
- This place looks nice.
- Yeah.
Don't you think?
Wait here.
Hey! What did you do? Eat without me?
- How did you know I wouldn't take off?
- I didn't. We have reservations at eight.
Jenks, how do you feel?
My pride hurts worse
than my arm, sir. Any word?
The sketch is out to all Interpol substations in
Europe, stations, airports, border crossings...
- What's that?
- This is what I wanted to show you.
It's every appearance Belicoff has made
within the last 12 months.
This is from a speech
he made in London on May 7th.
And this is from some shitty political
luncheon in northern Georgia.
Someone took a photo from a mobile phone.
Look at the date.
May 7th. How is that possible?
I can't be sure, but unless he's figured out
how to be in two places at once...
- He has a double.
- He's paranoid enough.
- It explains the arterial spray.
- I hope he had health benefits.
When I was little I had this squirrel,
you know, with black stripes on the back?
- Chipmunk.
- Right, chipmunk. His name was Tishka.
I'm sorry, sir,
but this is for another gentleman.
- Table 26?
- That's right.
My mistake.
You know what table that is?
I saw the layout when we came in.
- Do you remember everything you see?
- No.
- What's the soup of the day?
- Lentil with sautéed onions and tomatoes.
The woman behind you, what's she wearing?
- With the red hair and the silk dress?
- Yeah.
That's not a woman.
What colour underwear am I wearing?
You're not wearing any underwear.
Come with us, sir.
Here we go. It'll be all right...
Nika, ask for the check.
- But I'm not done!
- Then hurry.
You scratch what I said
about you being charming.
Sorry, sir.
Mr Price.
Thank you for the introduction
to Udre Belicoff.
Little help, please.
- What the fuck?
- Let's go.
What?
Now.
Well, that was lovely.
Right up to the time
you dragged me out by my hair.
Undress me.
So we are good with firearms.
Not so good with ladies undergarments.
Careful. I'm not wearing any panties.
Nika, you're drunk.
And?
And this is a very bad idea.
You mean this?
Yes, that.
How about this?
Definitely that.
Then...
this must be really bad.
- The briefcase.
- Mr Price!
So you took it upon yourself to change
our appointment. How forward of you.
As I told your men, I was attacked earlier
by some lunatic. Common sense dictated...
Common sense should have dictated
you not abuse my good nature.
Sit.
I was just going over a few of my lines
with some of your competitors.
Lines.
My lines. You get it?
Where was I?
He's not Price.
This is the... the Kedr 9mm compact.
It's less than two kilograms,
select fire single or fully automatic.
Empty... and safe.
or if you're looking for an assault rifle, I have
the M203 with under-barrel grenade launcher.
A lot of Third World dictators
got a lot of 7.62s stockpiled.
Saves them from having to buy ammo.
Everything here is available in bulk,
of course.
Prices not negotiable.
Any questions, Mr Price?
Yeah.
What about the little one there?
Here. I show you.
This is a Makarov. 22.
A favourite of the KGB.
Particularly effective in the right hands.
But for a real target,
you need to find a soft spot.
Whoa, hold up. Hey, wait.
This is not a Kedr. It's a Chinese copy.
I don't know if it's the drugs or you're usually
this inept, but you're wrong about these guns.
If the gun you're holding is as cheap as this
one, even if you could shoot her in the eye,
and I'm not saying you could,
you wouldn't kill her.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- I need you to help me with your brother.
Mikhail? Fine. Fuck him!
I do whatever you want!
What the fuck do you want me to do?
Just this.
It says here that when the male penguin
meets the female penguin,
he knows in the first ten seconds
whether he's gonna like her or not.
- Are you listening?
- I'm listening.
I read that.
These articles are full of shit.
- Why do you buy these magazines?
- For the advertisements.
- What do you need luggage like this for?
- That perfectly holds my sniper rifle and 245,
and a gag for irritating talkative little girls
like you. You want me to stop and get it out?
I don't know.
You think we have time for foreplay?
You know, when I was a little girl,
my father raised grapes.
And I told him that one day
I'd own my own vineyard.
It looks nice.
We need to get off the road.
Jenks.
- Is that his suitcase? How did we get that?
- As a consolation prize,
Captain Gudnayev sent me our boy's stuff
from the hotel in St Pete in case it might help.
- Anything?
- Not much.
There is... this.
What do you make of this?
"Trust unto God
and He shall direct your path. " It's...
That's Psalms. I never figured our boy
as the religious type.
That's strange.
Nika...
I have to go.
So much for happy endings.
I don't want you to do this.
Belicoff needs to die.
I don't care about that. Not any more.
As long as he is alive,
they will never stop looking for you.
Take this.
At the next station, get off the train
as soon as it stops. Move with the crowd.
But I don't even know your name.
The place I was raised, they didn't
give us names. They gave us numbers.
Mine was 47.
Well, that explains a lot.
- How will I find you?
- Don't worry. I'll find you.
What are you going to do?
What I do.
You have no idea the pain
involved in the procedure.
They peel back the skin of the face
and screw a Teflon frame to the bones
to duplicate the facial features.
I wonder, if I had known the pain involved
would I still have gone through
with this whole double business.
You're drunk!
You don't want to drink
with your new president, Tovarishch?
We are celebrating, yes?
All the evidence is erased.
Mikhail Belicoff.
And his pathetic brother Udre.
Now I'm the one and only,
and the one man I have asked you to kill -
the only one who can expose us -
is the one man not in this room!
So... tell me, Tovarishch,
what exactly have you done to find him?
It seems if we wait long enough,
he will find you.
Us, Tovarishch Yuri. He will find us.
The organisation
has sent in their best operatives.
I know. Don't let your incompetence hinder
them. We won't have this conversation again.
Belicoff's brother was found dead in Istanbul.
They're waiting for the body in Moscow.
- Heads up.
- Michael, how's things going?
Belicoff's brother has been found murdered.
It's our guy. He's setting Belicoff up.
We're getting pressure from the ministry
and the EU to drop this investigation.
- The Russians will confirm...
- They're the ones leading the EU on this.
They deny your ghost exists
and filed papers with the minister's office
claiming you've overstepped your authority.
Who did?
The FSB. Specifically Chief Agent
Yuri Marklov. I need you to stop!
No, you don't understand.
The FSB is covering this up.
He killed Belicoff's brother.
Now, why? Unless...
.. Mikhail Belicoff will attend
funeral services tomorrow morning...
The funeral. He's trying to take Belicoff
at Udre's funeral.
This generator produces over 3,000 amps.
Much more than is necessary, but I wanted
you to understand the gravity of the situation.
At 2:30, that radio taped to your hand
will activate.
You'll have 30 seconds
to order the shooting of your friend Belicoff.
If you don't, the generator will start.
Your skin will melt,
your blood will vaporise.
There won't be enough left of you to identify.
You have gone to a great deal of trouble.
I am just a bureaucrat.
There is nothing I can do for you, I'm afraid.
I disagree.
This is not a request.
This situation is fixed,
and you know both possible outcomes.
Live or die. Your choice.
Here's something
to keep things in perspective.
I picked it up last night
when I was in your house.
- You bastard!
- If I were you, I'd keep that radio dry.
Yell all you like.
The Lord himself won't hear.
There are over 100 highly trained
alpha special forces soldiers in this cathedral.
It would be foolish to attempt any type of
violence. Your assassin would realise this.
But what if he does? Look around you.
How much civilian blood will be shed?
We are prepared for that as well.
Gas canisters are being deployed.
If anything occurs,
the civilians will be rendered unconscious.
Now, if you will excuse me...
Ladies and gentlemen, I'd like to start by
thanking you for your sympathy and prayers.
one minute, 50 seconds.
Come in.
We are deeply grateful.
My brother, he was a troubled man,
but he was not always like that.
one minute, 25 seconds.
one minute, 20 seconds.
Should we choose to be kind
and let her die, much like my brother?
or should we do what is necessary,
what is hard, to save what we love?
one minute.
I, for one, will not fail again,
not with this country.
Not with our children's future,
not with you - my countrymen.
35 seconds.
Hurry, come in!
Change target! Shoot Belicoff!
Are you sure?
Do it!
Come on.
Just fucking do it now!
Do not let the assassin escape.
Release the gas.
Lock down the doors.
I suggest you and your men follow me.
Let's go!
Your man has made a mistake.
There is no exit. He's trapped.
It doesn't make sense.
Why would he...?
"Trust unto God...
and He shall direct your path. "
Shit. He set this up from the beginning.
- Where does this key fit?
- The archbishop's personal chambers.
The third tower over the Moskva.
He's going into the river, like in St Pete.
Jenks, get our men. Let's go.
He is in the southwest tower.
Call in the gun ships.
Do not let him escape!
Seems I underestimated you.
Consistently.
A miscalculation on my part.
Who are you?
- Answer me.
- Let me help you.
How? By having me killed?
Ah, no. For that I'm sorry. It was a mistake.
Was Nika a mistake? or did you
destroy her life for your amusement?
What? You think you can take
what has cost millions, years of planning,
for the good of this country,
and destroy that?
Then what? Walk away?
You don't think they will let you do that?
If you kill me, they will never let you go.
They will hunt you for the rest of your life.
You did your job,
and you did it very well.
And for that, my boy, you should be proud.
That's it?
Yes. I'm offering you your life back.
That is why you are here, yes?
That is what you want.
- No?
- No.
He shot the president.
- Interpol! Drop your weapons!
- We have an arrest warrant for that man.
Don't move! Hands on your head!
on your head! on your knees!
Don't do anything stupid.
Just one thing.
Knowing how this ends, was it worth it?
Killing Belicoff?
Knowing how this ends...
definitely.
What do you make of that?
Hell.
- Who the hell are you?
- Agent Smith, Central Intelligence Agency.
- All you men, to the rear of that vehicle.
- You don't have jurisdiction!
We aren't here. Which means
when we shred you with automatic fire,
then this will never have happened.
We believe
you're involved in terrorist activities.
We're Interpol. In accordance with Section 3...
We're transporting an international criminal.
What criminal?
- oh, Jesus Christ!
- You know what? I'm sorry, man.
My mistake.
I thought you were someone else.
You prick!
on behalf of the US Government, I'd like
to extend to you our sincerest apologies.
Load up, boys.
- So now what?
- Now you have to answer my question.
Are you a good man, Inspector?
- I think.
- And yet you've killed men.
So, Inspector,
how does a good man decide when to kill?
If I think a man means to do me or my family
harm, then I'll do whatever I can to stop him.
But beyond that...
it's a crapshoot.
The key.
You knew I had jurisdiction and would
walk you right out through the front door.
I wanna be left alone.
- Just like that?
- Yeah. Just like that.
This is the man you've been looking for.
Ballistics will confirm
he was shot by your weapon.
The magazine is in the nightstand
next to your bed.
- Don't forget it when you call your superiors.
- Did you kill him here?
It's five. If you wait till the girls go to school,
you won't have to expose them to this.
- Explains why you waited so long to call it in.
- I can't go along with this.
I hope you can.
For both our sakes.
Goodbye, Michael.
I hope I never see you again.
I told you to leave her alone.
You should've listened.