Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
- Now how the hell should I know?
- You said he was distraught.
I didn't say I knew why.
I mean, you don't
look too happy, either.
Will you excuse me?
That's the fiancée of the deceased.
Miss Leonore Lemmon.
The one on the end is a houseguest.
Robert Condon.
The other two are friends,
Carol Van Ronkel and Bill Bliss.
Bliss found the body.
- What time the party start?
- Just after midnight.
He woke up, came downstairs,
20 minutes, half an hour,
said good night and went back to bed.
The coroner's ruling,
it indicated suicide.
Paterson.
Yeah.
The fiancée said he was depressed.
Also predicted he would do it.
He went upstairs, she told her pals
he was going to shoot himself.
So, why didn't she stop him?
Maybe she believed
what she saw on TV.
On TV?
What, him?
Faster than a speeding bullet.
Oh, hi.
I have new information.
Good.
I went to the office on Rossmore.
The office
is occupied by an orthodontist.
You can imagine my consternation.
We're setting up in a better location.
It's right off Wilshire,
adding an operative.
But delays, phone lines.
So, the time being...
We have reason to believe that
my wife continues to engage in illicit
carnal relations.
I'm gonna take care of the mail.
Good.
Mr Sinclair.
We did check into that and
there was nothing we came up with.
Yes, well, in that regard,
I blame myself.
How's that?
My wife became aware
of a change in my demeanour
and curtailed her activities accordingly.
- She still at Western Costume?
- I drop her off there every morning.
What transpires after that...
- All right, the fee is...
- $50 a day.
Three-day minimum, in advance.
We'll do everything we can.
It's not right, you know.
His money.
He's nuts.
Don't give me grief, okay? Nobody said
you had to stay in Van Nuys.
You're the one that wanted a backyard.
What did I say?
Disneyland.
He like it?
Russ took him on a canoe,
the Indian Village.
Seemed to go all right.
Russ...
Russell.
Rusty...
Am I supposed to ask your permission?
I just want to make sure
his intentions are honourable.
- Keeping busy?
- Yeah. May be something big.
- You don't believe me?
- Oh, I always believed you.
Every time.
Where's Evan?
What's going on?
That actor who shot himself,
the one who plays Superman.
- What about him?
- It's made him very upset.
He told you that?
Every kid on the block is upset.
Scout. Come on.
Your old pops is taking you to school.
What's on your mind, Scout?
Nothing.
Nothing?
You know, things you see on TV,
you know,
someone's a cowboy or a spaceman,
it's just pretend, right?
I know.
- You remember we talked about that?
- I remember.
Okay.
- Hey, what's this?
- I don't know.
Well, why don't you find out?
- Do you like that?
- Kind of.
All right, come on, turn the knobs.
2:00 in the morning, I'm thinking,
maybe I ain't the best PI in California,
but if I catch a one-eyed Negro Jew
sneaking into a house in Beverly Hills,
it's time to pack it in.
Davis is a very talented performer.
What'd Rick do?
What's the matter, Ace? Alpha Beta
not hiring any more parking lot guards?
Not with you moonlighting, Chuck.
Study this gentleman.
Observe him closely.
The haircut, the getup.
Nobody told him the world don't need
two Ralph Meekers.
Listen to him, kid.
And don't start smoking, either.
Filthy habit.
This isn't show business, pal.
It's just a job. You punch in every day.
- Let's get out of here.
- I'm still eating, Chuck.
Come on.
Sweetheart, cheque please.
Hey, Del.
- Rick working you hard?
- Payroll scam at Warners.
- Well, that's real detective work.
- I'm a real detective.
Anything you guys throwing away?
- Jesus, Lou...
- Look, I'm asking.
The shit you won't touch, come on.
You will?
If it puts me in a Fleetwood
bigger than Ricky Harris', yeah.
- He drives a Lincoln.
- Come on, Del, feed me something.
- Why should I?
- 'Cause you owe me, partner.
What?
What, the guy who used to play
Superman? He shot himself, what?
Someone thinks he didn't.
Oh, yeah? Who?
- His mother.
- How do you know what she thinks?
- She tried to hire us this morning.
What does she have the cops don't?
Look, you like a headline,
there's a headline.
What did Rick say?
Maybe you forgot, we're paid
to keep things out of the newspaper.
Helen Bessolo. She's in from Illinois.
At the Ambassador.
And you don't work for Rick Harris.
- What?
- When you pitch her,
you're not an associate,
you're not a stringer.
Who said I'm pitching her?
I'm done eating.
Oh, I forgot.
Have one.
- Guess who's a daddy?
- It's a boy.
Mrs Bessolo? I'm Louis Simo.
I called.
Our children, yes.
They'll always be our babies.
You work for Mr Harris?
I was an operative at the agency.
I branched out on my own.
May I?
Now, there are certain situations
the agency is not prepared to handle.
They come to me.
Your house full of strangers.
- How's that?
- The ones there, that night.
Van Ronkel, Bliss. And that woman.
This is Lenore? The fiancée?
Leonore.
How could you trust anything they say?
Did he give any indication to you?
About what?
Being, you know,
despondent?
Why would he be?
When was, if I may,
the last time you spoke with your son?
Do you know a Herbert Spirakis?
No.
He's also an investigator here.
Very professional.
He says I have a case.
Mrs Bessolo, I'm gonna level with you,
all right?
LAPD, Los Angeles Police Department,
they don't like to be shown up.
Okay, they've already closed the door
on your son. It's a suicide. End of story.
You want that door open again?
You want to make the cops
and the DA pay attention?
You need a headline this big,
only with the truth.
So that everybody knows. Okay?
You got to shove it in their faces.
Did Herbert Spirakis tell you that?
I have to pay by cheque.
Five minutes. I didn't let you in.
Hey. The $20?
Right.
Sorry.
Say, you know who people
wanted to see? Lana Turner's guy,
- Stompanato.
- No kidding.
I tell you, that kid of hers,
the knife was practically
sticking out of his ass.
- Think about how hard...
- What are these?
Huh?
These marks?
What'd he do,
beat himself up before he shot himself?
I don't know.
Don't do that. Hey.
- I didn't say you could touch anything.
- Don't worry about it.
Put it down, the coroner's
gonna be back. You hear?
Okay, that's it, you gotta go.
So, pal, who's T.M.?
Come on, what do you say?
You help me, I'll help you.
George. George.
Yes?
Don't order any more drinks,
I can't afford it.
We couldn't afford the cover, Nati.
Drinks are just gravy. Hello.
Billy Wilder. Hire me, please.
We're two steps from the men's room.
Anyone sees us,
they'll think we're queer.
You do look fetching tonight.
- Okay. I'm leaving.
- No, you're not.
You're gonna stay right here
and wait for the casting guy
from Fox, right there.
You and I are going to practise
the fine art of being noticed
without looking like you're trying.
Fred Zinnemann.
- Who?
- He's a director. Pictures.
He hires people.
George, no one's going to
hire me, anyway.
That's Rita Hayworth.
George.
You look absolutely ravishing, Rita.
- Miss Hayworth!
- This way.
Thank you.
Just made it.
- I beg your pardon?
- Into the picture.
Was someone taking a picture?
I hadn't noticed.
- My, we're awfully well-trained. Mr...
- George Reeves.
Was it the line or the delivery?
- I laugh when I'm happy.
- I see.
Who is it that I'm making so happy?
- I'm Toni.
- Just a poor girl with no last name.
I had no idea
I could spread this much joy.
Well, who knows
what you might be spreading?
- Your turn.
- I'm afraid you got me.
This way, please.
Thank you.
For you, sir.
Oh, George, George, George...
- That was your first picture?
- That was my very first paid acting role.
Your very first paid acting role
was in Gone with the Wind,
- the biggest picture ever?
- That's right.
And yet, I don't remember you.
You don't? How's this?
"We want all your waltzes, first Brent,
then me, then Brent, then me..."
- You were Tarleton!
- I was.
- Your hair was orange!
- Hardly. It was tangerine.
Ah, well.
All right, then. That was your first.
What was your last?
- That I'm fairly certain you didn't see.
- Try me.
The Adventures of Sir Galahad,
boldest knight of the round table.
Saturday morning serial, very cheap,
we all rode the same horse.
Well, I'm sure you
did a wonderful, professional job
and the children loved you.
I don't know, it's a lot of waiting.
A lot of wanting, and somehow,
that's your life.
- How dare you.
- What?
How dare you to permit me
to talk about myself
when I'm standing next to
the most beautiful woman?
Well, you're an actor.
And how about you?
Those friends of yours, over at Ciro's?
I know some of them.
- Good people to know?
- Not if you know them.
Really? That sounded sad.
Not at all. I was aiming for mysterious.
Mysterious is like this.
Oh, that's good. Do another one.
Noble.
Stoic.
Heroic.
Bad shellfish?
Very good, exactly.
Well, you don't seem sad.
What if I were?
I won't allow it.
I'm much too old for you, you know.
- We don't give out that information.
- Here's the thing, though.
Mr... The person I work for, he...
If I come back empty-handed,
I'll lose my job.
"Get me that watch that George had,"
he told me.
- George?
- George Reeves.
Oh, Mr Reeves.
Yeah, they were very close.
Like brothers.
You know,
they spoke every week, until...
Who do you work for?
No, I can't, I can't.
I just do what I'm told.
If the rest of the world knew
what these stars were really like...
Well, we got some stories, right?
Hold on.
A gold Chopard Quattro.
Unfortunately, no longer made.
Well, he was a good customer?
No, these are
Mrs Mannix's account. She...
She bought him
a lot of things, you know.
Of course. Say no more.
- Maybe there's some old stock.
- I'd be grateful.
No luck, huh?
- I'll go break the bad news.
- If I showed you something else?
No, I don't think that's gonna help.
Spencer Tracy.
- Now, how the heck did you...
- I'd heard he can be difficult.
Oh, between you and me?
Complete prick.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Mrs Mannix.
I don't have a problem
with a man drinking before breakfast,
but it is impolite not to offer me any.
Your husband
is the general manager of MGM.
He gives the word, I'm stuck doing
serials for the rest of my life, at best.
- He would never do that.
- No? Why not?
Because it would hurt me.
- What about me?
- It would hurt both of us.
Look, whatever I said last night...
It sounded true.
Was it? Or were you acting?
It was true.
Listen, Eddie's got a mistress.
Japanese girl, very sweet.
An apartment in Brentwood,
a cabin up in Big Bear.
And what do you have?
I have another seven good years.
Then my ass drops like a duffel bag.
- Well, it seems all right now.
- Thank you for noticing.
Tell me the truth.
Did you think I could help you?
I thought that you were
the most beautiful girl in the room.
And, yes, I did.
Do you know who you looked like?
Sir Galahad.
George, nobody ever asked
to be happy later.
Tell me what you want.
You can have it.
Should I leave?
No. You should stay.
I got a fiancée, I got a mistress...
Well, former mistress.
I'm not really sure on that yet,
but I got bruises on the body... What?
After you dropped her off,
she never left the building, Mr Sinclair.
I can't swear that nothing went on
in there, but she never left the building.
There's an entrance in the rear.
- Okay.
- And a loading dock.
Neither would be visible
from your vantage point.
Look, Mr Sinclair, maybe,
you know, you and your wife,
you sit down,
you have a conversation and you see...
This man. Here.
- He works there.
- No. I've seen him before.
Mr Simo, I have utter faith
in your abilities,
but you might wish to
entertain the notion
there is more going on
than you realise.
"I, George Bessolo Reeves,
"being of sound and disposing
mind and memory,
"do declare this
my last will and testament.
"I hereby give, devise and bequeath
all monies and personal property
"owned by me at the time of
my death to Toni Lanier Mannix."
What?
- Maybe there's another will.
- There goddamn better be.
Miss Lemmon,
can I talk to you for a minute?
I'm Louis Simo,
I'm a private investigator.
I've been retained by Helen,
the bereaved mother...
- Bitch!
- I agree.
...of your late fiancé.
I was just wanting to know
if I could ask you a couple of questions.
You're not an investigator.
Yes, I am, ma'am. I am licensed
by the State of California...
You know what he is? A catfish.
Go clean the mud out of your whiskers.
"A catfish"?
- Excuse me. You the Times?
- I'm the Times.
You're the Times?
What do you think about
Superman offing himself
and cutting his beloved fiancée
out of the picture?
Leaving the green to Eddie Mannix's
wife, huh? Like she needs the dough.
Hell hath no fury, huh?
I mean, people get killed
for less than that.
You saying
George Reeves was murdered?
That's a heck of a question.
What's your name?
Louis Simo. S-I-M-O.
- Did you go to the doctor?
- I went.
- What did he say?
- Those guys, they're all frauds.
Not a very helpful attitude.
Well, something
has to kill you, don't it?
Oh, I guess so.
- You under contract?
- I was, at Warners.
- But now you're not.
- Now, no, no.
- Tough game.
- Well, I'm always ready to play.
George was in
Gone With The Wind, Eddie.
That picture made money.
So, what brought you to Los Angeles,
Miss Yoshida...
- Don't talk to her.
- I'm sorry?
- She doesn't speak English.
- Oh.
Oh, yes.
Eddie, I found a darling little place
up on Benedict.
It's about $12,000. I'd like to buy it.
Well,
it's a good investment. Right?
Well, you know
what they say about land.
They ain't making more of it.
What's not on the menu?
We have some very nice
blue points set aside, Mr Mannix.
- How's the flank steak?
- The flank steak is very good.
Bring me that, Cobb salad,
dressing on the side, baked...
I'm sorry.
My wife will take another Gibson.
Well, what do you think?
The most I ever got from a girlfriend
was a tie.
- Just how Toni does things, I guess.
- You should be happy, George.
Wouldn't mind a job.
Well, maybe she can put in a word.
With her... You know.
Hey, take it.
- What's this?
- It's a couple of hundred.
- I see, but why are you giving it to me?
- Because I got it, you need it.
Go ahead, kid, make your first million.
- Your talent is required.
- All right.
"Lois and Jimmy,
what have you done with them?"
"They're safe for now, Superman.
"Just don't get any big ideas
about stopping the robbery."
"All right. You win this time.
"But if something happens to them,
"I promise you'll wish
this day never arrived."
Whenever you're ready, George.
All right.
"They're safe for now, Superman.
"Just don't get any big ideas
about stopping the robbery."
Actually, George,
you're reading the other role.
- Oh, Superman.
- Yeah.
He's, you know, the hero.
I suppose I've always felt
more the criminal type.
We're looking for
a new take here, George.
Someone the kids will buy, sure,
but adults, too. It needs a real actor.
What's the worst that could happen?
We offer you the part.
Well, okay.
"All right, Mr Prince, I got
your message. What is it you want?"
"It's not what I want, Superman,
it's what you want."
"Listen. I'm not in the mood for games,
"but I promise you this.
"If anything happens to
Lois or to Jimmy..."
An actor can't always act.
Sometimes he has to work.
You're talking to the man who defended
Camelot with a cardboard sword.
I enjoyed you in that.
You were the oldest boy
in the theatre, Art.
Look, it's a dirt-cheap kiddie show.
It doesn't even have a sponsor.
- Odds are no one's ever gonna see it.
- It's just sounding better and better.
And you need the money.
- There's money.
- I mean money of your own.
Oh, come on, George.
What do you want from life?
Oh, I don't know.
I'd settle for Clark Gable's career.
Take the job, cash the cheque.
Can I tell you something, Art?
Seriously.
Of course.
You're beautiful
when you take your glasses off.
So, does this mean we're saying yes?
Why is it so drab?
Superman wears blue and red.
Not on TV, not enough contrast.
But, maybe if the show flies,
they might film in colour.
For when the colour sets come out.
Then I'll get to wear the blue and red.
I look like a damn fool.
- Nice car.
- That's my baby.
- Lou?
- Yeah.
Hey. I'm Russ Taylor. We're...
Yeah, Goofy.
- I'm sorry?
- You went to Disneyland.
Oh, yeah, that's right, last week.
She's a little upset. I happened to
be in the neighbourhood, so...
That's convenient.
Hey, he's a good kid.
I saw that right off.
Well, you would know, huh, Russ?
The policy will cover it.
That's not a problem.
But she's concerned.
He took charcoal fluid, poured it
all over it and put it on the couch.
Put what on the couch?
What's the deal, Scout?
Your mom is very upset with you.
What if you
burnt the house down? Huh?
You wouldn't have a place to live.
You know people get killed in fires?
Huh? Use your noggin.
- It was just to get rid of it.
- What, the costume?
Scout, you begged me for that thing.
- You wanted it so bad, you remember?
- Not any more.
Why?
He shot himself in the head
with a Luger.
That's a Nazi pistol.
So, you know this man?
He was an actor.
And if he did shoot... Whatever he did.
You can still
watch him on TV, can't you?
Scout, I asked a question.
- Evan, you hear what I'm saying?
- All right.
Evan, you answer when I talk.
Evan! Put it down!
Come on, what are you doing?
- Let's leave it.
- Put it down.
- Evan. Put it down!
- Louis!
Stop it, okay, God damn it!
This kid...
- Why do you even bother calling me?
- I don't know. Possibly you might care
- that your son is having a...
- Maybe you should take a breath.
I do care.
I care very much, he's my son.
Just 'cause I don't have
every minute of the day...
No, you have so much going on.
Is that what this is? 'Cause I've heard it
already a thousand times from you.
The actor. This gimmick you're pulling.
We noticed the item in the paper.
- What? I was hired.
- Can't you see
what these
endless little tricks wind up...
This is how I make my fucking living.
Lou, that kind of language...
This is how I make money
that I send you.
- I'm sorry, is this his business?
- I'm just trying to keep things civil.
Russ, this is between Louis and me.
Listen, Lou. He asked for you.
I wasn't gonna call you.
He asked.
Well, I'm sorry I couldn't be more help
but, after all, I'm not Superman.
Jeepers, no, Mr Kent.
I suppose that would be
too much to ask.
I suppose it would, Lois.
I suppose it would.
Sorry, that's me.
Keep rolling.
Take it back a line, George.
All right, Tommy. Where were we?
Lois, would you like to see
the real Man of Steel?
Well, sure I would.
All right then, here he is!
You're next, Jimmy!
Leave the bowtie on!
Great Caesar's ghost!
More powerful than a locomotive,
Chief! No one is safe!
What did you think?
The scripts are awful.
And everything looks cheap.
- You were charming.
- Well, that's all that matters.
She's a lesbian, you know.
- Who?
- The one playing Lois.
- Mr Reeves?
- Hello?
- Whenever you're ready.
- All right.
- Phyllis? Is she really?
- No.
She is now. As far as you're concerned.
Well. There it is.
Cue fans!
Action, George! One!
Two!
Three!
Cut it! Cut it!
Unhook him!
- You all right, George?
- Leave him alone.
All right, let him go.
All right, all right.
I'd like to thank the Academy
and all the good people
of Galesburg, Illinois,
for making me who I am today.
Okay, everybody, let's take 10.
Okay.
Who was that next to you
when I came in?
Chad. He's in my acting class.
Yeah?
- He any good?
- He's okay, I guess.
You shouldn't hang around people
who are less talented than you.
You've never seen me act.
So?
So, you don't know if I'm talented.
You don't know what I could do.
You don't know
a thing about me, do you?
You ever going to tell me
how you got that?
- What?
- Under your armpit.
- Something stupid.
- A fight?
My pop,
he was on the gate at Warners.
A guard?
Yeah, he used to go to work
in this uniform.
You know, crease in the pants
like a knife.
I used to think
he was the Chief of Police.
He... He did that?
I was a month out of the Army.
It was 1946, so no job.
You know, Pop got me set up.
And there was a strike at the studios.
So, keep the union guys off the lot.
You know, platoon around the gate,
me and 40 other saps.
You know, bats and billy clubs.
Got out of hand.
Little Teamster shit
came at me with a razor.
Two years in North Africa,
all I get are crabs.
Six days in Burbank, and... Man.
And my pop apologised.
To you?
To the studio.
For his son screwing up.
Like the chicken-shit peasant he was.
- What's that look?
- I'm just watching you.
- Mrs Bessolo.
- I don't need this.
I do. Sit down, please.
Mrs Bessolo.
Right here.
- Mrs Bessolo.
I'm James Engelmann,
from RKO-Pathe Studios.
- The what?
- Superman was filmed on our lot.
And I'm here to express
how saddened we are over your loss.
My son was not lost, Mr Engelmann.
He was taken.
- One more, Mrs Bessolo.
- Over here, Mrs Bessolo.
What the hell
did you drag them here for?
Freedom of the press, right?
- These in the report?
- They weren't there then.
Hang on there, Mrs Bessolo, hang on,
hang on. Come on.
- Just let me sit for a minute.
- Okay.
Come on, make yourself useful,
grab a chair.
- Sure.
- Come on, let's get her out of here.
There you go.
Okay? There you go, very good.
Okay, good.
Here.
Okay? I'm gonna go handle this.
You just relax.
- Is she all right?
- That's her boy's blood. You tell me.
The deceased woke up,
joined his guests
for approximately half an hour,
returned to bed, no sign of forced entry
or physical struggle.
The Luger, found there on the floor,
heavily oiled. No prints.
He kept it in the nightstand.
The slug, there.
And the casing, on the bed,
underneath the body.
You want to explain to me
how a man can shoot himself
and end up on top of the shell?
Is this your strategy, Mr Simo?
To impugn the laws of physics?
There's no prints on the gun.
What, did he wipe it clean
after putting that hole in his head?
Prints aren't automatic.
Certain conditions have to be present.
Did you question the people
in the house?
They all signed sworn statements.
Forty-five minutes to call the cops.
That's plenty of time to come up
with some bogus story.
- But you got sworn statements.
- You accusing me of something?
Was Reeves
checked for powder burns?
It's a suicide shot to the temple.
Where's the burn?
When a gun is discharged
directly against...
Listen, the coroner never checked.
He didn't notice
the bruises on the body, either.
Which, by the way,
aren't automatic, okay?
Certain conditions have to be present.
Like, maybe a fight with a guy
that's about to...
Cause your expiration.
He won't be buried in that cape.
Mrs Bessolo,
RKO-Pathe would be honoured
to help you pay
for any sort of a floral tribute
that you might deem
appropriate for your son.
Since when do suicides miss twice,
lay down a rug and start over?
Is that normal? Just asking.
That cost the studio 15 grand.
You think you're worth that?
We were just...
This Farmer's Daughter picture.
What is it?
- The Mating Game.
- A $1 million investment.
You think I'm going to
let you fuck with that?
You think you're gonna be a star?
- Our concern here is...
- You're a face.
- Faces change.
- What Mr Mannix means...
He knows what I mean.
Out of my sight.
Set something up.
Him and some starlet.
Picnic, soda pop.
Already arranged.
They treat their contract
like shit, Howard.
Whatever the fuck they want.
The business is changing.
Fags and television.
And what are we, huh?
The Last of the Mohicans.
That was a UA picture, Eddie.
That spic,
wop, prick detective.
I sent Jim Engelmann over.
He used to work for us.
I'm sure you don't want
MGM coming into it.
- And?
- Louis Simo.
Two years with Rick Harris.
He shot his mouth off
about Susan Humphries
to Confidential for $5,000.
Harris fired him.
- Susan Humphries?
- Jennifer Jones type.
Under contract at Fox. Heroin addict.
- Drove off Topanga doing 90.
- You have a good memory, Eddie.
- What's the prick want?
- Money. Press. Whatever he can grab.
- What's he got?
- Some questions.
My wife won't get out of bed.
It's been almost a week,
she won't get out.
- I'll stop by and see her.
- Do that. Cheer her up.
She always liked you.
- Eddie.
- Yeah?
- You have anything to tell me?
- About what?
Anything I need to
have a story ready for.
- She's not here.
- Miss Lemmon?
- That's interesting.
- What is?
That you thought I wanted to
talk to her, since this is your house.
Is that your father?
- My husband.
- Oh, sorry.
He's a screenwriter.
Well, no one could blame you
for wanting to hang around
people your own age.
What was his name again?
Robert Condon?
I'm sure you're just friends.
Around back.
You really ought to prune these.
My husband does the gardening.
It takes his mind off his writing.
Well, what do you do,
Mrs Van Ronkel?
I don't go around
trying to get my picture in the paper.
You saw that, huh?
What are you going to do
when this blows up in your face?
There are two holes
in the bedroom floor.
What do you know about that?
- Leonore made them.
- Yeah?
- Months ago.
- Why?
I asked her to.
You asked her
to shoot a gun in the floor.
When you're drunk, everything's funny.
He shoots himself, you all wait
45 minutes to call the police.
That's unusual.
You ever been to a party where a man
goes upstairs and blows his head off?
No.
Then how do you know
what's unusual?
- So how do I find Miss Lemmon?
- She's not the way you think she is.
Yeah? What way is she?
She was only looking for love.
I just want to remember that one.
That's good.
That's nice, it's very futuristic.
- Hey, you're a detective, right?
- Yeah.
So, men hire you to find out what
their wives are up to, that sort of thing?
Yeah, they do that.
Does the truth make them happier?
Hardly ever.
You know,
he wasn't going to marry her.
Reeves?
How do you know?
Oh, she ran over here
when he told her.
I heard every word.
And how did Miss Lemmon react?
Like a longshoreman on a bender.
- Christ!
- Fuck you.
Nobody wants to hear
your mopey singing.
This is my house.
I'm tired of you treating it
like a goddamn bus station.
Woe is fucking me.
You goddamn miserable son of a bitch.
- Christ!
- Don't you walk away from me.
Shut up!
I haul myself out
to this shithole burg for you,
and you have the balls
to tell me it's off?
God damn it.
Listen, what are you doing?
- Put that...
- I'm the fucking man in this room!
- You're a fool!
- Do something, all right?
- You has-been! You sad old drunk!
- Give it to me! God damn it!
Georgie?
I had to take a leak.
What's your excuse?
This is a sealed crime scene.
Then I guess we both deserve
to get our bottoms spanked.
What's that?
Last I looked, it was $4,000
in traveller's cheques.
Georgie put it aside
for our honeymoon.
- That's off the plate now, isn't it?
- Is that why you killed him?
You think he was rich?
That Superman gig paid shit.
Oh, yeah? Well, maybe you found out
a little too late.
He was fun, knocked back the booze
like nobody's business.
Pretty good in the sack. Yeah.
Yeah?
Lady, I can nail you with this.
D'Artagnan, you couldn't nail me
with roses and a trip to Vegas.
And you're not a cop.
So what the hell are you doing
following me
into my dead fiancé's bedroom?
"And then, Mr Simo showed me
his member, Your Honour.
"And I became frightened."
You're in my way.
- I'm going to be on you, Miss Lemmon.
- Not unless you dope me first.
See how I got us in the paper?
Look at this.
Guaranteed, LAPD
is going to sweat this.
Now, the more heat they feel,
the more pressure they're under
to reopen the case.
- The police reopened the case?
- No.
They will if I keep it up.
Which requires a financial commitment
from you
so I can go on hammering.
I did get a copy of the police report.
Lots of holes.
And I'm not talking about the ones
in the floor.
Plus, something else.
Your son called the wedding off.
That's a new motive
for Miss Lemmon, okay?
- And I intend to go...
- She was never going to be his wife.
Oh, yeah? You knew that
he didn't plan on...
Do you think my own son
would get married without telling me?
And to a greedy slut like that?
All these people...
What about them?
They're sitting around
like they're so big.
I don't know who they are.
George starred with
Sinatra, with Gable.
He was an important film actor.
- Someone else can do that, you know.
- Well, now, it's a beautiful car.
Ought to keep it clean.
Why? Does this offend
your delicate sensibilities?
Yes. But you're new on the job,
so I'll let it pass.
Art got a call.
They're picking up Superman.
They're what?
Kellogg's. They bought it.
- After two years?
- That's right.
I will be on television in a month.
Wearing brown and grey underpants.
Well?
- Hooray!
- Christ.
Well, maybe it wasn't
your proudest moment.
No, I'm quite sure it wasn't.
But you did create a very likeable,
very attractive, very heroic character.
Is that right?
I'd fuck you in a second.
Well, one thing we can be sure of.
No one with a lick of sense
would watch that show.
Faster than a speeding bullet.
More powerful than a locomotive.
Able to leap tall buildings
in a single bound.
- Look!
- Up in the sky!
- It's a bird!
- It's a plane!
It's Superman!
Yes, it's Superman!
Strange visitor from another planet
who can change the course
of mighty rivers,
bend steel in his bare hands,
and who, disguised as Clark Kent,
fights a never-ending battle
for truth, justice,
and the American way!
"Homes with children.
Adventures of Superman,
"91 rating."
What does that mean?
No adults are watching?
No, they're watching
with the kids, George. Families.
Kellogg's has ordered 26 more.
They want to film in colour.
Well, I'll get to wear the blue and red.
- Maybe you ought to put that out.
- What for?
Superman doesn't smoke.
- Sir.
- Thank you.
Art, I'm coming right back.
Keep your mitts off my grub.
All right.
George Reeves?
Excuse me, Mr Zinnemann.
George Reeves will be reading
for the role of Maylon Stark.
Good morning, one and all.
Superman was on pain pills.
So he crashed his car
a couple of months back.
- Almost got killed.
- Drunk?
- There wasn't any brake fluid.
- How do you know that?
I went down to the Esso station
at the bottom of Benedict.
I said I was from the insurance
company. I spoke to a Mr Phelps.
- He was very friendly.
- Leak in the lining?
Mr Phelps couldn't find one.
Not bad, huh?
But they were still getting married,
at least then, as far as she knew.
Well, wouldn't that be why?
- Why Leonore drains his brake fluid?
- Why Mrs Mannix does.
He leaves her, right?
For this younger woman.
- She can't bear it...
- And Toni wants him dead.
Well, wouldn't that be better?
Help! Help!
They've robbed the Docville Bank!
Superman!
Stop right there!
What's that? Someone's in need.
You can't see my penis, can you?
Hey, Superman! Hey, Superman!
Well, hello there, young man,
what's your name?
Kenneth Giles. Can I shoot you?
Kenneth, why would you want
to do something like that?
So the bullet bounces off. Can I?
Well, if you did shoot me
and the bullet bounced off,
it might accidentally hit someone else.
- We don't want that to happen, do we?
- No.
Why don't you just, you and I...
Here we go, partner.
Why don't you just give me that?
Just hand me that...
One minute...
You think
I don't see what you're doing?
- I'm sorry?
- Day after day, taking pictures.
I'm just waiting for the traffic.
He leaves those where I can see them.
And then he pretends
he doesn't know what I'm talking about.
- Miss Sinclair...
- What is he paying you?
That's confidential.
He's been out of work
for seven months.
I don't know what he does all day.
He won't tell me.
Now, why don't you investigate that?
Ma'am, I'm just trying
to turn a buck here, that's all.
If there's a problem between you two,
maybe you should talk to a priest
or whatever.
Hash it out.
I can't fix your marriage, ma'am.
I don't know,
I thought you might put in a word.
- What do you suggest I say?
- He drops a hint to Zinnemann.
That's how
these things work, you know.
It was a very solid audition.
It's Harry Cohn's picture.
Eddie's at MGM.
Well, what ever happened to honour
among thieves?
Let's just save it
for something important.
Oh, I see.
This isn't important at all. Wow.
Here.
Because you've had a rough week.
Well, who needs another watch?
I just don't want some drunk finishing
what that horrid child started.
I don't know that a gun is the answer.
It would just make me feel
more comfortable knowing...
What would make me feel safe
is not prancing around in a monkey suit
in front of 8,000 screaming...
You'd be gone, George, all right?
And then what happens to me?
Mrs Mannix, please.
Who shall I say is calling?
Lawrence Farmer,
from the St. Jude's Foundation.
- To thank her for her generosity.
- One moment, please.
Mr Simo.
- Do I know you?
- No.
But I'm familiar with you.
Everybody reads the Times, huh?
I'm Howard Strickling.
I handle publicity at MGM.
How do you do?
And I'm wondering
why you would be trying
to approach Mrs Mannix
under false pretences.
Are you speaking professionally?
I'm speaking
as a friend of the Mannixs.
- Can I see Mrs Mannix?
- She's not well.
And frankly,
neither she nor her husband
appreciate being dragged
into this business.
- What business is that?
- Your business, Mr Simo.
You didn't have to go and do that.
You seem to have an inflated sense
of your importance.
They're on routine patrol.
Could you pass along a message
to Mrs Mannix?
And what would that be?
Hope to see her at the funeral.
Art! Where's the boy?
I've been hunting all over.
He's over there.
Zinnemann sure did keep us hanging
long enough.
But I knew it would pan out.
- How did you know that?
- What choice did I have?
And, Toni, thank you.
For what?
Whatever you did to help.
You know how much he needed this.
Hi, George.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Mr Weissman?
I don't want to disturb you, but I...
- You knew George?
- No.
- I'm Louis Simo. I'm a...
- I'm no speechmaker.
Saying what you really feel, it's hard.
Thank you for coming.
Mr Weissman,
I was just wondering if you...
Seeing me off the grounds again?
Mrs Mannix was unable to attend.
For reasons
I'm sure you can understand.
You do a lot for your friends.
And you're just doing your job.
But I am concerned.
- Yeah? About what?
- Your history.
People are rarely afforded the chance
to make the same mistake twice.
- Are you threatening me?
- I'm offering you an opportunity.
There's a place for you at Metro
if you'd like. The pay can be generous.
- I'd rather talk to Mrs Mannix.
- There's nothing there for you.
Yeah? Then why are you pitching me?
When it comes to publicity, what's
true or false really doesn't matter.
If it hurts the studio, if it stops
one person from buying a ticket,
I have to fix it. That's my job.
The offer's sincere.
Don't let pride stand in the way.
It won't get you what you want.
Sad day, huh, boys?
Tell you what's sadder.
Calling it suicide
when it's really murder.
Now why would the cops do that?
- Sing us a new song, Simo.
- What, you don't love me any more?
Two months ago, somebody drained
all the fluid
out of George Reeves' brake line.
Almost bought it right then.
Coincidence, right?
I mean, LAPD don't make mistakes.
Huh, Paterson?
What's the truth, huh, boys?
Who wanted him dead?
You guys might be lazy,
but nobody said you're dumb.
- Give me that.
- Name some names.
- You want me to write it for you, too?
- Hey, you got a story or not?
You want names? Ask this guy.
He's got the names.
The names, pictures.
What's he doing here when MGM
never cut Reeves a cheque in his life?
Huh? Come on,
do some work, will you?
Hey, Capa,
lift the fucking camera, will you.
There you go. Say, "Cheese."
- Excuse me.
- Hi, Bobby.
- Hi, Bobby. Good to see you.
- Thank you so much.
- Good luck.
How you doing, kid? Good to see you.
Well, buddy, they love it so far.
You got any prejudices against girls?
That's what I thought.
Well, now, it looks like
you're all primed for a big night, Tom.
- Hello, Stark.
- Want some company?
No, thanks, all tied up.
Leva tells me you've been
eyeing the Captain's wife
- like a hound dog at hunting time.
- He has, huh?
Superman.
Took up with a lot of men back there
at Fort Bliss.
Well, I wouldn't put stock
in stories like that.
This ain't no story.
Look up on the screen!
Not for long, though.
More powerful than a locomotive!
People can see you.
Faster than a speeding bullet.
Hey, where's Lois Lane?
Hello.
- I didn't think you were coming.
- Why not? I ain't late.
I'll always take care of my boy.
Nice shot, Louie.
Kit?
You listening?
Get the fuck out of my house!
Are you listening? Nod your head.
Be smart. Let it go.
What, your mother's snatch?
She won't let me.
Here's what I mean.
Louis? Louis?
Louis, can you hear me? Louis?
- I'm calling a doctor, all right?
- I don't wanna go to the doctor.
Well, at least some ice.
There's no ice in the fridge.
Stop being stubborn, all right?
You were unconscious.
There's no ice. What did you say?
There's no ice.
Sit down.
What's this about?
This murder bullshit I've been slinging.
I think it might be true.
I can help.
Oh, come on, you know I can.
Kit, let's call it a day, all right?
- What?
- You shouldn't be around me.
This isn't some TV show
you wanna be in.
This is just a fucked-up little business.
It makes you go around,
and you find out how shitty people are
to make the rent.
You don't really believe that.
I know you care about what you do.
You know what I care about?
That you're balling this Chad kid
and you don't got the guts to tell me.
Well, I was...
Going to. Yeah.
So, now you don't have to.
Do you want me here today?
No, I don't think I do.
Let's go outside.
- You packing?
- Not when I cross the street for lunch.
Lou, I do what I'm told.
You took the cash from that rag,
same as me!
$2,500 for ratting on
some hop-head actress
and I never said a word!
'Cause I'm loyal!
To my fucking partner!
- Rick.
- Why?
- Didn't say. Just, "Take care of it."
- You tell me why!
Look, when I helped you out
with the old lady,
I should've kept my mouth shut.
I had to make good.
You would have done the same thing,
don't bullshit me!
That's how the mortgage gets paid!
What?
Mr Simo.
Mr Sinclair?
You have to stop, okay, I'm not gonna...
I need your help.
Things are...
They're not what they seem.
- What are you saying?
- I've misjudged terribly.
And...
Can you meet with me, Mr Simo?
I won't bother you again.
Please.
Meet you where?
What are you doing here?
I... My client...
She was your client?
Shot her in the throat,
the heart
and then the vagina.
Mr Simo.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
I do wish you'd been prompt.
I suppose the fault is mine
for failing to see that you and
your whore were not aiding me,
but guarding the rampant fornications
of my wife.
I hope you've learnt the meaning
of justice.
Come on.
This one's easier
than your other murder.
So, what's the emergency?
Better have a drink, Art.
It's 10:30 in the morning. What?
- It's pretty bad.
- What is?
Enough, George. Let's deal with it.
We're cancelled.
I just don't see the point.
The point
is it's my production company.
If I don't sell myself, who will?
- The business is here, George.
- Yes, but the money's in New York.
I can get in the papers there.
- It's a lot of bother.
- I want to do this.
I'm looking forward to it.
I'll take charge of my own life.
- I see.
- No, you don't.
You think I should just sit around here,
doing God knows what,
- while the both of us...
- Yes?
While the both of us what?
My love, this makes sense to me.
I can set up my own projects.
Direct and produce and...
We'll get some other sap
to jump around in coloured underwear.
Who knows,
maybe I'll direct a picture for MGM.
I'll be back in two weeks.
Kiss me.
- Let me close this.
- You have to.
Kiss me.
I have to go. Toni...
- George, kiss me.
- All right.
All right.
Shit.
That bitch who hired you,
you think she loved Georgie?
- Who is this?
- He grew up without a father.
When he's old enough, she finally
tells him what happened to Daddy.
- Miss Lemmon?
- Suicide.
Pistol in the mouth. Georgie
never stopped thinking about it.
Fifteen years later, he gets a visitor.
His father, alive.
All he'd done was dump the bitch
for another woman. Left Georgie, too.
So Mommy tells baby,
"Daddy killed himself."
She tells her own son.
Georgie swore
he'd never speak to her again.
This lets you off the hook?
I didn't screw his head on backwards,
she did.
Why are you telling me now?
I'm...
I'm just a little blotto, sugar.
Kind of horny.
And pretty goddamn all alone.
- So...
- I don't know.
And I thought maybe
we had something in common.
Mrs Bessolo?
Mrs Bessolo.
Mrs Bessolo!
I won't be needing your services
any longer, Mr Simo.
- And when were you going to tell me?
- I intend to mail you a cheque.
A cheque? That's it?
I don't owe you anything else.
How about an explanation?
How about telling me your son
wouldn't give you the time of day?
Don't you use that tone with me!
- Mr Strickling gave me his word.
- Strickling?
A statue would be erected...
- A what?
- ...in my son's honour,
outside the Chinese Theatre.
You never gave a shit, did you?
You'll be paid.
Keep your goddamn cheque.
My son was a great star.
He deserves a statue.
- Can I take your picture?
- Sure.
- Wait, wait. I blinked, take another one.
- Sorry, no retakes.
My goddamn eyes were closed.
- You know who that is over there?
- Can I take your picture?
Superman.
Right. He's got to be loaded.
You know, my little cousins
are glued to that show.
Look at her ass.
Len, look.
What's really exciting to me...
Earl Wilson.
Look at you all dressed up.
I haven't seen you since...
You punched a waiter at Sardi's
and broke his nose.
I left a nice tip.
- Find something funny, junior?
- No, no, no.
- I know when I'm out of my league.
- Don't sell yourself short.
I got a big heart.
I'll bet you've got a big one, too.
That's very nice of you to say, Miss...
- Leonore Lemmon.
- Miss Lemmon.
So, how about an autograph
for my poor crippled nephew?
- Is he in an iron lung?
- He's in Yonkers.
Superman wants to get laid.
God damn!
Make room for fucking Daddy!
- You know what, stallion?
- What?
I think you're starting to
get the hang of this.
Let's do it again.
Hey, Scout.
- Mom's picking me up.
- I know that. I just wanted to...
I got you something.
I left it in the car.
I'll give it to you when we go home.
Come on. Let's go.
How come you're not at work?
'Cause I don't sit in an office, okay?
That's for suckers.
Your pop's an investigator, all right?
Come on, let's go.
I'm supposed to wait for Mom.
- What?
- I'm supposed to wait for Mom.
Your mom and me, we don't...
Evan.
Nobody has magic powers.
You got to be tough.
You got to show them
what you're made of, you know?
My father never taught me that.
Okay, here we go. Come on.
I'm fine.
I'm his son. He's my son, he is.
Tell him, Scout. Just tell him.
Evan, tell him, please. Come on.
Evan. Evan.
Honey, what's the matter?
Oh, Jesus.
- Could you take him... Just take him...
- Sure.
Whatever you want to say, you know.
Are you going to fight everybody?
I thought you liked tough guys.
- You're saying this why?
- I want to be honest with you.
My, that's noble.
What is that, from some script
you auditioned for in the '40s?
No. It's just me, talking to you.
I'm so grateful.
Straight arrow George!
You go to New York,
and you fuck some whore,
and you run back to tell me!
She's not a whore.
She's an actress. A singer?
Does she blow smoke rings
with her cunt?
Is it a fling you want?
- It's not a fling.
- Oh, you're in love!
- Two weeks in a hotel room?
- She makes me feel young.
Have you seen yourself, George?
- Your face is going.
- Don't do this.
Here, your eyes, your hair,
your stomach.
Stop it.
- You think no one notices?
- Toni, don't do this.
But you've got your projects,
haven't you?
You're going to be a director.
You'll sit in your little canvas chair,
polishing your balls.
Thank God I'm rid of that hag
I had to screw.
What was her name?
The one who paid for everything!
The one who
bought me a fucking house!
For God's sake!
You want publicity?
You'll get it. I'll say you're a Red.
And a faggot. A lush.
Nobody can call that a lie.
You know what? You've never
helped me. You never helped me!
You could've talked to Eddie.
You could've gotten me something,
but you didn't!
Because you liked me where I was,
in a fucking red suit!
You liked that! Well, that's not
who I am, you understand?
God damn you!
But, George, that's all
you were good for.
Ten-year-olds and shut-ins.
That was the best
you were ever going to be.
I knew that. Why didn't you?
They rushed it and closed the case.
I didn't like it from the start.
Why?
There was pressure.
Oh, yeah? From who?
Look, I can't do what you can do.
Understand?
I got a wife, kids, car payments.
- Look, I'm in for 20 and a pension.
- But I got nothing to lose, huh?
Look, think it through.
MGM buys off the mother.
I'm not getting paid, pal.
- That's all it's about for you.
- Hey.
I got that woman killed.
For nothing, okay?
Fifty bucks a day,
I'm stringing her husband along
like I'm running him 'cause
I can't see straight in front of me.
No. I'm done.
Look, this is how they work
and it just gets buried.
Don't you want to know about this guy?
Why don't you get on the right side
of something for once?
Where do you come off
telling me what I should do?
Well, I'm not the one
with the guilty conscience, am I?
- Who wants me to wrestle?
- Professional circuit. They're serious.
You might get a kick out of it.
What do you got, a party?
No. Just a few friends
of Leonore's making a racket.
So now when that old bitch calls,
this gizmo records it automatically.
- So at least the cops believe us.
- I got a delivery for Mr Reeves.
Hey, in there! Excuse me.
Sorry.
Put that on the table.
Georgie, why don't you show this boy
how much we love him?
All right.
Why don't we take it easy
on this batch, Len?
All right, kid, here's $100.
Go make your first million.
Georgie, you are directing
your own movie in a month.
Live a little, okay?
Or take a headache pill.
- Just don't ruin the party, okay?
- All right.
Give me a kiss. Go. Go on.
- All right, all right.
- I'll fix you a drink, all right?
Yeah?
That actor...
Eddie, it's very late.
What's he plan to do
with the rest of his life?
He has some spaceman script set up
with Wasserman.
To direct.
If you offered some kind of...
Yeah, yeah. I know how to handle it.
Well, all right.
Very nice.
Thank you. You're very kind.
What did you think,
my sweetest dream? Moved to tears?
I thought you sounded
like a goddamn beaner.
Well, and so good night.
Hey!
Universal is not the only studio.
Get him in the door someplace else.
- I already tried.
- Try harder.
He's your only client.
What kind of bullshit agent are you?
- Leonore.
- You come around here,
dragging around
like a wet goddamn dog!
Leonore, stop it!
Art, we talked about this.
This picture's important. Or it was.
These people don't want me.
They don't know what I can do.
And we got to show it to them, show
them I can do something different.
We got to cook something up
for me now.
The wrestling offer.
Does it pay?
Their only concern,
are you up to it physically?
Well, we'll...
You can film me, so they can see.
Why don't you just join
the goddamn circus?
How are you doing?
Mrs Mannix?
I'll just put it on the bed.
Mrs Mannix, can I talk to you?
It's about George.
George shot himself.
He was shot.
Someone shot him,
is that what you mean?
Who did that?
Mrs Mannix.
Can you help me understand?
Will you please help me?
Did you know George?
Why don't you tell me about him?
He really was the most beautiful boy.
Mrs Mannix, please,
if I could just come in.
You're not invited, Simo.
- Were you?
- We're working.
Come on.
Why don't you lay off?
- Mr Harris.
- Hello, Louis.
You come up from Palos Verdes
just to see me?
I came here
to celebrate my friends' anniversary.
- You've met Mr Mannix.
- No, but we got people in common.
Ain't that right, Eddie?
I've got nothing in common with you.
Bernice, the first missus.
You like that car crash gimmick, huh?
- Rick...
- Riva Watson.
She get all clingy?
How'd it feel, pounding her face in?
- Happy times, huh, Ed?
- Richard, please.
- George Reeves...
- That's enough, Louis.
Am I being indiscreet?
Bad for business, huh?
- Louis, your problems are your own.
- Ricky, you cover for this prick?
Whatever you're pursuing here.
Whatever fantasy...
You had a bullet put in Reeves' head!
...you constructed
will not alter your past.
He used the studio and the cops...
You're going to burn in hell,
you son of a bitch!
Come here.
You don't know me.
You don't know what I think. What I do.
I don't let you.
You're an old man, Eddie.
Who's going to wipe the blood
off your hands?
My hands?
I'm in the picture business.
No, you're a murderer.
Prove it.
You hear me? Go on, I'm ready.
Prove one fucking thing.
Oh, God.
People are waiting. You coming down?
- Help with the dress.
- Yeah.
Okay?
I'm gonna let some light in.
I want to tell you something.
You know I'll always take care of you.
Whatever's happened...
Whatever might have been done.
It doesn't matter.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Nobody gets to ask. I won't allow it.
You're safe with me.
With your husband.
Let me see what you look like.
You're beautiful.
You always will be.
I see the pieces.
How they should fit.
How I want them to fit.
But I can't.
I looked in his face.
I know he could do it.
Wouldn't think about it twice.
- Eddie Mannix?
- Yeah.
No, I would never say
it wasn't possible.
What about Mrs Mannix?
You had to like her. Such brightness.
Could she have done
what you're saying?
I don't want to think that.
And Leonore?
We never got along. Leave it there.
Mr Reeves?
A charming man.
Funny. Handsome.
Not like the ones today.
All the squinting and the mumbling.
A movie-star face.
Why wasn't he one?
Where he wound up,
it should have been enough, right?
Enough for a life.
But George...
Yeah?
I never showed this.
I knew it wouldn't help.
You watch it.
Tell me what you see.
Good night.