Little kitty...
You don't like Mama-san anymore?
Come out now.
I'll get you something to eat.
Come out...
Come...
Come, come...
...come, come...
You filthy dog!
You're going to starve
tonight...
You run again, I kill you!
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out, let me out.
Money...
Money... money...
Money, money, money...
Easy money...
You go beers...
Two hour, come gas...
Now that I've been released
and I am your new princess,
you will work five days a week
and in the weekend,
we throw a festival.
And everybody will get cake
and cookies and bread,
and all the kids will be awarded
with special magic toys...
You can go down to the cafe
to eat.
Barbara will keep an eye on you.
If you try to escape again,
I'll go back to your mommy
and take your little sister.
You understand?
I need money for food.
You start working,
you'll have money.
Here, you can come with us.
- How's it going?
- Fine.
- Did he pay for this?
- No.
Take out the trash,
change the sheets,
and get the foreigner
some towels.
Me no Cambodia.
Me Vietnam.
Village, all people... Vietnam.
Sinjao, Patrick.
Now, I eat soup, okay?
$30, she yum yum you.
No boom boom. She's too young.
You no like, you no pay.
- Two girl, $50.
- I best...
I yum yum very good.
I no money today,
Mama-san boxing me.
Bitch!
Look at her.
She just makes fun of you.
Where did you go?
I was just driving the moto...
You are not allowed to go
out of the village!
I bad person last life...
this life punish...
I good this life...
next life, I princess.
Have many shoes...
I no can.
I no luck...
I come speak you.
I want you buy me.
I no want other man buy me.
You buy me better.
We go village Vietnam.
We take Holly sister.
Mama no sell sister like Holly.
Get up, filthy dog!
You wanna die?
Moron...
You go take speedboat...
Phnom Penh.
Yes... no?
Don't look there.
I no Khmer!
Little girl!
Come here!
I never saw you here before.
Where are you from?
Good?
Phnom Penh... no bus.
I drive.
Two minutes, okay?
Come on.
Yeah, yeah...
Later... Later.
Hundred dollars.
She's Vietnamese.
She's got no one.
Hundred and fifty.
She is very young... pretty...
Two hundred!
Crazy girl... run to field...
No, no!
He's a foreigner.
The police will investigate.
No need to fix her up.
She's a virgin.
Virgin?
You're sure?
Go get your mama-san!
What is this?
I heard you have a new girl...
little girl.
She's not little.
She's eighteen.
You tell them to wait here,
and I'll take you up to see,
okay?
She's Vietnamese.
She's much too young.
This is not good.
Don't worry.
We keep her up here.
For special clients only.
She's very young.
You make $600 a week
on a girl like that, no?
Oh, no.
Less. Much less.
So, you paid $200 to my guy.
I want $300,
and we get to treat
our special guest
from the Vietnamese government.
See... I'm fair.
What's your name?
(Vietnamese)
So, the kid runs to his mommy
and goes,
"Mommy, Mommy, the baby chicken
is eating all my worms."
So, the mommy goes,
"It's okay, son.
Let him have some.
I'm just finishing up
eating his mother."
Eat...
It's good...
Ma angry me. Ma kill you!
I trouble. You trouble.
I no go!
Subtitles by LeapinLar