Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
See...
...man ain't like a dog.
And when I say "man,"
I'm talking about man
as in mankind, not man as in men.
Because men,
well, we a lot like a dog.
You know, we like to piss on things.
Sniff a bitch when we can.
Even get a little pink hard-on
the way they do.
We territorial as shit, you know,
we gonna protect our own.
But man...
...he know about death.
Got him a sense of history.
Got religion.
See...
...a dog...
Man, a dog don't know shit
about no birthdays or Christmas
or Easter bunny, none of that shit.
And one day
God gonna come calling,
so, you know,
they going through life carefree.
But people like you and me, man,
we always guessing.
Wondering, "What if?"
You know what I mean?
So when you say to me,
"Hey, I don't think
we should be doing this,"
I gotta say, baby, I don't think
we need to be doing this neither,
but we ain't gonna get no move on
in this world, lying around in the sun,
licking our ass all day.
I mean, we man.
I mean, you a woman and all,
but we man.
So with this said...
...you tell me what it is
you wanna do with your life.
I don't know.
- I mean, I guess I could, like...
- Hold up a second.
What's happening with you, man?
You like what you see, huh?
Look here, baby,
it break down like this:
Twenty in the front, 40 in the back.
Hello?
Why don't you walk over there
and explain it to that motherfucker.
- Damn.
- From the D&Z sports desk,
I'm Dennis Phillippi, and the answer...
- Hot 107. 1, number one for hip-hop...
- Nothing but a bunch of jive and junk.
Coming up, your chance
to win a trip to Las Vegas.
Holler at your boy, it's Hot 107. 1.
- Please! Fucking with me, man! Hey!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, what the hell?!
- Pull that shit again,
- Motherfucker, how you like that?
Boot your ass to hell.
- You heard me!
- Get the fuck up out of here.
Deranged son of a bitch!
- You all right, Nola?
- Thanks, D.
Come on in, man. Come on in here.
Damn, man, you gotta
get some security up in here.
I'm the only
motherfucking security in here.
Sure is good
not to be cracking heads.
So, what you need, man,
a half or full O?
Ounce will do good.
Fourth coming up and all.
Righteous, man.
Hey, you remember
that sticky herb you brung up
to my brother's house for playoffs?
Yeah, I remember that shit.
That ain't this, now, man.
We talking about... That's
a whole other zip-up bag on that.
That's fucking prime product
right there.
We got some big company
coming in here for the Fourth.
Thought you may want
to get you some money.
- Big company?
- Yeah.
- Like what?
- You know Skinny Black?
Skinny Black.
Yeah, that...
Yeah, I know who Skinny is, man.
I know Skinny from
way back in the day.
See, I know Skinny
when he was hustling
his underground tapes
down at the drive-in,
out the back of his Cutlass.
Not no more he ain't.
Last one he put out went platinum.
- Platinum?
- Yeah.
- That's more special than gold, right?
- But he's still in Memphis.
He and his brother Tigga hook up with
their friends every Fourth of July.
I shut the place down,
make it all private for them.
And they just buy me out.
- Bullshit.
- No shit.
Yo, Skinny rolling like that, man?
Best get your ass up here
with that good shit.
Those boys don't want
none of this dirt weed.
So you're trying
to hurt my feelings, right?
- Just trying to help out a friend.
- For sure, man.
All right, all right, all right,
goddamn it,
we're going into a 2-for-1
for all you balling motherfuckers.
You gonna love this shit.
These lovely ladies will be doing
two dances for the price of one.
We got Luscious, we got Phoebe
and we got Lexus
coming up to satellite one.
- Mike.
- What up, D?
- What's happening, baby?
- Wet out there, huh?
Yeah, sorry, man.
- It's like a motherfucker.
- All right.
Hey, baby.
- Hey, where Lex at?
- Over there on satellite one.
Don't miss out. Take advantage.
We got Monique coming up
on satellite one.
- You'll love this, 2-for-1.
- What the fuck? Will you let me...
These lovely ladies will be giving you
two dances for the price of one.
- Come here. Excuse me, daddy.
- Don't you see me on a hustle?
- Where you at?
- I ain't at shit.
- I was on my third dance.
- Don't tell me...
You think I can just run up in here,
snap my fingers
and make these motherfuckers
throw their money at me?
- Watch your motherfucking tone...
- I ain't even made payout yet!
This one is pretty good.
My motherfucking house
got broken into too, bitch.
- Hell, no.
- Hell, yeah, they kicked
both my doors in, girl. Stole the last
pound of hydro weed for the party.
You hear that?
That's my gut saying,
"Hurry the fuck up," okay?
- Come on.
- Look at this.
Hell, no. Look at this shit. What
the fuck you call that, the clapper?
Lights on, lights off. Don't play.
I'm gonna roll tonight.
I don't care what you say, D,
I ain't working day shift no more.
I don't care if I got to
take me a taxi ride home.
- You gonna work if I say you gonna.
- I ain't working with these skank-ass,
- trucker-bait ho's no more.
- Kiss my ass.
- Bitch, fucking take my shit again.
- Shit don't make no sense.
If I'd known y'all was gonna take your
sweet fucking time, I'd have come in.
Trudy says she made $500
last night, $500, you heard me?
- Bitch got that birthmark on her face?
- Five hundred dollars
for dancing for some man
who makes cotton.
- What she do for him? She tricking.
- It ain't fair.
I'm tricking! I ain't making $500.
- What the hell, fool?!
- Hey!
- D. Djay.
- Get your ass away from our car.
- What the fuck's wrong with you?
- Hey, D!
- It's only me, it's Harold.
- Get the fuck away from my car!
- It's me, Harold, Djay.
- Get away from my car, man.
- It's your dog.
- You're lucky as shit,
that's normally my barrels
under my fucking seat, motherfucker.
- It's Djay, nigga!
- Okay, Djay, I didn't mean no harm.
You got any of
that crankity-crank shit?
Nigga, I'm gateway mother... Man,
don't waste my time on no bullshit.
Wait, wait, wait. Check this out.
Check this out.
What can I get for this?
You think I look like
a pawnshop, man?
Is that...? I got "pawnshop"
written on my forehead?
Come on, Djay, fuck with me.
- Fuck with me, Djay.
- Where you get it?
You know the business.
- You took that shit from little kids?
- No, none of that, man.
I used to play this thing myself,
all the time.
- That shit work?
- Man, like a pro!
Let me see that motherfucker, man.
Yeah, man, I used to have
one of these when I was a little kid.
- Shit wasn't as big, though.
- But that's bigger and better.
Fuck with me, now, D.
- Fuck with me, Djay!
- Shut the fuck up, man.
- Nigga, I'll give you a quarter for it.
- A quarter?
Man, you mean a half and some. I can
get more than that at the pawnshop.
Take that shit to the pawnshop,
let's see what you get.
No, take it over there, man.
Give them your thumbprint.
- You on. You got it, you got it.
- Hey, give me that bag, man.
Shit.
You the man. You got it going on.
It's all good.
Nigga, you advertising my shit
right now.
It's okay, I'm gonna
fuck with you anyhow. It's all good.
You fucking with me already.
Hey, Stevie Wonder!
We hungry.
Motherfucking Carl Lewis
or something.
I called the power company about
getting an extension on the light bill.
They say I gotta come down there,
stand in line.
I can't be standing in line
how they do down there,
not if I got Roger with me.
You know, D?
Man, it's Skinny goddamn Black,
you know...
Hey! There goes Skinny Black, man.
Hey, Lex. Lex, come here, baby!
Look right there, look at that.
That is Skinny Black, man.
Me and him gonna be kicking it over
at Arnel's club on the Fourth of July.
- Ain't that some shit, huh?
- Who, you?
Yeah, me and Skinny gonna do us
some little catching up.
So am I supposed to piss myself
or something?
Okay, let's see who it is
that you know is somebody, huh?
Nobody in this here crib,
that's for damn sure.
- Where my baby, Roger, at?
- No, no, Lex, please!
I just put him to sleep, Lex!
Skinny used to DJ over at Booker T.
The same way I did at Westwood.
D, I know it's my job and all...
Ain't like he the only nigga
can spit flow.
- But why she gotta wake Roger up?
Ain't like he the only nigga
can spit some flow.
D, I need time for me too,
now.
Shit, I was just doing the same thing,
just over at my school.
Ask anybody, man. Go ask Carlos
on the corner, he'd tell you.
He was in my grade. Ask him.
We gotta get that extension, D.
Fuck. Paper money. Shit.
See, now, back in the day
you wouldn't even catch me
in this Bentley right here,
you'd catch me in a Crown Vic.
Bitch. Shit, back in the day,
- I was triple platinum. Ask anyone.
- D.
- I think I'll take a shower. Here.
- I don't give a fuck, man.
- I need you to watch Roger for me.
- Hey, give him to Shug!
Shug say it's her chill time.
Come on.
When is my chill time?
Come on, man. Hey. Hey.
Hey, man. No, no, man.
The bitch gotta go take a shower, man.
You relax your ass, man.
Come here. Come here, man.
Hey, man, you can't be
crying around like no bitch, man.
Hey. Hey, get rid
of them tears, man.
No. Cut them tears shit out, man.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, come on. Here we go.
Here we go, man.
Come on, come on.
Let me try something.
All right, push that one.
Do that. What is this right here?
Hey, I like that, man. Do that again.
Listen to that, man.
Now, that shit buck, ain't it, man?
Do it again, man.
What the fuck you doing
with my boy?
- Come on, give him to me.
- We just playing.
- Give him to me.
- Come on...
- He don't need to be playing.
- That's what I'm talking about.
Every time he gets settled,
you gotta come fuck with him!
I'm telling you, you gonna
give that little boy a twitch!
Better go easy, girl.
Man can't be no open candy store.
We tight this whole week.
Put your shine on, man.
I hear this one coming.
What's happening with you, man?
Don't act scared, man,
she don't bite.
She just nibbles a little bit.
Come on... Hey, hey. Damn.
Why can't I work the motels
anymore, D? At least they got air.
At least they take a cut
is what they do.
Thirty dollars an hour
on top of what we already charging,
for what, a five-minute nut?
Taking money out of my pocket
trying to keep
your little country ass cool.
God, D, all I did was ask about a motel
and you get so ugly with me.
- He's coming back.
- I'm all wet and sticky.
You gonna have to put a show on
for this one.
Do that little shit you do
with your tongue.
Now, come on, he's coming back.
Get your mind right, okay?
Come on, come on,
come on, come on. Fuck.
Fuck, man!
How come Lex gets to work
out of that strip club, and I can't?
Because we done been over this
ten times, Nola.
You got what they call
a bad equilibrium.
And it ain't your fault,
you just knock into shit.
I put you on that stage
in them heels,
tricks gonna be yelling, "Timber."
I'm in heels out here every day.
You don't see me fall down once...
Because you sitting, Nola.
Ain't that much of a fall to the floor.
Lookit, why don't you just let me do
the thinking for you, okay?
You do what you do,
and you let me do what I do.
One day, you'll have to tell me
about that.
About what?
What the fuck it is you do.
What did you just say to me?
Hi, honey.
Wanna see me walk in these heels
all the way to your lap?
I'll be right there.
Looks like he got air in his car, D.
Must be working hard as you.
Fuck you doing, man?
Doing my job? I got a mop for you.
Elroy, I'm having me a day
that won't quit,
so I'll need you to shed
just a little light on me, okay?
You got something for me?
Yeah. I got a grocery list for you too.
I need a...
A brick of that Big Easy bud.
What the fuck is this, man?
Got your stank all over this.
I don't even like my own sweat, D.
What the fuck is this?
Okay. Let's do it this way, then.
Let's give it some
of my sweet juices on it...
...and tell me you ain't
gonna take that.
You better watch yourself, D.
Let me get you on your way.
You cool yet?
You still into that shit, man?
I remember Coach Rosallis
used to let you flow
over the intercom in gym class,
back when we used to beatbox
like the Fat Boys, remember that?
Dude, man,
we went to East Middle together.
Clyde. Called me Key.
- Nigga, what's up, man?
- How you feeling, man?
Yeah, you used to spin them
little records at the after-school joints.
Yeah, yeah. It's not like I was
scratching or nothing like that.
I just made sure "Purple Rain"
got played for the ladies, that's all.
- Let me get these batteries, man.
- "Purple Rain."
Hey, give over, man. He cool. He cool.
East Middle, man.
Them was the days, man.
- Yeah, man.
- Them was the days.
I see you still doing the same.
Oh, yeah, you know,
like the post office:
- Through rain, sleet or snow.
- You looking good, though, man.
So, what, you got you
a dildo or something?
A do-what?
I mean, what's all the batteries for?
It ain't for no dildo,
I'll tell you that right now.
- I'm just fucking with you, man.
- Okay, okay.
They for my microphones, man.
- Microphones?
- Yeah.
So, what do you do?
I told Jesus
It would be all right
If he changed my name
I told Jesus
It would be all right
If he changed my name
I told Jesus
It would be all right
If he changed
My name
- Jesus told me
- Jesus
That the world would be against me
- If he changed
- Changed my
My
Name
Hey, Shug. Shug.
Wake up.
What, I gotta watch the baby?
No, everybody asleep.
- So he kicking now, huh?
- Usually after I eat.
He real active
during the day, though.
He must get that after his daddy.
He sure don't get that from me.
Whoever that is, huh?
You know, Shug,
you and me, we got history, right?
I mean, you been tricking for me
for a few now, so we got that, right?
And me not pimping you
because of...
...your demonstration,
it just puts us in a whole...
...different kind of place,
you know what I mean?
You want me to leave.
Hell, no.
Why would you say
something like that?
I just feel like...
Like I'm having one of them
midlife crisis, you know?
I mean, my daddy...
...you know, his heart
gave out on him when he was, like...
Well, shit, when I was 12 years old.
Shit, he was my age.
And that shit just been...
Just been fucking
with my mind, you know?
It got me feeling
like this is it for me.
I just don't know what
I'm supposed... Supposed to do.
I get bad dreams.
Dreams like me giving birth
to dead dogs.
Sometimes I'm breast-feeding
a big old ugly catfish.
- For real?
- Yeah.
But that's just my mind
touching in on something
I ain't said yet.
What's that?
I'm scared, D.
Sometimes I just get so scared...
Most gracious and heavenly Father,
we pray that you
bless this food and this house
in Jesus' name. Amen.
Amen.
So Beth Ann tells me
the reason I didn't
get that sales-supervisor position
is because she says I have issues
enforcing company policy
with my coworkers,
who, by the way,
she referred to as my friends.
Not "coworkers," mind you,
but "friends."
And I said to her,
"Hey, just because I am pleasant
and supportive does not mean
that I cannot crack a whip."
Because, you know,
I can crack a whip.
Yeah, you can, baby.
Because what we talking about here,
huh? Folding some sweaters?
Shoot, sales supervisors
don't even handle the safe.
So I go in and I talk to Leonard.
Because he always talking about,
"Come in and air your grievances,"
right? So I did.
- What did he say?
- You know what he says to me?
He says I am incapable of writing
somebody up because I'm so friendly.
And I said,
"Hey, give me a pen, Leonard, okay?
I'll tell you everything
that everybody's doing wrong."
What, Beth Ann, she take
way too long on her lunch break.
Alan, that little shit down in Receiving
came to work the other day high.
And Sally, just yesterday, came in with
this skirt with the discontinued line.
Remember that, baby?
Remember that little skirt I had?
And I know she didn't pay for it.
He think I'm gonna take some kind of
blind eye to all of these violations
if I was sales supervisor
just because I'm nice?
Clyde?
- Damn.
- What the hell you doing here, Djay?
Hey, look here, baby. I know you about
sick and tired of seeing me right now,
- but I just wanted to be able...
- Clyde. Who is it?
- It's just...
- Just an old school buddy, ma'am.
- From back in the day.
- Well, we was just having dinner.
I'm so sorry, y'all. And I'd have
left them in the car,
but this one right here, man,
she just
sniff out an air-conditioning unit
like an old bloodhound bitch.
Hey. Hey, man, respect my house.
Look, man, anyplace you and me
could just sit down
and talk for a minute?
Djay, things don't always
come together
just because you want them to,
all right, man?
Look, just because you got the bacon,
the lettuce and tomato,
hell, man, that don't mean
I'm gonna give you my toast.
Look, man, I know you done learned
a whole mess of shit
hustling out on the street, right?
Let me tell you what I learned
while working on my job.
- Thank you.
- There are two types of people:
Those that talk the talk
and those that walk the walk.
People who walk the walk,
they sometimes talk the talk.
But most of the time, they don't
talk at all, because they walking.
Now, people who talk the talk,
when it comes time for them to walk,
- you wanna know what they do?
- What is that?
They talk people like me
into walking for them.
Look, I'm just asking you...
Just listen to what I got here,
man, all right? Just listen to it.
And if you ain't... If you ain't feeling it,
man, I'm out your life, okay?
So can I get y'all anything?
No, ma'am.
Hey, I really like your hair.
It's got some, like,
chocolate colors in it.
Oh, thank you.
I have this great guy that does it
over in Germantown,
the coloring.
- That sound all right.
- The whole time it's gonna have
this thing going like:
- Then I come in...
- When you gonna start a rhyme?
Just gotta get my mode on, man,
just give me a second. All right.
These bitches pop it for some paper
Pop that ass for some cash flow
Do it like I like it
And I give you what you ask for
I try and do my hair
every couple of months
because it keeps the tricks guessing.
- You know?
- I'm sorry, keep the what?
Well, my hair has to be redone a lot
because these ain't me real braids,
these just extensions.
Nola, would you just
shut the fuck up, please?
What makes you think this lady
care about your kitchen-ass hairdo?
I think, you know what, it's nice.
It's okay...
Lady, you don't got to be nice to her
because she's sitting on your couch.
You think her hair look like a wet
dust mop, go on and tell her so. I do.
- Damn, Lex.
- Well, I didn't. I mean, I don't.
Lex, why you gotta be so ugly?
Get a nigga minx
Grab her by the hand
Take her back for some convo
Drop a couple grams
Now you're back at the condo
- Ugly as a swamp-duck ho.
- God!
Everybody else
says my hair looks sexy.
And then they nut.
Clyde?
Real fast
Shake it, shake it real fast
Put your hands on your knees
- What's up, nigga, you run out of spit?
- No, man, I just...
Clyde!
What are you doing?
Walking.
I see you're down with that next nigga
Tryin' to make your chest bigger
See you're down with that next nigga
Working on your flex
Figure what? Nigga, fuck that shit
Let's get this to work, Djay.
The roadblock
Got niggas jumpin' up
Tryin' to move the rock
It's like all my days, I've been
hearing this beat in my head, man,
like a pounding.
I mean, sometimes it's real raw,
like a eightball joint, but then
sometimes, man, it get real soft,
like Otis Redding and shit, man.
And this beat, this pounding, man,
that's what I been calling my mode,
this feeling. And, Key, if my mode
is cracking, man,
it's like I can't be stopped, man.
It's like I'm Mike, and it's showtime.
Nigga, it's on, you know what I mean?
You know?
Because, shit, when I'm out here
on this track,
I gotta keep my game tight, man.
Because it's hard out here
for a pimp, man. For real, man.
Hold on, I like that, man.
"It's hard out here for a pimp."
Hot 107. 1. Big up to South Memphis
out there, checking in.
I got your requests, and I got
that coming up for you.
Keep your radios locked.
This is messing with my mode.
This is a bunch of bullshit, man.
This is all I got
So I keeps it hot
How I'm supposed to not?
Read your post to plot
"Read your post to plot."
Baby, this is some hard shit
right here.
Trying to take what's
in your head, man,
and put it into words that fit together
like a puzzle.
So, you know...
I wish there was something
I could do.
You know, just...
Shit, baby, you my whole operation.
You might be what they call a...
Like, a primary investor, you know?
Making this shit happen
one trick at a time.
- Hey, Nola.
- What?
Remember when I first met you?
Right where I found you at?
Remember, you was at the truck stop?
Smallest little lot lizard I'd ever seen,
tricking them truckers for change.
But you had balls, man.
Big gorilla balls.
I got love for you, Nola.
Big love.
And I ain't talking about a way a man
love a woman or nothing like that.
I'm talking about like a brother.
Hey, do me a favor.
I want you to put your hands
right here. Both of them.
Now, I'm gonna put
my hands here too.
Know what this means?
What?
It means we in charge.
It means we got our hands
on the wheel. We in charge.
Not them tricks out there, man.
We in charge.
I wanna hear you say it...
...so I can believe in you
the same way you believe in me.
We in charge.
That's the best you can do?
Say it like you mean it.
We in charge.
You said you was all right with this.
It's what you wanna hear, right?
So let's just drop it.
No, Yevette.
I wanna hear what you really think.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
You say that,
but I know you wanna hear what you
want, so that's what I'm gonna say.
I'm sick and tired of people telling me
what I'm thinking,
like I don't know my
own goddamned mind.
Don't you dare take that tone
with me, Clyde, okay?
- I have supported you in everything...
- We already discussed this!
All right, fine! I'm thrilled!
Okay? Thrilled.
What woman wouldn't want
her husband spending all his time
in a house full of ho's?
What's all this shit again?
Drink holders.
Poor man's soundproofing.
So you ain't so dumb, huh?
- D?
- What?
There's someone at the door for you.
Well, shit, baby, you know my rates.
- I don't think he want no weed.
- Then wake Nola's ass up.
- I don't think he want that either.
- Shit, man.
We have to come up with some
fucking rules in this house!
- Well, if you just tell me not to
- I wanna put a red light bulb up there
- answer the door, that's fine with me.
- To say I'm working.
- It ain't for me!
- Every time I'm fucking working,
y'all come and bothering me.
Hey, man.
You Mormons is some
brave motherfuckers.
No, I'm Shelby.
Okay, you Shelby.
All right, look.
Hey, turntable's set up,
and the mixer that D got
has room for four inputs.
- Cool. You got a power strip?
- Oh, we tight.
How many outlets you need?
- Three. I brought my MPC.
- Smart move.
Hey, Key.
Let me holler at you
for a second, man.
- What's up, man?
- Who the fuck is this nigga, man?
That's Shelby. He play piano
down in my church.
You know, I figure we bring him in,
help him develop our sound.
You know he white, right?
No, he just light-skinned.
Yo, peep. I got this shit right here
that...
I keep this notepad
so that I can just jot down some shit.
It's something...
Get the fuck out of here, man.
It go like this, man.
Y'all sure y'all don't wanna, like,
burn one first, man?
No, man. We can toke up later.
Let's hear what you got.
Fine, man. I got...
Okay.
I bet you won't beat that bitch
Whoop that bitch
Got me acting buck and shit
Ho's telling me to calm down
But I'm like, "Fuck that shit"
I'm already on that Hpnotiq
And that Grey Goose
A couple of shots of Hen
That just gave me a...
What the fuck wrong?
You don't like that shit?
- No, D, look.
- I got other shit, man.
- No, look... It's okay, man.
- I think that's tight.
It's just that we want radio play, right?
You got a song called
"Beat That Bitch,"
they might hear that
and think that's degrading.
But that's if you're calling
a woman a bitch.
This sounds like a
tearing-the-club-up song.
Man, I ain't trying to call no ho
no bitch.
Yeah, I mean, besides,
most of the bitches I know are guys.
Look, man, y'all preaching to the choir,
all right?
If you had to say something different,
other than "beat that bitch,"
what would you say?
I don't know. Shit. Stuff like...
"Stomp that ho."
- Who gonna play that?
- Fuck.
- Shit, "whoop that trick."
- No, no, no.
- Go back.
- What?
- "Whoop that trick."
- That's it.
- Like what?
- Like a chant, man.
- Whoop that trick
- Whoop that trick?
Get 'em
Whoop that trick
Oh, shit, man, yeah.
Get 'em
Whoop that trick
Come on, Shel, find it, man. Find it.
Speed it up. Speed it up.
There you go.
I like that clap.
Not bad to be light-skinned, huh?
- Whoop that trick
- Get 'em
- Go!
I'ma make these suckers
Recognize I ain't playin', ho
If you violate off the top
Trick, you gotta go
I done held in a lot of shit
And I'm 'bout to flip
Now I think it's time to show
You bitches who you fuckin' with
Djay, that's the name
And I came to bring the pain
Ana on my chest got me
Bustin' at you lemon lames
You ain't know
You fuckin' with a street nigga
From the gutter
Pimp-type/drug dealer
Born and raised in the M
Memphis, Tennessee
Before it's said and done
You bitches gonna remember me
It's only the beginning
I got a lot to say
It's been a long time
And you got hell to pay
Ain't no love, ho
Just bring it to the door
I bar none let my nuts
Hang to the floor
So if you want some
This is your death wish
Better come correct
Because I came to break you off, bitch
- Whoop that trick
- Get 'em
Whoop that trick
- Whoop that trick
- Get 'em
Whoop that trick
Okay, let's go smoke that joint.
It's nice to have company, huh?
Thank you.
See, the thing is...
And I believe this, man... . Rap is
coming back home to the South.
- Yeah, man.
- Because this, man...
This is where it all began.
Heavy percussion, repetitive hooks,
sexually suggestive lyrics.
Man, it's all blues, brother.
"Back Door Man" to
"Back That Ass Up."
It's all about pain and...
And pussy.
Sorry, baby. And making music, man.
With simple tools,
by any means necessary.
You've got to get what you got to say
out because you got to.
Every man, you know
what I'm saying?
Every man has the right,
the goddamn right...
...to contribute a verse.
- Number one for hip-hop. This
your man Boogaloo in the house.
North Memphis,
throw your thumbs up.
South Memphis,
let's get ready to kick it.
I got this hot joint from my man,
Al Kapone.
"Get Crunk, Get Buck." It's hot.
- Do you just do music?
- Hey, man.
Do you got, like, a regular kind of job,
a day job?
Yeah, I got a job.
I restock vending machines.
- Really?
- Yeah, you know,
soda, candy, microwave popcorn.
All that shit.
- That's cool.
- No, it's not cool.
- Why?
- Because
I gotta get up every day
at the crack
and head out to all the truck stops
on the interstate
before I head to the high schools.
Yeah, I'm alone all day,
and I smell like...
Like sticky buns and Skittles.
I thought my job sucked, but...
Hey, man.
So this Skinny Black shit, that's real?
Look, man, because even if he
does listen to what we got, man,
we still don't know what he gonna do,
you know what I mean?
It's a one-in-a-million shot, D.
If I can pimp $20 ho's out the back
of this motherfucking Chevy,
I can pimp Skinny.
Nigga, you just get me
where I gotta be at.
I'm telling you, this dog got him
some tricks, man.
- You mean "old dog," right?
- I didn't mean it like that, man.
My wife, man, she a...
She a good woman.
She feeds me.
She get freaky on my birthday.
- What she do?
- None of your business.
But sometimes I feel, man, like...
Like I talked such a good game
when we was young, man,
about my own studio
and my own label that...
Shit, Djay,
now I'm just paying rent, man.
This shit right here, it gotta work.
It gotta work, man,
because it ain't over for me.
I am so sick and tired of you trying
to tell me what to do with my boy.
That's my son! You go on and
have your little baby, then you can do
- whatever you want!
- Lex, stop yelling.
My pussy paid for this.
I should be mad.
Lookie, lookie, who just decided
to waltz on in.
Where the hell you been at, Djay?
You know, I been standing outside
three hours.
Finally just went on ahead,
took myself a taxi ride.
Spent up all my little monies.
So I really hope you ain't expecting
shit from me today!
- Right back to your toys.
- You should go.
You know what, Djay?
You ain't never gonna be nothing more
than what you is right now,
and that's my motherfucking
chauffeur.
I make the money up in here.
Know what? Matter of fact,
I think I feel like
making me some money right now.
Feel like popping my pussy,
maybe shaking my ass.
Go on, boy. Go on, get my car for me.
You heard me. Go on, now, little bitch.
- What the fuck you just say to me?
- That's right, keep...
- What the fuck you call me?
- Called you a motherfucking bitch!
Now, do something about it, damn it!
Do something!
You and me...
...we done, okay?
We done.
You know what?
We been done.
And there you go,
running off to your little toys.
Because you ain't nothing
but a little punk-ass bitch!
- Lex, please back off.
- Just shut the fuck up!
Wasted five years of my damn life
working in this piece-of-shit hole.
So, what now? That's my shit!
What, you just gonna
throw my stuff out?
Oh, out the door! Hey, Djay!
You just leave my shit alone!
I paid for that...
No! No! No!
- I paid for this shit!
- Fuck! Come here.
- Now!
- Djay, no!
- Get the fuck off me! Get off me!
- No! No! Djay, no!
Talk now!
- Hey. Hey, come here.
- No, please, D.
Let go. Let go.
Come on. Come on.
Where in the fuck do you
expect me to go?
You can go to hell, all I give a fuck.
Y'all make him pay!
All right, man.
This is what I got so far.
Man, it seems like I'm duckin'
Dodgin' bullets every day
Niggas hatin' on me
'Cause I got ho's on the blade
But I gotta stay paid
Gotta stay above water
Couldn't keep up with my ho's
That's when shit got harder
North Memphis, where I'm from
I'm Seventh Street bound
Where niggas all the time
End up lost and never found
These gals take me through things
Leave a big headache
I'm hopin' every night
They don't end up being dead weight
Hold on. Hold on, one second.
My bad.
Baby.
Look, I'm in a session right now,
all right?
- What time you coming home?
- I can't give you that time.
If I give it to you,
you're gonna hold me to that.
- I don't see why you can't give a time.
- Because I'm not gonna do it.
L... Look...
If you just let me talk, I can be able
to tell you that I can't do it...
Because I said so, that's why!
You ready to work, lover-boy?
Hey, Shelby,
bring that beat back, man.
From the top.
You know what? Just kill it.
Fuck, man.
I got this flow I need to spit.
Look, look, Djay.
Now, we gonna have to make
a choice, man.
Either we just gonna lay down
some freestyle freefall,
or we gonna lay down a track.
You know, something that's gonna
get us some radio play.
I thought that's what we was doing
right here.
No, no, no. What we doing
is a whole bunch of flow.
That's all we doing.
And it just go on and on and on.
Man, the shit don't ever stop.
Yeah, D, what he's saying is that
we ain't got a hook.
Well, shit, give it some hook, then!
I mean, fuck, you the producer, man.
You just tell me what
you want me to do, then.
We need to lay down something,
Djay. Anything. Even if it's shit.
And I keep telling you, I ain't putting
no shit on top of no shit, man.
I ain't trying to sell no cash shit here.
Well, that's the wonder of audiotape,
Djay. We can just record over shit.
Go on, bring it back up, Shel.
- Go on, bring it up!
- You need some ass, nigga?
- What?
- Because I got a room full of pussy
right in there for you.
- Fuck you, Djay.
- Oh, fuck me?
- Yeah, fuck you.
- No, no, fuck Yevette, man.
Because she the one got your ass
wound up like a motherfucking clock.
Look here, you dirt-rascal pimp,
you keep my wife's name out
your mouth, you hear me?
- Hey, guys, come on, keep it light.
- Sound like your wife,
she the one need to put something
in her motherfucking mouth.
- You know what I'm saying?
- Fuck you say, man?
- You heard me, nigga!
- What the fuck you say, man?
- That's what!
- Stop it, man! Sit down!
- What?! What?!
- What's up, man?!
Can you please stop it?
Do we have to do this?
Can't we just smoke a joint,
for chrissake?!
- Who is it?
- It's me, Shug.
- Look, bitch, we working right now!
- I got something for you.
Come on, man.
Sorry to interrupt y'all's
recording session,
but they had this interview
with Skinny Black on TV
and look like he had one of these
in his studio where he uses,
so I thought I'd go out
and buy you one.
Y'all have fun.
That's a bottom bitch for you.
I mean, we got everything we need
right here.
And all this stuff in this...
This little-bitty space, man,
it just looks so much bigger now.
I'm here trying to squeeze a dollar
out of a dime,
and I ain't even got a cent, man.
It takes time, Djay.
Do y'all believe in omens?
Okay, Shug, put your headphones on.
- Move closer to the mike.
- Okay.
Can you hear yourself?
- Say something.
- Hello. Oh, yeah.
Okay, Shug,
what we need right now
is called a "hook."
That's like the chorus of the song.
Now, you're gonna be singing
what's on Djay's pad. Djay.
All right, now.
"You know it's hard out here
for a pimp
when trying to get the money
for the rent.
With the Cadillacs
and gas money spent,
got a whole lot of bitches
jumping ship."
"Jumping ship." Okay.
Now, Shug, I got an idea
how this should go.
Now, I suck,
but, I'm gonna sing it with you
until you get it down, all right?
Okay.
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When you tryin' to get the money
For the rent
With the Cadillac
And gas money spent
Will cause a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
- Okay, sing with me.
- Can I have that? Okay.
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When you tryin' to get the money
For the rent
With the Cadillac
And gas money spent
Will cause a whole lot of
- Bitches jumpin' ship
- Jumping ship.
- That's right. Okay?
- Okay.
No, hold on, hold on.
Nola, kill them fans.
Okay, here we go.
Okay.
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
Shug, I'm gonna need you
to sing out, okay, baby?
- Okay.
- Shug.
Feel that.
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When you tryin' to get this money
For the rent
With the...
Can I say "for"?
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
Will cause a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
Will have a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
Push that shit out.
Come on.
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
Will cause a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
Will have a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
That's it right there.
That's the money take.
- You got that?
- Hold on, we gonna see in a minute.
Hey, D, I wanna do one.
I wanna put one down.
No. Hush up, Nola.
- You got that, or don't you?
- Hold on, hold on, hold on.
We got something. We need to work.
Y'all need to leave the studio right now.
- Did I fuck up?
- You didn't fuck up. Just go.
Hey, Shelby, close the door.
We need to work.
This is my motherfucking house, man.
Ain't that some shit?
Come on, fuck all that, man.
You're on, dog.
All right, D.
We about to lay you down now, man.
That means we got
a fixed length, right?
So that means don't say no more
than what you got on that pad.
- I got you, man.
- Nola, kill the fan.
Hold on, hold on.
Shelby, you hear that?
Yeah. What is that?
- One of y'all leave the TV on?
- No.
Goddamn.
This day is really starting to fuck
with my mode, man.
Hey, man, R.L. Over here?
R.L., look, man, I'm sorry
to disturb you and all.
And I know you and me,
we done had words in the past and
some of them weren't too friendly.
But right now, man, I got some shit
taking place in my crib
that just requires a little bit of
silence. You know what I mean?
Now, I'd never demand of you,
I can only request...
...with a gesture of neighborly
friendliness, you know what I mean,
that you please, please consider
the mute button just for a spell, man.
All right, man.
- Stand by, everybody.
- Standing by.
I'm standing by.
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
Will cause a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
Will have a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
With my eyes, I done seen
Some crazy things in the street
Got a couple ho's working
On the changes for me
But I gotta keep my game tight
Like Kobe on game night
Like taking from a ho don't know
No better, I know that ain't right
Done seen people killed
Done seen people deal
Done seen people live in poverty
With no meals
It's fucked up where I live
But this is how it is
It might be new to you
But it's been like this for years
It's blood, sweat and tears
When it come down to this shit
I'm trying to get rich 'fore
I leave up out this bitch
I'm trying to have things
But it's hard for a pimp
But I'm prayin' and I'm hopin'
To God I don't slip, yeah
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
You ain't know, nigga
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
You ain't know, nigga
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
You ain't know, nigga
Will cause a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
You ain't know, nigga
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
You ain't know, nigga
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
You ain't know, nigga
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
You ain't know, nigga
Will have a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
You ain't know, nigga
Man, it seems like I'm duckin'
Dodgin' bullets every day
Niggas hatin' on me
'Cause I got ho's on the tray
But I gotta stay paid
Gotta stay above water
Couldn't keep up with my ho's
That's when shit got harder
North Memphis, where I'm from
I'm Seventh Street bound
Where niggas all the time
End up lost and never found
Man, these girls take me
Through things
Leave a big headache
I'm hoping every night
They don't end up being dead weight
I got a snow bunny
And a black girl too
You pay the right price
And they'll both do you
That's the way the game goes
Gotta keep it strictly pimpin'
Gotta have my hustle tight
Makin' change off these women, yeah
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
You ain't know, nigga
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
You ain't know, nigga
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
You ain't know, nigga
Will cause a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
You ain't know, nigga
You know it's hard out here
For a pimp
You ain't know, nigga
When he tryin' to get this money
For the rent
You ain't know, nigga
For the Cadillacs
And gas money spent
You ain't know, nigga
Will have a whole lot of bitches
Jumpin' ship
- Cut it. Cut it.
- What?
Wait, man.
I got another verse, man!
Djay, we need to talk, man.
Look, I just want it to be perfect.
And this mike,
it ain't shit.
What the fuck wrong with it?
That shit record, don't it?
Djay, the mikes we using, they got
a wider pattern, D. They go flat.
So when you start screaming,
man, they just distort and pop out.
Man, nigga, I don't know shit
about none of that shit!
All I know is that shit
in there was live, man!
And every time I get
my motherfucking mode up,
- you come and fuck with it!
- It ain't me.
That shit, it ain't gonna
be live like that again.
I don't give a fuck what mike I'm on!
Djay, that shit was live in there,
but it was also distorted, man.
God!
I just don't understand why
I gotta pay so much more money
for that microphone right there
when the one right next to it
look just like it but cost half, man.
Let's do it this way, man.
If I buy two of them, say you give
them to me both for $90.
This is studio quality. It costs $250.
Now, why would I sell you
two of them for $90 apiece?
Just because of that statement, man,
"The customer's always right,"
ain't you heard?
Not in this case, sir, no.
If you want quality,
you have to pay for it.
Look, man, can't you cut me some
type of break on this stuff here?
What was that?
- What?
- I mean, what you looking at, man?
- Nothing.
- Don't worry, Sparky, man.
I ain't gonna pop or nothing like that.
Look here, man.
The thing is, that gal over there, right?
I got it in real good with her.
I mean, she's my gal and all,
but she don't necessarily
belong to me.
You see, a gal like that, man,
she the type of girl that wanna
shut them doors, lock them,
see what type of specials
you got going on in the back.
And me, I'm the kind of man that
just walk out of here and
leave a girl like that behind
because, like I say, she with me
and all, but she don't belong to me.
Not necessarily.
And maybe when she leaves...
...she can take something that don't
necessarily belong to her neither.
It's like you say, man, you want
quality, you got to pay for that.
Hey, gal.
I need that microphone.
Okay.
I need you to go back there
and be friendly with him
and bring that microphone
out with you, okay?
No. No way.
Nola, I need that microphone.
Get it.
Y'all be good, now.
Hey.
- Don't ever do that to me again, D.
- What? I ain't...
No, I ain't some fucking cash machine,
where you can get shit for free.
Ain't like you was
in there sweating bullets.
- I gotta have a say in what I do!
- You was in there for a minute.
- Look, man, I was gonna give...
I'm not gonna suck dick
every time you come up short!
You got something for me.
- Do you got something for me?!
- Fuck you, D.
- Here, take it! You earned it!
- What the fuck's wrong with you?
This is expensive motherfucking...
Hey, Nola, bring your ass...
- I'm fucking out of here. I don't care.
- Nola! Don't you do this shit right now!
Nola! Bring your ass here, man!
Don't you ever walk away from me!
We do what the fuck
we gotta do, man! By any means!
Ain't that right?
We take care of our shit.
You think I like this shit?
You think I wanna
spend the rest of my life
pimping your pimpled country ass?
Well, not me! I fucking hate you.
I hate this shit!
D!
Do you know what I do
in the back of them cars?
Do you?
Everybody's got something to do!
Everybody's got something important
going on in their life but me, D!
And I want something!
- What do you want?
- I don't really know, but I want some...
- I don't know.
- Tell me what the fuck you wanna do!
- Not this, D!
You know what, man?
I just got you dressed all wrong.
You know, bitch like you, man,
you need to have on
one of them suits.
Get you a mobile phone and shit.
Get an ear jack.
Man, you gonna feel different.
I'm gonna put you in some
new shoes tomorrow, man.
And you gonna feel
- like you are in charge.
- D!
I know when you're messing
with my head.
Because I let you.
Because sometimes my head
needs to be messed with.
But right now, just don't.
Okay?
Okay.
Hey, Shelby,
I need some high-hat, man.
Give me some high-hat
up top, all right?
Okay, man. This takes a little time.
Look, it should come in right
after the kick. Right there.
Yeah, that's it.
- Try that bit.
- Keep hustlin'
- Keep flowin'
- How that sound?
Tell her to put some more dick in it!
- Most gracious and heavenly Father,
- Okay.
We ask that you bless this food...
...and our home.
- Hi.
- Hey.
My name is Yevette.
I'm Clyde's... I mean, Key's wife.
Oh, yeah. He in the back
with the rest of the fellas.
They fitting to cut something.
Cut?
Well, I like that first one, but you don't.
Well, I think you should
throw out your best ball.
And to me, that's the second one.
Okay. We gonna gab, or we gonna
do the damn thing? Which one?
- Hey, let's beat that bitch, then, man.
- Hey, everybody.
This here's Yevette, Key's wife.
And look, she brought
everybody sandwiches.
Yeah, yeah. There's...
There's some dill sauce there
in the middle if y'all wanna dip.
If you want.
Hey, you know...
...Key worked really hard
on this last one there,
so you might wanna
just take a little listen to it.
Oh, no. I don't wanna interrupt. I...
- It's just dinnertime. I thought y'all...
- But I think we'd like for you to stay.
Right, Key?
Yeah.
Okay.
Look, this track here, man, this...
This is my heart, man, so...
Before I do my thing,
put my mouth to this mike,
I wanna bless it with a kiss
from my primary investor, all right?
Come on, baby.
Go on, girl.
Hey, just like our primary investor,
that mike is hot.
So kill them fans.
Look, this is my life
And it's a battle within
I gotta survive
Even if I'm sinnin' to win
And if I show no remorse
I'll reap the devil's reward
He said he'd give me riches
But I'm lookin' for more
When I was young
Witnessed my dad standin' for right
Black pride in him
Even though he passin' for white
Took years from my life
Now I'm missin' the man
Mom's on some other shit
And now I'm missin' the plan
So I'm stuck
In this fuck-the-world mold
All the lessons
To a young teen nigga was cold
Then my pimpin' ass uncle
Put me up on the game
It really ain't no love
It's 'bout this paper, man
Put me in a position
Got me out on a mission
Collectin' from the ho's
Turned me on about pimpin'
A nigga from Memphis
Dealin' with life as a struggle
This is the gift I was given
So I just live by my hustle
Keep hustlin'
It ain't over for me
No, it ain't over for me
Keep flowin'
Flowin'
I'ma step my game up
And get what's coming to me
Keep hustlin'
It ain't over for me
No, it ain't over for me
Keep flowin'
Keep on flowin'
I'ma step my game up
And get what's coming to me
We got to get this shit done
by the Fourth of July, man,
because I got some people
I gotta slip this to.
- Who do you know?
- You remember Skinny Black.
I think I see a hater right there.
Hold up.
Hey, there go Skinny Black, man!
- "Skinny Black" Skinny Black?
- Yeah, I know who Skinny Black is.
I've got all of his early stuff,
back when he was still good.
Now, do you really know him,
or just know of him?
I mean, he may not know me, because
we went to different schools and all.
We went to different schools and all,
but, yeah, I know Skinny.
But I'm here to let you know
you ain't taking shit,
because I'm running
this goddamn thing!
You wanna make a dollar? Best get
your ass up here with that good shit.
Those boys don't want
dirt weed.
Me and him gonna be kicking it over
at Arnel's club on the Fourth of July.
If I can pimp $20 ho's out the back
of this fucked-up Chevy,
I can pimp Skinny.
Now I'm just gettin' by
And it's fuckin' with me
See others doin' big things
They was nothin' to me
I'm seeing what I used to be
And it's lookin' legit
Got my hands on some music
Started fuckin' with it
Put it down hard
Then I started pumpin' to this
I let some others get a dose
And they was nuttin' to this
Let me check my connections
'Cause we go back in the day
Say they was lookin' for 'dro
Heard I was hustlin' hay
Got me connin' my niggas
Spittin' game to my ho's
This my opportunity
I feel like anything goes
I was never supposed to see
The new millennium, man
And I refuse
To let my dad die in vain
So I give it my all
You feel my struggle and pain
If you ain't feelin' what I'm spittin'
Trick, you lame to the game
But the closest ones to me
Know I'm holdin' it down
You gonna feel me one day
We gonna be hurtin' the town
Keep hustlin'
It ain't over for me
No, it ain't over for me
Keep flowin'
I'ma step my game up
And get what's coming to me
Keep hustlin'
Keep on hustlin'
It ain't over for me
No, it ain't over for me
Keep flowin'
Keep on flowin'
I'ma step my game up
And get what's coming to me
Thank you.
Ain't you gonna be hot in your coat?
No, this is good leather, man.
The kind that keep you
at the temperature you wanna be at,
know what I mean?
See this thing right here?
This was my daddy's watch.
He used to work
for the school district and all...
...fixing them buses all over town.
Yeah.
Every now and then, when I see
them buses go by today,
I get all excited
because I say,
"My daddy used to work
on that," you know?
But, you know, after he'd been
there maybe about ten years or so,
gave him this and...
Kind of thought about burying
him with it, but then again I said,
"Maybe not, maybe I should keep it
as an heirloom," know what I mean?
- I got you something.
- What?
Well, it's like, you know, I been
watching them videos and all.
And it be like all them rappers,
they got some chain.
So...
Oh, shit.
Yeah.
You always talking about your name
being right and everything,
so I thought people
could see how you like it spelled out.
You know, with the J-A-Y.
Damn.
- This shit is perfect, man.
- Let me put it on.
- I wanna see it.
- Okay.
- D.
- What?
I can't believe...
I get like this
because I'm pregnant and everything...
...but, you know,
letting me sing on the...
On the demo and everything
like you do...
...well, it just...
It made me feel real...
Real special.
And...
I mean, I know y'all gonna
be moving on and moving up...
...and y'all are gonna get
real good people to sing,
you know, backup for you
and everything...
...but I just...
D, I need you to know
it meant the world to me.
Come here.
Thank you so much, D.
Djay, come on, man,
you gotta be there at 9:00, right?
Calm your ass down, man.
He gonna be there all night.
I ain't scared.
I know.
- Come on, man.
- Wow, check it out.
Okay, look here. Djay, I put some
extra demos in the car, all right, man?
In case they have
some label folk there.
Hey, if they want CDs, they just
gonna have to hit us back on that.
Man, I like that.
I need to get one of those.
D.
- You all right, man?
- You got your mode on, D?
Hold up for a second.
Came to party tonight.
What's happening with you, man?
Where your boy at?
Over at the big table.
- I don't see him, man.
- I'll take you over. You ready?
Hey, let's get a drink first, man.
All right, what the hell.
- Hey, I see you packing tonight, huh?
- Do a bear shit in the woods?
Hey, who the fuck is that?
Hey, who the fuck is that, man?
Oh, man, I can't believe what my
goddamn eyes are seeing right now!
I'm gonna have
to get a Seeing Eye nigga
just to tell me what the fuck
I'm looking at, man!
Is it? Could it be?
The one, the goddamn only...
Skinny!
- Is that you?
- Slobs!
- Boy, you fat, black and nasty,
- My nigga.
- Greasy ham-hock, chicken-eating,
- You Ethiopian poster boy.
- Can't-see-your-own-dick,
- Middle Eastern stepchild.
Ass-crack-longer-than-the-
M-l-S-S-l-S-S-l-P-P-I,
fat, black, nasty bastard!
- What's going on?
- Come here, nigga!
- How's my nigga?
- Back in the day, nigga.
- Yeah, that was it.
- Back in the day.
Back in the motherfucking day.
Bring your ass over here, man.
Let me get you a drink.
A drink in your hand
and some pussy in your lap.
Hey, I need that!
You ready to go over?
Hold... Hold up, man.
Hey, man.
Skinny, I think
you know my man Djay.
- Man, I don't know this nigga, man.
- Hey, baby, it's been a long time.
No, it's cool, man. It's nice
to see you home again.
Got all these folks telling me
I been gone too long.
Like I'm coming back or something.
Like there's a back to get back to.
I say, fuck!
Best place to keep Memphis
is in my rear-view,
you know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying,
whoever the fuck you is?
You know what I'm saying?
Hey, man, what's up
with your boy, man?
- Skinny.
- I don't need this shit.
This is the man
I was telling you about.
- Oh, this here the man?
- This here Djay.
- You and me, we went to different...
- Djay like short-for-something DJ,
or you mean like... that type of DJ?
- No, man. It's just... It's just Djay.
- Man, every time I come to Memphis,
my folks hooking me up with this
old dirt-ass weed out here, man.
Like they grow it out the ass
of some redneck or something.
But my boy Arnel here
say you slinging that killer.
Is that real, or what?
Baby, you be the judge for that.
How much I owe you for this, man?
Here now, seeing how friendly
you are to me
and the fact we go back in the day,
it's on me, okay?
Well, go on ahead and have a seat,
my blood brother.
Hell, yeah. Check this out here.
Smell that. Damn, boy.
Boy, he wasn't playing around
with this here! I think I'm in love.
You remember way back in the day
when you used to be hustling
your tapes over at the drive-in, man?
- What?
- Look at that ass, boy!
God bless America in this
motherfucker! What's going on, baby?
It's Independence Day!
It is Independence Day, right?
You know, I got that up from...
There's this little dude brought that
up from New Orleans, man.
Me first! Me first!
Hey, Skinny!
What the fuck
happened to you, man?
What the fuck did you just say?
I don't mean no disrespect and all.
I just remember when your first
underground crunk
hit the motherfucking streets, man,
that shit flew through Memphis
like a motherfucking typhoon.
Y'all was there, man.
Nigga couldn't even walk halfway
down the block without the pavement
crumbling underneath his feet
because some cat was bumping
your shit
out the back of his Caddy, man.
We just miss you, Skinny, that's all.
Miss me? Get up, bitch.
Hold up. Hold up. Hold up.
- Miss me? Nigga, I don't even...
- Fuck this nigga, man.
So wait, wait, wait, wait.
You trying to say
I can't cut it no more?
Like I ain't the shit?
That's what you trying to tell me?
- I ain't saying nothing like that.
- Then what the fuck is you saying?
What is you saying, then?
Dig this right here, man.
One day, this whole motherfucking
place is gonna be gone.
This club, this city, man.
This whole U.S. Of A., man,
is just gonna turn to dust, right?
And a whole new civilization
is gonna rise from this one.
And they gonna start digging,
you know.
They gonna dig up
the pyramids over in Egypt.
They gonna dig up the Eiffel Tower,
Statue of Liberty and the Empire State.
But if a nigga
wanna know about me?
Wanna know about Memphis?
All they gotta do is find your
first underground tape, nigga.
North Third Thugs. Motherfuck it,
man. That was the shit.
You know, I cut that shit in my
own mama's laundry room, man.
Boy, it was raw as hell,
but I put everything I had
into that shit, man.
Yeah, but see, to me that was a sign
of your genius, you know?
See, because it's not enough
for a man to climb Mount Everest.
You know, he gotta do that shit
with the least amount of tools.
- It's about the man. One man.
- One man and his skills.
Like the samurai say, "The sword is
only as powerful as its master."
And it ain't the size
of the dog in the fight, it's the size
- of the fight in the dog, nigga.
- Of the fight in the dog.
- My nigga.
- My nigga. Shit.
You know, and I know
a nigga like you, man,
a man gotta do
what a man gotta do, right?
You know, sometimes a nigga
gotta surround himself
with a whole bunch
of motherfuckers
that think they got a say
in who the fuck Skinny Black is.
Yeah, they pimping me.
I ain't gonna lie about that.
Gotta break bread with all these
number-crunching motherfuckers,
man. It ain't like it used to be.
Hey, baby, you ain't gotta explain
a damn thing to me, man.
Because I'm always
gonna be here for you.
Same way we was here for you
way back in the day.
- Oh, man.
- He got a cassette tape.
- Remember that?
- This nigga tripping, man.
Man, look at this shit!
Tigga, Slobs, you see what this nigga
got, man? My underground, man.
Where the fuck you get this from?
I ain't even got no more of these left!
Skinny, you got thousands of those
left in you.
All you gotta do is just come back
home, man. Because we miss you.
Come home, man.
You stand behind your product, nigga?
Is a pig's pussy pork?
I had this Mustang, right?
Motherfucking tight-ass ride!
You hear me?
Hood snout.
- What the fuck is a hood snout?
- Maple dash.
It's the goddamn hood come up,
like that from the sides,
- like a fucking nose.
- Okay.
- Hood snout, maple dash.
- Shit.
You know what I mean?
Two-tone metallic monster
- motherfucker, you know?
- I hear you.
So I go to my lady's crib
over there in The Courts, right?
- You had one in The Courts?
- I had one in The Courts.
- I had a few of them in The Courts.
So, look, man, I go up in there, right?
I get my ugly on real quick,
come out, my ride is gone!
You hear me?
- Gone in 60 seconds?
- Gone in 60...
And I nut pretty damn fast,
so them niggas must've
took my ride like that! You hear me?
So I call up my crew. I call my crew
up, I'm like, "Come pick me up."
Because I know there's only one place
them niggas going riding in my car.
That's motherfucking
Millbranch, man.
Millbranch. Millbranch, right?
So we go down to Millbranch,
and we wait.
And sure enough, just like I said,
not even an hour go by,
and these niggas
coming in my ride, right?
So we roll up in front. We box them in.
Next thing you know,
20 motherfuckers
come rushing at these niggas,
pulling them out of my car.
I'm just screaming
like a little bitch, like,
"Don't touch my car!
Don't touch my car!"
Tripping, man. I can sit back
and laugh about it now,
but goddamn it, it wasn't funny then.
You hear me? At all.
You know, I'm sitting here
listening to you, man.
And you ain't bragging and shit,
man, you just telling me how it is
being on the side of the moon
that you see from.
And I realize a nigga like me ain't...
I ain't but a slice of cheese
off your motherfucking cracker, man.
- Right.
- You know...
...but I got this thing right here.
My motherfucking heart
beats in this thing, man.
Fuck I'm gonna do
with a cassette tape, man?
See, that's my blood pumped
in this shit, man.
Dog, do you know it's
a new millennium, nigga?
I can't do nothing
with no cassette tape.
I don't even have
a cassette-tape player.
- What the fuck is this shit here?
- I ain't trying to play you.
I appreciate the fact you talking
to me man-to-man like this and shit.
Hell, treating me like an equal, man.
And the only reason I give you
that right there is because...
...you know, you and me,
we come from the same place,
- you know what I mean?
- Right. That's the truth, man.
- Hell, we old friends, man.
- Definitely. Definitely old friends, man.
And I'm gonna tell you something.
I miss you, Jay.
- Man, it's Djay, man!
- Djay.
- Djay, man!
- Djay, my bad, nigga.
- My bad. Djay, Djay.
- Djay.
You know, in real life, man,
you know, if you give me a shot...
...you know, just...
Just give me a chance
to get my voice heard, man,
you know, I wouldn't...
I think I wouldn't even have words
for that shit, man.
Let me tell you something, man.
Look here.
- Got something I wanna tell you.
- Shit, he getting up.
- Don't get up.
- Listen to me, this is important.
Now, this is serious. Look at me.
Look at me, man.
- Okay, man.
- You laughing, this shit ain't funny.
- I'm serious, now.
- Okay, I'm with you.
Everybody gotta have a dream, boy.
Everybody got to have a dream.
You hear me?
I hear you, man.
- You know what I'm talking about?
- Don't make... Don't fall, man!
I can't help you, man.
Where the bathroom at?
Nigga, over there, man. Go get it.
Hey.
Hey, hey, man.
You better help your nigga, man.
Thank you.
- I didn't think it was going in.
- How'd it go?
Played it like a pro, man.
My mode is just...
Just pounding in my head now.
I mean, and it's...
It's hard in my heart right now.
All that boy gotta do is just
play the damn thing,
and it's gonna be undeniable, man.
Undeniable, baby.
I think you gonna have to get your
weed from some other hustler, man.
You're on your way.
Hey...
...I got something for you.
Thank you for everything, man.
Let me get my jacket, man.
I'm gonna take me a piss,
and I'm gonna roll, baby.
You take care of yourself.
I will. Next time you see me, man,
I'm gonna be 100 feet tall, man.
Talking all this...
Shit, I can't...
Nigga talking to me.
I don't care about that shit, man.
Hey, Skinny, man.
You need to take a piss?
Hey, baby, let's try this shit
standing up.
Come on, man. Come on.
- Now, don't try...
- Come on. Big motherfucker.
Nigga talking to me
about his bullshit.
Nigga, I'm talking to you, man.
I'm talking to you, dog. You need
a little help, okay? Stay with me here.
I'm gonna pull your pants up, nigga.
I ain't no faggot or nothing.
You know, shit, ain't too many men
pull a nigga's dick up for him. Shit.
You better show me some love
for this one, man.
You know, one day...
One day, you and me
gonna be on tour, man.
- I ain't gonna do this shit for you.
- Tour?
- What tour you taking about?
- Shit, man.
Man, you know, a fucked-up nigga
would do some wild shit
to you right now.
Hey, hey, hey. Come on, man.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on, baby.
Let's get the fuck up...
Hey, Skinny, man.
You tell me this shit
just fell out your pocket, man.
Skinny?
Hey, bitch.
You tell me this shit fell out
your pocket, man.
- Hey, hey, hey, man.
- Hey, what, man?
You know what you could do?
What can I do, man?
You tell me what I can do, man.
You can suck my dick, bitch.
Hey, bitch, why don't you
suck on this shit? Motherfucker!
This what the fuck you want, man?
Oh, shit.
Oh, God.
Oh, Skinny, man.
Hey. Hey, nigga.
Hey, Skinny! Hey, Skinny,
wake the fuck up, man!
Skinny, come on, man!
Come on, man. Come on, nigga.
Breathe, you motherfucker!
Hey, yo, Skin...
What the...?!
Shit!
Get the fuck up! Get your ass up!
Get your ass up, motherfucker!
- Oh, shit!
- Hey, motherfuckers,
I'm coming out now!
If I see any gleam, motherfuckers,
I'm gonna shoot this motherfucker
in his head!
- Shoot this nigga!
- Get him!
- Fuck off, bitch!
Hey, niggas, back the fuck up!
- Not tonight, nigga! Not tonight!
- Shoot him! Shoot him!
There he is!
There that motherfucker go!
- Right there!
- Away from the door.
Hey, man, I ain't armed.
It's in the glove.
- It's in the glove, man.
- Djay! Djay!
Hey, wait, man! Hey, Shug, it's okay.
Hey, wait!
- Hey, get off my foot, man.
- Djay!
Hey lay off my foot, man!
- Fuck you, man! Hey, man!
- Get down on the car!
- Hey, get them off my girl!
- Hey, get your hands off her!
Hey, man!
- Fuck!
- What the fuck's up now, nigga?
- Bust his motherfucking head, man.
- Nigga, come on, come on.
Djay, please, what did you do?
Hey, man! Come on, man!
He turned himself in, man!
You ain't gotta dog-pile
on him like that!
Hey, yo, she pregnant, man!
Don't forget, man,
you knock this motherfucker out.
He's gonna have to come around here.
Djay, tell me what to do, please.
Please tell me what to do.
Baby, take my pad.
I want you to get that shit up
on the radio.
You put it in the DJ's hand
yourself, you hear me?
- Okay, I will.
- Get him up.
I got a stack of demos
right there in the car.
I want you to get Key and them...
Key, y'all put my shit on CD!
All right, man!
Nola, you in charge and shit,
all right?
In two weeks, I wanna hear my shit
in the yard at 2:01, you hear me?
- Get him!
- Motherfucker!
- Bitch!
- Don't hit him like that!
Get him! Bitch!
D!
I wanna hear my shit in the yard,
you hear me.
You in charge.
I wanna hear you say that.
- Say it!
- I'm in charge.
- You my partner.
- I know.
- Say, "I'm in charge!"
- I'm in charge!
- All right, man.
- Get in the car.
Watch your head.
I'm in charge.
Me. I promise.
Go get down in the yard.
I tried calling the house, you know...
...but the phone's just...
- They shut them off.
But me and Yevette, we...
We chipping in.
Thank you.
She precious, man.
Beautiful little girl.
- Named her Keisha.
- Keisha.
That's a good handle, man.
I like that.
You know, with all I gotta do...
...all these people in my life, man...
...feels like an eternity in here.
Can't seem to find my mode now.
Don't hear a damn thing.
Djay...
...did you know Skinny Black
before that night?
You know that
little girl Keisha, right?
One day she gonna dream big,
the way kids do, you know.
And she gonna come to me
and ask me
when she grow up,
can she become president?
Now, I know that little girl got a ho
for a mama and a trick for a daddy,
that nobody even know where he at.
But I tell you something.
I'm gonna look her right in the eye...
...and I'm gonna lie.
Because sometimes
that's what you gotta do.
How you been doing, man?
Back to the same old shit.
About six months ago,
my neighbor brought my mail.
It was mail that she'd gotten
from her neighbor.
It was addressed to me.
The court depositions
and the high school recitals.
Talk about eternity, man.
It's been on my mind too.
It's on all our minds.
We was just dead, Djay.
Locked up, just like you.
But ain't no sorrow gonna
take away Shug's song.
Let me tell you that.
That woman, she got love for you.
So when you talk about eternity...
...you think about your woman.
- Hey, how's Nola, man?
- Nola?
Let me tell you something, man.
That girl got a mode all her own.
She hit the bricks running.
For some reason, she got it stuck
in her head that she was in charge.
We can't lay around licking our ass
all day like a dog, you know?
I mean, we man.
I mean, I know I'm a girl and all,
but we mankind.
Man, she hit every shake joint,
radio station in Memphis
and then some.
I don't know how she did it.
That girl got skills.
Power 107. 1.
Number one for hip-hop.
This your man Boogaloo
holding you down.
Man, I got a brand-new exclusive
from my man Djay.
Straight from the north, north, north.
Put your thumbs up out there, man.
And I hear my man Djay...
Djay, you gotta call me,
let me know if it's true.
Did you slap Skinny Black?
Did you do it, man?
Holler at me, man.
Power 107. 1.
Brand-new, right here.
Hey, man, this is me!
I made this beat!
Whoop that trick
So if you don't mind,
Nola and I, we got a few points
we'd like to talk about
in regards to your agenda.
That's if you got a minute.
For you, Key...
...I got 11 months.
Hey, Al, hold up, hold up.
Ain't this the guy on the radio with
that "Whoop That Trick" song?
- What you talking about?
- Man, this the cat
who stomped on Skinny
with that "Whoop That Trick" song.
You know that song.
- Whoop that trick, get 'em
Whoop that trick
Get 'em
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Oh, shit, that's you?
Yeah, man.
Look, man.
- We in the rap game too.
- Yeah, you know what I'm saying?
We got it going on both sides
of the law, being from the streets
and being officers of the law.
You know what I'm saying?
Our stage name, Five-0.
They call me Big Five-0.
Look, man,
when you get a chance in
the rec room or something like that,
check out our demo
and tell us what you think.
Well, you know what they say.
Everybody gotta have a dream.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/3fccv
Help other users to choose the best subtitles