If to plan in the to univer exists,
if the prevails
by life patron,
podria to be discovered,
hidden and mysterious,
in those harvested lives
of blow.
Or we lived by accident
and we died by accident,
or we lived segun a plan
and we died segun a plan.
The day of the funeral,
Lima was in state
of critical moment.
They gathered as they could
the rest of the victims,
and as they could
they separated them.
It was a great funeral.
All deepened
in its hearts
by the grace of God.
Why it happened to them
to them five
Why not to my '
Friday, the best bridge
of the Peru rompio
precipitating to five travellers
to the abyss in its caida.
All we,
as soon as we found out,
persignamos us
and we remembered
that the habiamos crossed
recently
and that soon ibamos
to cross it again.
We lived in pais,
in a place
in that catastrofes,
peculiarly calls
"acts of God",
they are frequent.
The tidal waves devastate
whole cities.
Every week
there is an earthquake.
The diseases go
from a province to another one.
The oldness takes
to our better citizens.
The towers fall habitually
on good citizens.
But to all we
it has made an impression to us
and it has affected to us
the caida one of the bridge
of San Luis Rey.
The BRIDGE OF SAN LUlS REY
It seemed that the bridge would last
for always.
He was unthinkable
that it was broken.
All we have seen ourselves
falling in that abyss.
Ten minutes despues,
i myself…
Habria be I.
For that reason I decided to investigate
in the secret life
of the five people
that they fell.
Yasí to discover the reason
by that they went.
During 6 years, I called
to all the doors of Lima.
I made hundreds of questions,
I catalogued thousands of facts,
anecdotes and testimonies
with the greater precision.
As it is known,
the result is this book
whose I title is so heretico
like traicionero its content.
They are not but that done.
He is not so sinister.
The facts of five lives
tragicamente harvested.
We will never know
its true passion.
You vanagloriais
of to have investigated
but minimo detail
of its lives.
But, it is possible
that not hayais seen the source
that it nourishes the well
With your permission,
it limits to detail to me
these precious pictures.
I began in the reading room
of San Martín
with a bound book
with great wood covers.
There I found the only copy
of letters
of the Marquise of Montemayor
to its daughter Doña Clara.
You escribire often.
Every day, love mio.
And if my daughter has a little while…
You will take six months
in receiving answer
of Espana.
Single in Lima,
the life of the Marquise
she became solitary.
Its love needed the love
of its distant daughter.
It lived for the interminable stories
on its eccentricities
in its letters to Spain.
You do not worry yourself, love.
I will send
to Its Catholic Majesty
the best gold chain.
It will not know that to obtain it,
I had to enter a picture.
It remembers that in San Martín
there is a picture of Vela'zquez.
It is the virrey
that it founded the monastery
with its wife and son.
Its wife
she takes a gold chain.
I have decided that it will only serve
that chain.
The beautiful woman but of Espana
she wishes to offer
the best chain
that it can be
to the courteous sovereign but
of the world.
My mother,
the Marquise of Montemayor,
insistio in which occurred it
to Your Majesty.
For the ceremony of the baptism
of the lnfante.
A perfect gold chain.
It is it, Majesty.
I enter a picture of Velazquez
in order to take control of her.
I must know the Marquise.
lnvitadla to the Court.
Quiza we pass the evening
in a Tiziano.
We cannot bring it to the Court.
Not you inquieteis, love,
this fixing.
It can that becomes one
of the great women of the Peru.
Its indiscretions
they can bring problems to us.
We have interyielded three times
in order to separate lnquisicion.
Its Excellence returns
to have drop.
I say "returns" because
the flatterers insist
in which not always he has.
Since today he is San Marcos,
he went to the University
where they waited for 22 to him
new doctors.
They took to him
of they divan to the chair,
where encendio
a delicious cigarette,
and while escuchabamos
its long speech
but or less in Latin,
I ask for vos
but or less in espanol.
Always with the same humor
due to the drop.
And well…
It knows to defend itself
against the information
of lnquisicion,
it does not seem to you
Dear Marquise,
lnquisicion has denounced to you
three times.
But for the influence
of its son-in-law,
they already habrian to you burned
in the bonfire.
Pasadme the maps of Of Blasiis.
Dedicated
to the countess of Abuirre,
daughter of the Marquise
of Montemayor.
All the city admires it,
it is the rising sun of the West.
My dear Marquise,
despues to support the race
of this cartografo,
your daughter has gained
the reputation
of being the intelligent woman but
of the espanola Court.
As it is possible
that of its mother,
the daughter
of an astute fabric merchant,
the wife
of a ruined mentecato nobleman,
as she can be
that of the foolish utero of resemblance
sabiduria is born so much
Teneis my permission
in order to travel to Europe
and reuniros with her
in the Court.
Rey
he has invited to you personally.
Your Excellence
My proximo project
it is with the cientifico Azuarius.
Its treaty on the law
of the hidraulica
it was prohibited by lnquisicion
by its brilliance.
Haran lacks extreme forts
in order to silence you criticize them
of certain prelates.
My pequena is very astute.
The rent that you give me is not enough.
I must maintain
all the arts and sciences
of Espana
Some of your huge plans
they necesitarian all gold
of the Peru.
Me torturais reprochandome
what cost.
Wise person who your coming
not traeria nothing good.
Not me culpeis if no
nothing memorable has taken place.
Knowledge that my love
sera never corresponded
it is but of which I can support.
All we have succumbed
to tirania
of the love noncorresponded.
Ojala God grants a daughter to you
that it loves his mother
and it does not dazzle it
with its indifference.
That God you acompane.
The visit was prepared
with fed resolutions
in remorses.
One promised to be patient,
the other, to be contained.
Both failed.
It is almost impossible to imagine
reason why step donates Maria
in order to conquer the affection
of its daughter.
I frequent the society
in order to harvest its absurdities.
It was introduced in the group
of but the famous
conversadores.
Often men who encubrian
hereticos thoughts.
Some we feared for its sanity.
They feared in vain, archbishop.
Madness
I diagnose of the devil.
"Artistica" but is adapted
to its nature.
That the archbishop
I take care personally
of the searches
of lnquisicion.
I discovered it in letters
of the Marquise.
Even though it visited the convent
of Santa Rosa of the Roses.
"That strange genius,
the abbess
mother Maria of the Pillar,
one has fallen in love with an idea
in order to do in front
to the stubborness of this world,
and she wishes to give a little dignity
to the life of the women ".
Visperas, disculpame.
And well,
archbishop,
to that we must the pleasure
of your visit
I have come, loved mother,
in search of compania.
I am conscious of opinion
that it has the archbishop
of this convent.
No, no, it is not for my.
My pleasures
they are something but falsified.
Apparently,
lnquisicion thinks
that that crazy person,
the Marquise of Montemayor,
not estaria it as much
if she were not so single.
They have requested to me
that it looks for compania to him.
Since ningun pretendiente
one approached the widow,
pense in vos.
Although haria almost any thing
in order to win over to me
with my superior
and to obtain bottoms
for the convent…
Madre Maria,
teneis to ready girls
in the convent.
All is good,
a blessing of the sky.
Disciplined girls
that they beneficiarian themselves
coexisting with the woman
but rich of all the Peru.
Podeis to lend one to him.
It will think it.
Not it penseis, this deciding.
The Marquise visited manana to you.
I suggest to you,
by the good of your work
and because desire to see overwhelmed
your ambitions,
that prepareis to a girl
for the position.
Thanks, Nugget.
The archbishop does not have exigirte
that you incline.
Those single courtesies reduce
to the women.
I always think
that not to return to visitaros
sera one of the compensations
of the death.
Good night, abbess.
The archbishop
he has looked for a positioning to you,
while buscais
your vocation.
The fault is not yours.
The nature
she is so annoying
that it disables yours
permanence in the convent.
Quiza not sepais
that it interests filologia to me,
mainly the dialectos.
I compile the changes
of vowels and consonants
of the Latin to espanol
and to the indohispanico
in order to distract my future oldness.
I have found out
of your secret language.
As of both she is Manuel
and as Esteban
Well, we begin
with the verbs.
Like…
Like decis, for example,
"I saw"
Preferis the Latin
or espanol
Some of both understands
a spoken or written language
As soon as they knew to speak…
Sabeis to write
… they invented a secret
language.
To see.
It symbolized its deep one
and mutual identity.
You write aqui.
They do not serve for cotracks.
- they do not know to read nor to write.
- They write very well.
They have copied numerous motetes
of Morals.
That they are notary publics.
But not apostoles.
The virtue of a virgin
it is the miracle of Santa Rosa.
Nugget, sees with me.
You even know that these tasks
they are so educative
like learning to request,
to arrange hospitable rooms
or a spiritual way.
All task includes
monotonia and compensates.
That you value our work.
Ojala algun day you are decided
to follow my steps
and you occupy my position.
You know that there is place for you.
But before leaving the world,
you must know it.
Manana Saldras
in order to go to the palace
of Montemayor.
It is a heavy load,
but you hara but hard.
Daughter mia.
As you are called
Nugget.
My eyes estan tired.
You know to read, Nugget
If, senora.
Lee this.
That he hears it.
My poor letters.
"They represent" Trap advanced "
of Moreto in the Comedy ".
"They say that the Perichole
this magnifies of donates Leonor ".
"Asistire to a function
in order to see it i myself ".
"Nugget me acompanara".
Very well, it follows.
"you called to Me
a foolish provincial,
but asi are no artists
in Espana ".
"That extrano man,
the Tio Pio,
one does not separate from his side ".
"Sera its father,
its lover or his son "
He does not deserve this
admiracion of my daughter
The following boat
a month took.
It dedicated all his time
to the conquest
of the love of its daughter.
It sent letters to Spain
to newspaper.
It returns before
of which the boat weighs anchor.
But almost never
it received answer.
One felt less than loved.
A solitary soul.
I do not speak of martyrdom.
I limit myself to emphasize
the daily miracle present
in so many disinterested acts.
In truth,
I found out the existence
of the Tio Pío and Don Jaime
by letters of the Marquise.
Its description of the Tio Pío
it did not contradict
the sum
of dishonourable testimonies
that it had acquired
previously.
"If our old arlequín,
the Tio Pío,
it wrote up my letters,
all would applaud my talent ".
"Pity that is
so decayed
by bad companias ".
"I do not have left but remedy
that to reject to him as it shuffles dirty
and to leave him in the low world ".
Nugget, watches as it looks like
to an ant.
Offer message to the Tio Pio,
that it comes to the dusk.
My daughter must know it everything
before others.
The Marquise of Montemayor
she requires your presence.
Dear Tio Pio,
you are the pleasant man but
of the world.
Despues of the husband
of my daughter.
I must be the second man
but pleasant of the world
Really ingenious.
Hablais with exquisitez.
They are many anuses oyendo
to Calderon in the Comedy.
I have oido that the archbishop finishes
to return of Espana
with volumes of masses,
motetes and numerous ballads.
New compositions
of Palestrina.
Motetes de Morales.
And I complete it of Moreto.
Debeis to occupy a theater box
in the Comedy.
One feels like to me to mount
I complete it of Moreto
with the Perichole.
The Perichole is the unica in Lima
able to interpret
that wonder.
If, there is a monologo
flowery length and.
- the lover, donates Leonor.
- Pondra on approval its talent.
The virrey has the libreto,
debereis to request bottoms to him.
Excellence.
They say that teniais contacts
in the Court,
you supplied to Ejercito
and you urged the rebellion.
But yours discrecion
it was so
that the party frances I use to you
in spite of knowing
that espanol used the party to you.
They say that you were domador
and antique dealer,
that you dealt with silks,
dissipations and pleasures.
But that you mostrais obstinate
before the possessions.
Sold Habeis boxes
of red porcelain of Persia,
baules of Chinese objects,
vases Ming
to collectors of peculiarities.
And in spite of beginning
a commerce of pildoras
that you bought who knows
the remedies Incas,
as soon as any business
it threatens being Prospero,
abandonais.
lncluso when you investigated
for lnquisicion,
inspiring rebellions
in name of governments
so that they could squash them.
Said anomalia it amuses
the virrey, you follow asi.
They say that you were masterful
of song of the Perichole.
Others, its peluquero,
and even its masajista.
There are them insist
in which you are its father.
But Its Excellence needs
that him asegureis
that you are not,
under ningun concept,
its lover.
I am surrounded
by oceanos of boredom.
A boredom
penetrating and painful.
One awakes with me,
acompana me,
it watches me while I sleep.
My life lacks objectives.
It has Your Merced
algun objective
I have three objectives,
Your Excellence.
First
it is independence,
based on desire
of variety.
The second
it is to be always alongside
of beautiful women.
I adore them to all.
They torment to me.
And they feel comforted,
they say,
by discrecion
of your delivery.
I go freely
by its aposentos.
And as I am a fool,
I do not hope that they love to me.
For that, I visit the districts
but dark of the city.
Third
it is to be near those
that they love espanola Literature.
Debeis to know what feels
Its Excellence by verses
of Cervantes and Calderon.
There is a subject
by that desire to require
your mediation.
Although I do not make use
of my position
for the search of being able
or of frivola fantasia,
and that I do not approve the lightness,
I even conserve one picks
of Castilian salt,
that it inclines me by verses
of Calderon.
And by
its rich and reverencial one
translation
to traves of the interpretation
of the Perichole.
The discovery
of the Perichole
permitio to unite to me
the three objectives of my life.
Quiza podais to obtain
its presence stops
"interpretation unites petite"
some late.
Despues of the Comedy
Dona Leonor
in "Trap it advanced"
In espanola Literature,
the legendary lover but.
We have made sure
of the interest of the virrey.
If one feels pleased,
quiza considers to sponsor
a work of Moreto.
Mira.
"For the amiable Perichole".
"it is required of Your Senoria
that it has supper with Its Excellence
despues of the function of Calderon ".
God mio.
"Senoria" nothing less.
That passion.
In truth creeis
Estareis in agreement
in which they are scarce
the feminine papers
enthusiastic
in the drama espanol.
Single there are horsemen struggling
in the conflicts
of the honor and de la Cruz.
Nothing comparable
to the talent descriptions,
enchantment, passion
and hysteria of the French,
and of
venecianos.
He is a delicious man.
Don Andres of Shore.
You referis to Its Excellence
If, at least what it is of.
The good table
it has been able with.
From ahi the drop comes.
It collects currencies,
from ahi the debts come.
Yvinos
that they contributed the drop to him.
The books contributed to him
miopia.
And the actresses…
That they contributed to him
A tendency
to the convulsions.
Like result
of one of those disputes
that they arise espontaneamente
in the brothels,
one was forced
to change itself to the Peru.
Me encontro to the 12 anuses
in cafes singing ballads.
Me acogio,
it composed songs to me,
I embosom myself to improve
the timbre of my voice.
lncluso I buy a dress.
But never me pidio nothing
in return.
For that reason nothing in this world
it can surprise to me.
lnterpretareis to Moreto.
Dona Leonor,
i myself it will sponsor it.
The ghost of the passion,
that it turns a life
dedicated when having
in a fleeting dream,
he was destined, apparently,
to leave them.
And to vos you parecia,
fray Junipero,
that it was the moment
to include teologia
between exact sciences.
You threw in lack
a laboratory, quiza
A mere "act of God"
The caida one of the bridge
of San Luis Rey
it was the perfect occasion
You thought
that podriais to discover
the intentions of the Senor
The coincidence insisted
in disturbing to the reason.
The destiny returns in whim
the most insignificant event.
The Comedy, thanks.
- Letter of Espana
- No, senora.
I believe that it is an invitation
to the Comedy.
The Tio Pio.
"Yes, I will go to the Comedy
to see the work of Moreto ".
Three copies
for the film stars.
That the name of the Perichole
go upon I title.
In name of the passion,
I offer east bull
to the actress
the Perichole.
Never.
Never habia felt to me
so humiliated.
Excellence, the Perichole commands to you
its better desires.
Yyo I praise to you to sponsor
our work,
the wonder of Moreto.
Podeis to give back its desires
to the Perichole
and transmitidle
my humble indignation.
A killing one
a bull offers him
in name of the passion
while I…
Nonencounter words.
I request silencieis to the siren
in the horns of that killing one.
You come with me, senor.
Its Excellence does not lose
the time with the commons person.
The vulgar amorios
in a theater warehouse
as little they serve
for the interpretation
of this legendary lover.
The enthusiastic critical moment
that it requires this scene
it must resort
to all the shades of the love.
With its experience,
the actress incluira
the required effects
in the interpretation,
resorting to sabiduria
of its heart.
Resorting to the memory
of a little while loving.
Dona Maria,
the Marquise of Montemayor.
Her daughter is countess,
this very well Vista in the Court.
She is a drunkard,
a lunatic one.
As one dares
to make fun of asi, like
- We go, moon mia.
- a minute
- Camila
And the virrey
The real theater box is distinguished
by its absence.
Manuel.
Sera better than we go away.
The word love is not enough
in order to describe
the tacit unit and shamed
of the brothers.
Its mutual necessity
he was so great
that it produced miracles
so natural
like the ray.
The separation
she was so devastating
and strange like the calm
that it follows the storm.
My night of triumph.
So that not habeis been
But the everything
of your performance.
I want pediros
that realiceis a pequena task
that it fits
with your enchantments.
I am not the enough letter
with Your Excellence
Well,
that it desires to you
A verse, a song
- Quitaos the shoes.
- a dance.
It takes off,
like a gypsy.
No, you hope, poor man neck.
It cannot with the weight
of this necklace.
They enchant to me
our games.
Like podeis to breathe
so tightened
It is for my
We go, abridlo and poneoslo.
Poneoslo.
That…
That game is this
It is not a game, wanted.
Mofar of the aristocracy
in I publish does not have grace.
The offense deserves
a punishment I publish.
You will apologize
before the Marquise
and ireis takes off,
dressed
with this humble black article.
I am the Perichole.
I the virrey of the Peru
A great one of this world.
As far as the Marquise
to who habeis humiliated
in the Comedy tonight,
although it loses the head,
it belongs to the aristocracy.
But…
Like its son-in-law,
an importance personage
in the espanola Court.
Nothing must irritate to them,
nor to my
That reasons I have given
to Its Excellence…
By your good,
I hope that it is not truth
that me enganais
with a killing one
Or he is an actor
The shoes
What is
For the first time,
its will
it could not with the challenge.
As I hope to see leave
to the Perichole that night
There was lost the privilege
of the simpleza.
Sigueme.
The dissosciation of the love
and of the pleasure.
The pleasure became complicated
by the love.
Manuel, you are your If.
You must write another letter
for my.
Escribe.
"the Perichole does not accustom
to wait for nobody ".
Already this
"There are lost the judgment"
"Jamas you return
to offer a bull me ".
"you are not but that cholo,
even in Lima
there are better bullfigthers than your ".
"I am average Castilian
and I do not have pair in this world
like actress ".
"Not tendras another opportunity".
Already this
"nonvolveras to make hope me,
cholo ".
"I reire completes it,
then nor an actress ages
as soon as a bullfigther ".
The Perichole wishes to be received
by it donates Maria,
Marquise of Montemayor.
- You hope, please.
- Dile
that I bring presentation letter
of the virrey.
If, senora.
- the senora says…
-, thanks.
Pidele that hopes,
vere that I can do.
Very well.
The Perichole wishes veros.
The actress of the Comedy.
The one of the work of Moreto,
this ahi outside, hoping.
She goes dressed in the article
of the humiliation.
Dice…
It says that it has a letter
of presentation of the virrey.
Traeme a snow earthen bowl.
And a veil.
Your Gracia
not this victim
Victim
To offend to me your
My talented nina,
you are a great artist.
My panuelo, Nugget.
You are too generous,
senora…
I say, Your Grace,
when doing contingency not covered by law
of my puerilidad.
You allow that it kisses the hand to you.
As a old one can
foolish and without love,
to get angry with you
I feel like
if you were my daughter.
My daughter is very beautiful,
all they say it.
Conocias to donates Clear
Conocia well to the countess
of Vista.
So that you remain of knees,
daughter mia
Thanks.
A day we got angry.
Nonmemory so that.
We commentd out irreflexivos
and we separated.
Soon,
we wanted to request pardon.
Single it separated a door to us,
and hays aqui,
each one throwing by its side.
But, finally,
volume my face
asi
between its white hands.
Asi.
It is not of warm nature
and impulsive,
,
but, nina beloved, is…
She has such accumulation
of intelligence, grace,
of…
It is obvious that I was the cause
of the malentendido one.
He is not wonderful
that she pardoned to me so soon
Really wonderful.
The fault was mia.
But, as I watch myself.
Not sere the mother
of a so wonderful woman
by error
I am dificil.
I am annoying.
- You are two great women.
- Your Grace…
No, you do not interrupt to me.
You are an exceptional woman.
I am old a estupida one
and foolish.
It will kiss your feet.
I am impossible.
- I am impossible.
- Your Grace.
I am impossible.
This blind and excessive love
it gave to light letters
of great beauty,
but it was the last expression
of the egoísmo.
These anecdotas contradict
nocion of a guided world,
and they encourage to those
that they enjoy believing
that this world this patient.
Indeed for that reason
segui ahead.
My intention was to explain
so that they do not present/display
difficulties for the faith.
The brother already habia resorted
to the same experiment.
In the long-hauls
between parishes,
he sounded with metodos
that they justified
the existence of God.
For example,
the orations requesting rain
and the obtained results.
Esplendidos rituals.
But not even veia
a cloud.
For greater test
of its convictions,
despues of which the plague
Puerto attacked
and one took
to many farmers,
I write down privily
the characteristics
of 15 survivors.
Aqui we have a fragment
of this ambitious work.
VICTlMAS
KINDNESS PlEDAD UTlLlDAD
When sumais the column
of victimas and comparais
to the survivors,
descubris that…
That the deads valian
five times but
If.
The ensano plague
with the valuable inhabitants but
of Puerto
against yours teoria,
that conclusion sacais
The discrepancy between the faith
and the facts are greater
of which it is created.
Some say
that jamas we will know it.
Yque we are toys
into the hands of the Gods.
They kill to us by diversion.
The Perichole calls to Manuel.
Others, on the contrary, say
It needs a letter,
he is urgent.
that nor the sparrow loses
a pen
that it has not been grazed
by the finger of God.
Where this
"With all its respect,
Manuel informs to you
of which no longer podra to write
your letters ".
As one dares
Despideles.
To who
To those two stupid huerfanos,
those lunatic monsters.
Like bear to need me the respect
It does not have name
Echales of my house,
of this theater
You would never volveran
to darken its door
You hear to me
Captain.
Your, your and your.
You come with me.
They seem to you well
We will unload until the dawn.
Whichever but fast,
but money.
We go, we go
Fast, fast
Vamos.
We go, we go
Hourly
o'clock
until the pain disappears.
If affluent it beams,
science built miracles
with its leg.
You do not forget in that order
you must apply the unguentos.
Although they never spoke,
the world became strange
and hostile without its brother.
The shade of the Perichole
it had been crossed in his way.
So extraordinary
coincidences
they only can be
deliberate.
Single Quiza was an accident.
Quiza.
Quiza was work of the malignant one.
Quiza this also is work
of the malignant one,
and vos, fray Junipero,
his complice
in mind, body and espiritu.
For that reason we are aqui,
in order to protect the dogmas
fundamental of the faith.
Doubt does not fit
of which this legajo
it is work of the malignant one,
he is malignant.
A debil composition
franciscana
that it raises the coincidence
but alla of the faith
The belief
in a "act of God".
At the most, subversion,
like little, superstition.
It cries out by a judgment
at but the high level.
Each copy must be burned
to the dusk.
- I cannot memorizar as much.
- Camila.
- I cannot without the pointer.
- They see with Tio Pio.
They see with me.
You are not the admired actress but
of all Lima
These superficially
of rabietas own
of a mediocre talent.
I am fed up with this life.
But,
that ocurrira with the Moreto
that I brought of Espana
There am aqui the problem.
The Perichole feels like poor devil.
Artists.
That it happens
Despues to suffer
similar humiliation,
there is lost the good humor.
Sera necessary to find
parents.
lncluso a pair of cousins.
Decidme that I have
that to see with this.
Or vos.
To not habeis satiated you
of indiscretions
This on the verge of giving lineage
to the virrey.
And not this to the current.
The work is cancelled
by order of the virrey
Nonencounter nothing today in day
that the soul feeds so much
like teoria following:
The poor men,
when the unknown the happiness,
they are insensible to infortunio.
It is enough with watching
its houses and their clothes.
Single the cultured man
he can know that he is unfortunate.
There is a fashionable bath
in the montanas.
It is not far
of Santa Maria
of Cluxambuqua.
The bridge is crossed
of San Luis Rey.
Dare
to the Perichole
a pequena villa
to the style "Vichy"
near there.
It will take those repugnant waters
during its retirement,
while one recovers.
Paseemos.
You come, dear.
Wanted.
We will not raise the drop curtain
tonight.
lnforma to compania.
We cannot compete
with the carnival.
Nor I can allow that the room
return to be vacia.
Your indiscretion
it exhausts my patience.
It will spend this hour
with pequeno Don Jaime.
Tio Pio, these crazy person if you create
that volvere to the scenes.
Those days horrify to me.
The daily insults
in that stinking place.
- You waste the time.
- Wanted Camila,
single I request moments to you.
No longer you serviria of anything,
Tio Pio.
Not even you come to the theater,
all they comment it.
I do not publish either goes.
Single they give
two weekly representations.
We were mistaken
with the great teachers.
Wonderful Camila,
I was not right with you
in the scenes.
Me invadia a foolish pride.
You have always been
a great artist.
If you discover that you are not happy
between these people,
trasladate to Madrid.
Alli you prevailed.
No, never vere Espana.
The world is always equal,
in Madrid or Lima.
If viviesemos in an island,
they podrian verte as you are.
And amarte.
You have 50 anuses
and you continue sounding with those islands.
That island does not exist,
nor that love exists, Tio Pio.
Single you found it
in the theater.
I must return.
It had discovered the secret
of that nobody recovers
absolutely.
lncluso
in the most perfect love,
one of both loves less
that the other.
Perhaps it has never
two people who love themselves
in the same way.
Secret Algun I escape
when reconstructing its lives.
While it collected data,
I did not want to omit
but minimo detail,
then temia to lose
some track.
For that reason you wrote down
the insignificant details but
thinking that,
for the reader,
those data empezarian to move,
they encajarian
and they revelarian his secret to him
It did not wish to divulge the secret
of deads,
then you would estaran pardoned
by very great
that outside its abandonment.
Apostoles,
in the New Testament,
they reserved that honor
to Christ our Senor.
It was left,
crucificado
by our sins.
Dona wise Maria
that habia sinned.
Although its love
by his daughter it included
all the shades of the love,
it included certain tyranny.
It had not loved his daughter
by the good of its daughter,
but by his.
It longed for to free itself
of this vile bond,
but it could not
with so fierce passion.
It could not command in his daughter
if this one had put
4,000 miles among them.
It only requested to God
and to immortality
a test of the devotion
of its daughter.
An amiable word,
a little while affectionate.
A letter of Spain.
I will take it.
Nugget.
It comes from Espana
It leaves sees it.
Taking, dates haste, leemelo.
"Loved mother:"
"the time aqui is exhausting".
"Everything blooms simultaneously
and it even makes but dificil ".
"Soportaria the flowers
if not outside by its perfume ".
All that jumps,
there is nothing but no important
"If Vicente returns on time,
this letter finished
and you escribira
in detail about my
so that disfruteis ".
"Not ire to Provenza in otono
since my nacera son
in October ".
That son
That it is this frivolity
Santa Maria Rosa.
Desatate the hair.
I gave the servants
that they do not take the tied hair.
Red Consigueme chalk.
Mother of God.
We go, desataos the hair,
llevadlo loose.
It will leave all good,
sweet mother Maria
Santa Rosa de Cluxambuqua
She will leave all good
While I am
in peregrination,
aseguraos of which nobody is above
the noticeable steps
with red chalk.
The great rite
of the Peruvian homes
in the delay
of the happy event.
It started off for the sanctuary
of Santa Maria de Cluxambuqua
in order to request a safe childbirth.
Friend mio.
God attends to us.
It leaves helps you.
It eats a little.
If you do not leave ayudarte me,
it tell me at least as you are.
Manuel
God has taken him
between its hands.
For Alvarado captain.
It is the personified sincerity.
Will be given now it,
you go with God, Don Pio.
ld with God.
Llevadme to its side.
We do what we can.
We followed ahead, Esteban,
as better we can.
And it does not last much.
The time
it continues happening.
Sorprendera to know to you
how quickly it happens.
Fast
Its Excellence
it wishes to speak with vos.
That devils it happens
The epidemic, fool.
That epidemic
Hundreds have caido
by the smallpox.
The glass of the envious ones
one fills to overflow
with the rumor
of which the Perichole has it.
It advanced
All my gifts
given back without an explanation.
I must go to see it immediately.
I have tried it.
It has seen somebody it
It does not want to see anybody,
single to its servant.
It does not confirm nor it denies the rumor
of which this disfigured.
Its Excellence has tried to see it
without result some.
Him devolvio a strong sum
acompanada
of a letter that reunia
the greater bitterness
and the greater possible pride.
And now,
this pequeno message
fury plenty.
Like many handsome women
that they have lived
between admirers
of its beauty,
creia, without cynicism some,
that it was the base of the affection
that they had to him.
And that all future attention
naceria
of a compassion
obliging
that one was glad
of similar change of fortune.
Please.
Not menosprecieis to Its Excellence
nor to the court.
You leave finishes.
I feel curiosity
to know the conclusion.
There are no words
in order to explain
what it could have been
or not to be
if it does not get to break itself
the bridge of San Luis Rey.
The Perichole had been changed
with its son, Don Jaime,
to a farm way
of Cluxambuqua,
towards where the Marquise
she ascended
in its pilgrimage
by the $andes
while she repeated
the mysteries of the Rosary.
Nugget, very devoteely given
to its intention,
it followed it
on foot.
Wanted
abbess;
In spite of nonveros never,
I always think about vos.
Memory which you said
of my future
with the sisters.
Sometimes, I ask myself
if you have not forgotten it.
It wanted to leave this world
for always
in order to be on the foot de la Cruz
and to follow the way of Christ.
Mother in the Gentleman,
only desire to do
what vos you wish,
but I feel so single.
I do not speak with anybody.
Perhaps you let to me return
to the convent
although it only is
for days.
If you had a minute
in order to write words to me,
it would hold,
but you are occupied.
Leemelo.
It is a letter
I must lower to by coal.
That can hope.
Gustaria oir to me as you write.
"Loved abbess:"
"In spite of nonveros never,
I always think about vos ".
"Memory which you said
of my future with the sisters ".
Sometimes, I ask myself
if you have not forgotten it.
It wanted to leave this world
for always
in order to be on the foot de la Cruz
and to follow the way of Christ.
Dear Nugget,
he is very beautiful.
Creeme.
It is not it.
He is not brave.
Yescribió which called
his first epistle.
His first and brave letter
with misspelling.
It is famous epistle 56
to that the enciclopedistas
they call Corintios l
by the inmortal paragraph
about the love.
"Between the thousands of people
that they are known in a life… "
Ysigue.
This one, its last letter is,
of course, inmortal.
Even asi,
its daughter hardly if I watch some.
In spite of its suplicas,
all was given back.
We must to Nugget
that they have been conserved.
Dejame to live now.
Senor,
it allows that it begins again.
Two days despues
they returned to Lima.
When crossing the bridge
of San Luis Rey,
ocurrio the accident
that we already know.
I look for a strong man
for my proximo travels.
Hard work, good pay.
Very far from the Peru.
And well
I ask to you
if you want to acompanar to me
in my proximo travels.
This deciding.
Not these customary to the cold one.
One feels like to me to sail
between the ice islands.
lmagina the prow opening
a sea of seaweed,
waking up a cloud of fish
like grasshopper in June.
Sides, son,
tapeworm a daughter.
Often salio
to dismiss to me
and to receive to me.
I do not have form to know
if he were but intelligent
or but beautiful
that all demas,
but he was mia.
God me Quito
when it was not watching.
Sometimes I have the impression
from which it has left
to a long trip
and that I will return to find it.
I cross the hemispheres
while it spends the time
between now and the oldness.
The words resisted to him
unless it spoke of the sea.
Sometimes, to speak of trivialities
it requires value.
Before starting off for
the distant Atlantic coast,
they followed the way Inca
gathering merchandise
in order to deal in the trip.
Arriba.
That is.
Not permitira that entreis.
In that case,
with pleasure I will have left aqui.
Its pride fears
that it can feel sorry to me of her.
Dile that respect its incomodidad
in this hour
and that its spiritual humility
it makes even want it me but.
I can be util with the nino.
Or to fix this patio.
Apartate of my, salt of my house
I said that jamas
queria to return to verte
Tapeworms you order
Prohibited tapeworm to enter.
- It vetoes, dejame
- Camila
Santa Madre,
when she frees to me of you
Escuchame.
Single Escuchame once,
you the request.
In question
Camila,
it leaves takes to Don Jaime
and that lives with me in Lima
an anus or two.
Sere its teacher.
Aqui cria between servants.
It does not learn anything.
No.
Camila, that sera of
- No.
- Him querre.
Him mimare, will take care of of.
I was not a good teacher
I did dano sometimes to you
You are cruel,
you resort to my gratitude.
Gratitude, gratitude,
very it was been thankful you.
Good.
But now that no longer I am
the same woman,
no longer I have
so that estarte been thankful.
That you acompane Jaime
if asi wishes it.
Estara ahead
of the inn to twelve.
For.
Mr..Pio.
When arriving at the bridge
of San Luis Rey,
the captain lowered until the river
in order to supervise the step
of the merchandise.
Pero Esteban
I cross the bridge.
Yun little behind went
Doña Maria,
the Marquise of Montemayor,
and its young companion,
Nugget.
Esteban happened ahead
of the Tio Pío.
We will rest
when we cross the bridge.
Pero
it was not necessary.
It seems to be
that its errors in the love
they do not podian to last much.
Salvacion was his.
With this recopilacion of data
about that they fell
of the bridge of San Luis Rey,
that concluis
I conclude with a passage
that it tries to explain
so that the Senor escogio
to that person that day
in order to demonstrate Su sabiduria.
I have leido the conclusions.
You are incapable to determine
that victimas had
a characteristic in common.
I believe that the art of the biografo
he is but dificil of which it seems.
And, peculiarly,
those that knew more,
like the captain,
they spoke less.
I could not interview
to the Perichole.
It had had to do
with all the victims.
Convinced that all
they are mofaban of her,
recorria the mounts
remembering,
looking for the souls
of its dear beings.
It thought that the sky
it had returned to speak.
The first time was the smallpox.
Yluego,
the fall of the bridge.
They were not accidents.
Debio to support
one lasts servitude
before understanding
the sense of loyalty
of the true love.
During the six years
that I dedicated to the deceaseds…
Mother.
… one shut in
in the convent of Santa Maria
Rose of the Roses.
I know you, daughter mia
She was actress, the Perichole.
For a long time
that I want conocerte.
You had a lost one
in the bridge.
I perdi to two
of my huerfanos.
But
that you lost your son.
- Asi is, mother.
- and to a great friend.
Asi is, mother.
It happens to the garden,
podras to rest aqui.
All we were mistaken.
Ven.
The abbess of the convent
Maria Rosa of the Roses.
The Camila sister declares,
the Perichole.
It is the Perichole
It is it.
Eras the name actress
Camila Micaela Villegas
called the Perichole
Ten the kindness of identificarte.
It retires your veil.
I have requested to you
that you retire your veil.
Abbess.
Your Excellence,
it fears to be Vista in I publish.
Since when an actress
she fears to be Vista
Your Excellence,
we cannot accept the testimony
of a hidden actress
under I live of nun.
Your Excellence,
I respond of his…
Talent or formality
Whichever better actress,
worse witness.
Your Excellence,
reconoceis to…
I request perdoneis to you,
it is the Perichole
No.
I cannot say
that I recognize it.
Like
Senor.
I do not know this woman.
By very enthusiastic which outside,
not habia love
in the glance of the Perichole.
Nobody is so blind,
Your Excellence,
like that it does not want to see.
Silence
Archbishop,
you resume the conclusions.
Brief thirst,
please, or we will perish
in this infernal heat.
As much vos as I,
Your Excellence,
we see that fray Junipero
planning to seed
the flower
of but the perfect skepticism.
It is evident.
Also that never habia been
as much time without smoking.
The plan
it is looked like the efforts
of those presumptuous ones
that they wished to be above
the paving stones of the sky
and they built the tower of Babel
in order to reach it.
For this franciscano,
incredulo where there are them,
the faith is not enough.
It wants classified tests
of the divine intention.
Historicas tests.
Matematicas tests.
The doubt flows eternal
even when lnquisicion
it can read the thought to us.
Ahorradnos your thesis on
the meritos of lnquisicion.
It is not necessary to praise
the statutes to execute them.
It will save the generalizations to me
of the brother.
Single dire that creyo to see,
in this caida,
the destruction of the bad ones
and the call of the sky
to the good ones.
It saw the condemnation of the pride
and of the wealth,
and him parecio a good lesson.
At the same time,
the poverty and humility
they were crowned
for construction of the poor men.
But these reasons
they did not satisfy the brother.
The book, once finished,
it has been judged
and described as heretico.
Thus
this finished.
I propose,
Your Excellence,
to lnquisicion
that fray Junipero
it has worked for the malignant one.
This book,
this volume is one herejia,
and it must be described,
by badly that does,
as it builds of the devil.
Therefore,
all the copies
they were burned to the dawn
to the time that the author.
The verdict is accepted.
That they prepare the bonfire
for the dawn.
The intention of God is that one
The guideline that I did not know to discover
in the five deceaseds
it continues escaping
even now.
Me hariais a favor,
daughter mia
You allow that she embosoms my work to you.
That God pardons to me.
Nonwise
to love.
Single conocia the love
to traves of the passion.
Perdonadme.
My husband,
the count of Abuirre,
he has ordered to me
that he gives to you
the confiscated goods
to the franciscanos
in name of lnquisicion.
It does not wish to take those wealth
of return to Espana,
it prefers that you quedeis vos
for your work.
Disculpadme,
I must see the serious patients
in order to say words to them
in case they cannot sleep.
Except I, nobody remembers
to Esteban and Nugget.
The Camila sister remembers
to the Tio Pio and its son.
And this lady, to its mother.
Soon we will die all
and nobody will remember
to those five people.
Also to us
they will love a time to us
before happening to the forgetfulness.
But it was enough with that love.
All those impulses of love
given back to the love that I create them.
The love does not need
of the memory.
There is a earth for the alive ones
and another one for deads.
The bridge is the love.
The surviving unico.
The meant unico.