INNOCENT
Carriage for Mr. Hermil
-Very good, Mr. Hermil - Thanks
- Here is your carriage, Sire - Thanks
Continue tomorrow. I must rush,
by now I am late. I must go
- agreed, tomorrow - tomorrow
Please?
On guard
I have not understood
Well yes, I said that for me the
coldness of English is a myth...
... pure invention - and
who would be the inventor?
- The Italians, perhaps - and
why invent such a thing?
- For envy - Indeed?  Why do you say that?
You don't say?
- Good evening - Good evening
- And how did it end, contessa?
- and he said endure or not
Is it tonight for her to sing Speranza?
- Not, next tuesday
- That's a pity, I shall not be there
- They say that she is extraordinary
- As singer or as woman?
I only mean of song
If the princess knew the little
invites that you come for music...
She knows very well they are
like a penance that inflicts us
We come here to court the
contessa Teresa Raffo...
... for penance Mozart, two
Schubert and four Liszt
- That appeals too - Good Evening,
Good evening, beloved
- What sin makes you arrives late
- The guilt is mine, princess
I am more than convinced
You missed a beautiful Liszt and Mozart.
Sit near me.
She interprets Chopin very well
I wanted to thank you,
princess, I have to leave
Go already?  That's too bad!
- She is an extraordinary pianist
- I think so
Goodbye
Where do you go?
Stay if you are with her
- I did not know that she would come
- Yes I know
Farewell.  Enjoy yourself
- Teresa, please - You come walk with me?
I cannot, you understand
you come out with me now, or this
is the last time that you see me...
... the last time, and I speak seriously
Tullio Beloved, don't forget that the
Princess invited him, if he goes
It does not matter to me, prince
I have an other festivity
- You want to tell Conte Egano
that I am waiting for him?
I will Contessa
It doesn't matter, here he is
Stefano Beloved!  I want to go early
Come, Tullio
I want to go back in before
the ossessa recommences
My wife takes much offense
if she does not see me...
... little enough to make them happy
Thanks
I will return to take you later
But, why?
- I will send back the carriage...
... I don't believe that I
will return, I am not well
I'll come with you
- Let's not complicate. Later
Come in
As you see I know you enough well...
... I knew that you would come
Ah, I would have preferred to wait
for you before leaving again...
... more rather than to risk
finding you on my return tonight
Give me the keys of the house
I could not come here come with you
My wife wanted me to accompany her
to the concert of her best friend
Why have you not told me that
you would have gone too?
I went just because I knew
that you would have gone
It was time for you to face the situation.
Don't you think?
Up to now you have succeeded,
with the ability of prestige...
... to not understand
things as they truly are
- and therefore I have taken the initiative
- What did you want to discover?
That I am married?  You have always known
- I accept - Then?
But from what you say, is
that much of the time...
... that the relationships between
you and your wife would be... formal
- So they are - Not true
Enough to see you together to see it
You are like all the bourgeois
husbands of this world, my beloved
You vow to the lover not to have
relationships with the wife...
... and to the wife swear
to not have a lover
Is it not mean, that denial
I am a free woman, really,
not only a word... like you
You are jealous of her?
I do not share a man with an other woman...
... even if she is his wife
You do not share me with
anyone, and you know
Do not think that I do not
have you within me, always
That presence is made felt
continuously, obstinate...
...even an enemy.
You must leave. You return to your wife.
You leave me
No, I do not leave you
You remain with me
- Still wide awake ?
- You had said that you were not well...
Stupid me , I was worried
I have opened the window one hundred
times in order to see you return
See what I was doing?  I was writing to you
But now that you are here...
Tomorrow I leave for Florence, I do
not know how long I will be away
This time is no laughing
matter, I must tell you
- You go forever?
- Forever. Such a large word
I feel, Giuliana...
... I have not never spoken
to you of it but I am sure...
... that some pious spirit will have
told you of my acts of infidelity to you
I have not spoken you of it because they
were not important and above
all because between us
...since the beginning is clearly a pact.
From our wedding
Love is hard until ...
... after become common affection,
esteem, friendship, interests...
Always that it is possible, clear
and therefore have been
because you have accepted...
... without to rebel to you, a
situation that exists from much time
Were history without
importance, like you say
for I have tried to ignore them,
do not give matter to us...
- For me marriage must...
- Yes, our marriage had...
... to be defended also
from own resentments
and you have reason.  You are extraordinary
although my love for you has...
... faded , as is fated to happen...
... the affection and the
respect I have only increased
I love you and I respect you..
... as the sweetest sister of
which I could not make less
I understand that you would
have the right to leave me...
... but I would suffer
much if you abandoned me.
I want you to continue living with me?
To help me?
To help you?  In what sense?
Support me.  To face a situation that...
...according to the ways of our
society, I would surely be criticized
- the woman who I love - Teresa Raffo
- Yes, Teresa - She is a widow, free...
... Then what prevents you living
with her, if you have want?
I have said to you that I love
Teresa, not that I want to marry her
She is a sensual woman, beautiful
I desire her
No woman has ever succeeded in
occupying me with herself... like she
But how would it be? I
arrive and she leaves.
Hey, anyone home?
Federico
- Tullio - Federico
I have three days of leave,
I arrive, and you leave?
No, I go alone
- Fortunate that you are here
- Must you go?
Truly...  How many leave days have you?
Three, three and half, exactly
I feel, I...
... I am in one situation...
... that I do not know how to define
I must leave and Giuliana remains alone
I do not want to martyr her, but...
... to only know that you
are here will calm me a lot
I want to pass the three days in
Rome, but not with my sister-in-law
- a delicious, adorable Creature...
- No, you can do what you want...
... To me it is enough to
know that you are here
Enough that in the evening before going
out, you step into her apartment
say hello and tell her what you do. She
will be content, it is a delicate gesture
You are the only tenant in this house?
From outside it seems therefore large
I will explain how they happen, if
it will not disappoint you too much
I promised to show them one of the
most beautiful houses in Rome and...
I did not say that it is not beautiful,
is very beautiful, only that...
Not, it is not beautiful
This villa was made to
instructions of my mother...
... wanted trees around...
... to see the green even
if we were in cities
My father did all in order to please her...
... but, died he, my mother returned to
Badiola, the house in the country...
... where there are many more
trees, much more green than here
When my brother married, he
came here here with his wife...
... I have held for me these three
rooms, I am really independent
Then this is not truly your house
Yes, yes, this is true also I assure you
Federico!  Federico!
Giuliana, what has happened? What
happens to you, Giuliana? answer
Please, help me
- I go to call the doctor
- Wait here, Gentleman
She has not passed out.
Must have taken something
is nobody at home, you are alone?
Not, they already have
gone to sleep except me
I was depressed and I have taken
something in order to sleep
and instead calming me...
... it brought anguish, fear...
- I did not want to remain alone
- We are here, how do you feel?
- It is nothing, I am stupid - Feel better?
Yes, better
Forgive me for having disturbed you
Do not raise you
This is my friend Filippo
D'Arborio, he is a writer...
... you do not think that you
had such important friends, eh?
Ulterico Vinicci
Signora Elviretta, my
sister-in-law Giuliana
- Good evening
I ask excuse all...... I
have ruined your supper...
... return to table,
- You cannot remain alone, this evening
Come
When you have to sleep as I say...
... or, you can sleep here,
rocked from our voices
- When I was intern with Filippo...
- You were in college together!
I was a poor boy...
... my family did not have
sufficient means for me to study
I lived in college, in a room
by reputation the smallest
- next to which there was Federico
- He went to sleep before me always
Just so, as soon as I began to
speak he fell asleep. Perhaps
... it was the tone of my voice
that produced this effect
it would appeal to me that also this time
it would succeed in making her sleep
breakfast is served
What scent!
They are lillies?
In this season?  How you have found them?
How kind !
They are from, it appears, Stefano Egano
How can you allow that imbecile?
It's not good to read the letters of others
You are being foolish...
... if I have wanted someone,
I would be with him, not you
I did promise to go to see
his horses race at Cascine
and instead I am here with you
Are you complaining?
I hoped to see you yesterday at the races
my horses won prizes
There are too many people, I have had fear
Tomorrow are the steeplechases
I have two horses entered. I can
make them to have the major places
I'm afraid that will not be possible for me
In case you change your mind...
I can assure you that Contessa
Raffo will not change her mind
- I would like to talk to the contessa
- I explain to you, that's enough
If you change your mind...
She is busy
Of course
Many friends of Egano say
that he has returned to Rome
and also it seems
She has broken with Tullio.
You have done well to come
Forget those that make comments.
They do not commiserate with you
Do not accept the role of the
betrayed and abandoned wife
You are here in order to
demonstrate to contrary
I hoped to arrive on time
to say not coming...
... would have certainly come ..
...but my train was delayed
While I fought with some idiot in
Florence, she left saying nothing
she wants to see again
the cost of a scandal
She is a liar, false, unseizable
In the moment that you feel
she is yours, she escapes
You already feel that I am
chasing other fantasies
I must find the strength to make
it finish, not to see her anymore
and you must help me.
- What I can do?
- I do not know, many things
To remind me of my purpose not
to see her more, to convince me
Nobody can less convince you than me
Not true
The most dangerous thing is the
desperation which I find, that makes...
... me feel therefore unhappy but at
the same time renders me alive, vital
This is the first time that I find
myself in a situation as this
It is true that a man ends by
selling his soul for his youth
and then finds himself
in love without defense
You talk as if I never existed
You have reason, I am unjust. Excuse
you must have patience with me...
... like with a sick
sick one that felt sorry
for it's own disease
- Was it you singing?  - Yes
- You go out?  - Yes.
- Where are you going?
- To the auction of Di-Castro
I do not succeed to pin
my veil, help me, please?
Thanks
You have a new scent?  What is?
Crab-apple, an English scent
La Fiamma
To Giuliana Hermil, Turris
Eburnea dishonourably I offer...
... Filippo D' Arborio - You do not leave?
- Do you know D'Arborio?  - Yes
- I did not know, from when?
- Your brother introduced me to him.
- Have you read it?
- Yes, I have leafed through some pages
He is a mediocre writer...
... does he not seem to you?  - No
He has a haughty, emphatic style ...
... insufferable
- How can you talk like that?
He has an extraordinary style,
bewitching to me, like music
you cannot judge an artist
having read only a few pages
You take him to heart!
He may be a great writer, like you
say, but he is badly educated...
... this I will acknowledge to you
The dedication that he has written
to you is not only emphatic...
... but also inopportune if it
is believed that it is meant...
...for a lady met a single time
I have seen him other times
since Federico introduced me
Take the carriage?
No, I prefer to walk
See you later
I have seen all
4500 Liras and 4500 Liras twice
- Contessa Raffo, compliments!  - Thanks
Now a pin in dove shape.
Diamonds, rose and rubies
Value estimated at 5-6000
we start from 1000 for this
1000, 1100, 1400, 1600...
... 2000, 2200 mrs.
2400, 2800, 3000...
... 3500 here in bottom, 4000 in
front of the bench, 4500 the mrs....
... 5000 here.  I feel the room heating up
Good evening, Mr. Hermil.
6000, I adjudicate to 6000...
6500, 7000, 7500.  It makes it appeal to
8000, 8500, 9000, 9500, 11000
Selling for 11000, 11000 and
one and two, 11000... sold!
Now for auction a beautiful fashionable
bracelet, of most recent invoice...
... with more than one hundred diamonds
and sapphires, mounted in platinum
Estimated 10000.  Start with 1000
Who offers more? Thousands, thousand
Liras, two thousand, two thousand Liras
-Good evening my lady - Good evening Emilio
- Mr. Tullio is at home?
- No, my lady, he has gone out
Tell the kitchen that I
have already had supper
- Good night - Good night , my lady
I have passed entire nights
downstairs, watching your windows
I know,  I have seen you
and you have not called me
Why are you so cruel to me?
You are one of those men made to suffer
Egoist, proud...
... controlling, and master of love
If you knew how much it has
cost to me to resist...
... to want to call to you
But they have succeeded...
... so you had to come to seek for me today
But I did not seek for you today
I was at home
- it is not true - Yes, I swear to you
I was at home from where I did not leave
My wife has said me that she
went to the auction, and then...
That was what your wife said?
But she was not there, I assure you
I did not have anything to do,
and arrived half an hour early
I , that arrives everywhere late
I saw all enter, one by one
Oh God, I ruined it
Your wife does not say the
truth to you, she deceives you
perhaps she has a lover
Sorry, I joke
I have only seen people that were within
... and I have not seen
those that arrived after
Not after I had seen you
- Good evening, Sir - My wife has returned?
Yes, an hour ago, but then she has left
She made to take the train at 20:30
She said that she went to see
your mother in the Badiola...
... I believe she has
left a note in the study
Mr.Hermil, is waiting
He is the only punctual roman,
I introduce Filippo D' Arborio
- Tullio Hermil - D'Arborio
- Do you make an academic bout?
- If it appeals
- Yes - Please
Blades in line?  Salute
Mask...
...on guard
Gentlemen, to it
Tell me if I have done well
Who do you want next to you at table?
To right Prince Fondi, who
you prefer on the left?
But I do not know
- That book  appeals to you?  - No
To me, yes. And also the
person who has written it
I had invited him this
evening, but he is not in Rome
D'Arborio?
I will see what will remake his
life, as soon as he returns
I will organize another evening, I
want you to get to know each other
- I know him, thanks
- So how can I have known that?
- You are in a bad humor?  - Not at all
Then, give your approval to
me for the table places?
Do not forget that we must give an
answer this evening to Dampierre
What do you say? Are we
going to Paris or not?
It was you that was invited
I'll go if you come also
How many things you want me to do? To
give a lunch to D'Arborio, travels...
To become a bachelor again and give to me
I am here, the ambassador to my
right and Dampiere on the left...
... Good?  - Yes, its good...
I have put Dampierre close to
me to talk about next week...
...if we will go to Paris with them - OK
Thanks
Tullio
- How are you, Giuseppe?  - Well, thanks
- Tullio, beloved - Mother, how are you?
You are all alike, you arrive all
at once when one least expects you
- and Giuliana?
- Well, also she waited for you
Where is Mrs. Giuliana?  - In the garden
Go to call her. Tell her please
that Mr. Tullio has arrived
Yes, my lady.
How is Giuliana? How
does she spend her days?
- Fortunately she has friends - Friends?
Her friends from Rome are
staying with the Torrigiani...
... Giuliana says that they
are likeable persons...
... and therefore at least pass the time.
I never do go out, I see nobody
I have said to her to invite who she
wants, but in order not to disturb,
Giuliana goes out
It will be a beautiful surprise
for her to find you here
- I find You well - I was not expecting you
To tell the truth, not even I wait for you
I was at the station, I had
already a ticket for Paris...
... Then I saw a train that came
here and I have changed my route
I know that Tullio was a little
crazy, but until this point
Wait
Will it displease you if he
occupies a room in the left wing?
Tullio reads until late and
keeps me wide awake...
... therefore in order not to disturb
each other we sleep in separate rooms
As you want, there are many rooms
Take them there please
- You want tea?  - No, thanks
Thanks
Ever been to Villalilla?
- No, I never go there
- Like never?  - We have not been
We will have to speak about Villalilla
There is a former English diplomat who is
in love with it and it wants to buy it
I said that an optimal
transaction could be made...
... but I am contrary to sell it.
I should rent it but
Think how much that costs ourselves...
... when just married you
said that you wanted
to live there six
months of the year...
I have never thought of us there
If I rent it we recover
expenses of maintenance
uninhabited houses suffer
depreciation before time
Think about it. I do
not speak for interest
For me it will be always your house
Mother is right, for less I
would have to go to see it
If tomorrow you do not have
other engagements, I will go
Welcome Sir.  Welcome Mrs.
Hello, Callisto
Give a drink to the horses
and also a little graze
For fifteen days I open the windows
to give air to the house...
... I knew that the
gentleman was at Badiola
I have been late to come, because
I waited for that time, so..
Do you have to do like you told your mother
Rent it
Yes, would be the more reasonable thing
If the diplomatic Englishman would take it
I would be sorry
Are you not very well?
You have the same air,
halting and afraid...
... of before the time that we have come
here were the same flowers, same scent
Yes, it was the same season
Try to be two new persons,
at their first encounter
Depend only on us...
... if we do not succeed we
will return to our unhappiness
... to our miseries
It is not possible, do not torment me
Because? You are my wife, my sister...
... but you are never my lover
love is not just this... above all this
and I have not never taught you...
... has been guilt mine, has mistaken
Tell me that you want to
make love with me, tell me
Tell me that you want me also, tell me
I began to think you stayed,
I wanted to send someone
How goes it?
- You want me to accompany you?
- No, thanks
Hello, mother
Giuliana is not well, I wanted to
remain, but she did not want to
- She is ill?  - Nothing serious...
a light malaise, perhaps
she has caught a chill
You are right when you say that it
is a sin to leave the villa empty
But not for the English diplomat,
we would go to live there....
... at least some months of the year
- But...
- Yes... I know you don't believe me
... But you should see. It
was there beautiful today...
... The scent of the lillies
will be why Giuliana felt ...
...a little unwell, the
scent went to her head
I will go to tell Giuliana to
remain in bed, it is prudent
I will get the doctor to come quickly
I wanted to get him to come last
week, but Giuliana did not wish it.
Giuseppe will not have detached
the gig yet, tell himi to go for
... Doctor Milani, it will
please me if he comes tonight
Calm, calm, mother, you are
exaggerating without need
... Giuliana is well, you
worry about nothing.
Giuliana has forbidden
me to speak to you of...
... until we were sure, but
by now there are no doubts...
... and I will speak to you of it ...
... why she does not ride
the gig for that journey
Giuliana is pregnant
- Pregnant ?  - Yes
She has told you?
No, I have worked it out. She has
had many malaises, like today...
... Nausea, dizziness, insomnia,
the things that you imagine...
... I have asked. She has said to
me that perhaps she was pregnant...
... but wanted to be sure of
it before speaking with you...
... in order to not deceive you and
to not disappoint you, naturally
I myself recommended she see the doctor...
... because even if I tell her to take
precautions, she does not believe me
She will be in the third month. But you,
do not betray me, wait for her to tell you
I have asked for this
with much insistence...
I am so happy!
I have yearned for this moment!
Now we must be prudent, the first
months are most dangerous...
... above all for her, she is so  delicate,
Beloved, our beloved creature
Goodnight mother.  I go to sleep
If Giuliana is awake, I hear it
Yes, did you see the doctor?
If Giuseppe had found him ,
he already would have arrived
- If you have need of something
- No, thanks, goodnight
Tullio...
...do not go away, I fear to be alone
you have taken something in order to sleep?
Tullio, you have slept here all night?
- What has happened? - you have
asked to me to remain here
I?  When?
You do not remember?
I had taken a sleeping pill...
... perhaps more than usual
Since when do you take sleeping pills?
The doctor knows it?
Yes
- Show me what you take
- I do not remember where I have put it
I waiting
I believe..
... I have finished all and I
have thrown out the bottle
Is it true what my mother has said to me?
That you are pregnant?
Yes, it's true
I wanted to tell you. I tried
to say it to you at Villalilla
- For this you left Rome?
- Yes, but still I did not know
- and he has followed you
here - followed? Who?
We were already all ended
before I came here...
... before I knew that I was...
... so.  I had found the strength...
... to overcome the loss.  I was alone, sad
I do not want to justify
myself, or to accuse to you
I was deprived of hope, so desparate
But I came after, you rather...
That which I have always said
for me, were worth also for you
We  are two friends, two free persons
At least you could...
It would have not been in order to reclaim
a right, but I never thought to have
I swore fidelity to you for always
For you it was different...
... but I...
There is one thing that I want to know
And it is uniquely important
Our life until now does
not interest me anymore
In these last days I have
returned from you many changes
- and yesterday at Villalilla...
- I pray to You... You I pray
I felt I have found you again and I
believed that you were agreed ...
... that it would have been beautiful
to recommence all from the beginning
For a moment I believed that
all that had happened...
... was that not a dream, a nightmare
It was you and I, like when we just married
You are sincere?
Nobody must suspect anything
Why?
You want that I remain with you?
Yes
I see that you are wide awake
I came to tell you that I am enrolled
in the international championship
I have need of your help. You will not
want that I dishonour the family?
I will have to be at least well placed.
You will come down?
- I'll catch up to you soon.
Good day, Giuliana
Good day, Federico
Touche, Bravo
Why do you not go you to the
championship in my place?
You still fence beautifully
In guard, Tullio
Calm boys, be careful
What are you doing?  Are you crazy?
Not right, tell me what's happened
Not now, I am tired
Boys now enough!
The doctor is with Giuliana .
If you want to speak to him,
All is good
But he wants Giuliana to
remain in bed some days...
... is more prudent. So, he
will talk to you. You go!
No, I am sweating, I want to change...
... I would make him wait
for me, make my excuses
It is useless to pretend
As you can yourself imagine,
mother has told me already
I am really happy. Also because therefore
she will stop tormenting me...
... to marry
An heir has been assured. Congratulations
Do you allow me to speak
them also to Giuliana?
Best not now
Better Mother had kept quiet.
Giuliana is not well
It is probable that she will not
carry this pregnancy through
But the doctor?  What does he feel?
There was another time, when
Giuliana was pregnant...
... a little after we were married...
... said that all was good
and it did not go at all well
If you left suddenly, against
the advice of the doctor well,
... my mother would make a tragedy.
Therefore
you will remain
here for some days
I meanwhile will go to Rome to
speak with Professor Magli...
... and to prepare all
However I will have to ask some details...
- In what month are you?
- I have ended the second...
... a few days ago
For how much of it I know,
it is not still dangerous...
... if  due precautions are taken
I do not understand
My love, you do not want to
carry the pregnancy ahead?
you have already had a miscarriage...
... and that will make a
second pass unnoticed
I speak for my mother, my brother and
for all those that I know already
To professor Magli I know what I must say
But I cannot
- you cannot what?  - I cannot
Because you cannot? Why you have
fear or because you do not want?
I cannot because it is a crime
A crime?
How can you think that I...?
While you can calmly give my name,...
... my affection to a stranger
This for you is not a crime?
Why do you not answer
I have said that I want to help you
I love you and I do not have
rancour for what you have done
I am grateful to you, very grateful, but...
But what?
you have said that is history...
... those refusals, that you
do not want to remember
are not true, because
if therefore it were...
... as you can think that...?
- Impossible, in fact. I recognize
I must always allow you.
Giuliana , the true crime
is what you want to commit
Before the remorse of having been
with another man torments you
... But of this guilt you
acquit yourself alone...
... and begin to torment to you instead for
the consequences of the relationship...
... and conditions acquittal with such
a hard punishment all the life...
... not only for you. You see
the absurdity of your behavior?
I am atheist...
... That does not mean that I do
not have moral problems, indeed
I face them with full knowledge
of all that it involves
Because I do not delegate to divinity
the decision of what is right
I Assume awareness of the responsibility...
... I know that my sins if sins I have...
... are not redeemed with repentance...
... or the inflicting  of punishments
I am a free man
the earth is my single country
because it does not live temporarily
my story begins and ends here...
... I do not have a hell to fear...
... neither heaven in which to hope
Secondly we can only count on ourselves
that is not a comfortable
solution that I propose to you...
... a solution that faces the
truth of the existence...
... that it is not
sheltered in the faith...
... of a God manifactured
from our fantasy...
... and of another life that
assigns the prize or pain
If I could think like you...
... to have your security
To live in fundamental freedom...
... without fears
Reflect, it is for you to decide
However, tomorrow I go to to you Rome
and I arrange all as I have said
You come after me soon
you must do me a favour
you must let me meet your
friend Filippo D'Arborio
and I must go to Rome for this?
If you write a letter, he will
be happy to come, we are friends
He will run, with the hope
of seeing Giuliana again
They met one evening at my house
and was as if struck by lightning
when he took her for a walk...
I do not want to invite him, I want...
... to see him at your house.
You invite him
and I will visit your house
It is a delicate matter which
I cannot explain to you
The mistake is mine. With this
warmth, we said to ourselves...
... that the gentleman will
not come back for sure
and since there was need, one
covered up downstairs...
... to make to beat the carpets,
therefore I have thought...
I want you to replace them
In about a week Madam arrives
- Who is in house? - the
cook, Virginia, Alfredo...
Sir has instructions?
Like?
Ah yes, I have need someone
to deliver a telegram
I will send the coachman
or if you want, I will go
OK I call when it's ready
Then?
I would have caught up to You, as I wrote
to you and as I have telegraphed to you...
Not even for a moment I have thought
that you would be returned so soon
you are contradicting yourself
you had thought of us
In fact today you have sent the
waiter here, then to Paris
I was not in anxiety, I did not have
your news, before I started my journey
You want to make me believe
... that you wanted truly
to catch up to me to Paris?
- No - you see?  I have done good to return
I believe that the truth never
does not say itself to four eyes
So many factors takes part in
the intimate relations, and...
... most times nothing is understood more
- But to understand what?
- That for you it is finished, my beloved
Time for the truth...
...  soon
It is not beautiful for a woman to be left
There are those ready companions
and they do not appeal to me
There are those that will put
in doubt her fascination
and this does not please me
You sent me a note when I was
already on the train, saying...
... that serious transactions of family...
Not even an employee of the land
registery would use such little words
has sincerely believed, to a catastrophe
I wanted to go to Paris, yes,
in order to amuse myself
I arrived in Paris and I
have not even unpacked
I am returned immediately, I
thought that you had problems...
... you would intend to have come to me
my friends will laugh for sure...
... when I will tell the
history to them of my defeat
What you say ? You still want
to have supper together?
As you prefer
- No compliments - Please, Teresa...
... You are only person in the world to
which I will perhaps be able to say...
has left me. I hope that there
is not another day, for us
Good evening.  I ask to excuse
My brother Federico, Contessa Raffo
Contessa. Osvaldo has said
to me that you were here
You are upset.  Insomnia,near enough
I have gone to do what you know,
but have not found my friend
I did not seen him again
before he left for the field
I did not know not even that he
had gone to Africa. In Africa,
to do what? Now he is found
in isolation in hospital
He has been taken by a very serious disease
also you perhaps know my friend
- writer Filippo D' Arborio
- I was introduced to him
I am one of his admirers
He is between life and
death, they have said to me
The truth is that they understand
nothing of tropical diseases...
... To the danger of the disease add
that too many do not know how to cure it
Sad news
I am sorry to be bearer of these... indeed
Come to me when you go
We will meet tomorrow, too late tonight
You come to me, I will wait for you
- As you wish
Good night
Know what I say to you?
I suffer less than how much you believed
Perhaps will come a day I will
listen what you have to tell me
What's happening?
- Nothing - What nothing?
the door was open . You said
to me to come to any hour
Ah yes, I wanted...
... I wanted to know in what
hospital is D'Arborio recovering
In the Policlinico block, they
do not allow approach to anybody
Now you must explain to
me what you want from him
When you asked me to know it...
... I do not hide to you
that I have thought
you feared that there was
something between...
... D'Arborio and Teresa Raffo
Logical , in as much as all the
gentlemen of Rome of are in love
On the other part, your Teresa Raffo,
without offenses, of course...
... are not at all type to refuse a whim
and instead nothing. They are
informed to me, who meet her
She has seeen only you...
... did not know not
even that you were sick
and so?  What are all these mysteries?
I cannot tell you anything
Is a issue that regards a personal friend
Beh, I go to sleep, day is made, by now
at least tell me when...
... when he has left for Africa
I inquire myself, but advise
your friend to leave it in peace
D'Arborio is ill, very ill. He
is a man who deserves respect
He is not only a great
writer also he is an angel
the only person , thinking next
to which I have a sense of shame
because?
It is those thoughts makes
us understand us, even you
We are intelligent, we have
travelled, we have studied...
... we amuse ourselves well
therefore, we are rich...
... and then?
- That piffle you are saying?
I do not know even that.  Goodnight
At what time are we going to the circle?
You must fight me again
I do not know
I do not know what happens tomorrow
- Goodnight - Goodnight
Good day. Mrs. Giuliana has
need of lighter clothes...
... and has sent me to take them.
The weather is warm in Badiola
mrs. has not said to you that she will
come in the next few days to Rome?
No, Sir
My excuses, my head!
These are from Mrs.
I have some jobs to do
on behalf of your mother
I hope to be able to leave this evening,
if the gentleman has instructions...
No, not anything, I will arrive before
I cannot do what you ask me
I prefer to go, to disappear
from your life...
... but I cannot commit a crime
- I have spoken about it also ...
- With who have you spoken of it ?
With my priest
Has it been him that advised
you to go through with it?
He approves of it, but he has let me decide
I hope that he will help to
give my name to the child
and why not its father?
He does not know anything
neither must he know it
Is that true or do you say words?
you know what it will happen
if you decide to leave me?
It is not important to me, none
of the scandal, that's very clear
But your situation as a single woman...
... that has deceived to save its
child depriving it of father
Be sure that your decision is
dictated only from yours...
... religion, or morals,
call them as you want...
... if I felt you were mine only mine...
... I could support anything
the sons are of him who
educates them and raises them
Hello?  Good day madam, it is nine o'clock
Come, come, I'm wide awake
have you seen it
It was known in Rome that
he was seriously sick
You have nothing to  say?  strange
What!
I would have sworn you
would have said about it
One disease taken in Africa?
Why you do not look at me?
What are you thinking?
Why do you torment yourself
Here is the doctor
I'll go meet him
Good evening, is the
obstetrician here already?
Yes
Come with me doctor
The doctor has come, the doctor!
- He comes at last, - doctor.
I must say one thing
and want to declare it
in presence of my mother
the last time that you visited my wife...
... you said to me that an
alternative could be introduced
It is very clear, and I assume
all the responsibility for it...
... that if this unfortunate
circumstance were to occur...
... we want to save the life of the mother
I hope that we will not face this choice
We are grateful however of being
exempt from all responsibility
- I know that the catholic religion...
- I know. No there is no need
It is an immoral, criminal law.
I do not regard it
Come doctor
Breaths
Good, long breaths
Calm
So , good
Mr. Tullio!  Mr. Tullio!
Mr. Tullio!  Mr. Tullio it's a boy
he has already opened his eyes
here safe and sound both.  we have done
Compliments.  A most beautiful child
All has gone well
Go also to the Madam, but do
not let anybody enter the room
She had a fleeting crisis. She
is well, but she is very weak
It is nothing, do not worry.
Yes, insomnia has one curious
psychical reaction...
... do not want to see the child, cry
How beautiful! God bless him
Raimondo, Raimondo, of grandmother
Tell the truth! he is not the most
beautiful child of the world?
Look at the eyes, I pray you make
a good impression of your uncle
Don't cry, treasure. Nothing
but to eat and to sleep
Look at the hands. It comes high, eh?
But how beautiful ,eh?
Like all the babies. The
foals distinguish themselves
- You saw what has been born to Zara - Beh?
Gray silver, one splendor.  But a child...
you say that in order to make me angry.
What do you know of children?
When you had been born you were most ugly.
Red, wrinkled...
... you were not at all like he.
Talk to Tullio, instead of making humour
You must say: Tullio your son
is as beautiful as the sun
- That must say I?  - Yes
Nanny, you close the windows against
the cold, it is an ugly day
You have fear of saying to him that
the foal is better than Raimondo?
Don't worry, Mother. I will say
that never has a wonder similar
been seen and that he is
proud of coming from father
Who is?
You joke, but I am deprived
of hope, deprived of hope
- But what do you say?
- But you do not have any idea
I do not take with Giuliana why
she has told the doctor...
... it was the reaction
to the state of tension
But your brother! So strange!
Before he was taking care for
her, and can understand it...
... but now that all has gone well
Do you know that he never
looked at the child?
Like if it did not exist,
nor even speak of it
only thing that your brother
has known tells me..
... is that if we want to christen
it, we do it on our behalf...
... without receptions, nothing
you had made me scared, that's all?
You know that Tullio is not religious.
He has his ideas
You want to say that the reception
we will make on an other occasion
- You care about this?  - Yes, a lot
and above all
Always blocks from him about that...
Hostile
But no, these are good news
For a while we will not have
the trouble of reception
and then Tullio and Giuliana
come to agreement...
... and are forgotting
even they have a son.
On, then all will be well
Tullio will come into church,
good like when he married
and Raimondo, it is decided that
Raimondo he will be called?
Your crazy husband has has decided
to make mother deprived of hope
It was better if you did not come, if you
had to make that apparition from devil
I have said to mother and the nanny to
come to drink a little champagne...
... therefore calm down
Are champagne,  not holy water
Come in
Oh!  Bravo, come, come
No, not here, go
Giuliana must not be made tired.
You go also
Let's go, Federico
Indeed, does it not please you if
we are here with you, Giuliana?
The doctor has said that if you can move
little, the effort would do you good
Come, make an effort
-Come away, Federico - For me
Go on, see you later
I want to prepare a beautiful
christmas to make peace with mother
You have some ideas
Do not count on me, I won't be here
So? You do not remain
here for the festivities?
Mother has told me for sure
I am sorry to disappoint her
but I have changed my mind
I do not make it
There is an atmosphere here,
than does not appeal to me
I wish well to all, but
I too have my problems
and I need to pass the few days
leave that I have peacefully
I will celebrate elsewhere
He has fed
I hoped to find him awake
He is well covered? It seems
to me that he has cold hands
- Shall we put his mittens on?
- No, no, Madam, do not worry
...he is beautifully warm
He is fast asleep, do not have fear
It is soothing for children
to hear our voices...
... to know that are not alone
I am going to sleep also , goodnight
Goodnight, Madam.
Nights I spy on you and that
I see you goto cosset it
Scream to the four winds
what you want , do not lie
have at least the courage to say truth
I have come here because
I seemed to feel a call
This has happened other times to me
I seem to feel a call as
if something had happened
It is not true, you were seen also
when you get up hidden in the dark...
... trying not to make noise
- What bad have I done?
Also you come here in the
night, the nanny has told me
It's true, it's true
But it is not the same thing
I try to discover your
secret by watching you
I try to overcome, to forget.
But I do not succeed!
Cursed be the day on which
I accepted this torture
You are not the same as when he is there.
You are happy!
So why do I not satiate
myself here to watch
and you are not the cure for my suffering
You I do love, and loving him
you think and love his father
You know that is not true
I have even wished that
he died when he was born
That is horrible, but is so
Also I feel anguish in his presence
Yes, I also hate him for the
suffering he brings to me
You cannot see that, why
do you not believe me?
It's true, I hate him.  I swear
You think thus?
Yes, because he has been put between us...
... and I would want that you and I...
Let's go away. We will
be happy away from here
We will leave after Christmas.
I promise you
Mother is downstairs.  We go to mass
- Fine. I will wait for to you here
- Your cape, madam.
Take that away.  You do not wear my gift?
It does not seem the right
event, it is too opulent
Nonsense, it pleases the peasants
to see their masters well dressed.
The bells have already played twice Madam!
We must hurry. - I am coming
Nanny, you can go to mass if you want.
I remain here
Thank you, Sir. I will go.
The child is fast asleep.
Goodnight, Sir.  Happy Christmas
Goodnight
Giuseppe, serve supper immediately
Of course,Madam...Immediately
and so this Christmas is passed
and we will leave here, as we have promised
After Christmas, but when?
When you want, tomorrow even
- Madam!  Madam!  - What is it?
- Come. The child does not breathe
- My God!
He does not breathe!  My God !?
Oh my God !  Oh my God!
I do not want you to go in there
Why?
Stay with me, I am so afraid.
Come
Mr. Hermil, Mr. Hermil!
No!  It is not true!  It is not true!!
He is dead?
Yes
Get off, do not touch me
- I am not your accomplice
- Be quiet, Giuliana, I beg you
- It is you
- Why do you say this? You knew all
The guilt is yours, yours. I hate you
Not, you have also said you hate him
No, I wanted to save him, with
all my strength, from you
- All I have done in order to save him
- But what are you saying
Yes, everything I have done with you,
I have only done in order to save him
and now, and for the rest of my days...
... I will have to living
with this sin on my spirit
My God, help me!
It will make you as unhappy as I am Tullio
You lie to yourself . You
have always wished him to die
Not even a moment have I
wished to be free of him...
... because I loved him
My poor creature, a thousand
times I disown those words
And well that you know that , therefore
you will understand that it is all ended
I have loved and I will love
always the father of that creature
Until the end of my days, you
I can only hate, hate...
... and despise you
Is extraordinary, the
faculty that women have ...
... to adapt the truth to the romantic
ideals of the worst literature
The adventure of my wife with
Filippo D'Arborio lasted...
..the time of a sigh
So like many of your friends have said...
...it would have been whimsy
of our fashionable writer...
... that it has been his fate to catch
a horrendous disease in Africa...
... that he has paid respect to his creator
All here. I am sorry to
only have contributed ...
... to supply elements for
this pessimistic serial
They will not think that really
it would have been you to have
caused the death of that innocent?
I do see it as strange when
a newly born child has...
... extraordinary resistance. It
takes more than the cold to kill it
And therefore, do not make remorse
If he is dead, it is sure
because it had one...
No, that does not have importance
What more concerns me are
the intentions that drive
and in my intentions there
are no possible doubts
I have I acted with perfect
clarity of conscience...
I do not have remorse,
I am not justifying it
The justice of men does
not touch me because
... no court on earth will
be able to convict me
I have bored you?  Sorry
Is still early.  We still can be together?
you would give me great pleasure
Your house pleases me
You know how many times I
have tried to imagine it...
... without ever succeeding
It's strange, because it is similar
Indeed
- With all that which is in you
- so beautiful... and so ugly
What is there ugly.  What we feel
slowly without haste
I must watch well...
... and to reflect
- you offer me something to drink?  - Sure
So?  You have decided?
What is ugly in me?
You want me to tell you
let me drink
I should not. I have drunk
a lot with supper...
you have put to Me a lot of...
... melancholy
Give me another
A little ago you have asked to me what
I thought about what you have told me
Now I say to you
I think you will always
be in love with your wife
Enamoured to make pity
That is not my spirit.
I admit I have had, in these past months...
... a drunken, clouded
experience, if you want morbid
Only pure ones are capable of such excesses
Think of the life of ascetics
You are still enamoured of her
Since the first time you were defeated
you are still fighting...
... because he has died.
Poor Tullio
But that nonsense you say?
If there is one defeated in
this lugubrious history...
... It is my wife
she that decides to live with
the ghosts of the cemetaries...
... instead of living her life freely
Refusing to believe
... that our problems are
resolved on the earth...
... and not in a hypothetical afterlife
I instead am what I am
Without illusions, without repentances
The day in which I will no
longer have pleasure for life...
... no curiosity...
... I would make an end of it.
There are those that say
instead when the moment comes
in which you stop living...
... you are only begun to exist
But if of it we do not explain
and if unfortunately we do not notice it...
... we hope for eternal life
That is not my case,  I swear
What do you know of it? It will
always be the same for you
and instead we know nothing of what
the future reserve us
Not even a little
... crazy with desire and jealousy
I committed many platitudes...
In order to suffocate my love for you
Goodness knows because you men...
... with one hand us you want
to always raise us to stars...
... and with the other drag us down?
Why do you not let us walk beside you?
Creature beside creature,
woman beside her man
None more, none less
Sure
I have decided to live with you...
Live with me?
But I do not love you more treasure
You are a monster
Not for what you have told me this evening
Further, that is not the
natural conclusion of all
You are the most attractive man who
has never held me in his arms...
... But if one day you persuaded me
of being the arbitrator of my life...
... I would not want to feel dishonourable
Now leave me Tullio
What happens if I lived here?
You sleep?  Perhaps
I have drunk too much
Do not sleep.  I beg You
Impossible.  I must sleep
Do not sleep, Teresa
I want to make you to see
that I know how to finish