Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Are you one of the patrol?
Yes
Good.
One of Ritai ' s men?
Yeah.
Fine, then cut him loose.
What are you looking at!
Don' t stop.
Hold the leg up.
Turn the head a bit.
Give me the knife.
Kekexi I i,
the last virgin
wi lderness of China.
This plain nearly
four mi les high,
is the only remaining habitat
of the Tibetan antelope.
In 1985
Poachers began hunting
antelopes for their fine wool
which was prized in
foreign markets.
Within a few years,
the number of antelopes plunged
from one mi I l ion to
under ten thousand.
To fight the poachers, a volunteer
civi I ian patrol was formed in 1993.
It was led by Ritai
a retired Tibetan army officer.
The patrol fought fierce
battles with the poachers
and aroused the attention
of the outside wor ld.
In the winter of 1996,
Poachers murdered
one of the patrolmen.
My newspaper quickly
sent me to cover the story.
(Tibetan)Hey Mister.
Take our picture. Good morning.
(Tibetan) Where' s Ritai?
(Tibetan)Ritai! Ritai!
(Tibetan)He' s over there!
(Tibetan)Thanks!
Good Morning.
I ' m Ritai.
I ' d I ike to interview you.
Who are you?
What?
Do you have some lD?
I ' m a reporter from Bei j ing.
I don' t have time.
Wait a second!
You want this place to be
declared as a nature preserve area
Maybe I can help.
(Tibetan)Dawa Dawa
Yes
Take him upstairs.
Your bag, fol low me.
(Tibetan)Prepare dinner.
(Tibetan)Okay.
You are...
Yangj in
Are you Ritai ' s daughter?
(Tibetan)Yes
What are you reading?
Just some documents.
Oh
(Tibetan)Get some rest.
Where' s Liu Dong?
Sit.
Here, have some meat.
(Tibetan)You' re cutt ing
in the wrong d i rect ion.
You understand Tibetan?
(Tibetan)My father' s a Tibetan.
Tibetan always point
knives toward themselves.
(Tibetan)Samba Cha Cha Cha...
Samba Samba Cha Cha Cha...
Dragon Dragon Cha Cha Cha...
You cheat, you lost it!
Liu Dong, dr ink up!
Let me dr ink it for him.
Liu Dong, let' s go.
Songj i.
What' s wrong? Where are you going?
(Tibetan)None of your business!
Honey, where are you going?
Liu Dong!
Liu Dong.
Yes.
Give me a hand.
Take your guns.
Ok
We' re going into
the mountains. Hop in.
(Tibetan)Come back al ive!
Take care yourself!
Midnight of November 1st, 1996
Here is a truck.
We have a check point here.
Can you catch poachers here?
Maybe.
We' re close to the
antelope breeding grounds.
They often pass by this road.
Where are you coming from?
Wudaol iang construction site.
Where are you going?
Ge' ermu.
We' re the mountain patrol.
We' I l check your cargo,
get out.
Do you have pelts with you?
No.
What are those?
It' s cotton!
One more time! What is it?
It' s antelope wool! Move over!
Get off!
What wi I l you do with him?
Let him go.
He' s just a carr ier.
We don' t have the power
to arrest anybody,
just to confiscate the pelts.
Day 2: Budong spr ings
conservation station
AWang, he' s a reporter
from Be i j ing.
He I lo!
He' I l make you a big star!
Alr ight!
Have a seat.
Here are the suppl ies
for this month.
Great! Put them in the corner.
AWang, hurry up with dinner.
(Tibetan)OK
My radio is broken.
What' s the latest news?
(Tibetan)Qiangba' s
not with us anymore.
(Tibetan)Chasing
another gir l?
He was ki I led.
You be careful!
(Tibetan song) I Give This
Song to the White Temple...
I Sing This Song for
the White Temple...
I Give This Song to
I Sing This Song for
the White Temple...
I Give This Song
to the White Temple...
I Sing This Song
for the White Temple...
Bless you! Be careful!
See you!
(Tibetan)Bless you!
He has stationed
there al I by himself...
Yes, he has been
there for three years.
He keeps the poachers away.
Three years...
We are short of hands.
we have no enough people
Day 3 : Zhuonai lake
403 404 405...
Are there al l
Tibetan ante lopes?
(Tibetan) Bastards
You! Come here!
Where are you from?
Suihua.
What are you
doing here?
Col lect ing worms.
Seen any poachers?
Yes
How many?
I don' t know.
What about you?
I saw some.
How many?
Don' t know.
Don' t I ie to us!
We c losed our eyes
when they started shoot i ng.
It was too dark,
we saw noth i ng.
Do you have a
f i sh i ng permit?
No
Fi ne them.
We bury more than 10, 000
ante lopes each year.
Day 5 : Yak Val ley
No gas.
It' s them!
They were here not along ago.
Let' s go.
Day 7 Cumar River
That' s them! Over there!
Stop! Al I of you!
Don' t move! Al I of you!
Hold it there!
Get down on the ground!
Take off your pants.
Cross the r iver.
Don' t move!
Down on the ground!
Al I of you!
Captain, they don' t
have pelts or guns!
Down on the ground!
Where' s his injury?
His leg.
There' s no hope.
It' s the artery.
I don' t want to die!
What' s your name?
Ma Rui.
Where are you from?
Hualong.
How old are you?
Have you ever
ki I led any antelopes?
Please help me!
(Tibetan prayer)
Take them across the r iver.
Hurry! Kneel down!
Ma Zhanl in, do you have
anything to say this time?
Let me have another coat...
I ' m freezing cold.
Where' s your boss?
We just skin them.
Don' t I ie!
That' s al I l do...
Tel I us the truth.
I don' t know anything...
re you the gunman?
No!
You' re the gunman!
No, I ' m not.
Then what do you do?
I ' m a dr iver.
Who' s the gunman?
I don' t know
Who knows?
My son i s not the gunman!
Who i s the gunman?
I rea I ly don' t know.
Who knows?
He knew! He h i red us.
Ma Zhan I i n, cut the crap!
I ' m just a dr iver...
You' re the gunman?
No! I ' m the dr iver!
Then te I l us who
the gunman i s?
I don' t know.
They' re lying.
I real ly don' t know.
They say you' re in charge.
They' re lying to
save themse lves.
Why are you st i I l
here if you' re the dr iver?
The truck broke down,
I couldn' t fix it.
They can' t see you now.
Talk!
I real ly don' t
know anything.
This is your last chance...
I real ly can' t help.
Talk!
I know nothing...
I just dr ive the truck...
I don' t know. I real ly don' t...
Talk to us!
I don' t know anything...
Talk!
I know nothing...
Talk to us!
Let me go
Talk now or
I ' I l shoot you!
I don' t know anything...
I know nothing...
Talk now or I ' I l shoot you!
Alr ight I ' I l tel I you.
Don' t ki I l me.
The pelts are here..
Dig!
They' re al I here.
There are more underneath...
How many do we have?
547, mostly female.
Now it' s the breeding season.
What a shame.
The gunman got away.
What about the
men you captured?
They were from
sma I l ca I i ber r i f les.
The real gunmen
use machine guns.
I ' ve been chas i ng
them for years.
Can I have one?
Thanks.
What do you do?
I skin the animals.
How much do they pay you?
Five Yuan for each pe lt.
I ' m the fastest
skinner in Ge' ermu.
Al I my chi ldren
are here too.
He' s my oldest,
the middle one and the youngest.
They' re al I skinners.
In the past,
I was a shepherd.
I herded sheep,
cattle and camels.
Now the grasslands
have turned into desert.
The sheep and cattle are
al I gone dead or sold off.
It' s tough to survive here.
I need to pee.
Me too.
Alr ight stop yel I ing.
Gayu hand me the bucket.
I want to pee.
Take your turn.
The gunman had to
cross this r iver...
if they' re head ing north.
It' s crossable.
(Tibetan) 1, 2, 3
Get up and he lp!
Who wants a dr ink?
Day 9
Rope.
Everyone gets a half.
I want more!
I haven' t had anything in days!
We are shar ing our food
with you! That' s al I you got!
Thank you.
(Tibetan song) Like
flowing water...
Oh, dear mother...
no matter how far I travel...
I shal I return...
Clouds of br i I l iant white
please del iver my message,
I long for home...
I pray for you
in my heart...
Get inside! Turn around!
Can' t sleep?
Air is thin up here.
It' s better outside the car.
Your nose is
bleeding again.
It' s alright.
It' s beautiful!
Isn' t it.
I get homesick every time
I go out on patrol.
Even the I ights in the
highway remind me of home.
But when I ' m home
I start thinking of Kekexi I i.
Do you know what does
Kekexi I i mean in Tibetan?
It means beaut iful
mountains and gi r ls.
Isn' t it.
In Kekexi I i,
each step may be the
first human footpr int ever,
ever in that spot
since the wor ld began.
Those are not my words.
Two years ago a geologist
came from Be i j ing.
I took him to Kekexi I i
and he said that to me.
Later the geologist
was miss ing.
No one has seen him since then.
There' s a lot of
quicksand around here.
(Tibetan)You idiot!
Where are the poachers?
Where are they?
Ma Zhanl in escaped with his sons.
When did you fal I asleep?
Around 5 AM.
Captain...
Let go of me!
Hunt them down!
Stop!
Stop! Did you hear me.
Get down! Down!
Watch him!
Get up!
Where' s the key?
I don' t have it.
I real ly don' t have it.
What' s this?
What' s wrong?
Pulmonary edema.
Water?
There isn' t any.
I can help...
Let him try, he was
a vet in Ge' ermu.
Hold his arm.
(Tibetan)Liu Dong, you take
Dawa back to see the doctor.
(Tibetan)Ping Cuo,
you should go back too.
(Tibetan)My shoulder
wound isn' t that bad.
(Tibetan) I can he lp
watch the pr isoners.
(Tibetan) Alr ight.
(Tibetan)We need money
for the doctor.
Give him some money.
It' s not enough.
Do we have more?
One the fine for the county.
Give it to him.
Sti I l not enough.
Se I l the pe lts.
I ' m going after the gunman,
you take the route
through Huatugou.
(Tibetan)OK
(Tibetan)Good Luck.
Good Luck.
(Tibetan)Goodbye.
Goodbye.
(Tibetan) Be safe.
Captain,
we' re almost out of food.
How many suppl ies
do we have left?
Two days.
not count ing the pr isoners.
Fue I ' s near ly gone too.
We should turn back...
No way!
How much fue I left?
Four days i f we
give up the truck.
That should be
enough to catch them.
Step back.
Remove the handcuffs
Ma Zhan I i n, every t ime
I catch you, you pay a f i ne.
Th i s t ime I am
lett i ng you go without a f i ne.
Rea I ly?
Yes.
I can' t make it back
from here, I ' m too old.
I don' t have food for you,
I ' m short of fue I too.
I ' m going after your boss.
I can' t take care of you.
I can' t make it.
Yes, you can.
There are 200 ki lometers
to the Al Mountain.
And 100 more to
the Kunlun Pass.
You can make it.
If you can' t make
it then it' s your fate.
Good luck.
May God be with you!
Day 10 Bugedaban Peak.
What' s wrong?
The engine' s gone.
Out of oi l.
Why d idn' t you
check the oi I before?
We' ve been going
non-stop for two days...
Can you fix it?
Wait here for Liu Dong.
Let' s go.
(Tibetan)Good luck.
(Tibetan)Good luck!
Can Liu Dong find them?
If it doesn' t snow...
Day 12
Day 15
(Tibetan) Doctor. Doctor.
(Tibetan)Get up, Get up.
(Tibetan) This bench is for
pat ients, Your fr iend is al r ight.
What do you want?
I ' m st i I l working.
Where have you
been for so long?
You' re a mess.
I ' m working. Let go of me.
Aren' t you cold in
those fishing net.
It' s my working outfit.
What do you want
from me anyway?
You look I ike a lunatic.
Are you playing deaf now?
I miss you!
You miss me but you
didn' t come to see me.
I went patrol I ing.
I thought you were dead.
I need some money.
You pul I this shit
every time I see you!
Lengxue.
Do you think I own a bank?
Did you spend my money
on other women?
I don' t know how you can
I ive that crazy I ife.
I just want to be with you
I ' m leav ing...
You' I l forget me soon.
And find yourse lf
another gi r l...
Lengxue..
Can Ma Zhanl in make
it out al ive?
What about your men?
I hope it doesn' t snow!
What' s wrong?
They' I l never find us.
We' re going to d ie here.
Shut up!
Your whole situation
looks pretty desperate.
We' re short of money,
short of men, short of guns.
My guys haven' t got
paid for almost a year.
Can the county he lp?
We' re not official ly employed.
How do you pay for the patrol?
We have to come up
with the money ourse lves.
What do you do with the pelts?
We hand most of them
to the author it ies.
Do you se I l some to
raise the money?
Se I l ing the pe lts is i I legal.
How should I wr ite
the art icle?
I always thought
I ' m a good journal ist...
I know you' re a reporter.
You think Kekexi I i is
protected by you reporters?
I ' I l go to pr ison if
I have to.
I know sel I ing
pelts is i I legal.
But I can' t worry
about that now.
Ever seen prostrators
on a pi lgr image?
The i r faces and
hands are fi lthy.
But their hearts are pure.
I sold pelts before,
I had no choice.
It' s highway on the other
side of the mountains.
We have to catch them
before they get there.
(Tibetan)Look around
for something to eat.
How much bul lets do we have?
A few dozen.
Yixi, what d id you do
before this?
I was a student.
Where?
Qinghai Normal University.
You should be a teacher.
This job is more interesting
Gayu, are you married?
No.
Girlfriend?
We broke up right before
I came here.
Just I ike my patrol,
each time they go out their
girlfriends leave them.
There are plenty nice girls
out there.
Isn' t that right, Yixi?
Right.
What did Bading do before?
A professional rabbits hunter.
Nonsense.
He worked at a
highway checkpoint.
For logging trucks.
They worked al I kind of
jobs before joined the team.
Liu Dong was a Taxi dr iver,
AWang was a soldier,
Songj i was a herder.
For you.
Have some!
Up in those mountains,
there' s nothing to eat.
Day 17
Can Yixi and Bading
find their way out?
I think so.
Should we wait for them here?
Ma Zhanl in, you' re sti I l al ive.
I am. But many died
on the way out.
My team got separated too.
This is captain Ritai,
This is our boss.
Captain, have a smoke.
I ' ve been chasing you
for years.
Why?
You ki I led my antelope.
So did a lot of people.
That' s no excuse.
So what do you want?
You come with me.
Captain,
if you let me off the hook.
I ' I l buy you two cars,
And I ' I l bui ld you
a new house too.
Our boss is kind,
And he' s r ich... Shut up!
Surrender your guns
and come with me.
Sure! Let' s give the
Captain our guns.
We' I l join his
mountains patrol...
Who fired?
Who fired the gun?
I did.
Fuck you.
You almost hit me.
He' s sti I l al ive.
Are you a patrolmen?
No, he' s not Ritai ' s guy.
You' re a dead man if you are!
He' s not.
Fol low our footpr ints for five
ki lometers to find the highway