I am Uhtred, son of Uhtred.
Defeated at Ethandun,
Earl Guthrum was baptised
and became King
Aethelstan of East Anglia.
While in Wessex, Aethelwold still sees
himself as the true heir to the throne.
I see it as a king would see it.
Yet, King Alfred has other plans.
I am to be married?
A permanent bond between
Wessex and Mercia.
Which one of you is Aethelred?
Alfred forced me to renew my allegiance.
He sent me to kill the Northmen
brothers, Erik and Sigefrid.
Argh! Aah!
After taking Sigefrid's
hand, I banished them.
You will take one ship and
you will leave Northumbria.
- You will not return.
- I swear.
And at last, in Northumbria, I
took my revenge against Kjartan
and his son, Sven, freeing
my enslaved sister, Thyra.
Let me help you.
Having defeated the Danes,
I married my love, Gisela.
And now all seems quiet.
But for a warrior there
can never be peace.
Destiny is all.
_
We're here.
Ground herahead.
And be ready.
She says she loves me.
- I swear! She says she loves me.
- She would.
Sihtric, she's a whore.
- No! She's past that.
- What she loves is your silver.
Is that the name of his cock?
I wish to marry her.
And I wish you to kill
Danes and survive the night.
We're the only chance
the villagers have.
They have begun.
Elgin, pass me the flask.
Ah...
If you wish to live, boy, take
your hand away from your sword.
Yah! Aah!
There will be no more than 30 raiders.
We hide and we wait.
We attack on my command, not before.
You all heard the Lord. We find cover.
Keep them moving.
Be quiet, woman!
Don't look at me!
Come on, come on! Stay together.
That's enough. You're
alive, girl, be thankful.
Elgin! Elgin, get up!
You can help rope the
prisoners. And keep them quiet!
Elgin!
Are you drunk?
Now!
We kill every bastard one of them!
To arms! Defend yourselves!
Run! Argh!
What's your name?
Her name is Aethelflaed, Lord.
- You're her mother?
- No, Lord.
King Alfred...
He has a daughter named Aethelflaed.
She's strong and brave.
You will need to be the same.
Go back to your village
and take care of your dead.
Finan?
Hang three of the dead from the
trees... visible from the river.
Lord.
Take back what belongs to you.
You're safe now.
You will go back to your rat's nest
and tell anyone who cares to listen...
Beyond Lunden, the River
Temes belongs to Alfred.
And it's guarded by
Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
Synced and corrected by rickSG
www.addic7ed.com
_
Now there's a welcome sight...
My wife and my boy!
Whoa! Oh-ho! I think we
might be feeding you too much.
Don't forget your
daughter, she's here too.
- It went well?
- It did, not a scratch.
You have a visitor.
He has been here all night.
Aethelwold.
How much of my ale have you drunk?
Not a cup.
Not a drop of ale has passed
my lips for ten days or more.
You've been ill?
Not ill, but... sober.
Which, as you know, is unlike me.
But it is important that
you accept that I am sober.
Say what you're here to say,
you have waited long enough.
The dead speak.
I have seen it, heard
it and the dead speak.
The dead?
A corpse.
I saw him rise from his grave and speak.
And what did this corpse say?
Well, what he said concerns us
both, us all, hence my visit,
and what I tell you are his
words, not mine, you understand?
And what did he say?
That I should be King.
No, believe me, it is true.
He said that I should be King of Wessex
and that you, you should be a king too.
He said that you, Uhtred,
will be crowned King of Mercia.
Bjorn heard it through
the three spinners.
Bjorn?
That is his name.
He is a Dane?
A dead Dane, yes. And
therefore, a good Dane.
We are royalty, you and l.
I have done my utmost to serve Alfred,
but with no reward, no
respon... Where are you going?
To wash the blood off
my hands and then to bed!
Do you not believe me?
Where did you see this corpse?
Mercia. Beyond Watling Street.
You crossed into Daneland?
I went to the part of Mercia that
Alfred gifted to the Danes, yes.
You happened to wander
across Watling Street?
I was sent for! I was invited!
And the same will happen to you.
I know what I saw.
You will be a queen.
I may not wish to be a queen.
When Bjorn is ready to speak,
there will be a messenger.
Tell me...
Do you wish Alfred harm?
No. No, of course not.
I mean, I wish him dead,
but I would not harm him.
I know what I saw.
I will not outstay my welcome.
Thank you for your kindness.
You are sworn to Alfred.
To become King of Mercia you
would need to break that oath.
If that is my fate.
Then you believe he speaks the truth?
No, I do not.
But I know he's not telling lies.
The truth is another matter.
We do not want an enemy such as Alfred.
And Alfred will not
want an enemy like me.
There appears to be good progress, Lord.
The people of Coccham
seem to be in good spirits.
- It would appear so.
- Welcome, Lord King.
We shall see.
Lord King.
Open the gates!
- Finan.
- What?
Lord King! Welcome to Coccham.
Finan.
Lord Uhtred is at the
fortress, the burh.
Would you fetch him, Finan?
We'll be waiting in the hall.
I will, Lord.
The man must have a priest
for each day of the year.
God be with you.
Lord, we are crossing into Wessex.
This stretch of river is
protected by Lord Uhtred.
You say you have trade there?
I do, Lord.
Lord, please, I cannot
risk losing my ship.
You will KEEP your ship.
It's easy enough to say it.
It is a pagan's hall.
Lord, you say the same
every time we visit.
Uhtred IS a pagan, as is his hall.
I find it annoying
that he will not grow.
He insists upon clinging
to these ancient beliefs.
The beliefs of our forefathers.
Who knew no better.
Lord King.
- Refreshment.
- Thank you, Gisela.
I, uh... I trust you are well?
I am, Lord, and better for your visit.
The ale is freshly brewed.
Ah! Excellent.
You are content in Wessex, I hope?
I am, Lord.
I am well, my family are well,
and there's peace, this is all I ask.
And what of you? Are you content?
My daughter is now old enough and
will soon be gifted in marriage,
I am...
apprehensive.
Aethelflaed is a sweet girl.
- She is.
- You are fond of her suitor, Lord?
Aethelred.
He serves a purpose. He is godly.
Well, we look forward to the
wedding celebrations in Winchester.
And I wish her... happiness.
The purpose of marriage is
not to be happy, my dear.
Then I am fortunate.
I pray my own wife might say the same!
Oh, I imagine she does,
Odda, she so rarely sees you.
Lord King. Lord Odda.
Steapa, my friend.
Uhtred, you do not deserve
such a charming wife.
Oh, I can only agree, Lord.
I was not expecting you,
there's been no message.
I'm hearing you've hanged a man.
I hanged many men just
lately. Raiders, Danes...
And already dead, Lord.
I'm speaking of a Saxon man,
a man of Coccham, of Wessex.
- That is why you're here?
- Amongst other concerns.
That man was a thief,
Lord. Sinful to the bone.
You hanged him without trial.
He was guilty. Three times over.
It is the purpose of a
trial to determine guilt.
People must witness justice being done.
Then I shall arrange a trial.
It's a little bit late for that, I fear.
Has there been a complaint, Lord?
There are laws, carefully written laws.
If you wish to remain an
ealdorman, you will adhere to them.
You shall not impose your
pagan ideals within my kingdom.
We are west of Watling Street, not east.
Yes, Lord.
We do not cross over into Daneland,
we do not cross over into Danelaw,
in mind, nor body, norspirit.
No, Lord.
My nephew... Aethelwold, he was, uh...
Well, he was seen doing just that.
Leaving Wessex, crossing
through Mercia from west to east.
Are you aware of this?
I am not.
When Aethelwold was here,
he mentioned nothing of
crossing into Daneland.
Hm, what did he mention?
He mentioned you, Lord,
and how you took his crown.
Aethelwold is permanently idle.
My advice is the same
as it has always been -
you should put him on
trial and then kill him.
Should the devil begin
to whisper in his ear,
then I may have no choice.
Besides the man you strung up,
how many of the raiders did you kill?
We killed about 30 men in total.
They had sacked a village.
- Which was in Mercia.
- Lord, we hear the screams at night.
Mercia is weak. Its people have
no protection from the Danes.
Mercia is disorganised
and that will change.
There will be burhs.
What is that?
That structure there?
It's a place for prayer, Lord.
A church, Uhtred?
Not quite, Lord. it's... a
shack, with a cross attached.
If it is for the purpose of
prayer, then it is a church.
Lord! A ship is near.
Traders.
Perhaps you'd like a
moment to pray, Lord?
I'll need to watch the trader.
Yes. Yes, I would like that.
Lord!
I was just thinking about you.
You were in my prayers, is what I mean.
Thank you, Hild.
Please continue, do not
let me disturb your peace.
Would you care to sit
with me? In peace, Lord?
I would, Hild. I will.
May I ask...?
Have you found your lasting peace?
I am near, Lord.
I feel more content here
with God than with my sword.
Courage without the sword
is the more difficult path.
It must, in time, become the only path.
I pray you find your
peace sooner than I.
Thank you, Lord.
You, stay with the ship.
Godwine, I was expecting you days ago.
Are you carrying the axe heads?
I am, Lord, Frankia-made.
Would split an oak tree.
- How many?
- How many do you need?
My man saw warriors aboard your ship.
Is this true?
Three men only, Lord. It is a Northman.
He wishes to speak with you. Alone.
Can I trust this Northman?
He says that you know him.
His name is Erik, he
has a brother, Sigefrid.
Finan... First sign of
trouble, fire the ship.
There'll be no need for fire, Lord.
Sihtric, fetch me a
whole bunch of torches.
I like to be prepared.
Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
Here you are, lost in Wessex once again.
I am sworn to King Alfred.
That is why I am here...
Why are you here?
I'm not looking to fight.
Not yet.
Can you believe I'm travelling
to meet with a dead man?
You deal in sorcery now?
It is my fate, or so I'm told.
You have my word that I will
make my appointment in Mercia
and then I shall return to Frankia.
Sigefrid is in Frankia?
He is, but not for much longer.
My brother is... restless.
We have grown strong in
the years since Northumbria.
We have a fleet now. 19 ships.
Which you will sail to where?
Oh, we have no firm plan,
other than to listen to Bjorn.
The dead man.
You say it without surprise, Uhtred.
I think you might have
gotten wind of this ghost.
He speaks the words
of the three spinners,
we cannot ignore him.
- "We"?
- You and l.
After his defeat at Ethandun,
the Earl Guthrum rejected our gods
and they are angry.
They want a revenge.
I believe we have been chosen.
You will receive your invitation,
you shall see for yourself, I'm sure.
What if I refuse to
meet with this ghost?
That is a matter for the
three spinners and the gods.
And what if I believe
this ghost to be a trap?
To be Sigefrid, wanting to kill me?
You have my word that
it is not. I swear.
All that we want is Uhtred
of Bebbanburg at our side.
Now, am I allowed to pass
to keep my own appointment?
You are.
Safe journey.
All the way back to Frankia.
Uhtred Ragnarson...
You will always have my respect.
But do not forget you
were raised as a Dane.
The broth was suitable, Lord?
- Mm, the broth was a delight, Gisela.
- As is the ale.
You should moderate, Odda, you have
a ladder to climb to find your bed.
You can always be carried, Lord.
It wouldn't be the first time!
And I guarantee it
won't be the last time.
Lord, you make me out to be a drunk.
Though my head will be sore
in the morning, I know it.
Well, then, it's ale for
breakfast, Lord! The only cure!
Was my nephew drunk
when he was here last?
Aethelwold is often drunk, Lord.
But this last time, he
did not touch a drop.
He mentioned he had been sober for days,
which came as a surprise.
- That's a miracle!
- Not quite.
Aethelwold is not a complete fool, Lord.
If he's idle, then could he
not help bring order to Mercia?
- He fought well at Ethandun.
- As he is fond of reminding people.
He's as good a man as Aethelred.
Uhtred, you speak of matters
you do not understand,
matters that do not concern you.
The safety of Wessex concerns me.
I'm happy to hear you say it.
Which is why we killed
the raiders, Lord.
Raiders who once
belonged to Earl Guthrum.
His name is now King Aethelstan.
That has been his name
since he became a Christian.
Regardless of what he is called,
it's his men who now break the peace.
- You are sure of this?
- I am.
They gather at the mouth of
the Temes river at Beamfleot.
It's true, Lord. 200
or more, we've seen it.
And the number grows.
If these rogues are Aethelstan's
men, then they are his worry.
Until they decide to
blockade the river, Lord.
Then Wessex will be starved of trade.
- Aethelstan shall deal with them.
- He must kill them.
I believe WE must kill them.
What we must do is hold the peace.
War cannot always be the answer.
Lord, forgive me, but you speak of
matters YOU do not fully understand.
These men will not listen to Aethelstan
and Aethelstan will not deal with them.
For now, they are rogues,
but should they find a lord to serve,
then they will become an army.
So answer me this. Where
might this lord come from?
Do I know of him?
Should I fear him?
You can be sure he will
not be called Uhtred, Lord,
if that is your meaning.
My advice, Lord, is to send
ships and men to Beamfleot.
We shall maintain the peace.
They say it is an honour
to have the King stay,
but his men and his
priests have eaten almost
a winter's worth of food.
Uhtred, how can you serve a
man who doesn't see your value?
Oh, he sees it, but his god
won't allow him to embrace it.
He dislikes me more by the day.
Then you should ask
him to release you...
and we will go north.
To my brother and to Ragnar.
I am content here, but we
cannot become an enemy of Alfred.
Lord!
Hild. You look fearsome.
I think I preferred you with a sword.
Ah, my sword has become heavy.
But you could probably kill
someone with that, though.
I need to speak to you plainly.
I would like to build a house,
a nunnery, here in Coccham,
but with your permission and
that of the bishop, of course.
The time is the right time.
You have my permission, no question.
Thank you.
And you have my protection.
Always.
Abbess Hild.
You will always be too
good a woman for God alone.
Alfred will be pleased.
_
Stow the oars! Make her secure.
- And, Haesten...
- Lord?
- Ensure the ships are guarded well.
- Yes, Lord.
The fortress of Beamfleot.
And all the men inside.
They are ours now.
Even the air is rich here.
Lunden is how far up river?
Half a day, with the tide.
We take it at the earliest.
And Uhtred?
As we planned.
_
Looking forward to the wedding, Father?
I am. I am, Father Beocca.
I enjoy a wedding as
much as the next drunkard.
And how is your own
lady, Father, the Dane?
Thyra? She is not my lady.
She's well.
She is something of a strange beauty.
Yes. She's, uh... She's...
Yes.
I inform God each evening how
much I miss the company of a woman.
He sends me nothing.
We talk, Thyra and l.
She's a pleasant woman.
There is no finer sight than that
of a naked woman, arms outstretched.
Almost there.
Lord? Lord?
Beocca, come in.
- Father Pyrlig.
- Good day, Lord.
I read of nothing but
skirmishes and raids.
What kind of a place must Daneland be?
- Sinful, Lord.
- Without question.
They aspire only to kill and fornicate.
Lord, are we to wait?
For a moment.
Lady Aelswith.
Lady, I'm begging your
pardon for my somewhat
colourful description of life as a Dane.
We are prepared, Lord.
- Father Pyrlig, I have a task for you.
- Lord.
You are familiar with
East Anglia, are you not?
I am, Lord, a land of
quite unremarkable beauty.
You are to go to King Aethelstan.
He may need help with the
reading of this letter.
Aethelstan.
He is to deal with the rogue
Danes at Beamfleot and swiftly.
- If you could emphasise swiftly.
- Emphasise swiftly.
You have been allocated a guard. They
are waiting for you in the stable.
- I am to leave now, Lord?
- Swiftly, Father.
May I say, I was somewhat looking
forward to the celebrations, Lord, the...
The whole of Winchester
shall be... celebrating...
Swiftly.
Yes, Lord. I will gather what I need.
Lord.
You are ready?
I am.
There is still a little
decorative work to be done.
Now, do not touch it, you
have ink on your hands.
Say what you think.
Do you like it?
I have not seen anything so beautiful.
- He does not deserve you.
- Did I not say the same?
I hope that Aethelred says the same.
Aethelred should consider himself
a very fortunate young man.
And in time, you will
grow fond of him, I'm sure.
I'm already fond of him.
0h, shush now, you've barely met him!
The last time, over a year ago.
Aethelred is a good and godly man.
Who is a little too fond of himself.
Will Uhtred be coming to the wedding?
Sadly, he will, I'm sure.
I consider him to be our lucky charm.
Now, now, there'll be no
mention of luck or charms.
There is God's will and nothing more.
Praise him.
Hold the horses.
Get some water.
It is fertile land, Lord.
No greener than Mercia.
Though Wessex does have
the advantage of not sharing
a border with the Welsh.
The Welsh to the west,
the Danes to the east
and Alfred to the south.
We're surrounded.
I would say we're perfectly positioned
at the very middle of
Alfred's idea of an England...
Pivotal.
Yes, I like that.
Lord? Lord!
Have you made a decision yet?
- Have you given it thought?
- Given thought to what?
Uhtred.
Well... my request to marry, Lord.
I... would like to have a family.
Lord, you will answer the man.
I will speak with her at
Winchester and give you my decision.
Thank you, Lord.
But you are to give her no more
of your arm-rings, nor silver!
If it is not the great Lord Uhtred
of the small and little-known
village of Coccham.
I see you're drinking again, Aethelwold.
It's just a cup or two, nothing more.
I have news for you.
You know where to find me.
Before you take yourself away to
an inn, I wish to speak with you.
About what?
Privately.
Uhtred, please. Let us not
rush to make an enemy of Alfred.
And if the dead man and
the gods say differently?
They will not, if they are truly gods.
And also...
This girl whom Sihtric loves,
you will not belittle her.
She's an alehouse whore.
And what is Aethelflaed? What
is a peace cow if not a whore?
There's a difference, clearly.
She will marry and be humped
by a man she does not know
and for a price.
Where's the difference?
- It's the way.
- She is a whore in a wedding gown.
If it is the way, then I
belong to your uncle still.
I will say no more.
Well, I am pleased to hear it.
Uhtred.
Uhtred, as always, it
begins as a joy to see you.
And you, Father Beocca.
- You look well.
- I am well.
Oh, I would like you
to meet Father Pyrlig.
Lord Uhtred, I've heard much about you.
Father Pyrlig here was
once a warrior himself.
Sword and spear, Lord,
but a man tires of sticking ironware
into the bellies of other men.
I would have enjoyed a
cup of ale with you both,
but I must leave you.
You have the letter secure?
I do, Father. I've put it
right next to my ball bag.
Lord Uhtred, it was an honour.
- Unusual priest.
- Yes.
Uhtred, there is a matter upon which
l find myself in need of
your advice... about Thyra.
Well, as I say, she's-she's
well, she's... delightful.
But my problem is this...
She... must leave, I feel.
Join you at Coccham or return to Ragnar.
You don't want her here?
No. Yes, I mean...
No, I do want her here, it's just
that l... l simply cannot think.
I can't work, I can't sleep.
It has been like this for months.
I mean, I can barely pray,
and even when I do pray,
I pray only for myself,
which is wrong, very wrong.
- Sinful.
- Wrong.
I didn't realise she had
become such a burden, Father.
I mean, she's not a burden.
She could never be a burden.
Then, Father, I'm lost.
Why must she leave?
Because I cannot think
of anything but her.
It is constant and it is
pathetic and hopeless because...
Well, she is fair and I am, Beocca,
a man old enough to be
her... much older brother.
- You're smiling.
- No.
You're laughing at me.
No, Father, I swear,
I'm not laughing at you.
- Well, I can see your teeth.
- I'm sharing your joy.
There is no joy.
I feel I am in a purgatory of sorts.
Thyra will not go to Ragnar.
She is happy here in
Winchester with you.
- Nonsense.
- Beocca, you are her peace. Her happiness.
- Marry her.
- Marry her?
You should marry her,
Father. And bed her.
And then give thanks to God
for giving us such a joy.
Praise him, Father. Praise Him!
But what if she refuses?
- Is that Aethelred?
- Hmm.
From what I know, Alfred could
not have chosen a bigger turd.
I've never met the man,
but by the look of him, he was
indeed shat out the arse of a giant.
He is to be King of
Mercia, they are saying.
The Ealdormen of the
Witan, they're saying.
The Lord of Mercia, perhaps.
Alfred would never allow
another Saxon to be called King.
Nor would a certain
dead man called Bjorn.
- He wishes to meet you.
- Come with me.
You're pinching my skin!
This was clean!
Why is it that you are being
trusted with my business?
- Who gave you this message?
- A skald. A pagan skald.
- His name?!
- Eilaf? Eilif?
Something Dane, something
odd! Are you any wiser?
No, you are not. I am a
messenger, nothing more.
Like it or not, we
are bonded, you and l.
- Bonded?
- Yes!
Our ancestors were kings and yet we
are barely acknowledged as Ealdormen!
We deserve more. You
especially deserve more.
As for me, I have a chamber
in the palace and that is it.
That is the sum of my land.
He has given me nothing.
I am no longer part of the Witan, even.
Uhtred, I can see you are torn,
but why should we stand by and watch
while power and wealth is given to
the likes of Aethelred of Mercia?
You were witness, you saw him just now,
riding through Winchester like
a peacock, like he was King!
When?
When am I to meet with Bjorn?
If we leave tonight,
we can be back here in two
days, in time for the wedding.
I am to take you there.
Watch him rise from his grave and
you will know that it is all true.
He will not ask again.
Lord!
Don't speak! Don't move!
We leave as soon as my
horses are cooled and fed.
The winds are blowing
a change, Lord King.
You'll be glad to hear that
I have made my decision.
You may marry this girl...
- Lord, thank you!
- Upon completion of a task.
You'll fetch Clapa, you'll go
to the stables and wait for me.
Ensure the horses are
watered and fed, but ready.
- Yes, Lord.
- Go.
And thank you, Lord. We will
name our first son Uhtred, Lord.
- No, you will not!
- No, I will not.
Thyra?
Beocca. You... you gave me a fright.
Forgive me.
Are you coming inside?
I have supper.
Something I needed to say, Thyra,
something I need to... to ask.
- You should ask it...
- Marry me!
I...I said... l said, marry me.
It was selfish of me to ask,
to even mention the word.
But... l fear you have become
someone I cannot live without.
You fear?
Life without you...
Fear no more.
I am here.
Always.
Supper?
Praise Him.
This is it.
Skalds' Hall.
It was given to Eilaf by
his lord, for great service.
Sihtric, you will go no further, not
until we are at the hall and inside.
- At all times, you will remain unseen.
- Yes, Lord.
If the dead man rises,
when he returns to his
grave, you will keep watching.
What if he sees me, Lord?
What if... what if he
knows that I'm near?
Then you shit yourself.
You will remain unseen and keep watch.
Yes, Lord.
There are men. Warriors.
We are here to see Eilaf, the Skald.
We have an invitation.
Who leads here?
- You?
- I do.
I am Haesten, and you
are Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
You spared me at Eoferwic, Lord.
You are expected and welcome.
Go take a piss.
- Who is he?
- A thief, Lord.
I serve Erik, Sigefrid's brother.
He sends you good wishes.
Erik is not here?
He is not, and if I had my way,
I would not be here.
My men are afraid.
Of ghosts?
It is not a sight you will forget.
My Lord wants you to know that by now
he will be at Beamfleot and not Frankia.
With Sigefrid?
And his brother and with the fleet.
He insisted you were told.
And where to after Beamfleot?
I can't say.
But it is hoped that
you will join us there.
Eilaf is resting, Lord,
in preparation for tonight.
You may wish to do the same.
They have a fleet. How many, I wonder?
19 ships.
That's more than 500 men,
plus those already there.
- And those who will come.
- Then, it has started.
What?
The end of the peace.
You stand too close, girl.
Do not make me speak to you again.
Once the marriage is made,
you should consider making
Aethelred earn his privilege.
Skirmishes and raids from the Danes
must not be tolerated, not one.
It should be made
Aethelred's responsibility.
And the Mercian Ealdormen should
be invited to attend a Wessex Witan.
For the purpose of what?
For the purpose of bowing to the King
and watching the Lord
of Mercia do the same.
I do not doubt for a
moment that Aethelred
has dreamt, is dreaming,
of overtaking me.
It would be a simple
reminder of his position.
Excuse me, Lord.
Odda. Come in, join us.
Lord, it is about both
something and nothing.
Sit.
Uhtred has left Winchester, last night.
- And gone where?
- We don't know for certain.
- And what of his current witch?
- His wife, dear.
The lady Gisela remains in Winchester.
Well, he can't have gone far.
Aethelwold is with Uhtred.
- They went in which direction?
- Mercia, Lord.
I think it is something
more than nothing, Odda,
and I am wholly tired at
never-ending disobedience.
But it will not ruin
your appetite, Lord.
It will not.
Put a watch on Gisela.
She must not leave
until her husband has returned
and explained his absence.
Father Beocca.
Lord. Lord, Lady, I have news.
Uhtred has returned?
From where, Lord?
What is your news, Father Beocca?
I am to be married.
The once proud and brave Earl Guthrum.
He now calls himself a Christian!
He now calls himself King Aethelstan,
but he's nothing but Alfred's
hound, and he's shamed us all!
He has shamed every warrior
that has gone before us!
He has shamed the gods!
And the gods call upon every man
gathered here today to avenge them!
And avenge them we will!
By sunrise tomorrow, Lunden and
all of its riches shall be yours!
Believe me when I tell
you, the gods are with us!
The gods are with us!
_
Forgive me for not being
awake to greet you, Lord.
Bjorn has given me little
rest these recent times.
We understand.
The gods are wanting true men.
So, I thank you for being
here, Uhtred of Bebbanburg.
After tonight, I hope to sleep.
Fetch the blood.
It is time.
It's a Christian graveyard.
Yes, Lord.
Perhaps that is why Bjorn cannot rest...
Nor pass.
Please, no. Please. Please!
To raise the dead, Lord, we need
to send a messenger across the gulf.
- He is guilty?
- Twice over.
Please, I beg you, Lord, please! I
have a wife, I have children! Please!
- What did you steal?
- Just a lamb, Lord, for my family.
- And furs.
- For my family, Lord!
I'm sorry, but a thief
twice over deserves to die.
- No! Please, please!
- Put it in his mouth.
Please, no, please,
Lord, I beg you, please!
I can fight, I can work, I can serve
you, Lord! Please, I beg of you!
I am on your side, Lord!
What is it? Please!
No, Lord, please, no!
Shhh.
A harp string, Lord. A bridge
from our world to Bjorn's.
Kill him.
No, please, Lord!
Please, Lord, no, please!
Get the message into
his mouth and kill him.
Spare me! Spare me and I
will repay you with gratitude!
Please, Lord! Please, Lord!
Bjorn, you have blood.
I have given you life.
I have sent you a message.
If it's peace that you want,
you shall not have it
until we hear you speak.
The harp string.
Welcome, Bjorn. This is Lord Uhtred,
who has sent a good many Dane
to the place where you live.
I do not live.
You have a message for Lord Uhtred.
Lord Uhtred. I see you now.
The gods have had their
sacrifice and the brothers
have tonight begun that
which cannot be stopped.
Lunden's streets are
red with Saxon blood.
You are to be King.
King of Mercia, King of Saxon and Dane.
King of other kings.
You, Lord Uhtred.
Bury him.
Lord King? It is done.
What we have just witnessed.
Do you believe it to be true?
I do.
And me.
It put a shiver through
your spine, no doubt.
So, what now? You are sworn to Alfred.
Alfred is nothing compared
to the gods, I would suggest.
Uhtred, it is our birth-right
to be called kings.
Haesten!
Lord?
The brothers Sigefrid and Erik,
is it true what Bjorn says?
They're attacking Lunden?
I cannot say for certain,
Lord, but that was the plan,
to sail upriver and take Lunden,
which would now be your city,
as King of Mercia.
Synced and corrected by rickSG
www.addic7ed.com