Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
I'm inviting you for breakfast.
I can't.
I have to go to church.
Well, after church then.
Come on,
we haven't seen you for so long.
Why don't you put this on,
because
I don't want your little baby
to get sick.
It's so cold out.
- Come on!
- Okay.
Okay?
You'll come?
Oh, yeah.
Great!
- Could you put the whole thing on?
- Oh, yeah. - Okay.
See you.
You owe me five dollars.
Not till he's sitting at the table.
I don't owe you anything yet.
Something's going on with him.
I'm worried.
You keep saying that.
I think your...
Your maternal instincts
might be kicking in.
In all the world,
there are books and books
and books of laws.
But in all this world,
there really is only one Lord.
We need never ask:
"Lord, what should I do?",
because the Lord
has told us what to do.
"Love one another."
That, my friends,
is the one true law.
Love is God in action.
The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ,
the love of God,
the fellowship of the Holy Spirit,
be with you all now and forever more.
- Amen.
Hi, Mrs. Gruner.
Do you want some help?
- Thank you, dear.
- Okay.
It's my turn
to drop them off at the hospital.
You're a good-looking fellow, Lars.
Where's your girlfriend?
I don't have one.
- Are you gay?
- No.
My grandson's gay,
I know all about the gays.
I know, but I'm not gay, so...
- Well, don't leave it too long.
It's not good for you. - Okay.
Here.
Give this to somebody nice.
For a start.
Hello, Lars.
I guess...
- I'll see you at work tomorrow.
- Yeah, okay. Bye.
Karin, my brother is 27-years-old.
Maybe he wants to be left alone.
- That's not what he wants.
- Really? Hey, just...
Go.
How do you know that exactly?
Because that's not how people are.
There he goes.
Lars! Come on, you promised!
- Is that normal?
- Five dollars.
Morning!
Good morning, Cindy.
Did you have a nice weekend?
That new girl's kind of cute, huh?
You and Margo!
What do you think?
Lars, you've got to see this!
I'm not really in the mood
for porn this morning.
It's not porn.
Okay, it is,
but check it out, alright?
You like?
Man, it's solid!
If she'd weigh 125 pounds,
then she weighs 125 pounds.
Is that right?
You can customize everything.
They've got different heads and parts.
You can design your own woman!
And, Lars...
- Lars!
- Yeah?
They're anatomically correct.
You aren't going to buy one, are you?
I wish.
Look how much they cost.
I'm wiped out from the X-box.
Morning.
- Morning!
- Oh, hey! Yeah. Morning!
Margo's here, everybody!
Hurray!
Could you put the headset on?
I was thinking,
we're the only ones from the lake.
We could carpool.
Lars, it's your day for coffee, buddy.
Oh, yeah.
You know what your problem is?
You're just too aggressive.
- Just chillax, you know?
- Shut up.
Wait. Stop.
Stop!
Karin! What? What?
We want you to come for dinner.
Will you come?
You scared me.
- Sorry! Sorry.
- You scared me.
Oh, sweetheart. Sorry.
Wait.
- It's okay. I can't. I can't.
- Why not? No!
Why not?
Come on, Lars, we miss you.
I brought my work home, so I have to...
I'll get in trouble.
No, you didn't.
Did you hear that?
That's my phone, I think.
No, come on, wait! Wait!
Lars! Stop! Stop!
- Come on, please?
- I have other plans.
And I can't.
Lars, there's salmon
and cherry pie in there.
- Could you please let me go?
- No.
Okay.
Is that all you can eat?
- Yeah, that was delicious. Thank you.
- Okay.
No, no, you stay there.
No, it's my turn.
You boys talk.
Okay...
Karin's been worried about you.
She thinks you've got a problem because
you spend so much time by yourself.
I'm fine.
That's what I told her.
That's exactly what I said.
Okay.
Dad was kind of like that too, so...
Yeah, but he didn't want
anyone around. That's the difference.
That's not true.
Okay. You know? Yeah, sure,
maybe after mom died,
but you didn't even know him
before that. So...
I mean, not that you could have,
but I'm just saying...
Karin and I would really like it
if you moved in.
No, that's okay. Thank you.
The house is half yours.
I know, but I'm fine, thanks.
I'm just putting it out there.
- Well, goodnight. Sleep tight.
- Goodnight.
Wait.
Here's some leftovers for you.
Do you have my blanket?
- Oh, yeah. It's on the...
- I'll get it. Grab these.
I'll be right back.
It's a beautiful blanket.
- Gus says your mother made it for you.
- Yeah.
When she was pregnant.
She must have loved you very much,
like we do.
- Are you mad at me?
- Is he coming?
- Here we go. - Goodnight.
- Thanks. Goodnight.
What?
We talked, he's fine.
6 weeks later...
- Hello?
- Hey, Lars. It's Karin.
They just delivered
a huge box for you.
It's in the garage.
- Okay, thanks.
- Okay, bye.
Thanks.
That's a nice sweater.
Hey!
Come on in.
That's okay.
Is Karin gonna come to the door?
Karin!
Yeah?
Honey, come here, it's Lars!
- Really?
- Yeah.
She's just doing some kind of...
It's pregnant women's yoga.
No, it's good.
It's good, good stuff.
- Hey.
- Hi.
What's up?
I have a visitor.
- You have?
- In the garage?
- Now?
- Yeah.
A visitor?
That's great!
Yeah.
And she's not from here.
She?
Yeah.
Wow, what do you know?
Where did you meet this person?
- On the Internet.
- Yeah, everybody's doing that now.
That's great!
She doesn't speak much English, though.
That's okay.
It's the same with the guys at work.
- It's not that big a deal.
- Okay.
Oh, yeah.
You know, she's in a wheelchair,
so I don't want her
to feel weird about it.
- We don't care.
- Oh, no. No.
Okay.
And I have to ask you a really...
I know it's a really big favor.
Yeah.
Well...
She's really religious and,
because we're both young and single,
it doesn't feel right for us
to stay in the garage alone together.
No.
We'll put her in the pink room.
- She could sleep here.
- In the pink room? - Yeah!
- Okay.
- Sure! And there are new towels.
Just give us half an hour to pick up
and get something in the oven.
- Okey-dokey.
- Let's get the place ready.
Okay. Let's get started!
Man, that is...
You quiet ones...
You know what they say.
It's great. It's great.
See you in a little bit.
- Okay.
You know, Bianca's a missionary.
Was a missionary.
Right, sorry.
She was raised by nuns.
But now she's on a sabbatical,
she can experience the world.
Isn't that neat?
She's shy.
Well, you are.
Everything's so new
for her. Right?
- Are you hungry?
- We're starving.
Gus, will you give me
a hand in the kitchen?
How was that?
I know.
He's out of his mind.
Oh, my God!
It seems crazy, right?
I mean, he's crazy!
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know. - What are we gonna do?
Oh, my God!
We have to put him in a hospital,
I think.
I can't afford that.
Karin, I can't believe this.
My little brother is totally insane!
- Pull yourself together.
- How am I? - Gus!
- Calm down! - How can I?
- Calm down, okay? Now!
He's talking to a doll!
We've just got to get
through this somehow, okay?
- I don't know how we're gonna
do that. - Me neither.
But you've gotta be calm.
Okay?
Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Karin, she's not gonna eat!
You're never gonna believe this.
It makes me mad.
Bianca's from the tropics.
She's Brazilian.
Well, half Brazilian, half Danish,
that's right.
And somebody stole her luggage.
Yeah!
And they stole her wheelchair.
That's terrible.
Yeah!
Can you believe that, Gus?
- Yeah, I can't believe it.
- Right.
Well, it makes me angry.
Anyway...
I wanted to ask you a favor.
She doesn't mind, I promise.
Karin, would you mind lending Bianca
some clothes? She doesn't have any.
Do you?
I'm not sure we're the same type, Lars.
That's okay, Karin, because
Bianca doesn't care about superficial
things like that, so it's okay.
- Sure.
- Yeah, that's right.
See? I told you.
Thanks.
This used to be my mom's room.
So...
If you need anything,
Gus and Karin are across the hall.
I'm in the garage.
You know that, so what else?
Your towels are brand-new,
thanks to Karin.
Lars, I think we should go to bed.
Oh, okay.
Just one second.
I just wanted to say
I'm so glad you're finally here.
I think right now...
Yeah. Okay, goodnight.
Wait!
Gus had a good idea.
He's concerned about Bianca's health.
You know, with the traveling,
the change of climate, and everything...
Well, it's stress, you know?
I'll make an appointment
with Doctor Berman for tomorrow.
For early tomorrow.
We'll all go.
Yeah. You remember Dagmar?
- Okay. Do you think that's a good idea?
- I do. I think we should do it.
Yeah.
- That's a good idea, I was gonna go...
- Let's go to bed.
...shopping for wheelchairs, anyway.
- So, goodnight.
- Night.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh, my God.
Natasha escaped from Moscow,
where she was forced to strip
for the Russian mob.
Now all she wants is
an all-American male to love.
Midori left a high-paying job in Tokyo
because she was unsatisfied as a woman.
Tammy dropped out of high school
to join the rodeo.
Are you the right cowboy
to tame this wild filly?
The doctor will tell us what to do.
But she's family practice.
We need a shrink.
No, she's a psychologist, too.
She says you have to be,
this far north.
What'll people think?
We can't worry about that.
Right.
Right there
is where my dad used to work.
Our dad.
That's the library. I have a card,
you can borrow it if you want to.
Actually, I'll have to take them out
for you, but you just tell me.
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know, actually. Gus?
What was it that dad did?
Water and Power.
My job's at the School Department.
I miss everybody, but there's
so much to do in the house.
I'll go back
as soon as the baby's old enough and...
Yeah. Sure.
"Reader's Digest",
"Midwest Living" or "Country Home"?
That's what I would say.
Well, her blood pressure's low.
- Is that serious? - Could be.
We'll have to wait and see.
It's fine.
Mine's probably low, too.
I...
I want you to bring her in
every week for a special treatment.
Can you do that?
Are you sure that's necessary?
- Yes.
- Okay. Okay.
What do you think?
If that's what she says,
then we should.
Okay.
You can set that up with Joanna,
at the desk.
I look forward
to getting to know you, Bianca.
- Karin, I'm telling you,
he belongs in a hospital! - No!
My Uncle Garth went to one
of those places and never came back.
But he needs more help
than we are able to give.
- I told you something was wrong
and you wouldn't listen! - If I may.
Has Lars been functional?
Does he go to work,
wash, dress himself?
So far.
Has he had any violent episodes?
No! No, never. He's a sweetheart,
he never even raises his voice.
Okay.
We gotta fix him.
Can you fix him?
I don't know, Gus.
I don't believe he's psychotic
or schizophrenic.
I don't think this is caused by genes
or faulty wiring in the brain.
So, what the hell is going on then?
He appears to have a delusion.
A delusion?
What the hell is he doing
with a delusion, for Christ's sake?
That's what we have to find out.
Chances are he's been
decompensating for some time.
I guess we didn't realize.
Have there been any changes
in the family in the last year or so?
No, everything is
pretty much exactly the same,
except that Karin is pregnant
and Lars is nuts.
You know, this isn't
necessarily a bad thing.
What we call mental illness
isn't always just an illness.
It can be a communication,
a way to work something out.
Fantastic.
When will it be over?
When he doesn't need it anymore.
How can we help?
- Go along with it.
- Oh, no. No, that's...
Oh, my! No, no, no.
I mean, pretend that she's real?
I can't.
I'm just not gonna do it.
- She is real.
- Well... - I mean,
she's right out there.
Right. I get that.
But I'm not gonna do it.
You won't be able
to change his mind anyway.
Bianca's in town for a reason.
- Right, but...
- It's not really a choice.
Okay. Okay. Alright.
Then we'll do it. Whatever it takes.
Oh, yeah.
And everyone's gonna laugh at him.
And you.
She loves kids.
- More coffee, Lars?
- Yes, please.
You see the funny face?
Does Bianca want some?
Yeah.
- There you go.
- Thank you, Karin.
Gus? No? Okay.
Sure.
Are you not gonna
go to work today, Gus?
- I don't feel good.
- Oh, no.
Bianca could help you.
She has nurse's training.
No, she doesn't. She doesn't
have nurse's training, Lars,
because she's not a person.
She's a big plastic thing.
That's amazing.
Did you hear that?
Bianca just said that's why
God made her, to help people.
Are you gonna be late?
For work?
I am gonna be late.
I have to go.
Okay.
But I'm going to check in.
Okey-doke.
- You have my number at work,
right, Karin? - Yeah.
I wanted to tell you
you look really pretty today.
I hope you feel better, Gus.
Me, too.
- And thanks so much for breakfast.
- No.
- Okay, gotta go. Bye!
- See you!
Well, I had to try. You know...
- What? What? What?
- It's just... I don't know.
It's true. We've been all wrapped up
in ourselves. We have, Gus!
This is not my fault, though.
It's not my fault.
Come on, Bianca.
Let's make a couple of calls.
Good morning, Cindy.
You look pretty today.
Thank you.
Oh, Mr. Sunshine...
It's way in advance, but you know
how excited I get about these things.
- Where are they? I know you took them.
- Did not. - You did, too. As revenge.
- For what?
- The fake rat I put in your drawer.
Oh, that.
Lars, I'm missing 3
of my action figures.
It's your turn to get coffee.
Listen up, Margo. Those action figures
are extremely important to me.
They're worth a lot of money.
If I don't see every damn one
back on my desk soon,
you can tell your teddy bear
to watch his back.
I'll return them.
One at a time.
- Are you going to Cindy's party?
- Oh, no.
I was hoping you would.
I really wish you would.
Well, maybe.
That'd be great!
Do you think
I could bring my girlfriend?
Yeah!
Yeah. I mean,
I'm totally bringing somebody.
Wow.
I didn't know there were sex dolls!
Love dolls.
That's what they call them.
I saw a special on cable.
So you're serious?
Bianca really has a...
She's really
just one of the girls then.
I'm sorry.
Que un hombre se compro
una muneca que se infla...
Le salen las tetas asi,
el tipo se la come...
Sale volando.
No way!
Does she have a sister?
I wish I had a woman
that couldn't talk.
It's not that funny.
We don't want anything to do with her.
She's a golden calf.
We all know what happened with that.
He's not worshipping her.
They're just dating?
These young people have no willpower!
He's sick, alright? He's sick.
We were just hoping, if we came to you,
you could help pave the way a little.
If you could just try to understand...
- He is a nice man.
- We can try.
- I don't know why we're here.
- Oh, for Heaven's sake!
What's the big deal?
Sally, your cousin
puts dresses on his cats.
Hazel, your nephew
gave all his money to a UFO club.
Arnie, everybody knows
your first wife was a klepto.
- She wasn't! - Why is she buried
in a pair of my earrings?
That's enough.
These things happen.
Lars is a good boy.
You can depend on me.
Thanks, Mrs. Gruner.
Well, he's not bringing her to church,
is he, Reverend Bock?
Well...
The question is, as always,
what would Jesus do?
#Oh, Holy, Holy,
merciful and mighty. #
#God in three Persons.
Blessed Trinity. #
I would like to take the opportunity
to welcome all of our new visitors
to our church today.
Bianca, it's good to see you.
Lars, God bless. God bless.
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
- Watch yourself.
- Easy, easy.
These are for you, Bianca.
Thank you.
Bianca, this is my friend,
Mrs. Gruner.
She has a darling figure.
Those are nice. They're not real,
so they'll last forever. Isn't that neat?
Hello.
Get back here!
There we go.
Watch your head on the way in.
Watch, watch!
There we go.
Are you comfortable?
I'll get the chair.
Can you put her seatbelt on?
Bianca, Gus is gonna
put on your seatbelt.
- And put that on her legs.
She gets cold. Thank you. - Yeah.
Thanks, Gus.
Where are you guys going?
Just one second.
She doesn't know. It's a secret.
But I can tell you.
She's asking questions all the time
and wants to know all about me,
so I thought I'd take her
to the lake, where we used to play.
- Yeah.
- Do you remember that? - Yeah.
That sounds nice.
Yeah. I gotta go.
I'm coming
Why are you yelling?
Gus and his friends
used to come up here all the time.
In the summer they'd go fishing.
In the winter they'd play hockey.
Watch your head.
Here we go.
That's okay.
This was our tree-house.
The rope's here.
And the ladder.
#L is for the way you look at me, #
#O is for the only one I see, #
#V is very, very extraordinary, #
#E is even more
than anyone that you adore. #
#And love
is all that I can give to you, #
#Love
is more than just a game for two. #
#Two in love can make it... #
You should watch me
chop wood, too.
I'm really good at it.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't wait.
I wanted to see how she was doing.
After the treatment, she has to rest.
It doesn't work without the resting.
Keep me company?
Lars?
Keep me company.
Do you know how many sessions
she's gonna have to have?
No. I don't, it's a tricky illness.
But, what I could use
is a more complete history on her.
- Parents...
- They died when she was a baby.
- That's not fair.
- Yeah, but...
She doesn't feel sorry
for herself or anything.
She just wants to be normal,
have everyone treat her normal.
- That's nice. I admire that.
- Me too. Is that your husband?
- Yes. He died.
- Oh, no.
I'm sorry.
- Do you have kids?
- No.
You must get really lonely.
Sometimes I get so lonely,
I forget what day it is and
how to spell my name.
How about you?
You're funny.
So what's the difference between
a delusion and a hallucination?
It's false perception
versus false belief.
- So when Moose thinks
the FBI's after him... - The DEA.
- INS.
- IRS. ATF. AAA.
That would be a delusion.
Hey, dude,
they are after us.
My dad told me that
wood warms you three times:
First when you chop down a tree,
then when you chop it up...
- What are we doing? Why are we
doing this for him? - Come on.
It's funny.
Is it?
I don't know.
Maybe not.
So tell me about Karin.
- I don't know her very well.
- She's wonderful!
Gus and I are both very lucky
with women. She's wonderful.
But she...
We don't have to talk.
Let's find you something to read.
- No, it's just... Between us?
- Of course.
I'm worried about her.
I think she has a little problem.
- Maybe you shouldn't tell me.
- No, it's okay. It's just...
And I think it's
'cause she's insecure, but
she's just always
trying to hug everybody.
You know, some people don't like that!
Some people don't like to be hugged.
But she doesn't realize that.
She takes it personally, and thinks...
You know?
It hurts her feelings.
I don't know what to do about that.
Do you?
But it's such a comfort sometimes,
to have somebody's arms around you.
Don't you think?
- No.
- Come on, it feels good.
It does not feel good.
It hurts.
Like a cut or a bruise?
Like a burn. Like when you go outside
and your feet freeze
and then you come back in
and they thaw out. It's like that.
It's almost exactly like that.
Same with everybody?
Well, not really with Bianca.
But everyone else.
So, you don't let people touch you.
Lars, isn't that hard
to get away with?
Not really here,
'cause I have all these layers.
- And that helps.
- Look...
We can't change Karin.
But I can help you.
That's fine.
Pain?
Yeah, but I can take it.
Are you okay?
- Well, that's enough for today.
- Yeah. Thanks.
What?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Well, it's scientifically proven
that everyone's favorite word
is their own name, so
if you just
say their names a lot, you're okay.
You can see
it's gonna make them happy.
Okay.
Yeah.
Okay...
Mr. Sunshine!
And this must be Bianca. Welcome!
Welcome. Come on in!
I have my boots on,
but I brought my shoes.
Don't worry about it. Baxter?
Baxter, baby.
Lars, this is my husband.
Hi, Lars.
Bianca...
How are you?
Is that for me, Bianca?
Thank you!
Can Baxter get you two
something to drink from the kitchen?
Lars?
I'll have a beer.
And for Bianca?
She doesn't drink.
She doesn't like it when I drink either,
but I'm just gonna have one.
I can help you with your coats.
Hi. This is Margo.
And this is Bianca.
Hi. Hi, Bianca.
I'm glad you sent around that memo.
I would have freaked.
It's so bizarre.
- It's a disorder.
- What a weirdo.
Lars?
Look at him. He's in love
with that slutty hunk of silicone.
- Her name's Bianca.
- Does he have sex with her?
Babe, that's what she's for.
- So, I hear you guys
are getting married! - Yes! - No!
Tickle fight!
I would kill to have hair like hers.
Oh, I'd cut it to here,
long in front, short in back.
Lars would never let her cut it.
Guys and long hair...
I don't care.
However she likes it,
that's how I like it.
That's my kind of guy.
I need wine.
I'll get it.
- Anyone else?
- Oh, no. - No, thanks.
Dude...
Hey, Lars.
Bianca? Total babe.
- Thanks. - The best thing is,
she doesn't know how hot she is.
That's what you want in a woman.
They stay with you,
'cause they don't know
they could get somebody better.
You know what I'm saying?
Is she flexible?
Yes.
Did you have fun?
Yeah.
I'm just happy, that's all.
And so he solaced himself
with pacing up and down the meadow
and writing and carving
on the bark of the trees
and on the fine sand
a multitude of verses,
all in harmony with his sadness.
In sum and praise of Dulcinea.
But what distressed him greatly
was not having another hermit there
to confess him.
Pain?
That's okay.
I can take that.
You must be excited
about a baby on the way.
Don't you want to be an uncle?
Yeah...
- Do you ever wanna be a mom?
- I don't know.
Yes.
But I'm not able
to have children of my own.
Oh, that's too bad.
Bianca's like that, actually.
She can't have babies, either.
That's a shame.
When she was a baby,
her mom died in the middle of things
when she was being born.
Like yours.
You have a lot in common.
Lars, you know we've learned a lot
since then.
- Things are better.
- But it could still happen, right?
It's highly unlikely. It's
rare.
- Yeah, but it still could.
Lars, just take a breath.
That's okay.
I'm sorry.
It's just so dangerous.
- I don't like to think about it.
- Lars, sit down.
Put your head between your knees.
Sit down.
Just put your head
between your knees. Bend over.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay. Take a breath.
We should get cell phones.
Then we can call each other
whenever we want.
How about afternoons,
Mondays and Wednesdays,
and then maybe all day Saturday?
Yeah? You sure?
Okay!
Bianca, is that okay with you?
Bianca wants to volunteer
at the hospital on Thursday afternoons.
You do?
What about your blood pressure?
Just think of all the bald children.
Wouldn't they love her?
That's true.
A little bit of layering here
and some texture right there.
And I don't know
what you guys think, but...
- Bangs?
- I like that. - That's pretty.
Are you sure?
Because it's not growing back, right?
"What's That Sound?"
By Veronica Charles.
- I hear the telephone.
- Ring! Ring!
- Hey.
He's not gonna get any better, is he?
No, probably not.
He's gonna love that thing
his whole life,
and it's all my fault.
No, it's not.
I don't know.
I mean, I left home
as fast as I could. You know?
I never thought about him.
Then the two of us
move back here all fat and happy,
and he moves into the goddamn garage
like the family dog.
And I let him.
No wonder he goes
and orders a fiance in a box.
Come here.
There was this pair of... Benji?
- Oh, Basenjis?
- Basenjis!
Yes, there were these two Basenjis.
They don't bark at all.
Hello!
Bianca!
We're upstairs!
What's going on?
It's the hospital volunteer banquet
at the VFW.
- Doesn't she look beautiful?
- She does. She looks beautiful!
Because...
We were supposed to play Scrabble.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Her schedule's on the refrigerator.
Did you check?
No, I didn't. I forgot.
Could I have a moment
alone with her, please?
Thank you.
You're my girlfriend!
I shouldn't have to check a schedule
to see when you make a plan!
You have 10 people
around you all the time!
You can't ask one of them
to call me and let me know?
- They never fight. - At work I get
excited about playing Scrabble...
I don't like his tone.
Now, you listen to me.
Bianca has a life of her own.
No self-respecting woman
is gonna be at your beck and call!
The sooner you learn that, the better.
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah, you're away
at yourjob all day.
What's she supposed to do? Wait for you?
Would you do that for her?
Would she even ask you to?
She's out in the community doing
things for others less fortunate.
- You should be proud of her.
- What about me?
Big baby.
He's just like my husband!
She'll be home at 11.
She's my girlfriend and I shouldn't
have to check a schedule to see her!
Are you okay?
How would she feel if I just left her?
- What if I abandoned her? - She didn't
abandon you. She'll be back.
How do I know that?
People do whatever they want.
- They don't care.
- No, we all care. Lars, we do care.
No, you don't.
That is...
That is just not true! God!
Every person in this town
bends over backwards
to make Bianca feel at home.
Why do you think
she has so many places to go
and so much to do?
- I don't know.
- Because of you!
Because all these people love you!
We push her wheelchair,
we drive her to work,
we drive her home,
we wash her, we dress her,
we get her up,
we put her to bed, we carry her!
And she is not petite, Lars!
Bianca is a big, big girl!
None of this is easy for any of us,
but we do it!
God, we do it for you!
So don't you dare tell me
how we don't care!
I think it's the person's job
who's upset, to say they're upset,
because they cannot, you know...
- Hey!
- Oh, hey.
- How was the game?
The cheese inspectors
beat the crap out of us.
Is everything all right?
I usually put Bianca to bed.
I know.
Okay, tell him.
We wanted
to talk to you about that.
You don't have to do that anymore.
I'm gonna do that.
Are you sure?
Because I don't mind.
I thought that you...
Sorry.
- It's just been one of those days.
- It's... It's fine.
It's up to you.
- I'll leave you guys.
- Hey, Gus?
- What's that?
- Thank you, though.
- I didn't do anything.
- Yeah, you did.
Okay.
I'm tired.
- Did I miss something?
- We had a big fight!
- Really?
- Yes!
Are those hand knit mittens?
I think it's kind of cold out.
- Lars, have you met Erik?
- Not officially.
You're famous around here.
I know.
Hell of a grip too, pal.
Yeah.
Yes?
- My office.
- I think I'm gonna stay.
She's feeling pretty lousy today.
We'll both stay.
I asked her to marry me last week.
Congratulations!
When's the happy day?
She said no.
I know. I couldn't believe it.
Yeah.
Stop it! You have no right
to talk to me like that!
No, you don't!
You don't.
I don't talk to you like that!
Have you stopped yelling?
I was talking to Bianca
and she was saying that, in her culture,
they have these rites of passages
and rituals and ceremonies...
Just all kinds of things
that when you do them,
or when you're done,
if you live through them,
they'll let you know
you're an adult.
Doesn't that sound great?
It does.
- How did you know?
- How did I know what?
That you were a man.
I couldn't tell you.
Was it...
Was it sex?
Yeah, you know...
Yeah, yeah, it's kind of...
No. Well, it's kind of sex,
but it's not, you know?
I don't know.
It's a good question.
Yeah, but I have to know.
Hold that thought.
- You should ask Dagmar.
- I did ask Dagmar.
She said I should ask you.
- I can only give you my opinion.
- That's all I want.
It's not like
you're all one thing or the other.
There's still a kid inside.
But you grow up
when you decide to do right.
Not what's right for you;
what's right for everybody.
Even when it hurts.
Okay. Like, what?
Like...
Like you don't jerk people around,
and you don't cheat on your woman,
and you take care of your family.
You admit when you're wrong.
You try to, anyways.
That's all I can think of.
It sounds like it's easy and,
for some reason, it's not.
- I know, because nothing's easy.
- It's like the old man.
He didn't have
to take care of 2 kids alone.
He could have given us to an orphanage.
People do that.
But he loved us and tried to do right,
even though he didn't know how
and even though
he had a broken heart.
I shouldn't have left you
alone with him.
He was too sad.
It scared me and I just...
I just ran.
That was selfish
and I'm sorry.
That's okay.
Okay.
You've crossed the line!
- You kept swiping my action figures.
- I hide them! I don't hang them!
Whatever, you're too old
for that thing, anyway. Okay?
- Take off the noose.
- No. - Take it off!
Face it, Margo! The bear is dead.
Okay? Burn on you!
I warned her.
It's not just the bear.
I broke up with Erik.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, I didn't even
have a good reason.
He just wasn't very interesting.
Then why was he your boyfriend?
I get lonely.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Sure.
Hey, what are you doing
on Friday night?
I have a School Board meeting.
Bianca got elected, so...
- That's great!
- Yeah. - Yeah.
Okay.
Why?
I was just thinking that maybe
we could all go out sometime.
- Never mind.
- After I drop off Bianca, I'm free.
But just me, so...
That would be great, Lars!
Thank you.
Okay.
Nice shot.
You're putting
too much spin on the ball.
I know.
Sorry, we're full up. Next week's
the Ladies League Tournament.
- Nada? - Dude!
- Tell them lady go.
No way, Nelson,
they'll shred me.
Is that Lars?
- Hey, buddy!
- We're full. - No problema!
- I kicked your butt.
- No, no, I'll kick your butt!
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
This was exactly what I needed.
Things look so much better!
Thanks for going bowling with me, Lars.
I don't...
I don't want to give you
the wrong idea about this.
It's just,
I never could cheat on Bianca, ever.
Oh! No!
Oh, my God,
I hope you didn't think that, Lars.
I would never do that.
Oh, okay, good. Yeah.
Because a man doesn't cheat
on his woman, and that's that.
Absolutely. And vice versa.
Besides, I don't mean
to steal anybody's boyfriend.
One day,
I'll find a man of my own and
we'll be happy, too.
That's the way it works, I guess.
Thanks.
Snow!
I was hoping that winter was over.
No, it's a thaw.
Winter isn't over till Easter.
Thanks again.
Hey.
Goodnight, Lars.
I'm not sure how well
these treatments are working.
No?
What do you think?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
It's hard, because
I know that she loves me, but
I ask her to marry me
and she says: "No".
Or she says: "I don't know".
Or she doesn't say anything.
Nothing?
When I was a child, I spoke
as a child. I understood as a child.
Hey...
Wake up!
She won't wake up.
- Bianca! I think she's unconscious!
- Are you sure? - Look at me. Bianca?
Hey, hey, hey!
- Bianca's unconscious!
- Can you hear me?
Bianca!
Wake up!
Hey, she looks alright!
She looks alright!
- Hey, hey!
- Call 911! - Okay.
- 911? - I don't know! You always
expect me to know what to do!
They're here.
Call Doctor Berman.
#... you look at me, #
#O is for the only one I see, #
#V is very, very extraordinary, #
#E is even more than anyone... #
I'm sorry,
you'll have to wait out here.
#... that you adore. #
It's okay.
The doctor's on the way.
Hello? Hello?
- Lars!
- Yeah.
What?
Bianca's very sick.
No, she's not.
Come on, she's not sick.
She's not! Lars?
She's dying.
- But...
- God!
We're gonna keep her here
till she's stable, but
she wants to go home
with Lars tonight.
- Can I see her?
- Sure.
What?
I'm sorry, but I just don't get it.
What's this gonna do to him?
How could you let this happen?
I'm not letting it happen, it's Lars.
It's always been Lars.
He's making the decisions.
He's the one who found her unconscious;
he's the one who said she's dying.
Are you okay back there?
They gave her something,
so she's asleep.
Anything you want, Lars?
We're gonna stay together
in the pink room tonight.
Come down to the family room, Lars.
Let Bianca rest.
We sent Gus and Karin to the movies.
They didn't want to leave you.
No, I'm glad...
I'm glad they left.
I feel terrible that all this is
happening so close to the baby coming.
That's how life is, Lars.
Everything at once.
We brought casseroles.
Thank you.
Is there something
I should be doing right now?
- No, dear.
- You eat.
We came over to sit.
That's what people do
when tragedy strikes.
They come over and sit.
Okay.
Don't you feel a little better?
I got spring fever, we're going
to the lake. You wanna come?
Lars, why don't you come with us?
It would do everybody good.
Bianca?
Don't you wanna see
this beautiful day?
- Is there a storm coming?
- The weather said no.
Looks like a storm to me.
Well, I need to stretch my legs.
Let's take a chance.
Lars?
We're gonna watch the water.
- We won't be far.
- Holler if you need us. - Okay.
- You think it's not that color?
- It doesn't match the curtains.
- I think so. Here, just be careful.
- Okay.
Gus...
No. Don't run. Lars!
Lars!
Lars asked us not to wear black today.
He did so to remind us
that this is no ordinary funeral.
We are here to celebrate
Bianca's extraordinary life.
From her wheelchair,
Bianca reached out
and touched us all
in ways
we could have never imagined.
She was a teacher.
She was a lesson in courage.
And Bianca loved us all.
Especially Lars.
Especially him.
Hi.
- Are you okay?
- I'm sorry, I just...
I don't know, it's just funerals
and mom and dad, you know.
- He's unbelievable, huh?
- He is.
I wanted to thank you for...
Gus!
Yeah.
So, shall we see you at the house?
- Of course.
- Okay. - Sure.
She asked me not to be sad,
but I can't help it.
Yeah. Me neither.
But it'll get better with time.
That's what everyone keeps saying,
so...
It's true, I think, in a way.
But there'll never be
anybody like her.
I suppose we should
catch up with everyone.
Do you wanna take a walk?
Yes.