Are you ready?
Everything's cool?
Good.
Use your imagination...
and your skills.
Everything is subjective.
Don't elaborate.
He who thinks he's bigger than the rest...
must go to the cemetery.
There he will see what life really is.
It's a handful of dirt.
Pay attention.
I am paying attention.
Give him the keys.
Go to the towers. Then go to the café.
Wait for a couple of days.
Look for the violin.
The universe has no center and no edges.
Reality is arbitrary.
You want me to translate that?
I don't fucking get it.
Forget it.
He gets it.
What can I get you?
A double espresso?
Here you are, sir.
Here you go.
Two espressos...
...in separate cups.
The customer is always right.
You don't speak Spanish, right?
It's very loud here.
I believe that musical instruments,
especially those made out of wood --
Cellos, violins, guitars --
I believe that they resonate, musically,
even when they're not being played.
They have a memory.
Every note...
that's ever been played on them...
is still inside of them...
resonating in the molecules of the wood.
I guess, like everything,
it's just a matter of perception, no?
You don't speak Spanish, right?
Something for the señorita?
A bottle of water, please.
...for the beautiful señorita.
That leaves one more night
for our beautiful love story.
You don't speak Spanish, right?
The universe has no center
and no edges.
Excuse me.
Are you an American gangster?
He says he's not.
Maybe he's just saying that...
We're closed.
We're not open now,
they're just rehearsing something.
You don't speak Spanish, right?
He who thinks he's bigger than the rest...
must go to the cemetery.
There he will see
what the world really is.
It's a handful of dirt.
You don't speak Spanish, right?
Son of a bitch.
She's crazy beautiful.
So beautiful.
The old men in my village used to say,
"Everything changes by the color
of the glass you see it through."
Do you know who the Huicholes are?
Okay.
I get it.
It's cool.
Go ahead, get in, get in.
Okay, cool. Crazy. Cool.
Those who think they're
bigger than the rest...
should go to the cemetery.
There,
they will see what life really is.
There...
he will see...
what the world really is.
It's a handful of dirt.