Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
The winner of a $30,000 scholarship
is Miss Louisiana, Erika Schwarz!
And the new Miss America
is Miss Kansas, Tara Dawn Holland!
..scholarship
is Miss Louisiana, Erika Schwarz!
And the new Miss America
is Miss Kansas, Tara Dawn Holland!
There are two kinds of people in this world:
winners, and losers.
lnside each and every one of you,
at the very core of your being,
is a winner waiting to be awakened
and unleashed upon the world.
With my nine-step
"Refuse to Lose" programme,
you now have the necessary tools,
and the insight, and the know-how,
to put your losing habits behind you,
and to go out
and make your dreams come true.
No hesitating.
No complaining.
And no excuses.
Now l want you to go out in the world,
and l want you to be winners!
Thank you.
l'm on my way. l don't know how long.
l don't know!
Richard, he has nowhere else to go.
l'm not smoking. l'm not.
Look, l'm at the hospital.
Yeah, OK. Bye.
Ms Hoover? Your brother's fine.
Keep him away
from sharp objects - knives, scissors.
lf you have medications, depressants,
in your house, keep them secure.
- l'd prefer to keep him, but...
- Yeah, l know. The insurance.
You wanna see him?
Hey, Frank.
Sheryl.
l'm so glad you're still here.
Well, that makes one of us.
..will pass out across New Mexico tonight,
bringing with it moisture
that will cool things off.
We may even see a five- to ten-degree drop
in temperatures in Albuquerque.
You wanna talk or not?
No.
Hello?
Anyone?
Down here, we have you with Dwayne.
Dwayne, hi. Uncle Frank's here.
He doesn't mind, Frank. We talked.
l know, l know. But we can't have
you sleeping alone. The doctor said.
l'm sorry. l have to insist.
You'll get along fine. He's really quiet.
And here's your cot.
Please, Frank.
Please.
Thank you.
l've gotta start dinner.
You come out when you're settled.
And just leave the door open.
That's important.
Dwayne, honey. There's a bucket of chicken
in the car. Can you get it? l'll make a salad.
- Olive?
- Yeah?
- ls Grandpa with you?
- Yeah.
- What are you guys doing?
- Rehearsing.
- OK. Well, dinner in ten minutes.
- OK.
- Hi.
- Hi. Frank's here.
Oh, God. Did Stan Grossman call?
Well, check the machine.
Dwayne, please. Come on.
The chicken. lt's in the car.
And will you set the table?
Just do paper plates.
..runner-up in the regional
Little Miss Sunshine...
Hey, it's your sister!
Fuck.
Hi. Richard Hoover
for Stan Grossman, please.
Any way to reach him, or...?
Well, l'm just wondering
if this darn book deal is done or not.
lf...
Yes.
OK. Could you have him call me
any time over the weekend?
He has my cell number.
Just to let me know we're on.
OK? Thank you.
- Bye.
- So what happened with Stan Grossman?
- He's in Scottsdale.
- Why didn't he call?
Will you let me worry about this, please?
Dwayne, can you check on Frank?
Tell him it's dinnertime.
Olive! Dinnertime!
Coming!
What? Dinner?
What, you don't talk any more?
Why not?
You can talk, you just choose not to?
ls that Nietzsche?
You don't speak
because of Friedrich Nietzsche.
Far out.
Frank, you can sit here next to Dwayne.
Here's the salad, and...
l'm gonna run and get Sprite for everyone.
- Olive, come on! Dinnertime!
- OK.
So, who do you hang out with?
No one?
What about your family?
Frank! Hey.
- Richard.
- Good to see you.
l'm gonna get Olive.
Olive? Dad?
You guys, go on and start.
- Frank, some Sprite?
- Yes.
And l want everyone
to have at least a little salad.
Thanks, Sheryl.
Honey?
So, Sheryl, l couldn't help noticing
that Dwayne has stopped speaking.
Yeah, he's taken a vow of silence.
- You've taken a vow of silence?
- He's gonna join the Air Force Academy,
become a test pilot, and he's taken
a vow of silence until he reaches that goal.
- Hi, Uncle Frank.
- Oh, hey, Olive. Wow.
You're getting big. Almost like a real person.
- What happened to your arms?
- Olive.
That's OK. l had a little accident. l'm OK.
- How's the routine coming, honey?
- lt's good.
- Yeah? Why don't you show it to us?
- l don't know. lt's up to Grandpa.
A couple of days. lt still needs work.
What's that? Chicken?
Every night it's the fucking chicken!
Holy God Almighty.
ls it possible just once
we could get something to eat
- that's not the goddamn fucking chicken?
- Hey, Dad.
Dad! Whenever you want to start cooking
your own food, you're more than welcome.
- At Sunset Manor...
- lf you liked it so much,
you shouldn't have gotten yourself
kicked out of there, right?
So, when did you start with the vow?
lt's been nine months, Frank.
He hasn't said a word. Not one.
l think it shows tremendous discipline.
l really do.
l think we could
learn something from Dwayne.
Dwayne has a goal. He has a dream.
lt may not be my dream, it may not be yours,
but he's pursuing it
with great conviction and focus.
- l was thinking about the nine steps...
- For crying out loud.
..and how Dwayne's utilising at least
seven of 'em in his personal quest.
- Richard, please.
- Well, l'm just saying... Come around.
l think he could use our support.
How did it happen?
- How did what happen?
- Your accident.
- Honey, here.
- Oh, no. That's OK.
- Unless you object.
- No, l'm pro-honesty here.
l just think, you know, it's up to you.
Be my guest.
Olive, um...
Uncle Frank didn't really have an accident.
What happened was, he tried to kill himself.
You did? Why?
Sorry, l don't think this is
an appropriate conversation.
Honey, let's let Uncle Frank
finish his dinner, OK?
Why did you wanna kill yourself?
- Don't answer the question, Frank.
- Richard!
- He's not gonna answer the question.
- l wanted to kill myself
- because l was very unhappy.
- He's sick in the head.
l don't think it's an appropriate conversation
for a seven-year-old.
- Well, she's gonna find out anyway.
- OK.
Go on, Frank.
Why were you unhappy?
Well, there were a lot of reasons.
Mainly, though, l fell in love
with someone who didn't love me back.
- Who?
- One of my grad students.
l was very much in love with him.
Him? lt was a boy?
- You fell in love with a boy?
- Yes, l did. Very much so.
- That's silly.
- You're right. lt was silly. Very, very silly.
- There's another word for it.
- Dad.
So that's when you tried to kill yourself?
Well, no. The boy that l was in love with
fell in love with another man,
- Larry Sugarman...
- Who's Larry Sugarman?
Perhaps the second most highly regarded
Proust scholar in the US.
- Who's number one?
- That would be me, Rich.
Really?
So that's when?
No. What happened was, l was a bit upset,
so l said some things l shouldn't have said
and did some things l shouldn't have done.
l was fired from my job and forced to move
out of my apartment and into a motel.
And that's when you tried to...
Well, no. Actually, all of that was OK.
What happened was, two days ago
the MacArthur Foundation, in its wisdom,
awarded a genius grant to Larry Sugarman,
and that's when l...
Decided to check out early.
Yes. Yes, and l failed at that as well.
Olive, the important thing to understand here
is that Uncle Frank gave up on himself. He
made a series of foolish choices - l'm sorry -
and he gave up on himself,
which is something that winners never do.
So that's the story, OK?
Now, everyone, just let's move on and...
ls he always like this?
How can you stand it?
Olive. Tell him about your routine,
why you're doing this.
Little Miss Chili Pepper is a beauty contest
for everyone in Albuquerque,
but you have to be six or seven,
and you have to be a girl.
- This is our sister.
- Cindy.
Spring break,
Dwayne went to see his dad in Florida
and Olive went to Laguna to see her cousins.
She made it to the top of the regionals.
- l was in second place.
- Well, what do you think your chances are?
l think l can win,
because some of the other girls,
they've been doing it longer,
but l practise every day.
- Well, good luck.
- lt's not about luck, Frank.
Luck is the name losers give to
their own failings. lt's about wanting to win.
Willing yourself to win.
You've gotta want it badder than the rest.
- l do.
- Then you're gonna be a winner.
- Richard...
- lt's the truth.
Actually there is a message
from Cindy on the machine.
Something about Little Mrs Sunshine...?
- What? Little Miss Sunshine?
- Yeah.
What?
lt's Cindy. Remember Olive was second
in the regional Little Miss Sunshine?
The girl who won had to forfeit her crown -
something about diet pills.
Anyway, now she has a place
in the state contest in Redondo...
- ..the number is...
- l won, l won!
- Finish your dinner!
- What happened?
l'm just calling to... Cindy!
Yeah, we just got it.
- Yeah, she basically went crazy.
- l won, l won, l won!
No, l didn't get that.
The machine cut you off.
OK...
Redondo Beach... This Sunday?
Are you guys going?
- l'm going! l'm really going!
- Yes?
- Well, can you put it off?
- They have to! They have to.
- Well, where does that leave us?
- We can't do it.
No, no, l understand that, Cindy. Yeah.
l just... No, l'll just figure it out.
- OK. Bye-bye.
- lt's this Sunday?
- Why can't Jeff and Cindy take her?
- They have some equestrian thing.
They do that horse shit every single weekend.
Well, it's the nationals. They're taking
both horses, so apparently it's a big deal.
What about Olive?
Little Miss Sunshine!
Little Miss Sunshine! l won!
l won!
l'm going! We're going!
- You promised?
- We'll fly out, come back Monday.
- How are you gonna get around?
- We'll rent a car.
- And stay in a hotel?
- We can afford it.
- This is our seed money!
- Well, if l had help bringing it in...
- lt all goes to your nine steps.
- l'm gonna talk to Stan Grossman.
We'll be locked and loaded on this deal
and start generating some income!
- But in the meantime...
- OK, OK! We'll drive!
- l'm not driving.
- How are you gonna fit Grandpa in the Miata?
- Grandpa does not have to come.
- What?
l coached her, l gave her the moves.
l gotta go.
- Why don't you take the VW?
- l cannot drive a shift. l cannot do it.
- We'll fly there.
- We can't afford it!
Well, that's what we're gonna do
unless you have a better idea.
Here! This is dessert.
l won, l won, l won,
l won, l won, l won, l won!
l won! l won! l won!
Little Miss Sunshine!
Little Miss Sunshine! Little Miss Sunshine!
- All right. l'll drive the bus.
- Richard!
l was told explicitly not to leave Frank
by himself. No offence, Frank.
- None taken.
- You got Dwayne here.
- They can look after each other.
- No! lf something happened, l'd...
We can't go, then,
unless Dwayne and Frank go with us.
- Mom! Where's my bathing suit?
- Right...
Frank?
l've found it!
OK.
l'm going! l'm going! l'm going!
No, Dwayne, come on. Please.
Think of your sister.
Come on, Dwayne.
lt'll be a lot of fun.
You can go to the beach, and...
"This is unfair."
"All l ask is...
that you leave me alone."
Dwayne? Flight school. l will give you
permission for flight school.
l've gotta go pack. l won.
l can't believe it. l won. l won.
l'm gonna win this one, too!
"But l'm not going to...
have any fun."
- We're all with you on that one.
- Grandpa. Grandpa.
- ls Grandpa coming to California?
- We're all coming, honey.
Olive? Come over here for a second.
Come here. Sit down for a second.
Look. There's no sense in entering a contest
if you don't think you're gonna win.
So, do you think you can win
Little Miss Sunshine?
Richard...
Are you gonna win?
Yes!
We're going to California.
Good night, Dwayne.
Not on your watch. l wouldn't do that to you.
Thank you, Dwayne.
Coming from you, that means a lot.
Good night.
Jesus, l'm tired. l'm so fucking tired.
You know how tired l am?
lf some girl came up to me,
begged me to fuck her, l couldn't do it.
- Dad?
- That's how tired l am.
- Watch the language, huh?
- She's listening to music.
l'll give you a million dollars
if you turn around. See?
- All right. But the rest of us.
- Oh, the rest of you.
Can l give you some advice?
Well, l'm gonna give it to you anyway.
l don't want you making the same mistakes
l made when l was young.
- Can't wait to hear this.
- Dwayne. That's your name, right? Dwayne?
This is the voice of experience talking.
Are you listening?
Fuck a lot of women, Dwayne.
Not just one woman. A lot of women.
- That's enough, all right? Dad!
- Are you getting any? You can tell me.
- Come on. Please.
- No? Jesus! You're, what, 15? My God, man!
You should be getting that young stuff.
That's the best stuff in the world.
- That's enough! Stop it!
- Will you kindly not interrupt me?
See, right now you're jailbait, they're jailbait.
lt's perfect.
l mean, you hit 18...
Man! You're talking about three to five.
- l will pull this truck over right now!
- You're not gonna shut me up! Fuck you!
l can say what l want!
l still got Nazi bullets in my ass!
The Nazi bullets!
You're as bad
as those fuckers at Sunset Manor!
- What happened at Sunset Manor?
- Frank, don't encourage him.
l'll tell you what happened.
l paid my money, they took my money.
- l should be able to do what the fuck l want!
- He started snorting heroin.
- You started snorting heroin?
- l'm old!
- That stuff'll kill you.
- What am l, an idiot?
And don't you start taking that shit.
When you're young, you're crazy to do it.
- What about you?
- What about me? l'm old.
- When you get old, you're crazy not to do it.
- We've tried. The intervention was a fiasco.
- He was worse than a two-year-old.
- Can we please talk about something else?
- l take it you didn't like it at Sunset Manor.
- Are you kidding? lt was a fucking paradise.
They got a pool, they got golf.
Now l'm stuck with Mr Happy here,
sleeping on a fucking sofa.
Look, l know you're a homo and all,
but maybe you can appreciate this.
You go to one of those places,
there's four women for every guy.
- Can you imagine what that's like?
- You must have been very busy.
l had second-degree burns on my johnson,
l kid you not.
- Forget about it.
- What are you guys talking about?
Politics.
Fuck a lot of women, kid.
l have no reason to lie to you.
Not one woman. A lot of women.
You heard what l said?
- Did it go in anywhere?
- l think we get the point, Dad.
Don't show me the pad.
l don't wanna see the fucking pad.
- Mom, how much can we spend?
- l would say four dollars.
Anything under four dollars.
Hi. You ready?
Yeah. l'm gonna have the number five
with coffee, please.
Number seven, over easy,
and a grapefruit juice.
l would like a fruit plate, and...
Do you have camomile?
- Yes.
- With honey, please.
l would like the Lumberjack and coffee,
and extra bacon.
- Extra?
- Dad, you should probably...
- Don't start.
- He could kill himself.
- Well, it's his life.
- Thank you, Sheryl.
Garden salad?
- And you?
- l'm sorry. l...
- Take your time.
- Don't apologise, Olive.
- lt's a sign of weakness.
- Well, l want...
OK, OK. l know what l want.
Can l get the waffles and...?
- l don't... What does "a la modee" mean?
- That means it comes with ice cream.
- OK, a la modee, then.
- Olive. For breakfast?
- You said four dollars.
- OK. You're right.
OK. Be right back.
Actually, Olive, a la mode, in French,
translates literally as "in the fashion".
Mode is derived from Latin, modus,
meaning "due or proper measure".
- Frank, shut up.
- Richard!
Olive, can l tell you
a little something about ice cream?
lce cream is made from cream,
which comes from cow's milk,
and cream has a lot of fat in it.
- Richard.
- What?
- She's gonna find out anyway, remember.
- What? Find out what?
Well, when you eat ice cream, the fat
in the ice cream becomes fat in your body.
- Richard, l swear to God...
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, honey.
- So, if you eat a lot of ice cream,
you might become fat,
and if you don't, you're gonna stay
nice and skinny, sweetie.
- Mom...
- Olive, Richard is an idiot.
- l like a woman with meat on her bones.
- l don't... Why is everyone so upset?
No one's upset, honey. l...
l just want you to understand
it's OK to be skinny,
and it's OK to be fat, if that's what
you wanna be. Whatever you want, it's OK.
OK. But, Olive, let me ask you this.
Those women in Miss America.
Are they skinny, or are they fat?
Honey?
Well...
- They're skinny, l guess.
- Yeah.
- l guess they don't eat a lot of ice cream.
- OK. Coffee?
Coffee...
- Grapefruit.
- Thank you.
Camomile.
And here's your ice cream.
A la modee, right?
l'll be back with your waffles in a sec.
Does anyone want my ice cream?
Yeah. l'd like a little. Dwayne? Frank?
Olive's not gonna have her ice cream.
- Do you mind if l have a little?
- Let's dig in.
- That looks really good.
- l feel sorry for anybody
that doesn't want to enjoy their ice cream
so early in the morning.
Are you sure you don't wanna have some?
These waffles are gonna be awful lonely.
- Watch this.
- Wait! Stop! Don't eat it all.
- All right, Olive...
- Richard!
Stan?
Stan? lt's Richard. Again.
l know you're busy,
but we're just dying to hear
what sort of numbers you came up with
in Scottsdale, so give me a call, please.
- Did you get him?
- No. l can't get a signal out of this thing.
- How long till we get there?
- A long time, honey.
- l know. But how long?
- We've gotta do 600 miles of driving today
and 200 tomorrow.
That's a lot of driving. Let's go!
- Honey, l'll drive for a while.
- No, l got it.
No, you're right. l've gotta learn how to
do this. You're doing it. How hard can it be?
- Push the stick down harder.
- l'm pushing hard.
OK, there you go. Now push the clutch in
all the way to the floor.
lt's on the floor!
lt's on the floor.
That is a sticky one there.
Push down hard.
Well, you got a problem.
Your clutch is shot.
- Can we get a new one?
- These old buses,
- you have to order the part.
- How long does it take?
Well, it's the weekend.
So...
Maybe Thursday.
ls there a dealership around here?
Well, they're probably gonna be closed.
lt's the weekend, you know.
Yes, we're aware of that.
l tell you what. You know these old buses?
You don't need the clutch
to change from the third to the fourth.
You only really need the clutch
to go from number one to number two.
But as long as you keep parking on a hill,
and you let it go,
and it goes 15, 20 miles per hour,
you start it in third,
and then you go from third to fourth.
What if you're not on a hill? There's no hill?
What if there's no hill? What do you...?
Hey, it's...
Olive? Dad? l want you in the car first.
- l know! We know.
- All right. Here we go.
Everybody push! All right.
Here we go! Push!
Push!
- OK!
- l just want everyone here to know
that l am the pre-eminent Proust scholar
in the United States.
l'm putting it in gear!
- Go, honey.
- Come on. Come on, Olive. Run, run!
- Come on. Come on.
- Sheryl, let's go!
Sheryl!
- Frank, let's go!
- You're losing them! Slow down!
- Come on, you dumb bastard.
- l can't slow down. l can't slow down!
- Let's go!
- Come on!
Come on! Come on, get in.
No one gets left behind!
Outstanding, soldier! Outstanding!
Outstanding.
- Was that fun?
- Yeah.
So, finally l'm just sitting there, and l decide,
"This is Stan Grossman. What the hell?"
And l start pitching him the nine steps.
And about... l don't know, two minutes in,
he stops me, he says, "l can sell this."
- lnteresting.
- And this is the guy who knows how to do it.
You start with a book, then you do a media
tour, corporate events, DVD VHS series -
there's a whole fascinating science
into how you roll these things out.
So he's in Scottsdale right now, building the
buzz and getting the whole hype thing going.
He's doing what the pros call
"a ticking clock auction".
How about that?
Yeah, and l can detect
that note of sarcasm there, Frank.
- What sarcasm? l didn't hear...
- But l want you to know something.
- l feel sorry for you.
- You do? Good.
Yeah, l do.
Because sarcasm is the refuge of losers.
lt is? Really?
Yep. Sarcasm is losers trying to
bring winners down to their level.
- That's step four in the programme.
- You've opened my eyes to what a loser l am.
- How much do l owe you for that?
- That one's on the house, buddy.
- OK, you guys. That's enough.
- That was on the house.
- That was for free?
- No charge.
- Stop it!
- He started it.
Wait a second.
Quiet. This is it. This is that call.
Hello?
Stan?
Stan Grossman. Richard Hoover.
Finally! How you doing?
l know. We were on the highway and l lost
you on my cell. Forget about it. How'd we do?
l'm gonna use the ladies' room.
You need to go?
No. l'm gonna go
practise my routine over there.
OK. Well, don't go too far.
Well, l think we just gotta talk to him a little.
No, you gotta talk to...
No, Stan, listen to me. Hold on, now.
l'm going to get something to drink.
You want anything?
- What? Yeah. Get me some porn.
- OK.
Get me something really nasty, too.
l don't want any of that airbrushed shit.
OK, here's a 20. Get yourself a little treat, too.
Get yourself a fag rag.
All right. l will.
That one. Yes. And that one.
And l would like that one - no, down. Yes.
Yes. Yes, l would like that one.
And l will have a blue raspberry Slushee.
Frank?
Oh, my God. How are you?
l thought you were gonna be in Santa Fe
for the conference. l was looking for you.
- Aren't you supposed to be in New Haven?
- Yeah.
You heard about Larry
and the whole "genius" thing, right?
- lt's official.
- Oh, good.
So we're going to this private spa in Sedona
for the week, and then...
- Larry's here?
- Yeah. He's out filling the tank. He's...
- Yeah. There he is.
- Wow!
- l can't believe this. How've you been?
- l've been fine.
Good. Good. You know,
l heard that you got fired.
Yeah. No. l quit,
because enough is enough, you know?
Good. Good.
So, what are you up to now?
l'm weighing my options, and...
..just, you know,
taking some time off, and so...
Great. That's great.
19.79, sir.
So...
- Well, it's great to see you.
- Yeah, you too.
- Take care of yourself.
- You too. Bye.
You forgot your Slushee.
You're in Scottsdale right now, right?
OK. l can come by.
l'm gonna be coming through there.
l could swing right by. We could...
Christ. He's not getting it.
Did you talk to him? Did you try that?
Well, listen to what l'm saying, Stan! l'll...
- So, what happened?
- Nothing. Let's get outta here.
Wait a minute.
l thought you said this was a done deal.
- He said it was a done deal.
- What, you didn't get anything?
- Where does that leave us?
- Fucked, that's where.
l can't believe l'm hearing...
Did you even try negotiating?
Of course l tried! What do you think l...?
Let's just go, OK? Let's go, let's go.
Come on.
Let's go!
Where's Olive?
All right. Frank?
Come on, sweetie. Jump. We can't stop.
l got her. l got her.
Richard.
Yeah?
Whatever happens, you tried
to do something on your own,
which is more than most people ever do,
and l include myself in that category.
You took a big chance,
and it took guts, and l'm proud of you.
OK, Dad. Thank you.
Thank you, Dad.
OK. Here's 11.
Frank, you're 12.
- Grandpa's 13.
- Can l sleep with Grandpa tonight?
- You'll have to ask Grandpa.
- Grandpa?
We got two beds.
You could still use some rehearsing.
Yeah, that's what l was thinking.
All right, everybody.
We have a long day tomorrow,
so l'll knock on your doors at 7am.
That means no lollygagging. We need
to be packed and on the road by 7:40, guys.
- Frank, you guys'll be OK?
- We're fine.
- Well, good night. Sleep tight.
- Good night.
OK.
What a fucking nightmare.
Richard, we have to talk.
Please, Sheryl,
let's just get through this, and go home.
- Richard, we have to talk now!
- l tried to tell you we couldn't afford the trip!
- l never realised we were going bankrupt!
- We are not bankrupt.
Don't listen to that.
Let's turn on the tube.
l'm gonna brush my teeth.
Secretary Rumsfeld and l thought long and
hard about this important choice. To meet...
You said this was a lock.
You said it was a done deal.
- Stan Grossman said it was a done deal!
- l'm not married to Stan Grossman!
l trusted him, all right?
Trust in order to be trusted. That's step six.
Oh, fuck the nine steps, Richard!
They are not working!
Forget it. lt's over. l never want
to hear about the nine steps again!
Perfect. You're the world champion growler.
Time for your beauty rest. Get in there.
There you go.
Good night.
- Grandpa?
- Yeah?
- l'm kinda scared about tomorrow.
- Are you kidding me?
You're gonna blow 'em out of the water.
They're not gonna know what hit 'em.
- Grandpa?
- Yeah?
- Am l pretty?
- Olive...
You are the most beautiful girl
in the whole world.
- You're just saying that.
- No, l'm not. l'm madly in love with you,
not because of your brains or your
personality. lt's because you're beautiful,
inside and out.
- Grandpa?
- What?
- l don't wanna be a loser.
- You're not a loser.
- Where'd you get the idea you're a loser?
- Because Daddy hates losers.
Back up a minute.
You know what a loser is?
A real loser is somebody that's so afraid
of not winning, they don't even try.
Now, you're trying, right?
- Yeah.
- Then you're not a loser.
- We're gonna have fun tomorrow, right?
- Yeah.
We can tell 'em all to go to hell.
Good night, sweetie. l love you.
What are you doing?
l'm gonna fix this.
Richard...
Here we go. Here we go.
Here we go.
Hi.
Hi. Stan Grossman, please.
Stan, it's Richard. l don't know where the fuck
you are. l'm at the hotel. Call me.
He's standing in front of my office,
and he says:
"The book is really a memoir.
lt's from my life experience." He's, like, 20.
So l said, "You want me
to teach you about life experiences?"
"You can write a book about my experiences."
So he says to me...
Hello, Stan.
- You said it would sell.
- That's what l thought at the time.
lt's a great programme!
You said so yourself. l don't understand.
lt's not the programme, Richard.
lt's you. OK?
No one's heard of you. Nobody cares.
- What's the next step?
- There is none. We had our shot.
lt didn't fly. We move on.
- You mean give up?
- Richard...
One setback and you're ready to just quit?
Richard, listen. l pushed this thing hard, OK?
l rammed it down their fucking throats,
and no one bought it!
lt's time to move on.
You're not gonna win this one.
OK. OK, you know what? Good. l'm glad.
You know why? Because this
is what the nine steps are all about.
- Right here, Stan. Right here.
- Richard, please.
No. You blew it! You blew it, you're out.
Mom?
Dad?
What is it, hon?
Grandpa won't wake up.
Wanna take an eye test?
Uncle Frank? An eye test?
Olive, come here. Put those away.
We'll have a family meeting.
Dwayne? Family meeting.
First of all, the doctors are doing everything
they can to help Grandpa right now.
He's had a long, eventful life,
and l know he loves both of you very much.
But if God wants to take him,
we have to be ready to accept that, OK?
Whatever happens...
we're a family.
And what's important
is that we love each other.
Cos l love you guys so, so much.
- Are you the family of Edwin Hoover?
- Yes.
l'm sorry. We did everything we could.
He was... Well, it was too much.
He probably just fell asleep
and never woke up.
l'll have someone come and talk to you
about handling the remains.
Thank you.
Linda!
Mom?
- ls Grandpa dead?
- Yeah, honey. He passed away.
Hi.
l'm your bereavement liaison, Linda.
- My consolations for your loss.
- Thank you.
OK, these are the forms you need to fill out.
Death certificate.
A report of the death.
An ME pink slip.
Please try and be as detailed as possible.
This is a brochure
for our grief recovery support group,
and if you like l can refer you
to a funeral home
so you can begin making arrangements.
Actually, pre-arrangements
have already been made in Albuquerque.
- Albuquerque?
- We're on our way to California.
lf the body is crossing state lines,
you'll need a burial transit permit.
OK. But we're trying to get
to Redondo Beach by three o'clock.
Three o'clock today? Huh.
Ain't gonna happen.
OK. Can l just...?
l know that this might be a little unusual,
but if maybe we could just go,
and then we'll come back
and take care of all the paperwork, and...
- No. You can't just abandon the body.
- No, no. Nobody's gonna abandon the body.
- The hospital becomes responsible.
- We'll go, and come back.
- Sir, we have ways of...
- You're not following me.
Sir, you are not the only one that's had
somebody die here today, OK?
ls there any way
we might be able to view the remains?
We haven't had a chance
to move him downstairs.
So someone may come in in a few minutes
to take him to the basement.
- Tell them who you are, and they will wait.
- Thank you.
When you're done with the paperwork,
l'll be at the nurses' station.
- Great. Thank you, Linda.
- Thank you.
Goddammit, Dad.
Goddammit.
Stupid...
We'll go to Little Miss Sunshine
next year, OK, honey?
Next year.
No. No.
We've come 700 miles. l'll be damned
if l'm not making that contest, Sheryl.
Well, Richard, we can't leave him here.
We're not gonna leave him.
Richard, what are you doing?
Fuck!
- Dwayne, go around outside.
- What are you thinking?
- We're gonna take him with us.
- No, that is not happening.
He's better off with us than these people.
Go round underneath this window.
- Frank, you go with him.
- Dwayne, don't move.
You stay here. We'll take Olive.
Frank can drive.
We'll be there in two hours. Listen to me.
l'll call a funeral home once we get there.
One thing my father would have wanted
is to see Olive perform in this pageant.
l believe we'd be doing
a grave disservice to his memory
if we were to just give up now, all right?
There's two kinds of people in this world.
There's winners, and there's losers.
You know what the difference is?
Winners don't give up.
So what are we here?
Are we winners, or are we losers?
OK. OK.
Let's do it.
You guys go. Olive, you watch the curtain.
l don't know. l have no reason
to assume it's gonna be otherwise.
Watch. Get the back, get the back.
Go, go, go.
Yeah, five o'clock.
Now, he's very heavy. Be gentle.
- One, two...
- OK.
Three.
Wait, wait, wait. Not yet, not yet.
OK. Go. Go, go, go.
OK.
- His knee's...
- l've got him. Come on.
Daddy. Daddy, hurry up.
You got him? OK, he's slipping.
l got him, l got him, l got him.
Be careful.
Hurry up!
Keep watch, Olive.
Watch it. Watch the kerb, watch the kerb.
Watch his head! Watch it!
Keys?
- Swing him round this way.
- Olive, get in.
OK, let's go.
- Let's go, Frank.
- Did l mention
that l am the pre-eminent
Proust scholar in the US?
- Here we go. Here we go.
- Are you OK?
- Dad?
- Yeah, honey?
What's gonna happen to Grandpa?
Uncle Frank?
Yeah?
Do you think there's a heaven?
lt's hard to say, Olive.
l don't think anyone knows for sure.
l know, but what do you think?
- Well...
- l think there is one.
- Do you think l'll get in?
- Yes.
- You promise?
- Son of a bitch!
- What happened?
He cut me off.
- OK, just leave it.
- lt's stuck or something.
- Maybe try pulling it from here.
- No, no. Just leave it.
- l'll fix it when we get there.
- OK, fine.
Dammit!
Oh, Jesus!
God! l'm being pulled over.
Here we go.
OK. Everybody just pretend
to be normal, OK?
Like everything's normal here.
How you folks doing?
Yeah, we're fine. Just...
- Little trouble with the horn?
- What?
- Having a little trouble with your horn?
- Yeah.
A little trouble. Sorry.
- Sorry.
- Could you step outside the vehicle?
- Step this way, please.
- No, no.
- What?
- Don't.
Don't what?
- Do you have something in your trunk, sir?
- lt's nothing. l... Don't open it.
Sir, you just gave me
probable cause to search your trunk.
- Sir, put your hands on the vehicle, now!
- l just...
- Don't move!
- OK.
- lt's not illegal!
- l'd advise you to keep your mouth shut!
Oh, God. What is he doing?
- lt's not illegal.
- Goddamn!
Sir, could you come back here?
l love this stuff. l love it.
God bless you, God bless you.
- Don't worry, l'm not gonna bust you.
- Thank you.
How you doing?
- Cute. Cute family. That's nice.
- Thank you.
And this on the side.
Little of this, little of that.
- Sweet sweetness.
- That is sweet, yeah.
- And dirty.
- And this one is one of my favourites.
Ah, good. Yeah.
That's a little different choice.
No?
- l'll leave that with you.
- All right.
- You have a good day there.
- Yeah.
What happened?
l'll tell you when l regain consciousness.
Frank, Dwayne, get out and push.
OK, there it is. Redondo Beach, 46.
lt's 2:15. Might be a few minutes late.
They said three o'clock sharp.
We can't cross these people. Trust me.
- Mom, Dwayne has 20/20 vision.
- l bet he does.
OK. Now l'm gonna check
to see if you're colour-blind.
Asshole!
What's the letter in the circle?
No, no, no. lnside the circle.
Right there. See?
lt's an "A". Can't you see it? Right there.
lt's bright green.
Oh, man.
Dwayne, l think you might be colour-blind.
You can't fly jets if you're colour-blind.
We've got a little bit of...
OK, we've got an emergency back here.
- What is it? What's the emergency?
- Just pull over!
lt's all right, man.
Dwayne, Dwayne. lt's all right.
- Just pull over the car! l'm not kidding!
- All right!
- Get him to pull over, please?
- Richard, pull over! Pull over the car!
- We're pulling over.
- l'm pulling over.
Please! No, no, no.
Dwayne! Dwayne! Sit down!
God, this better be good!
l'm pulling over.
- All right!
- Stop the car!
- lt's gonna be OK , Dwayne.
- Do not open the door when we're stopping!
Fuck!
- What happened?
- He's colour-blind. He can't fly.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, no.
Just give him a second.
Dwayne?
Dwayne, honey, l'm sorry.
- Dwayne, come on. We have to go.
- l'm not going.
- Dwayne...
- l said l'm not.
OK? l don't care.
l'm not getting on that bus again!
Dwayne, for better or worse,
we're your family.
You're not my family! OK?
l don't wanna be your family!
l hate you fucking people! l hate you!
Divorce? Bankrupt? Suicide?
You're fucking losers! You're losers!
No. Please just leave me here, Mom.
OK? Please, please, please.
Please just leave me here.
Shit.
l don't know what to do.
Well, it's getting late. Maybe...
Can somebody stay here with him?
- l'll stay.
- That is not happening.
All right. Well...
Just worried about the time.
Olive? Do you wanna try talking to him?
Richard, there is nothing to say.
We just have to wait.
Honey...
OK.
Then let's go.
l apologise for the things l said.
l was upset, and l didn't really mean them.
lt's OK. Come on.
Let's go.
- 2:55.
- Right, everybody look for the exit, OK?
- Here! Here's the turn-off. Turn in here.
- Does anybody see the Redondo Suites?
There! There's the hotel!
Little Miss Sunshine!
There it is. Olive, we're gonna make it.
We're gonna make it.
How the hell do you get over there?
Sheryl?
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- No! No! You're passing it!
- You've gotta turn round.
- You drove past it!
- You've gotta turn round!
- lt's back there!
l can't turn around.
Does anybody see a way back?
lt's a one-way street!
- We've got parking lots on the right.
- Put your seat belt on, baby.
- What are you doing?
- l can't slow down. l can't.
- What time is it, Frank?
- 2:59.
- Dad!
- lt's a straight shot from here. We'll make it.
- Oh, it's a dead end!
- l'm not going back!
That is a one-way road. That will take us
all the way back to the freeway!
You're the one who told me
to go left back there!
l'm not turning back!
Richard!
- What are you doing? You can't do this.
- God, Richard!
- OK, here's the hotel.
- OK.
- Where's the entrance?
- Right here. Right here.
- You're passing it.
- Hold on!
Here we go. One more time. Little bump.
Come on!
- Hello? Hi, we'd like to register.
- Sorry. We're closed.
No, we have the entrant right here.
We just wanna check in.
- Registration ended at three.
- lt's three o'clock now.
- No...
- Have a heart. We're four minutes late.
- We drove all the way from Albuquerque.
- You should have been here by three.
- There must be a way we can work this out.
- Everybody else was here before three.
- l'd be giving unfair advantage.
- We're not looking for an advantage.
- We just want her to compete.
- Don't yell at me, sir.
l didn't make you late. We've settled on
a schedule, we've turned off the computers.
Our line-up is final,
and l have a hair check to do
l'm sorry that you're late, but l can't help you.
Please.
You don't know what we've been through.
Ms Jenkins?
l can put 'em in the system.
- Oh, Kirby, you don't have to.
- No, it's OK. lt's five minutes.
Well, it's your time. Excuse me.
- Thank you, Kirby. Thank you very much.
- You don't know what this means.
Please. lt's only five minutes.
l'm not working for these people next year.
These people are crazy.
- So, what's your name?
- Olive.
Olive. That's a nice name.
Are you the dad?
- lt's Miss California. lt's really her.
- Do you wanna go and say hi?
Thank you.
- Hi. What's your name?
- Olive.
- What's your talent, Olive?
- l like dancing.
Dancing was too hard for me.
l'm a singer.
- You must be a good dancer.
- l am. l'm really good.
l bet you are.
Well, thanks for stopping by, Olive.
Best of luck.
- Miss California? Do you eat ice cream?
- l love ice cream.
My favourite flavour
is Chocolate Cherry Garcia,
although technically,
l think that's a frozen yoghurt. OK?
OK. Thanks.
- Bye.
- Mom! She eats ice cream.
- l heard.
The packet has tickets in it,
and your badge number.
- ls there anything else?
- Yeah.
ls there a funeral home around here?
OK, let's get your swimsuit on.
You wanna get changed behind the curtain?
This is the last touch-up, everybody.
Final touch-ups. Last touch-up.
- OK, wait.
- l will wait for you!
Let's get outta here.
Olive Hoover?
l need your music.
- Music. Right.
- Yeah.
- Here you go.
- This?
- Did you choose this?
- No, my grandpa did.
Your grandpa?
- Which track?
- 12.
We're driving five, six hours...
Thought he was napping.
By the time we figured it out,
it was, you know...
Too late.
So, where's the body?
- Personal effects.
- Thank you.
You take care.
You too.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to
the 24th annual Little Miss Sunshine pageant!
Yes! Now, please put your hands
together once again,
and help me welcome to the stage
our 12 beautiful contestants!
Let's have a big round of applause
for our lovely contestants!
At the end of the evening, one of these girls
will be crowned Little Miss Sunshine!
- Olive, honey? Are you OK in there?
- Yeah, l'm fine.
What?
You got a kid in the show?
First time?
Yeah. Yeah.
America! lt's so beautiful.
Sometimes l just wish
l could go to sleep till l was 18,
and skip all this crap, high school
and everything. Just skip it.
- You know Marcel Proust?
- He's the guy you teach.
Yeah. French writer.
Total loser.
Never had a real job.
Unrequited love affairs. Gay.
Spent 20 years writing a book
almost no one reads,
but he's also probably the greatest writer
since Shakespeare. Anyway, he...
he gets down to the end of his life,
and he looks back and decides
that all those years he suffered,
those were the best years of his life,
cos they made him who he was.
All the years he was happy, you know,
total waste. Didn't learn a thing.
So, if you sleep until you're 18...
Think of the suffering you're gonna miss.
l mean, high school?
Those are your prime suffering years.
You don't get better suffering than that.
You know what?
l mean, fuck beauty contests.
Life is one fucking beauty contest
after another:
you know, school, then college, then work.
Fuck that. And fuck the Air Force Academy.
lf l wanna fly, l'll find a way to fly.
l mean, you do what you love,
and fuck the rest.
l'm glad you're talking again, Dwayne.
You're not nearly as stupid as you look.
- Wanna go back?
- Not really.
Yeah, we should go back.
And now, the moment we've all been
waiting for: the talent competition.
Miss Carly Nugent!
Yodel-ay-hee-hoo, that was great!
Wow! Funkylicious!
- l'm going backstage.
- Yeah. Right. See you.
Oh, look at you.
ls that your costume?
OK, here.
- What's going on?
- l just came to wish Olive good luck.
- How are you doing, honey?
- Good.
- Nervous.
- Yeah. You're gonna do great. l just know it.
- Can l talk to you for a second?
- Yeah.
What's up?
l don't want her to go on.
- Are you authorised to be backstage?
- No. Where are the dressing rooms?
- Are you allowed to be here?
- Just tell me where the dressing rooms are.
- Listen, we're not in Albuquerque any more.
- How are you feeling?
- Better. Where's Olive?
- Just there. What's up?
- Mom, l don't want Olive doing this.
- Oh, my God.
- Look around. Mom, this place is fucked!
- He's right!
Look, l don't want these people
judging Olive. Fuck them!
- lt is too late.
- lt's not. You're the mom,
and you're supposed to protect her.
Everyone is gonna laugh at her, Mom.
Please don't let her do this.
Olive Hoover, two minutes.
Look, she's not a beauty queen.
She's just not. l'm gonna tell her.
No, you listen to me. Olive is who she is.
She has worked so hard,
she's poured everything into this.
We can't just take it away from her. We can't.
l know you want to protect her, l know, honey.
But we've gotta let Olive be Olive.
Olive Hoover! Are you the family?
OK?
Olive, it's time. Are you OK?
- Yeah.
- We've gotta go.
- Now.
- Hang on.
Olive, look at me.
lf you don't wanna do this, that's OK.
lf you wanna sit this one out,
it's totally fine by us.
- We're proud of you anyway.
- We gotta go.
lt's time!
Ready? Let's go.
Good luck, honey.
Copy that. 25 is performance-ready,
and we're walking.
As fast as we can.
- ls she going on?
- She's going on.
Pure fairy-tale magic!
Miss Charisma Whiteman!
Wasn't that a stardust fantasy?
Thank you for that.
You have been such a patient audience.
We have one more contestant,
and then we'll be crowning our winner.
Please give a warm welcome
to Miss Olive Hoover!
ls everything OK?
l'd like to dedicate this to my grandpa,
who showed me these moves.
Oh, that is so sweet.
ls he here? Where's your grandpa right now?
ln the trunk of our car.
OK...
Well, take it away, Olive!
You suck!
Those little fuckers! l will kill them.
You stink!
No, no, no, no, no.
What is your daughter doing?
She's kicking ass. That's what she's doing.
Get over here. Get over here!
l want that little ragamuffin off this stage.
Go get her.
- Right this minute!
- Don't touch her.
Your act's over, honey.
Stop. Stop. Honey...
Let go of my daughter!
Holy shit!
Just let her finish!
Help! Get off me! Get off me!
- Take charge! Just take charge!
- Keep dancing! Daddy's OK.
Get your daughter off this stage right now!
Now!
Honey?
Yeah!
All right!
Housekeeping, dial two-three.
Any available bellmen to the main entrance.
OK. You're out, on the condition
that you never enter your daughter
in a beauty pageant
in the state of California ever again.
Ever.
l think we can live with that.
All right. We're back in business.
Lock and load.
Olive, your grandpa
would have been really proud of you.
- Yeah, you were great.
- You were beyond great.
- You were incredible.
- Thank you.
Let's get outta here.
lt's in gear.
What in the world...?