Let's go, cop killers.
Give you 30 seconds to give yourselves up.
Come out slowly with your hands in the air
like you're playing a nice little game of volleyball.
This here is John "Rugged" Rudgate, the gangster.
The badass who outfoxed the cops
and hightailed it out of town and into the history books.
Hey... you guys want to buy some speakers?
Rugged was supposedly behind
every unsolved crime in New Hampshire
in the last 10 years...
from breaking into the peewee league storage shed
to murdering that fat fuck lumberjack, Rod Connelly.
Not too many places get their own legendary criminal.
Chicago had Al Capone with his huge fucking empire
of whorehouses and speakeasies.
New Mexico had Billy The Kid, who stole so many horses
they had to invent the car just to fucking get around.
And New Hampshire had Rugged.
The amazing thing was, I was gonna get to work with him.
I was gonna nab a stack of diplomas
from the Andover tractor-trailer trucking school
and he was gonna turn them into big coin.
Was I nervous? Fuck, yeah. But who wouldn't be?
- What's up, Marcus?
- What's up, Rugged?
Relax, man. You look conspicuous.
How'd we do?
Well...
Got five.
Five O.K.?
Yeah. Shit hot, man.
That's real fucking good.
Well? What do you think we're gonna get for them?
You don't worry about that. That's my deal. O.K.?
But considering trucking school charges
four grand for one of these jobbies,
I'm thinking we'll start north of a thousand.
Well north.
- Apiece?
- Mmm.
I'm not saying I'm gonna get that.
My rock bottom floor is 500. At 500, I walk.
And by the way, you back me up
no matter what I do, O.K.?
If I walk out that door, you are on my heels.
If I get angry, you act fierce.
If I decide to jump up on this table and start screaming,
you act like I do that all the fucking time. Get it?
Yeah. Sure, Rugged.
They're here.
It's the guy from the Clam Shack. Parka boy.
Still shucking oysters, parka boy?
Yeah, right.
Show 'em the goods, Marcus.
Well, it's, uh... 60 bucks apiece, man.
That's not bad for a morning's work, hmm?
Not bad? I was at that
fucking tractor-trailer school all week.
You only grabbed five, man.
You got to get more next time.
There's not gonna be a next time.
Ah, don't quit on me, man.
You didn't even fucking negotiate.
What?
You were scared of those guys.
What are you talking about?
I was looking at you. You're a coward.
Hey, watch it.
What are you gonna do, whack me?
Like you whacked Connelly?
What... what a lie. You're a fucking liar.
O.K., fine.
You want to walk away from a good thing here, Marcus?
Let me tell you something,
you're not gonna make this kind of money
working at the Clam Shack, all right?
This is tax-free.
O.K., so Rugged wasn't quite the badass yet.
So now you're wondering,
how does a small-time coward
turn into some kind of Granite State Billy The Kid?
Well, that's what this story's all about.
It's a tough economy, Marcus.
Fuck.
Whoa...!
Goddamn it, man.
Motherfucker.
Hey.
Rugged.
- Lagrand?
- What's up?
Nothing, man, you know.
What are you doing around here, man?
I, uh, I thought you left the state.
- My old man died.
- Ah. No shit.
- Well, I guess he was fat enough.
- Yeah.
So how long you in town for?
I don't know.
I'm running the U-Lock. I inherited it.
No shit. Really?
Yeah, I'm running it. It's mine, so...
Shit hot, man. It's a great fucking gig.
Yeah, it is.
My mom, she rents over there.
It's, uh, 126.
Yeah, I know.
Lagrand, running the U-Lock.
That's fucking great, man.
You're, uh, you're set.
You should be buying the good stuff.
Yeah.
If you want. I, I don't care.
- I kind of like Gordon's.
- Yeah, stick with Gordon's.
You know what I've been up to.
- You heard about me?
- No.
Let me get a Wizard Of Odds
and two Dough-In-A-Rows.
Yeah, man, I've been into some heavy shit.
Heavy shit.
I'm doing very well for myself.
You and I should talk.
- Yeah. Cool.
- All right.
So I'll stop by next time I'm at my mom's locker.
- Sounds good.
- All right.
- See you around.
Can you get another bottle?
This one's missing the code.
One hand under the box, Kelly. Both hands.
And fragile, careful.
Uh, brake fluid, two-for-one.
$14.34.
What are you doing?
It's a rebate check.
It's, uh... it's good till the 16th.
Out of 15.
Move it to the road, John.
Yeah, I got, uh, brake problems, Larry.
I'll just be a sec.
You know where this stuff goes?
Is it the master cylinder?
Uh... I don't know. Could be.
Haven't gotten your rent check yet.
Yeah, I'm gonna make it out right after this.
It's, uh, it's the e-brake. It's dead.
- It keeps hitting the floor.
- That's a cable.
- What's a cable?
- The parking brake. It's a cable.
It tightens the shoe against the drum.
- Can I keep it here?
- Leave a key in it.
Don't use the water.
Why not?
The septic tank's leeching into the well.
- You're shitting me.
- No.
It should clear up soon... as long as it doesn't rain.
Ahh! Oh, God!
Mr. Rudgate, Logan from Black and Decker.
O.K., I think I was able to get you the $85 rebate check
for the professional grade skill saw.
Uh, the only thing is,
my boss will need that receipt.
- All right.
- So when your uncle gets back from Greece...
Yeah.
...please send it to us... thank you.
Who da boss? Who da boss?!
Who da boss? You da boss?
Who da boss, man?
You da boss.
Sped!
Hey, Sped.
Special Ed? Remember that?
- That was a mistake.
- I know you're not retarded.
I spent a year with those moos.
- Keep up with any of them?
- Fuck no.
I'm kidding, man. Relax.
So, you want to knock off and get a burrito?
Yeah.
Is McMann still around?
McMann? No, he joined the coast guard
or the merchant marine or something.
Whatever the fuck they do.
I didn't even know you knew him.
Yeah. He was the guy that had me eat
that flaming stuff thing.
The sterno. At the China Tiki.
You ate the buffet.
You ate the sterno. When was that?
I don't know. It was a while ago.
We were working at the Clam Shack, right?
Clam Shack. What a joke, man. Fucking Clam Shack.
I almost completely forgot about that place.
You don't work there anymore?
Fuck no. What, are you kidding me?
Remember when Omar
threw those crab legs at you?
Yeah. Well, Omar wouldn't throw
crab legs at me anymore.
Because you don't work there anymore.
That's the least of it. That's the fucking least of it.
- You haven't heard about me, Lagrand.
- No.
No. You probably don't even know about Connelly.
What's Connelly?
Rod Connelly. Fuckface logger?
Happened to get his head decapitated from his body,
mysteriously.
- Oh, yeah, I did hear about that.
- Mm-hmm.
Let's just say that's one logger
that won't be giving me shit anytime soon.
Nope.
Get what I'm saying here?
- You understand what I'm saying, Lagrand?
- Yeah.
What, you did it?
You didn't hear it from me.
Lagrand, when you left here,
I was some scared little kid.
Riding to work on a moped,
getting seafood tossed at me.
By Omar.
Getting pushed around.
But I've made my bones now, man.
I get women. I buy what I want.
Most importantly, nobody in this town fucks with me.
Damn.
That's not going anywhere.
That's a Windsor knot.
All right.
Your buddies need speakers,
you tell 'em come talk to me.
This... this label's got your name on it.
Oh, yeah. Pick... pick that off, will you?
- I thought you said they were stolen.
- Yeah, yeah.
I make like they're stolen
so people think they're getting a deal.
Cracks me up. It's a complete scam.
- That's a good scam.
- Yeah.
I mean, not that I have a problem
with stealing, you know.
Not that I have a problem with that at all.
You know, I don't like unnecessary risks.
Chief?
I have a kid out here
who says he bought some stolen speakers.
- Can I give him to you?
- Why?
The, um, "check oil" light came up on the cruiser.
I wanted to take it to the Texaco.
Well, it can wait. Bring him in, Putney.
This is, um, Todd Thompkins.
Todd Thompkins.
- You Ted Thompkins' boy?
- No.
Well, it's a common name.
So, uh, tell us about the seller, Todd.
They were these two guys.
They were pretty old.
I don't know, definitely out of high school.
One of them didn't say much,
he was just, like, a big goon.
The other one was around my height. Tan jacket.
- You said he drove a tan van?
- A blue van.
- Was it a minivan or a big van?
- What do you mean?
Well... a Dodge Caravan is kind of big,
but it's considered a mini-van.
Well, I, I've ridden in those-- this was a van.
Um, I'm sorry, Chief.
I really... I want to take care of this before they close.
Fine, Putney.
Did you get a license plate, Todd?
Let's talk about you.
Running the U-Lock. Not too shabby.
That thing's a cash cow.
Why?
I mean, it makes... makes pretty good money, right?
Oh, yeah. Tons.
Course, uh... man, that is a tough business to run.
Especially all by yourself. I mean...
My sister helps out.
Sometimes. With little stuff. Only.
Yeah, but, I mean, you know,
it's not exactly the opera crowd you got
hanging out over there, man.
I mean, you got people hiding shit,
storing shit, stealing shit, you know?
I mean, I just, I hope...
I hope you got somebody good
handling security, that's all.
Yeah, I hope so.
Well, who you got?
- Um, I don't think my dad had anybody.
- Your dad?
- Your dad was a tough guy.
- My dad was a tough guy.
Your dad was a motherfucker.
Your dad was a fucking marine, man.
He had a reputation, like me.
Maybe not as strong as mine, but...
Your dad kept his distance, man.
Me, I like to get in close, man.
I like to feel it, get my fucking hands dirty, you know?
I'll shank a motherfucker, man.
And then I'll go to bed that night
and I'll sleep like a fucking baby.
Man, I wish I could help you out, man,
but I don't have buttloads of time.
Yeah.
Ah, fuck it. You know what, man?
You're a fucking friend. I'll make time. Let's do this thing.
- O.K.! Cool.
- So you want to do it?
- Yeah!
- All right. All fucking right, man.
All right, so how do you want to work this thing out?
What do you mean?
Well, you want to do like a,
like an equity thing or a, a fee?
Like some kind of combination of the two? What?
I don't know.
You were just all fucking psyched up about it.
Yeah, I just didn't know it was like an official thing.
Lagrand, I'm doing you a favor here, man.
- Yeah... but I just need to think about it.
- What's there to think about?
You know, like business things.
Lagrand, this is a great fucking deal for you, man.
Do you know who I am? You understand?
I'm a stone fucking killer, man.
I kill people with my bare fucking hands.
You have a murderer working for you,
don't you get that?
Yeah... yes, and I know how cool that would be.
Listen, I just got to figure stuff out.
Figure... All right, fine, man, you figure it out.
You figure it out, man, you know what,
'cause I got stuff to figure out, too.
I got a lot of shit to figure out, you know.
'Cause this deal,
this deal could be a real pain in the ass for me, man.
A real pain in the ass.
Cheryl.
Hey, did Dad prepay the funeral expenses?
I don't know. Cheryl.
I think the mortician's double-billing us.
- Um, so you remember...
- So, how'd it go with the doors?
- Fine.
- Really?
- Listen, Cheryl...
- Did you finish them?
- Not yet.
- We get major complaints when the doors stick, Jeff.
I'm sorry. Listen, Cheryl...
I feel like I'm doing everything around here.
I'm doing stuff.
Well, what are you doing?
There's nothing else to do.
There's this and there's that.
Finish the doors, please.
I hate talking to these people
any more than I have to.
O.K. Um, so, you remember Rugged.
I used to work with him at the Clam Shack.
- No.
- John Rudgate.
-- Rugged Rudgate.
No! I don't remember him.
We have a Rudgate-- Doreen Rudgate.
- That's his mom.
- O.K. What?
Well, he's a... I was talking to him and
he said that maybe he could help us out and...
- Help us out with what?
- Um, security.
- Security? What's his rate?
- I don't know.
Equity.
- He's not getting equity.
- Why not?
- Equity is ownership.
- It is?
Yeah. Security's nothing.
It's, like, 50 bucks a month.
Well, I just thought, he's somebody we want to work with
and I don't see what the big deal is.
Why don't you see if he can do it for 50 a month?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
50 a month. All right. Cool. I'm sure he can.
- He's a really cool guy.
- Great.
- What's up, man?
- Lagrand. Partner.
Have a seat, man. Step into my office.
- Office.
- Been here before?
- Yeah. All the time.
- M.G.D. On me.
- Thanks, sweet pea.
- Fuck off.
Never try a ménage-à-trois, my friend.
They say they're cool with it,
then they freak out. Yeah.
So, listen, man, I'm fucking pumped
about this U-Lock thing.
- Yeah, me too.
- Yeah? It's gonna be fucking great, man. Cheers.
So, listen, man, when we talk terms...
I want you to know,
I'm gonna be a hardnose motherfucker, O.K.,
because that's just the way I do business.
I don't think you'd expect anything less of me.
But, but the way I negotiate has nothing to do
with how happy I am
we're gonna be working together, O.K.?
Working together again, right?
What, what do you mean?
Clam shack.
Fucking Clam Shack.
That place was a joke, man.
What did they pay us there, like 50 bucks a week?
Chump change.
No, no, no, this is something, man.
This is a fucking enterprise.
I mean, something to hold on to.
Give me some figures, man.
What are you thinking?
Throw out some numbers.
Give me something to chew on.
Parka boy. You even feel that?
- Fuck off, Oldfield.
- What?
Don't worry about those guys. I know them,
they're just screwing around. Playing.
What were you, uh... what were you saying?
Listen, Rugged.
I don't know if this is gonna work out.
Because of that?
That, that's fucking, that's bullshit, man.
You don't think I'm gonna respond to that?
- I'm gonna respond to that shit.
- It's not that.
I'm holding back. Those fucking guys
are walking dead men, O.K.?
They're fucking dead.
I can't do anything right now.
- My buddy owns the bar.
- It's just...
it's that I don't think
I have that much money right now.
That's fucking... that's bullshit, man.
That's fucking bullshit, that's what that is.
What do you need to see, huh?
You need to see me get real?
You want to see me get real with these guys, huh?
You guys are dead, man. Fucking dead.
Yeah, laugh. Laugh like Connelly did.
Oh, yeah. You killed Connelly.
We're shaking, parka boy.
Ooh...
Show some fucking action, man.
Fucking man of action.
Man of action. Man of fucking action.
- Lagrand!
- Huh?
Listen, Rugged, I'm sorry about...
No, man, you listen.
There's something you need to know.
- I really want to work with you.
- I don't care.
I don't care about that, man, O.K.?
You need to know something.
Those motherfuckers in there tonight,
they fucking walked into a bear trap, O.K.?
They don't know it yet, but they did.
And I think you could really learn something
by watching how this shit goes down.
- Uh-huh.
- I'm serious.
Yeah.
- You free tomorrow night?
- Yes.
You prepared to see some serious shit?
'Cause you're gonna see a side of me
you ain't seen before, man.
Yes.
O.K. I'll pick you up at the U-Lock at 5:00.
Bring cigs. Go. Go.
Fuck! Damn it!
What happened with the oil light yesterday?
Tweedledee at the Texaco said you didn't come by.
The oil light? Oh, it, um...
It, uh, fixed itself.
Wow, that's some luck.
Mrs. Connelly. I thought we sent them flowers.
Today, today would have been his birthday, so...
Uh-huh.
Say, uh, what happened with the speakers?
Well, interestingly enough, the D.M.V. says
there's only four blue vans registered in town,
and one of them is registered
to a Mr. John Rudgate-- ring a bell?
"Fart," right?
He's the juvenile
who painted the obscenity on the patriot tree.
But there were two in the van.
The goon? Yeah, well, he'll show up.
They always do.
This come out of petty cash?
No, I, uh... I bought it myself.
Uh-huh.
It's very nice.
What are you doing?
Waiting for Rugged.
If he's doing security,
I'm gonna need his social or his tax I.D.
- I told you that.
- I'm working that out.
Cheryl, do I have equity?
Yeah, we both do.
If I wanted to, could I give my equity to Rugged?
Uh, no. That would make it impossible
for us to sell this place.
Why?
'Cause then buyers
are gonna have to deal with you and me
and some ridiculously overcompensated
clam shucker security guy.
If we sell this place, do I still get to work here?
No. That's the idea.
Well, I don't think that's a good idea.
Well, Jeff, you know,
you can do whatever you want with your share.
You can buy another U-Lock, half-size.
No... I like it here.
This is the best job I've ever had.
Of course it is. You don't do anything.
Well, I'm doing something tonight--
I can tell you that much.
I feel bad about this whole...
I got a certain way of doing things,
Lagrand, you know?
Some fucker messes with me, man,
I don't necessarily fight him right there.
I bide my time. I cogitate.
Or ruminate, whatever the fuck it's called.
Grab that brown bag back there.
That fat fuck Oldfield is gonna get his tonight.
You and me are going down
to that little shit-box house of his near the gravel pit,
we're gonna wait till he leaves,
and we are gonna give him
something I like to call a welljob.
You know what that is?
You gotta speak up, Lagrand.
I'm going out of my way to educate you here, man.
If you don't understand something,
you ask me a question.
I'm happy to answer.
I'm happy when you ask questions.
For God sakes,
don't just sit there like a fucking moo.
- I'm not a moo.
- I'm just saying.
O.K., what's a well chop?
A welljob is when you fuck
with somebody's water well, man.
It could be anything:
a leaky septic system, poison, whatever.
Me, personally, I like to use...
brake fluid.
Will this kill him?
Nah.
Well, it might kill him.
You cool with that?
Yeah, I guess so.
You better be goddamn sure, Lagrand.
This is serious shit. This is big time.
Did you even pack these, man?
This is like smoking air.
You got to pack 'em.
Car 2-9-0.
Lieutenant O'Shea has asked me to relay
that he would like no mayonnaise on his sandwich.
No mayonnaise for lieutenant Billy O'Shea.
What are you doing, Putney?
Uh... just, um, taking a little break.
Staking out your own house?
Stacy send you packing?
No... it's... It's Susan.
Oh. Well, whatever her name is,
she's a terrific lady.
Listen, buddy...
I think that Connelly case
has got you a little bogged down, am I right?
But you can't get hung up on one case.
I mean, you're a good cop, Putney.
You got to learn that every case counts.
I mean, my first case was just some indigent old woman
who was stealing pennies from the
"leave a penny, keep a penny" dish,
but in some ways it was my most gratifying.
Hell of an interrogation...
but she broke.
They all do.
What if he doesn't go out?
It's Friday night, man.
Everybody goes out.
You got to jiggle it.
Hey, that's the guy from the bar.
Get down! Get down!
- Your hands are sweaty.
- Shut up!
All right, he's gone.
You want to do this?
This is the real shit, Lagrand--
I need a real fucking answer from you.
Yeah, definitely, so...
Good.
Fuck!
Thank God I had a big lunch.
Mmm...
Eat the chicken strips.
I'm not eating anything in this shithole.
Clams? You know, my grandfather
used to sell those shits to summer people
and laugh his fucking ass off-- you know why?
This smell funny to you?
Because they're fucking bottom-feeders, that's why.
They eat their own shit.
I need, like, tartar sauce or something.
I need, like, a big thing of it.
Great... shit and mayo, that's appetizing.
These little necks?
- Where'd you get those?
- The bucket.
That's the fucking garbage.
They're going out.
Nobody told me.
How can you not fucking smell that?
I been serving them.
Jesus...
Keep it under your fucking hat.
Fucking-A, man!
We fucking did it!
We did it.
Fucking right we did, man.
Whoo...!
Now, I want you to take what I taught you tonight,
I want you to apply it to this place, man.
'Cause I am all the fuck over this place, man!
I'm gonna hit this place...
...right fucking back!
Rugged, listen, I mean, what we did...
Fucking don't... don't fucking think
about it tonight, man.
You're crazy, you're out of your mind, you're...
coursing with adrenaline, man.
You probably don't know half the ramifications
of what we did tonight.
- I know.
- Just... don't fucking think about it.
Just, sleep... sleep on it.
Think about it.
All right.
Sleep and think, man.
Fucking clams were bad.
I can't feel my tongue.
Don't give me that shit.
What shit?
You're fucking licking me tonight, you got that?
Donna, I'm a mess.
I am out of here. I'm getting a cab.
- No, baby, I'm sick.
- Get your fucking hands off me!
Baby. Ba...
You have reached Hanson Automotive.
Our normal business hours
are 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., pacific time.
If you know your party's extension...
Fuck no...
Hello?
- Hello? Hello!
- Yeah?
Yes?
Yeah, hi, um... I, I,
I'm calling about your,
uh, your C15 heat-resistant brake fluid.
I need to speak to somebody.
It's an emergency.
Everyone's gone, man.
Yeah, I know that, but I...
I poured your brake fluid into my,
uh, in my water w... fountain,
uh, and I think...
I think I'm in trouble.
Why'd you do that?
It was an accident,
but the important thing is that I...
My dog may have drank some of that shit.
- How bad is that gonna fuck him up?
- That's bad shit, man.
Sometimes when we make it outside,
the birds, they die.
Holy fuck.
O.K., um...
Is there any way to, uh...
I'd stick to the bottled stuff for now.
Yeah, is there any way to neutralize it?
Hope you got a lot of vinegar.
Vinegar? O.K., good.
How much? How much vinegar?
Or... what's it called,
not sodium-- the brown liquid.
Stick to the vinegar, O.K.?
How much?
A lot.
Change.
Oh, fucking, so fucking stupid. Fucking...
Oh, fuck no.
Fuck, man. Fuck me! So fucking stupid!
Fuck!
We've moved on to breakfast.
Don't,
don't sit, don't sit there.
Sit, sit behind me.
Sit in the next booth.
Sit behind me.
- Like this?
- Turn around. Turn around.
Did you get to the hospital?
Yeah.
How's he doing?
He's dead.
What?
I held his hand while he went-- it was creepy.
You're fucking kidding me.
I said I was one of his friends
and they told me to comfort him.
He's dead?
Yeah.
Oh, and they know it's poisoning.
What?
Well, I heard the nurses talking
and they said poisoning.
So...
Fuck.
Are we O.K.? 'Cause I've never
been in this situation before.
Where are you going?
John Rudgate!
This your van?
Yeah.
You O.K. there?
Bad danish.
You know, I was wondering
what you were up to yesterday.
- What do you care?
- Just following up on some reports.
What reports?
If you're so interested,
we could go down to the station, I could fill you in.
You charging me with something?
We're just talking.
'Cause if you're not charging me with something,
why don't you just back the fuck off?!
You watch it.
Yeah, I'll watch it.
And I'll watch you.
I know it's you...
Rugged.
You're the rotten danish.
"I know you did it?"
Yeah.
Does he think I did it?
What the fuck does that matter, man?
Well, I don't know.
I've never been in this situation before.
Neither have I.
I mean, yes, yes, I have,
but not like this, you know?
I knew that he was gonna get sick,
I knew he was gonna get very, very sick.
I didn't think he was gonna fucking die.
Oh, God, we are fucked, man. We are so fucked.
Why are we fucked?
He didn't book me.
- What's going on?
- They got nothing, Lagrand.
If they had anything on us,
we'd be squatting on a steel toilet right now.
Why are you throwing those things?
All right, here's the plan, man.
We got to wash the van.
We got to wash our clothes.
We got to come up with an alibi.
Something solid. Uh...
I'll buy a TV Guide.
What else?
The check!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Hey.
What are you doing?
Where do we keep the checks?
Why?
Because I need to buy something.
What? What?!
What's the difference, Cheryl?
Fine...
Just wait. God.
And make sure you put the name
and the amount in here
so that I can put it into Quicken.
The name and the account.
Amount.
Where are you going?
Um, hardware store.
We have an account there,
that's the difference.
We get charged 15 cents per check.
There's a quarter.
And we get the float,
and I get an account summary.
Well, I just wish you'd clear that deal with me first.
- Did you get it?
- No.
What's the problem?
- Where are you going?
- We have an account there.
So?
Why can't we use one of your checks?
I told you, we're not throwing good money after bad.
I got a rebate check in there already.
That's what this whole thing's about.
Well, I don't want to fuck things up, O.K.?
I mean, we have an account there, it floats...
- What the fuck are you talking about?
- They have to be balanced, and that's the books.
You're not making any sense.
Cheryl's gonna make a fuss, all right?
Cheryl? What the fuck does she care about it?
She signs the checks sometimes.
You let her do that?
Well, when I'm busy and
I don't have one moment to do anything.
That's fucking twisted, man.
Well, also, we're out of checks, so that's that.
Out of checks?
That's easy, man-- we go to the bank,
we get a new check. Problem solved.
Come on. Come on!
You shouldn't let Cheryl handle your money, man.
It's like handling your balls.
- She's fucking 17.
- She's 19.
Whatever. It's fucked up.
Got it.
Great.
John!
Mrs. Blodgett, hi.
- I can't talk right now, I got to go.
- You stay right there!
This lady's crazy, man.
She's a friend of my mother's.
I did a job for her, like,
five years ago or something.
It was last week.
And he didn't do it.
That litter box was filthy.
I just gave you that job as a favor to your mother.
Against my better judgment!
$3.40.
Check? O.K.
There you go.
Have a pleasant one.
Yeah?
I already have one, so...
I don't need to write a check.
O.K.
Did you see the checks?
- Yeah.
- Where are they?
Um, under the register.
Ah, good work, man.
No alarms, right?
Yeah, I saw a sticker.
Fuck.
All right, well, sometimes those stickers are decoys.
Did it say like, uh, "Acme Alarm", "U.S.A. Alarm",
"Official Alarm Company", something like that?
It said "Granite State".
Fuck. That's real.
That's who my mom uses.
Well, you can get by an alarm, right?
Usually. Not Granite State, man,
that's the real shit.
I know a guy...
Gazaniga.
Not the kind of guy you want to work with, man.
He's a fucking loose cannon.
You know anybody?
Um...
No. No.
Fuck.
This guy's fucking Satan.
You ever watch U.F.C.?
No.
Take two fighters, put 'em in a cage,
take away the rules and see what happens.
Anything goes:
pinching, biting, strangulation.
- He does that?
- He wants to, yeah.
That's the kind of sick, messed-up motherfucker
we're dealing with here.
What's up, Gazaniga?
What do you want?
You doing U.F.C.?
Got the application.
Can you still get by an alarm?
What are you talking about?
My mom's house?
I don't know shit about your mom's house.
You got by her alarm.
I didn't fucking get by anything.
Listen, man. I don't care about that, O.K.?
It's in the past.
I just need some help here.
Just don't accuse me of stealing
from your ho-bag mom.
Fine. Whatever. I'm sorry. O.K.?
So, here's the deal.
We've been casing this store.
Who's the giraffe?
It's Lagrand. He runs the U-Lock.
No shit.
Alex.
Jeff.
You got two lockers over there, right? Two sizes?
Yeah.
What's the little one run?
- Could I, uh, get a go-cart in there?
- Yeah. I mean...
We can help you with any need...
O.K., could you guys pick this up some other time?
Listen, here's the deal.
Me and Lagrand have been casing this store
and they've had some major fucking cash sales, man.
Major sales, all cash.
How much?
I think, like, 600...
600 bucks, easy.
Talking about the U-Lock, right?
No, man, he's not robbing
his own fucking place, O.K.?
- Don't worry about that, listen.
- I can't.
The question is: can you still get by
a Granite State alarm?
I get half.
Fine.
So, you can do it?
Oh, yeah.
O.K.
I never knew you were into this kind of shit, John.
There's a lot about me you don't know, Gazaniga.
A lot.
Let's go, Lagrand.
Motherfucker was wearing
my mother's engagement ring, man!
He really broke into your house?
Fucking garage sale.
My skates, my Cars And Drivers.
Good shit, man.
Yeah, um, would you please tell me
if you sold a small gold charm
with engraving on the back?
Caught a break in the Connelly case.
You know, I'll, I'll call you right back.
My ears on the street are saying John Rudgate did it.
- Rudgate.
- Vandalism. Theft. Murder.
It's a slippery slope, Putney.
He was combative when I questioned him.
So I'm gonna take you off the speaker case.
It's just...
Well, if this all connects, I want to do it right.
Put this Rudgate guy away.
O.K.
Gift for the Mrs.?
"From loving cock."
I found it in her drawer.
Must be the name of a store.
She's, um... she's cheating on me.
Oh, come on, Stacy's crazy about you.
It's fucking Susan.
Well, maybe she's upset about your language.
Yeah, right.
Look, I'll, um...
I'll give you the paperwork
I have on the speaker case, O.K.?
Look, if you want to talk about anything...
my door's always open.
Thank you.
Come on, baby. Come to papa.
There. Right there.
Got it?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
There she is.
Yah!
Aah...
What the fuck was that?
Jesus.
Oh, yeah. It's done.
That's a bullshit way to do it, man.
Anybody could have done that.
No, anybody couldn't have.
Where's the fucking cash drawer?
How come there wasn't a hole in my mom's wall?
Because I didn't fucking do that.
Where's the fucking cash drawer?
Is that why you have my CDs?
I didn't have your fucking CDs, John!
The cash drawer's right here.
Good eyes, Jeff.
Thank you.
Haah!
You're amazing.
Uh, where's the cash?
There's, like, 43 bucks here.
Oh, what do you know?
Lagrand, where's the fucking checks?
Here's a 20.
John, where's the fucking 600?
I told you about 600.
There better be something fucking nice
in this shithole.
This is shit!
Where's the checks, Jeff?
Here's where he was hiding 'em.
This is shit!
It's an inkidata rebate check,
man, 15 bucks.
It was, like, ink-jet or ink cartridge
or inkidata or some shit like that.
Holy shit!
Fucking porno!
Big time.
Holy shit.
Fucking dirty dog.
I'm calling all this shit.
Yeah, go nuts, man.
"John J. Rudgate."
Fucking jewelry, too.
Nice.
This shit looks targeted, man.
We got to jack all this shit.
Bust it up.
Fucking roll.
Fucking X-Actos?
Oughta get 50 bucks, though,
for these badasses.
From who?
Garage sale.
Aw, no, man, no fucking way!
No garage sale. Not again.
What the fuck do you mean, "again," John?
You can't fence this shit.
You'll tip the cops.
Sorry, man, I got bills.
I got the sweetest fucking love seat on layaway.
You got bills to pay?
Why don't you sell that ring
on your pinkie finger?
You know what, John? I'm gonna come up there
and show you this fucking ring.
No fucking garage sale.
Fine. You stop me.
Fine. We're fucking buying this shit off you, then.
Fine.
And this shit I'm fucking keeping...
for my personal...
Those speakers are worth
a hell of a lot more than this shit.
They're nice.
All right. No backsies.
I'm just saying, man,
you're getting a hell of a deal here.
Hell of a deal.
Keys.
When you bringing her back?
What?
The van.
"Yuh, right!"
I'm serious.
The van was part of the deal.
The fuck it was.
You think I want these ugly fucking speakers?
Oh, God.
You know what?
Fuck this.
This is why I don't...
Jeff, give me a hand
with these Taiwanese pieces of shit.
Hold on, hold on!
You know how much that van's worth?
- This is a piece of shit.
- It's not a piece of shit, man!
The exhaust on that fucking thing is brand-new!
Do you know what the blue book is on that guy?
- Nobody gets blue book.
- Fuck that, man, I get blue book!
The thing's got tow package, cassette,
the heat fucking cranks-- I roast in that thing!
Fine, fine, fucking take it.
Just take it, take it.
Take it, please.
Get the fuck out of here, please. Go.
Keys.
O.K.
Hey, Jeff, you find the right buyer,
you'll do all right with this stuff.
Thanks.
You're gonna kill him, aren't ya?
He's not all bad.
That was a good van.
Pretty good.
It's just, like, when does it stop, you know?
The killing.
Whoa, whoa-- what the fuck are you doing?
- What?
- This is evidence, man.
We can't keep this shit here.
That ties it to me with a fucking ribbon.
Well, what are we supposed to do?
I don't know, fucking...
fucking bury it or something, man.
There's got to be a shovel in here somewhere.
Fucking Gazaniga, man.
Half the place is gardening shit.
He can't steal one fucking spade?!
There's probably something inside.
Hey.
It's a fucking snow shovel, man.
It's a snow shovel.
Here's another... one.
Oh, shit hot, man.
That's good. Yeah, grab that.
What are you doing?
I thought we had a break-in.
No, I'm just getting a shovel.
Who's this?
That's Rugged, remember?
I told you about him.
Oh, yeah.
Rugged. Rudman.
Doreen. Mom.
Clam. Security guy.
Yeah, that's right. I looked around.
You got a lot of, uh,
weaknesses in your perimeter.
You mean like the fact
that you two left the gate wide open?
I thought I told you to leave it locked
after 9:00, Jeff.
I thought we had a break-in
with all that crap lying around.
Yeah, well, if it had been a real break-in,
that crap wouldn't be there.
It'd be gone.
But you don't need to worry
about someone breaking in with me around.
Not if they value their health.
Is that your service? Fear-mongering?
Maybe I should just post your picture
up on the gate.
It's a lot more than mongering.
I've had a security license for 10 years, O.K.?
What did you do here?!
You know what, you guys get out of here.
Clean up outside. I'll take care of this.
Goddamn it, Jeff.
I had this stuff organized.
Yeah.
You sure she's your real sister?
Your mom didn't marry some other dude
or something?
Yes. No.
I guarantee you there was some kind
of hanky-panky going on somewhere.
Hey, hey. What about there?
Sure.
Yeah, that's good.
Shit hot, man. That's perfect.
It's all rock.
It's called the fucking Granite State for a reason.
It's gonna take a long time.
It would go a lot quicker...
if you did some work.
Look at this pile I got here.
What have you got there, man?
You got nothing. Come on.
I got a bad shovel. It's all bent.
All right, all right.
Let's just stop complaining
and get the job done, O.K.?
Oh, fuck. Motherfucker.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
- Fuck 'em.
Stump grinders... band saws...
outdoor lighting.
I had a beautiful two-person raft right there,
and now it's...
this is a fucking insane asylum here.
- Yeah.
- And I don't have insurance.
The bean counters wouldn't insure me.
I was high-risk.
Fucking cunts.
What do you make of this?
It was probably more than one guy.
They disengaged the alarm...
cleaned out the register.
They probably were disappointed with the take
and then they, uh, got a little violent, Chief.
A little violent?
Maybe they were rushed.
No, look at the cubbies, Putney.
I mean, this is all gratuitous.
What are they gonna do with this stuff,
hold a garage sale?
No, no, I got another idea.
I think our culprits
really wanted to stick it to this guy.
What do you mean, like revenge?
Shit!
Cunts took my pornos!
Vintage shit! Gone!
Why don't you, uh, get some shots of the outside?
O.K., Chief.
Mr. Hesh.
I want to ask you something.
I want you to think hard.
Think you might have any enemies?
Why's that?
Well, there's just so much gratuitous damage here.
I find it hard to believe
that this is just a simple burglary.
Sure. Right.
I mean, who the fuck steals X-Actos?
Is there anybody you can think of
who might have something against you?
Yeah. My next-door neighbor.
- Yeah? What happened there?
- The guy's a cunt.
Plays his goddamn drums
while I'm relaxing in my spa.
So, why would he do this?
I don't know.
I hurt his dog.
I mean, you know,
it was kind of an accident, but...
It really wasn't, you know.
But it looked like it.
His name?
Stallard.
The roofer?
I don't think so.
This guy's in a wheelchair.
It could be that cunt from the pharmacy.
- What's his name?
- Who? Marty Swain? Swain drug?
No, the kid at the register.
With the pimples?
What's the cunt's name?
Hey, watch the...
Corky...?
- Watch the language, will you?
- All right.
Anybody else?
Well, my kid's teachers: math, gym, English.
Tell me about them.
You know, they were picking on him,
so I made some threats.
What kind of threats?
Ah... "If you do this, I'll do that..." You know.
Names?
Yeah, uh... Mr. Harris... Mrs. Trapezio...
And, uh... whatever the cunt.
Uh, short little lesbo...
Look, I'm not gonna ask you again
about the language!
Sixth-grade gym.
She's sixth-grade gym.
Anybody else?
No. That's it.
O.K., well, uh, I'm gonna talk
to some of these people.
If any other names come up,
tell me about it, O.K.?
Yeah.
Uh, hold, hold up a sec.
Uh...
Maybe there is somebody else.
- Um...
- Yeah?
There's this guy.
Uh... I've been banging his wife.
It's, uh...
Guess who.
It's your partner.
It's the guy out there.
- Putney?
- Yeah.
Does he know it's you?
That's the thing.
I don't know.
You think he'd do this?
So, what do you think?
Any hunches?
Well, I, uh... I think we should, uh,
maybe start at the swap meets.
See where they're fencing this stuff.
You seem to think it's more than one person.
I doubt anyone did this alone.
Uh-huh.
You know, you're a good cop.
Good cop, Putney.
You know, maybe I was holding you back
on this speaker case.
Bet you'd like another crack at that one, huh?
Yeah, sure.
All right, buddy.
O.K., you're on the varsity now.
Here, now, give me that camera.
I will take this case...
and that...
and you stay on Rudgate and the goon...
and you call me if there's any developments.
Or if you... you know,
if you need to talk about anything.
Anything at all, all right?
Sure. O.K.
O.K.
Thanks, Chief.
Congratulations.
O.K.
Rugged.
What time is it?
9:00.
Fuck it.
This is deep enough, man.
Let's bury the shit here.
What the fuck?
Was that there?
Where the fuck are we?
I mean, how could you not have noticed that?
I don't know.
This is a major, major fuck-up, Lagrand!
This is a goddamn embarrassment, man!
Fuck!
Pick up the flashlights, man.
Let's go.
I've got a blue van selling speakers.
License plate 1-5-4-0-1-7-1.
Copy, car 12.
I'm making a stop.
Just you?
Yeah.
License and registration, please.
Yeah, uh... I lost my license.
Um... just, uh, got the van, actually, so, um...
Step out of the vehicle, please.
Step to the front of the vehicle.
Yeah. Uh, what's the problem?
Where'd you get the speakers?
Oh, they came with the van.
You know, if they're stolen,
that's got nothing to do with me.
That's, uh, the previous owner.
I can give you his name, if you like.
What's that?
Oh, that's, uh...
That's definitely not stolen.
That's from my girlfriend.
"From loving cunt."
Uh... she's a freaky one.
Is that what you think, cock?
Uh, what?
You think she's freaky, cock?
Uh... I don't know.
You think she's married, cock?
What?
- Fuck!
- What the fuck, cock?
Huh?
Yeah... you motherfucker.
I killed a man because of you.
Help!
I killed Rod Connelly.
Help...!
I'm gonna regret that the rest of my life.
I'm not gonna regret killing you.
'Cause you're the real cock, aren't you? Huh?
You fuck people's wives?
You fucked my wife?
You wife fucker.
What the...?
Oh, you motherfuck.
You motherfuck!
God... Fuck!
Fuck!
You fucking piece of shit.
Good work, man.
Let's go.
That is why you dig to six feet, Lagrand.
O.K.
We'll throw this in the pond.
Car seven, please escort the pastor
to Susan Putney's house.
Provide her with any assistance she might need.
Chief. Found these in the van.
Lagrand.
We've got the goon.
You ever still think about that logger?
All the fucking time, man.
'Cause I've been thinking about that guy, Oldfield,
and I'll tell you...
I wish I didn't go to that hospital.
Hey.
You stop that.
You stop that right now. You listen to me.
That fuck had it coming.
Just...
What?
Just don't kill Alex, O.K.?
Yeah.
Six fucking...
You don't evict someone
for six fucking days, Beckett!
Fuck.
Come on.
All right.
Jimmy this fucking thing.
Fuck.
Oh, shit.
It says "Homicide".
Come back, back, back, back.
Should we kick it?
No, no. I got a key.
What about those old train tracks,
the ones that run behind Neighbor's Market?
- What about 'em?
- Well, they go north, right?
They go to Canada.
You think they got a border check there?
Not for a train, right?
I mean, a train that doesn't even run.
Why would they have a border check?
It doesn't make sense.
Let's give it a try.
Fuck... almost out of gas.
You got any cash?
Fuck it.
Let's pump and run.
Can't fuck up our rap sheets any worse.
Let's ride.
Hey, you got to pay first after 8:00.
Just ignore him.
Hey.
Hey, man, you hear me?
Marcus?
I didn't know you worked here, man.
Listen, I got some shit going on right now.
I'll pay you later, O.K.?
Yeah, I heard.
Listen, uh, sorry
about that whole diploma thing, you know?
I fucked up.
And I totally believe you about Connelly.
Wait. What'd you hear?
On TV. The killing.
Really?
Yeah. So, uh, you guys just take
anything you want, O.K.?
Yeah.
It's on TV.
TV?
I never seen him like that before.
Shaking like a leaf.
Come on.
Hey, what the fuck are we hurrying for, man?
Let's go back there.
Get some free chips,
a little sustenance for the outlaws.
Chief, I spotted them at Neighbor's Market.
Copy, car 12.
So, Marcus...
you, uh, you think
you might want to work with me again?
Oh, yeah. Sure, man.
It's like you said, nobody fucks with you.
I don't know, man.
I mean, last time you had a lot of trouble
following instructions.
- You think that's gonna change?
- Definitely.
Ooh... ice.
Fuck!
You're surrounded, Rudgate.
Give yourselves up.
Come out slowly with your hands high in the air
like you're playing a nice little game of volleyball.
Oh, fuck... so stupid, man.
So fucking stupid!
What are we gonna do?
They're everywhere, man.
We're fucked. We're fucking surrounded.
Let's just tell 'em the truth, Rugged.
I mean, it was kind of an accident.
How do you accidentally kill a cop?
He wasn't a cop.
Lieutenant Putney.
They showed his picture on TV.
Well, as usual, they got it wrong, man.
He wasn't a fucking cop.
He was some piece-of-shit plumber, John Oldfield.
Oldfield?
- Yeah.
- The guy who got food poisoning?
It wasn't food poisoning.
Yeah. It, it was.
At the Clam Shack.
I was working that shift.
Well, tell him that, man.
He held his hand while he died.
You know what?
The nurses did say food poisoning.
I forgot that.
I forgot the "food".
Food poisoning?
That's why I'm working the pumps.
They closed us down, dude.
Let's go, cop killers.
Give you 30 seconds to give yourselves up.
So, what the fuck are they talking about?!
So... you're not the cop killers?
No!
This is all about some fucking cop?
Lieutenant Putney.
We didn't kill Lieutenant Puppy.
I don't even know who he is.
Then who did you kill?
We didn't kill anybody.
I didn't think you'd kill anybody.
Let's tell them, Rugged.
Shut up, Lagrand. Shut up.
We killed somebody.
Who?
We killed Putney.
You said you killed Oldfield.
That was a lie, man.
That was a cover story.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Lagrand, we fucking killed a man, O.K.?
We killed a cop.
We killed a cop and if they catch us,
we're gonna fucking fry for it.
What?
We got to make a run for it, man.
We got to get the mopeds and make for the border.
You're crazy.
Yeah, I am fucking crazy.
You've got to be pretty fucking crazy to kill a cop.
And you fucking remember that, Marcus!
You tell all your little friends
and you tell everybody in this town.
John J. Rudgate is a fucking cop killer!
I, I... I think I winged him.
No one could believe
he went out the front door,
let alone make it past the bullets...
but the dude fucking did it.
The police were sure they'd hit him.
They even found some blood, but...
Chief Monson cut his hand on his car door,
so it could have been from that.
I'm thinking all those Marlboro cartons made Rugged
a fatter Target than he was.
I mean, the dude looked like Jabba The Hut
running out of there.
Sounded like him too.
When the nationwide manhunt didn't turn him up,
we all knew he rode the railroad tracks
straight up to Canada.
Some even said he was running drugs
from South America,
'cause his mom's phone bill
showed a call from La Paz.
She said it was a wrong number.
Whenever weird shit happened in town--
like the high school mascot getting served up
at the awards banquet--
people blamed Rugged.
Channel Five even did a special report.
This kid's a fucking legend.
My friend.
Women whispered about him.
- Kids started talking like him.
- Shit hot, man.
The army-navy store
moved a lot more parkas and knit caps.
Rugged put our 'hood on the map.
People were proud
a hustler from west bumfuck came to be something.
A renegade, an outlaw,
maybe even a kingpin in the Bolivian drug trade.
As for me and Lagrand,
we were booked and released.
"Lack of evidence," they said.
Lagrand bought his own U-Lock
to get out from under his sister.
Went out of business in about a week.
I think he's working for Alex Gazaniga
doing pet grooming or some shit like that.
Down! Down!
Down, weimeraner.
As for me,
I hate waiting on a paycheck,
so I ended up picking up some of the crumbs
Rugged left behind.
I sent in buttloads of rebate coupons,
ran a fake charity,
harvested sod off the football field...
But my best scam I called
"A.A.A.A. Trash Collection Service".
I dodged the landfill fees 'cause
I used the dumpster behind the coffee shop instead...
Till some fuckface caught on and padlocked it.
So there I was, stuck with a full load
of stinky diapers and stale beer.
I decided to drive out of town
and dump it in the woods.
I found a clearing down an old logging road,
a place even turkey hunters wouldn't bother with...
Big enough to keep me working till Christmas.
And that's when I came across it.
He'd gone over 10 miles.
Must have been riding on pure nicotine.
I thought of all the people I'd tell...
the cops, the newspapers, Lagrand...
and then I thought twice.
So he didn't make it.
Big fucking deal.
I bet if you looked hard enough,
you'd find Billy The Kid pissed his pants
once or twice.
So I'm not telling anyone.
Legends are just too hard to come by around here.