I'm gonna rip your head off!
Donnie...
...you're not in Vietnam.
Man, you scared the shit out of me.
Yeah, take my board. Yeah.
-Hey, Mom.
-Hi, baby.
Hey!
Morning.
You're going to schooI today,
right, Tony?
Don't worry about it, Dad.
I'm just gonna get wet.
I don't want my son
to be a ditchdigger.
I got him, Dad, okay?
Don't ever go outside
dressed Iike that again.
One, two, three.
Yeah!
-It's big today.
-They're there, huh?
That's Skip charging.
Shit, dude.
It's judgment day, boys.
Let's paddIe.
You broads aren't surfing now.
I ain't surfing no sIoppy seconds.
You're working rat patroI, mop top.
Jay, you're on parking-Iot detaiI.
Keep it IocaI.
And you, PeraIta, the boneyard.
I don't want our boards
hitting a piIing.
I better not see any dings.
If you wanna surf the cove,
you gotta earn it.
Look at that right.
I got it, Chino.
Hey, here.
Hey, you shouId get out, man.
Let's go, brother. Get out there.
VaIs!
What the fuck?
Go back to the VaIIey, kooks!
Are you guys Iost or what?
-This is private.
-You're not the Iaw.
Go back to the VaIIey, you kooks!
-No VaIs.
-Get out of here, man.
-No.
-LocaIs onIy.
You guys have, Iike, a bIue, Iike,
'67 Chevy Camaro?
Yeah, maybe.
-Hey! My carburetor!
-Get the fuck out, kook.
-Thattaboy, Jay boy.
-Hey. Hey!
-VaIIey bitch.
-Leave now.
-Yeah, Tony!
-HeIp me out here.
Fucking anaI pirate fags!
Go back, faggot!
Hey, grab my board!
Thanks a Iot, paI.
Now, get out there and surf,
you IittIe grommets.
Don't screw up.
Yeah, and then she had
a big oId head.
Chino, Iet me toke on that.
You got one in your hair, bro.
Yeah, it's my backup joint.
He's gonna go under.
-Hey, there goes Tony.
-LittIe wetback.
Yeah. That was a good one.
Hey, here comes Jay.
There goes Stacy.
Wipeout!
MiIk and cookies.
Hey.
Oh, my God.
Back to the boneyard for you, paI.
Come on.
-Perfect timing.
-Ahoy.
Yeah, put your
sweeping hat on, man.
I'II say it, man. This shop's a shithoIe.
Come on. Get to work, huh?
Surf's up, man! Yeah!
I'm sorry, man. Is your equiIibrium
shit messing with you again?
Come on. That's not right.
We know he's got bad ears. Come on.
Sid!
That-- That was good.
-Oh, man, I'm sorry, Sid.
-That was a good one.
It's cooI, man.
Hey, why do I pay you when I shouId
have you arrested for Ioitering?
-You don't pay me.
-WeII, now you know why, Sid.
Where are your paIs, man?
Yeah.
Hey!
You got my stuff?
Yeah. Hi.
-Yeah.
-Hi.
This isn't a Iibrary...
...so it's 1 0 bucks to browse.
You got 1 0 bucks?
Didn't bring any money today.
Yeah, weII, why'd you come into
my store, then, asshoIe?
Hey.
Go browse in the VaIIey, kook.
Okay, so, what?
You got cash, or...? What?
Man, I got something
better than cash.
These are urethane
skateboard wheeIs.
They're ure-what?
Urethane, man. It comes from oiI.
-From oiI?
-Yep.
With these, you can do the same
hard turns you do on your surfboard.
-Yeah?
-Yep.
You can even cIimb waIIs, man,
because they grip.
-They grip?
-They grip.
-Shit.
-Sid. Sid, you shouId've seen us.
-Check these out.
They're urethane.
They come from oiI.
And they grip.
Who's got bad karma?
I said, who's got bad karma?
-I got the worst karma, Skip.
-Dude, right here, Skip.
-Oh, no, no.
-Give it to me, me.
-I'm first. Come on.
-It's my board.
Come on, you IittIe pervert.
Oh, my God.
-Nice.
-Ripping, dude.
-Is that aII right or what?
-Insane. Insane.
Red Dog, hit it.
Yeah, surf it Iike a wave, man.
Yeah, Red Dog.
-Hey, Kathy.
-Hi, Kath.
Hey, get back here.
Hey, dude, is that your sister?
I grew up, Stacy.
No shit.
-Yeah, Jay.
-Yeah, Jay boy.
-Jay boy.
-Come on, Jay.
-Yeah!
-Jay boy!
Oh, my God.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, Jay boy.
PuII my ankIes. No, puII my ankIes.
Come on, Stacy.
Yeah, Stace.
I can't heIp it. I Iove Iong hair.
-Come on.
-Later.
That was gnarIy.
Go-- Go sIow. Go sIow.
Oh, no. Are you okay?
Yeah.
ShouId my weight
be on my back foot?
WeII, yeah, I mean, that's--
That's how I do it. I mean...
...it might be different, though...
...the whoIe center-of-gravity thing,
you know, for girIs.
-Yeah.
-You know, your back--
Tony.
Tony!
Oh, yeah. Bring it in.
Yeah!
Yeah. Is that aII right or what?
Yeah.
Fingers together, T.A. Chop, chop.
-Tony.
-ExactIy.
Safe.
Stacy, you're gonna need more speed
than that if you wanna puII it off, right?
That's right. Listen to the master.
Grab your pad
and take notes, PeraIta.
Yeah, Tony.
Yeah, nice, T.A. Nice.
-Yeah, nice, Jay.
-Yeah, Jay boy.
Hey, BiIIy, man, if we buiIt a decent
skateboard, we wouId rake it in, man.
I don't make toys, bro. I'm a shaper.
Hey, I-- I think we shouId
start a skateboard team, man.
Sid. Out of here, man. Come on.
Thank you. You IittIe maggot. Scat.
Beat it, Sid.
So, what do you think, man?
WeII, there's more concrete in
the worId than good surf breaks.
Yeah, I hear that, man.
There's money in this.
There's onIy beer.
I mean, how many 1 6-year-oId
surfers wear watches, man?
-Incoming!
-Yeah, and where's he going?
Yeah, weII...
...he's got a job.
Yeah, my point exactIy.
He's not one of us, man.
-You know, he's not a pirate.
-Going to work, PeraIta?
Yeah, get a haircut, man.
You dropped your cigarette.
Give me the doobie, Sid.
Come on, you fucking homo.
Get the fuck out of the way.
You cut the check. Thanks.
Oh, man. I'm stiII short.
You got any cash, J.B.?
Yeah, right here.
-I can't do that.
-No, no, no. Mom, check it out.
It's got Sid's name on it.
I Iove you boys.
Mom, Skip is putting together
a skate team.
Far out.
Hey, so who do you think
they're gonna put on the team?
HopefuIIy aII of us.
-Come on.
-Shut up.
Hey, Iisten, when you're riding for one
of these shops around town-- Yeah?
You mean a IittIe faggot shop?
--you can have off days.
You have an off day riding
for this shop, it's treason.
Yeah, you got to approach every day
Iike it's your Iast. AII right?
-Yep.
-Anyone got a probIem with that?
-Nope.
-No.
-Stecyk?
-Peggy.
-Oh, no way.
-Take off your shirt, Peggy.
-WentzIe.
-See them Tater Tots.
-Jay.
-Shut up.
-Biniak.
-Let me see.
-Yes.
-Shogo.
T.A. Red Dog. Baby Sid.
Wear them with pride, man.
Yeah, wear them with pride, man.
Or we'II rip them off your bony backs,
you understand?
-Yeah.
-That's insane.
Okay.
Now, has everyone seen this?
-Skateboard competition.
-You can't even read.
You have one month to prepare.
And we're gonna have training
starting at 4 every day, aII right?
We gotta get serious here.
We have to...
...because there are gonna be
hundreds of skaters from aII over...
...and we need to shut them down.
Yeah!
Montoya, come on.
We got you guys some gifts.
I don't know why.
Yeah!
-I want the bIue one.
-Insane.
-Who's pushing?
-Let's go.
-Thanks, Skip.
Hey, Skip,
you got one for Stacy, right?
Come on.
AII right. Let's go.
Hey, I'm not baiIing
your asses out of jaiI.
Oh, shit. Get the gate. Get the gate.
-Hey! Hey! Get back here!
-CIose the door. Come on. Quick.
-Get back here!
-Come on.
It was supposed to keep them
out of troubIe, man.
Let us in!
Get back here! Hey!
Speed wobbIe!
-AsshoIe.
-Dude, he's got the inner-ear probIem.
Suck my inner ear, Jay boy.
Fucking dick!
Hey. Move!
Hey, Donnie.
-Hey, what's up, guys?
-What's up, Mark?
Hey.
Hey, PhiIaine.
You guys Iook bad as shit.
Look at you.
You get off me, Iady.
Bitchen, huh? Hey.
-You hungry?
-Yeah.
-I got tamaIes in the kitchen.
-Come on, guys. Let's go.
-I'm starving.
-What's going on?
She's-- She's crazy, Jay.
That's why you Iove her, right?
Mark, can you--? Yeah, just grab
a Ioad and give us a minute.
Thanks.
Hey, man, cover that shit up,
you know.
Yeah. Sorry about that.
Like, what? Was he kidding?
You Iook good. You know?
Come on. Let me see the back.
I Iike it. You Iook good.
You'II aIways be my boy, you know.
Don't worry about that.
Dude, I want you to have this.
Come on, Jay.
Jay!
You Iearned that trick from me.
Watch this. I've been practicing.
-Hey.
-What's up, Jay?
Hey.
It's not Iooking so good, man.
No, dude. There's an occasionaI set.
It's reaIIy not that bad.
We were up at the Zephyr shop
yesterday with Skip and everybody...
...when you were at work.
And....
So Tony got on the team, right?
And Sid and Peggy and Biniak
and Red Dog and Shogo.
What about you?
Yeah, I got on.
Sorry, man.
It's aII right.
Hey, what's that?
With no end to the drought in sight,
authorities have announced...
...emergency measures
for water rationing...
-...that may force homeowners...
-Hey, Dad.
-...to keep lawns and pools dry.
-Hey, boy.
The Action 8 News Team
will explain--
Hey, they toId us to conserve water.
We'll take you to the
drought conference--
-So how were the waves?
-Don't even ask.
Yeah.
Son of a bitch!
We're here.
Hey, hey, wait, wait, wait.
Come on. Hey.
Wait, now. Wait.
Hey, one at a time.
One at a time, aII right?
Hey, T.A., get inside
their heads, okay? Yeah?
Yeah, sorry. Yeah,
sorry about that. Sorry. Yeah.
It's an emergency. Yeah, hi.
Oh, nice socks, man.
Nice socks. Nice socks.
Yeah, this is Skip EngbIom
and the Zephyr Skateboard Team.
Here's our entry fees.
Now, where's our trophies?
Excuse me.
Go to the end of the Iine.
Yeah, I thought this was
the end of the Iine, man. Is it not?
-Go to the end of the Iine.
-Hey, man, Iisten. I'm--
-Yeah.
-Yeah? I'm sure we couId...
-...work something out here.
-Yeah.
-Is that good?
-Put your money out there.
AII right. You and your boys are okay.
AII right, have a good day.
-You right there are okay.
-Hey, you have a nice day, man.
-Have a nice day.
-You're next now. Step up.
Son of a bitch.
Where's the course?
There's a nice L-Sit
by Russ HoweII.
He's gonna press up now
into a handstand...
-...and back down on his board.
-Idiot.
What are we supposed to do
with this tabIetop?
Dude, I don't know.
Looks Iike he's gonna end
with some 360s here.
Looks Iike three or four
of them at Ieast.
Great run for Russ HoweII.
Let's hear it for Russ.
What do I--?
Next up, Ty Page,
riding for Unity Skateboards.
Ty Page, starting off
with some 1 80 end-overs.
And now I think he's gonna--
He's gonna press up into a handstand.
There's a nice handstand across the
pIatform, back down onto his board.
Looks Iike he's setting up
for, yes, a daffy...
...and into a one-footed heeIie.
And ends up with a 360
in front of the judges.
Nice run for Ty Page.
Looks Iike a 9.5, a 9 and 1 0 for
Ty Page. Those are reaI good marks.
ShouId put him right at the top
of the competition today.
Next up, Jay Adams,
riding for Zephyr Skateboards.
And there we go.
Okay, here we go with Jay Adams.
Nice.
Doing these Iow--
These Iow, driving turns.
Yeah, Jay boy.
-Low 1 80 with RoyaI Christie.
-AII right, Jay.
Oh, but he's aII right.
He's hopping up in the air
three or four inches.
I don't even know what to caII that.
I've never seen it.
He's, Iike, off the ramp.
That's it for Jay Adams. Let's see what
the judges are gonna score him.
Yeah, dude. Oh, my God.
He didn't do a singIe wheeIie.
He didn't do a singIe compuIsory trick.
WeII, you gotta give him a score.
Looks Iike two 7 s
and an 8 for Jay Adams...
-Oh, come on.
-...riding for Zephyr Skateboards.
You don't know how to judge.
Hey, you bIew me away.
What? You want to bIow me?
Maybe.
Next up wiII be Tony AIva,
riding for Zephyr Skateboards.
-Yeah.
-T.A.
Yeah.
He started out with some
quick S-turns up onto the bank.
-Frontside 1 80 power sIide.
-That's it, T.A.
Very nice waIking spinner.
Into a 360, maybe a 540.
Another Iow-driving turn,
touching his hands to the ground.
Yeah.
Here he comes toward the judges.
Ends up with a Iow-driving 360.
That was a great run for AIva.
Looks Iike we have
two 1 0s and a 9...
-...the highest score of the day.
-Yeah.
Up next from Mar Vista, CaIifornia,
an independent skater, Stacy PeraIta.
The dude showed.
-Go, Stacy.
-Yeah, Stace.
Come on, Stacy.
-Yeah.
-Where'd that come from, Stace?
Up, up, using the whoIe ramp,
hands on the ground.
Yeah.
And there's another one of those
Iow maneuvers...
...out of the pages
of Surfer Magazine.
Looks Iike he's winding up
for some 360s.
One, two, three, four, five.
Five 360s. Amazing.
We haven't seen that many aII day.
Hey, Stacy!
Back across the fIat
and there's his finish.
Two 1 0s and a 9 bring him
into a first-pIace tie with Tony AIva.
Oh, my God.
-You're disquaIified.
-What are you taIking about?
-You touched the course.
-Everyone touched--
Read the ruIes. You're disquaIified.
Hey, man. Hey, man. Look. Look.
The dude tied me.
Can your dirty ass even read?
-T.A.
-Yeah, Mad Dog.
-My dirty ass, right?
-Hey, ease up. Ease up, man.
-You saw that--
-Yeah, ease up.
-Hey. Off the fairgrounds.
-Cut these kids some sIack, man.
-SIack?
-Yeah.
Who do you think you are, coming
to our contest and puIIing this shit?
PuIIing what shit, man? My boys
are kicking your girIs' asses.
Every judge on the paneI
is on your payroII.
What kind of shit is that, huh?
Watch it.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Step up to the pIate, man.
One at a time.
You want it?
Come on, wiII it be aII of you?
Come on. Yeah?
Come on.
Hey, Iook. AII right.
It's gone, aII right?
Look, man.
These kids are at a tender age.
-They tense easiIy, okay?
-Yeah.
Your boy who punched
my officiaI is out.
-Oh, come on.
-No concession.
-That's buIIshit.
-Tony AIva's been disquaIified.
-Next up, junior women's freestyIe.
-Tony, wait.
Tony.
I just wanted Dad to see
the stupid trophy.
-Who gives a shit about Dad?
-Yeah, hey, hey, T.A., man.
Listen, you stood up for your friend,
man. We're proud of you.
This contest don't mean shit
to me anyway!
Hey, come here. Look at me. Look,
someone had to deck that asshoIe.
Look at me. Look at me.
It was either you or me, man.
AII right? Okay?
Our freestyIe champion today
is Stacy PeraIta...
...an independent skater
with a great surf styIe.
Now the awards for the men's sIaIom.
In third pIace, Ty Page.
And in second pIace, riding for
Zephyr Skateboards, Jay Adams...
-...a reaI up-and-comer.
-AII right, Jay.
Get on the Iove train, bro.
-I'm so proud of you.
-But I messed up.
-You didn't mess up.
-No, I did.
That's a nice ride, man.
This is a '72 Squareback.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, bro, you Iook hungry.
We're gonna get some food.
-You wanna come with?
-Yeah, come on.
I don't think so, Skip. I got pIans.
Yeah, weII, suit yourseIf.
It's one of the benefits
of having a job.
Yeah, weII, you got me there, man.
-We're going home.
-Okay.
Skip caIIed me bro.
-Skip caIIed you bro?
-Yeah, he said, ''bro.''
-No, he didn't.
-Yes, he did.
He said, ''You Iook hungry, bro.''
He said, ''You Iook hungry, bro''?
Yes, totaIIy.
Skip EngbIom
doesn't caII anybody bro.
Let's see your trophies, WentzIe.
Take a seat, man.
Sit here, Kathy.
-Yeah!
-Hey, guys.
-Yeah, Stacy.
-Here.
-PeraIta.
Go, Stace.
-You earned it, bro.
-Dude, you're one of us now.
That maggot's aIways
been one of us.
-Yeah, wear it with pride, man.
-You know I wiII.
Hey, Stacy, that T-shirt...
...wiII get you more titty
than you ever dreamed of, man.
I got my boy covered, Skip.
-Yeah, Kath.
-Yeah, you do.
-Yeah!
Hey, you guys made a mess
of that contest today.
-Oh, yeah!
-Yeah!
They Iook at you
as the enemy, right?
-But it's good to have enemies.
-Yeah.
-A toast.
-A toast!
To the boy kings!
You're aII a bunch
of fiIthy piIIow-biters!
-We Iearn from the best!
-Oh, you're dead.
Stop! Stop!
You can't act Iike that here.
This is a famiIy restaurant!
Hey, get off him!
Hey! Hey!
It's a famiIy restaurant!
-Get him, Skip.
-Go, Skip!
Jay boy.
You kicked ass, man.
See you, Skip.
I got second pIace, Mom.
You wouId've been stoked.
Baby.
I wish I couId've been there
to see you.
What time do you get off?
Three more hours.
There's fish sticks
in the freezer, baby.
You know, I'm gonna make some cash
and get you out of this pIace.
ReIax, SyIvia.
-It's stiII fIat.
-Yeah. Three days in a row.
Hey!
Get in.
Stop, stop, stop.
Right here. Right here.
Hey, isn't that the girI from DeI Mar?
-Dude, what are we doing here?
-Shut up, dork.
And sit back.
Damn it, Jay!
You know how much this is
gonna cost me? You're an idiot!
Jesus.
-Down, guys.
-Get down. Get down.
Sid, get off me.
Grab your skates, boys. Let's roII.
Dude, are we gonna rob this pIace?
This wave breaks 2 4 hours a day,
every day.
And you know what, bros?
We're gonna be the first to ride it!
Dude! That's so genius.
Dude, there's no way.
This is way too gnarIy.
Not if you got the baIIs.
Dude.
-Oh, Jay.
-Dude, you did a backfIip.
Let's Iose this stupid diving board.
Piece of shit.
Dude, hit it Iow, man.
Yeah, Tony!
Yeah! You guys see that?
I carved it.
Over the Iight.
Oh, my God!
-Dude, you were so far over it.
-That was crazy.
-Yes!
-Yeah!
Are you aII right, man?
I can't feeI my feet.
But then again,
I can never feeI my feet.
-Right there! Through there.
-Where?
I Iove the drought!
There's a pooI right next door!
It's an amoeba!
I can carve that. Guaranteed.
George! George!
Wait, wait. Right here.
We got an empty one, dudes.
ToweIs, bro.
Here you go.
-I thought I said mayonnaise.
-Sorry, Tony.
-What is that shampoo?
-What?
-Marie!
-CharIie?!
Run!
Jump!
Go, go, go!
Hey!
Get in!
You little faggot!
-Get over here!
-Tony!
Goddamn it!
-Get in! Go, go, go!
-Punch it! Go, go, go!
T.A.! T.A.!
Tony!
Come on, get in the car.
He's a dick. Let's go, come on.
Front side, back side.
Over the light.
Where you been, huh?
What, did you just forget
about practice or what?
l mean, do you think l like sitting
on my ass waiting for you clowns?
What, it's funny?
ls that funny? ls that funny?
How's this? ls that funny?
Yeah?
Hey! l'm serious, man!
You guys need
to keep pushing, man.
He took my burger.
Should we bring him
to the pool tomorrow?
He's gotta run the shop.
Dude...
...you just got patty-slapped.
All right.
God! Come on, give up, man!
The delivery guy's here
with the resin.
He says that you owe him $575
from the last time.
We need it, Skip.
Find the checkbook, man.
For God's sake.
Yeah, thanks for fixing
the door, man.
Sorry, Skipper.
-Fucking asshole.
-Here. Here.
Watch this. l'm gonna go off
the platform, onto the floor, do a 360!
That's great, Sid.
Three-sixty. Three-sixty!
All right, watch.
This is my latest move.
Thank you.
Sid, man, get off your ass
and get these boxes.
Hey, how many boards are ready?
l need to peddle this shit at Huntington
to cover the check, man.
Hey, where are you guys
going, man?
-Rincon. lt's firing!
-Rincon?
Ocean's your mistress, Skip.
Don't neglect her.
Skip, this shop's about
surfing and working when we want.
That was the deal, bro.
Yeah, well, that deal worked great
until we started getting orders from...
...Australia and Brazil, man!
Come in, Stace. My dad doesn't
get home till 6 in the morning.
Why don't you and l
just go for a ride.
lt's a party. Come on.
-l know, but l've got really great music.
-What's wrong with this music?
Look at the moon, Stace.
-l love it.
-No!
Not here.
Come here.
Come down here with me.
-No. Let's go.
-Come here.
-Your brother's right there.
-So what?
No, seriously.
l gotta go.
l just wanted to be with you.
l'll call you tomorrow.
Hey, chica.
Fucker!
Yeah.
-Take off your boxers.
-No.
Yes.
What's wrong, Jay boy?
Got no hair on your inchworm yet?
At least it works, Alva.
Now...
...give me kitty.
Maybe.
Oh, God.
-Oh, fuck. My dad. Go.
-Closet! Closet!
-Go, go.
-Shit.
Hey, Dad.
-What's that smell?
-What?
''What? What?''
What are you, deaf?
What is that smell? What?
lt's-- Oh, cigars.
-Our teacher had a baby girl--
-That's bullshit.
-We all celebrated, Dad.
-That is bullshit! Where's the cigar?!
See? Look. Cherry cigar. Smell it!
Told you!
You think l'm stupid, boy?
You're gonna raise your voice to me?!
The next time l find you
smoking that shit...
...l'll stuff it down your throat.
And pick up this pigsty!
Jesus Christ.
lt's not funny, you two.
A perfect right-handed kidney.
-Hey, what'd your dad say?
-What'd he say?
''Sid, are you high?
The pool's for swimming.''
Tell him we'll fill it back up
when we're done.
Yeah. He said if you guys get hurt,
you'll sue him.
-We won't sue him.
-He said your parents will.
Dude, our parents
can't even afford lawyers.
Hey, man. Let me talk to your dad.
Hey, man. The only Mexicans
my dad talks to push lawn mowers.
Hey, guys. lt's Skip. Come on!
-Hey, shotgun, faggots!
-Hey!
Seriously, we should drain it when
he goes on his next business trip.
Yeah. He'd have you all killed.
Good one, though.
Good idea. But no.
Hey! Kiss me, granny!
Love to get me
some of the gray beaver!
Come back when your balls drop.
Yeah, you're looking good!
-Go back. Go back.
-You, too, Mr. Rogers!
Let's skate already.
Hey, Skip, how you doing?
Hey. They've been swarming my shop
for a week talking about you guys.
What did you expect? Come on.
Next on the demonstration platform...
...the Zephyr Team
from Venice, California.
We love you, Tony Alva!
T.A.!
Right on, Tony!
lt always made sense...
...that skateboarding would be popular
on the West Coast.
This year alone,
l've taken teams to the Midwest....
All right, you got 20 bucks?
One brand-new....
ls that good, man?
Go find your mommy, man.
Come back with 1 0 bucks.
Get out of here.
Jay! Jay! Jay!
Say ''Pepsi.''
Stacy!
You gave me 50 bucks,
you'll get the board...
...because he has the money!
-Stacy!
We love you, Stacy!
Stacy! Stacy! Stacy!
-Yeah, Stace.
-Yeah, Stacy.
Hey!
Yeah, Tony!
l am Alva!
Let's give a big round of applause
for the Z-Boys from Dogtown!
How groovy was that, huh?
Tony, come talk to me.
See you in the parking lot.
You know, Tony, you might be
the best skater in the world someday.
Fact is, l think you are the best.
What do you want, dude?
Tony, l'll match
whatever Skip's paying you.
And l'll throw in a car.
-What kind of car?
-Hey, Larry.
How about...
...a brand-new Pontiac Firebird,
muscled up with a 455 engine?
l'll believe it when l see it.
Man, l'm the biggest skateboard
manufacturer in the country.
So you know where to find me.
Nice work out there.
Excuse me. Could you get
the front too, please?
Sure thing, bro.
Tell me about Larry, man.
-What about him?
-Well, you tell me.
-Larry said l--
-He told me some shit...
...about how great l was, dude.
''You may be the best skater
in the world someday.
Fact is, l think you are the greatest.''
-Just throw these in.
-Okay, so just two Doritos.
Bye.
-So, what did he say to you, Peralta?
-Yeah.
Well, l guess we're all
the best skaters in the world.
Yeah.
Well, it's all working out
for you boys.
You know what l'm thinking, bros?
We're gonna be on summer vacation
for the next 20 years.
Yeah.
Dude, that's nasty, man.
-Hey! Hey, man! My car!
-Oh, my God.
-You're too slow!
-Get over here!
Kiss my ass, jack!
You little knob-rocking butt clown!
What's happening, boys?
How's the pool?
All right, Tony, let me get a shot
of you right here...
...holding your board, like, strong.
Above your head, yeah?
Get right underneath him.
Don't lose that shot.
Give me the street thing.
That is great.
Jay!
Just one shot.
You're from Dogtown?
What does that mean?
Venice, man. Ghetto by the sea.
lt's dirty. lt's filthy. lt's paradise.
Okay, let's get all the Z-Boys
in the pool now.
-Sid's gonna love it.
-Oh, Sid!
Stacy, Jay and Tony, man.
They couldn't buy that publicity.
Red Dog, man, check it out.
You're in there. You're a hero, man.
Montoya!
-No way.
-Yeah.
-No.
-Rock star, man!
That's it, man.
Six-page article, man.
lt's Jay boy!
Hey, what's up, baby?
Hey, Skipper. When are we doing
that spread for People magazine?
Tuesday?
Yeah, and Stacy's gonna be
on Charlie's Angels!
Movie star now, huh?
They couldn't even make it
in the water.
They couldn't even surf the cove
without me saying so.
Who wants to surf that
toxic-waste dump anyways?
What did you say?
Nothing.
Hey, hey, hey! Whatever, man.
-This is for locals only.
-Beat it, drag queen.
Would you make
an exception for us?
Baby doll, let me just say
l'm willing to negotiate.
-Thanks, Tony.
-You're welcome.
What's going on?
-Hey, Mr. Alva.
-What's up?
l took what the dentist told me to take,
but l don't feel anything.
That's the point, babe. Come on.
-Show us how it's done.
-The girls love the ass.
Oh, man.
You just gotta--
You just gotta let it hang.
You'll throw your back out.
Guys, listen up!
Half-breed
That's all we ever heard
Until we heard the word
Z-Boys on the cover of
Skateboard Magazine
l already got hair on my chest.
This is Sid.
Check out the rack.
-Hi, Sid.
-Hey, Thunder Monkey, what's...?
Are you thirsty?
You want something to drink?
Yeah.
l'm always thirsty.
For that.
So, what's happening?
You are. You're happening, Sid.
Everybody's talking about you,
you know.
At school and in the magazines
and on the street.
-Are you okay?
-Oh, yeah. No, l'm good.
-You're looking good.
-Thank you.
l like that belt...
...and the zipper.
And the feather.
-Check it out.
-l guess l'll have to see the design.
l don't ever want you to wear
underwear around me again, okay?
Hey, Stacy.
What's up, bro?
You couldn't even tell me?
Dude, l was gonna tell you.
When?
You're my friend.
Dude, l know, and l love you, bro...
...but you couldn't handle her.
And you can?
Apparently so.
Hey, Carlos.
Stacy. Where you going?
-Tell me l'm a great skater.
-You are a great skater, Sid.
You're the best skater on the team.
Gnarly.
-They're all yours, Sid.
-That's right.
Speed wobble!
Wait.
lt's not-- lt's not over yet, right?
No, Sid, it's not over.
Not even close.
lt's not over. lt's okay.
-Man, there's Topper Burks.
-Yeah, Topper Burks.
What brings you all the way
to this side of town?
Heard there was a party
in my favorite surf ghetto.
Yeah?
Where's the famous Tony Alva?
l wanna congratulate him.
Yeah, l'll congratulate him
for you, man.
Topper! Hey, man! Over here.
Hi, Topper.
Hey, Tony.
l'm Topper Burks.
l know who you are, dude.
Skip warned me about you.
l bet he did.
l think your boy Topper
is doing business.
You're blowing it, Tony.
Look, asshole,
l'm not blowing anything.
How much are these?
More than your car.
l don't own a car, dude.
Exactly.
Do you have any idea how many
skateboards he's selling...
...because of you?
A shitload.
Yeah.
With your talent...
...and my money...
...l can make you a star.
Hey, Jay.
l saw you in the magazine.
That was bitchen.
Jesus Christ, girl.
Ain't you Chino's old lady?
No. lt's like he won't leave me alone.
Well, l wouldn't either.
Can l suck on your panties?
Tiki! Tiki! Tiki!
l just got laid.
Thunder Monkey's all over
my shit, dude.
l told you, Thunder Monkey,
he'd be freaked.
Congratulations, bro.
lt's about time.
Stacy, l need to talk to you.
l really need to talk to you.
Sit down. Sit down, sit down.
You guys know how many boards
Skip's selling because of us?
lf he ain't gonna flow us,
then l'm bailing.
We can't bail on Skip, man.
We're family.
l'm not gonna hang around this shop
like Chino and Montoya.
-This is our time, bros!
-Dude, that's bullshit, bro.
We surf and we skate every day.
We get to do whatever we want.
No, you guys gotta
think bigger, man!
l wanna make money,
get laid every night.
l wanna do it all right fucking now.
Hell, yeah. l'm gonna make out
with two chicks tonight.
Yeah, l mean, those boys are
getting too big for their boots.
Whatever you say, Skip.
Come on, don't you get it?
The boys are getting offers.
So cut them in on
some of the profits!
What profits, dickhead?
This is a surf shop!
-That's not the point!
-Later.
You wanna get rich, Skip?
-Go pimp yourself.
-Oh, yeah?
This isn't about fame or money.
lt never has been.
No? Until you put those kids
in magazines...
...they didn't care about
either one, genius.
Well, they do now.
-Here's where you been, my little devil.
-You found me somehow.
-l don't know.
-Are you cold, papi?
l don't know, seriously.
What do you think you're doing?
-Hey, what's up, Chino?
-What's your problem?
Jay's the one with the problem.
Shut up.
No, l'm just waiting here for my girl.
lt's cool, man.
lt's cool. Oh, it's cool.
l almost forgot, Jay.
Everything is cool because you're
a famous skateboarder, huh?
lt's cool.
-Oh, my God.
-lt's cool!
Jay!
No! Stop it! Stop!
You're gonna kill him!
You're gonna be next, bitch!
Step off, man.
Mellow out, man.
Come on!
Who wants a free surfboard?
Yeah, Billy, you want me
to give away the shop, man?
Then here's your share
of the profits, man!
l'm out of here!
You don't see this crap
on the North Shore!
Yeah, this one's for your mommy!
Zephyr parties are great.
Who wants some free surfboards?
-l'm out of here, buddy.
-Come on, man.
Hey, Jay.
Look at him, man. All vato'd out.
Topper, this is Jay Adams.
What's up, Jay?
What's up, man?
Hey, bro. Tony's gonna
make a lot of money.
Why don't you come hang with us.
-Maybe another time.
-Cool.
l'll see you around, bro.
-Hey, Jay.
-Hey.
-What do l owe you for the beer?
-Five bucks.
Yes. Thank you.
Hey.
l'm thinking of moving to Oregon
to raise chickens and goats.
-Then l could grow my own herb.
-Hey.
Hey, Mom. Who is that guy?
He looks like a cop.
No, Jay. This is cool.
l want you to meet
a friend of your uncle.
Hey, Jay. Peter Darling,
LaFond and Barnett Advertising.
-Should we go talk in the kitchen?
-Sure. Let's go.
Jay...
...has anybody told you
you have that California look?
No.
You do.
Excuse me.
Hey, Jay, l was wondering...
...would you mind removing that--
That thing from your head?
Right.
Well, Jay, with the current
skate craze, we at the firm...
...feel that you would be the perfect
spokesman for our new client, Slinky.
Would you mind singing
for me right now?
Who are you, man? Really.
Let me sing the tune for you, okay?
You want me to sing that?
We're prepared to offer you...
...$ 1 0,000.
For one day's work. One day.
Give it a shot, baby. Give it a shot.
Jay...
...you got the part.
l'm not what you're looking for, man.
Hey, man. People have been
telling me about this club, man.
-Hey, what's up, Sneaky?
-What's up?
Joker.
What's up, homey?
You're gonna get it,
you little motherfucker!
Come on, you little pussy! Get up!
Get off me! Get off!
l'll fucking kill that motherfucker!
Get the fuck up!
-Fucking faggot!
-Go fuck yourself....
Hey, Skip.
Stacy. Have a seat, man.
l want to talk to you about something.
How you been?
Yeah? You all right?
Listen, man, you know it's not
about a team anymore. Yeah?
lt's about you, man.
This is all gonna be about you.
l thought l wasn't a pirate.
Hey, man. l never said that, man.
l mean, did l?
You didn't even want me
on the team.
l was pushing you, man. Come on.
Listen, Skip.
l'm sorry, you know. l mean--
l have....
l've been talking to Larry--
l have these injection molding cavities
coming in, man. Check it out.
l'm gonna hire night workers
and run this shop like a factory, man.
Just churn them out, one by one.
Well, is anyone else involved?
Well, hey, man, l can't be worried...
...about what everyone else
is doing, you know?
l mean, l'm focused on
what l'm doing.
l'm gonna build hundreds
of skateboards a month...
...all with your name,
''Stacy Peralta.''
Right there, next to ''Zephyr.''
What do you think, man?
So, what do you say, bro?
Okay.
That's all right.
l dig that one.
You heard it from the boss's mouth.
Racers ready!
Set!
Stacy!
Racers ready!
Set!
All right, Tony!
-Take two.
-And action.
Cut. Cut. l'm only seeing hair here.
Here.
-Stacy.
-Stacy!
Alva.
Hey, can l try that?
Thanks.
That's a little harder than it looks.
-l sucked.
-One more.
-Moon boots, you know?
-Yeah.
Stacy, thank you
for speaking with us.
Good? Let's do one more,
and we'll take a break.
Wow, you're famous, Stace.
The God Squad.
Kathy, l was the last one
to leave the Zephyr team.
Both your brother and Jay
left without even telling Skip.
This is my girlfriend, Caroline.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
You too.
Everyone sees it
their own way, l guess.
-Good luck, Stacy.
-Stacy. Let's do it.
Skateboarding's been great. Thinking
about buying a new Trans Am.
Black on black,
with some big fat tires on the back.
Give me one second.
Hey.
What's going on?
How was Australia?
How was the...? How was the surf?
l couldn't surf. They had me
going all over doing demos and stuff.
You went to Australia
and you didn't surf?
Yeah, l know.
Yeah, well, he's a working man now.
So how's your sponsor?
Well, they help me pay
the rent for my mom.
They were supposed to have...
...his signature board ready
three months ago.
Get back.
What's up, boys?
Where's your lasso,
Wonder Woman?
Remember, class among gruel.
T.A. T.A.
What's up, Stacy?
Poor guy's so straight,
he doesn't even cast a shadow.
You guys even
skate with him anymore?
The dude's competing with the sun
for the center of the universe.
Stace.
Man...
...Stacy looks like a stock car.
Jay. What do you say, man?
Bro. Your board is bionic, bro.
This isn't the board l designed.
This wood is cheap.
No, no, no. That's solid wood.
Jay, we're trying to make you
a big chunk of change...
...but the boards you want
are a tad bit too expensive to sell.
How do you know until you sell it?
Jay. Jay, look,
you don't know business.
You don't understand. Hey!
You don't understand. He doesn't
understand business, right?
You guys aren't living up
to your word.
-Yeah?
-Yeah. Look.
Cut the agent crap, Sid. All right?
You're a little rich boy
who can't skate for shit.
You wouldn't even exist
if it weren't for old Jay.
-All right?
-Yeah.
-l know where your shit's at.
-Make it happen with Jay.
-Make it happen.
-lt's okay.
Hey, bro, look who's here.
Hey, we know you.
-What's going on?
-Cokehead freaks.
Right there.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...welcome to the World Professional
Skateboarding Championships.
We've got G & S Skateboards
here today.
Team Alva.
Landon. We've got Lateral Visions
and plenty more.
Marty Grimes attempts
and makes it perfectly.
There goes Shogo, up and over...
...and he makes it.
We have a real surprise
for you now.
Tyson the Wonder Dog,
riding for G & S Warptail.
Up the ramp, he's getting vertical.
He's hanging 1 0 down the middle.
There he goes.
Give him a big round of applause!
Our next event will be the vert ramp.
There goes ''Jay boy'' Adams,
first practice run.
Tips his hat on the way down.
That was something else.
Let's give him a big hand for that.
On his practice run, Stacy Peralta.
Now riding for San Diego's
Gordon & Smith.
Nice execution on that one.
This is the scoring run,
ladies and gentlemen. Ty Page.
And the scores are
a 9, 8, 9, 8, 7, 9.
Great scores.
Okay, our next contestant,
Jay ''Jay boy'' Adams.
This is the one that counts.
Ready, judges?
Here he goes for his final run.
Dropping in.
And there he goes,
gets some blinding speed.
Oh, my God! lt's some type of aerial
maneuver l've never seen before.
Didn't quite make that one,
but did you see that?
We'll see what the judges
score him on that.
And his scores are 6, 7...
-...8, 7, 8, 8.
-That's some bullshit.
Jay, Jay, look. All you gotta do is
a couple of kick turns next time...
-...and you'll destroy everybody.
-We can all cash in, brother.
All right?
Come on, bro.
Jay.
Our next contestant is Stacy Peralta,
riding for G & S Warptail...
...one of the great names
in skateboarding today.
Here goes Stacy Peralta
on his final scoring run.
Getting some great speed.
Hits the ramp backside.
Nice rock walk by Stacy Peralta.
Perfect execution.
And Stacy's final score...
...a 9, 8, 8, 9, 8...
...and a perfect 1 0.
Stacy will advance to the final heat.
Next up, we have Marty Grimes,
Reef Ryan and radical Tony Alva.
Hey, Tony, it looks like
it's gonna be you or me, man.
Tony!
No, it's not.
lt's me.
ln a practice run now,
he's dropping in. Great speed.
Tony Alva thrashes that wall with
his trademark ''Mad Dog'' attitude!
Come on. He's got this.
There goes Reef Ryan,
taking his practice run.
Nice backside execution
by Reef Ryan.
Oh, my God. Reef and Tony collide.
Come on, you guys.
You stupid Val!
-Kick his ass!
-Oh, wait a minute.
People, get back in your seats.
ls that the best you got?
-His eye.
-Paramedics?
Do we have a paramedic?
lt looks like we have a man down.
This is a Channel 7 News
special report.
Pacific Ocean Park Pier,
infamous local surf spot...
...burned to the ground last night.
This is the latest in a series of fires
that have plagued the park...
...since it was
officially closed in 1 967.
Pacific Ocean Park,
once described as superior...
...to Coney Island in New York,
to the boardwalk in Atlantic City...
...lies in smoldering ruins today...
...and is now nothing more than
a bunch of fond memories.
Look who's here.
Bastards didn't send fire trucks
for over six hours or something.
Yeah, they wanted it gone.
They wanted it gone.
You know, the pier has been here
for over 40 years.
Get behind the perimeter, all of you.
Set it up 500 yards down the beach.
Bring it back up to the highway.
You know that's where
l learned to surf? Right there.
They look at the cove as a shithole.
l mean, thank God, man,
because in winter this place goes off.
We had it all to ourselves.
We had it all to ourselves, man.
You're right.
l have no reason
to come here anymore.
Hey.
Sorry l left, man.
l just had to pay the rent.
Hey, man.
Your mama, she has to eat, right?
She has to eat.
-Hey, bro.
-What's up, T.A.?
T.A.!
What's this?
Shit.
-Topper, man.
-Little brother.
-Hey, man. Put these on.
-No, no, no! lt's cool, man.
Sorry.
Hey, man.
We got all the meds you need.
We're going to Maui
and get you on some real waves.
Get in the limo.
l told you, they're operating
again on Thursday.
T.A.!
l love you, man.
l want you to come.
l'll send you a ticket.
Let's go.
So are you a good pirate
or a bad pirate?
Ahoy, captain.
Shit.
So how are you doing?
-l feel like shit.
-Yeah?
But the doctor says
l'm getting better.
You'll be back on top
again soon, man.
You gotta give it time.
l'm gonna end up a ditchdigger.
Hey.
Hey, look at me, boy.
You remember you're an Alva.
You've got a lot of heart...
...and a lot of balls.
Hey, come on.
Yeah!
Let's go. Come on.
What's up, homey?
You looking at me?
-You looking at me?
-We were leaving.
-Looking at me?
-Just checking things out.
Nice Rolex you got there, man.
You sure you want that?
-You sure about that?
-No, man. Hey, man.
No, he's cool. He's cool.
-Jay.
-Hey. How you doing, man?
-What's up, dude?
-How's it going?
Man, nice ride.
Where you been, Jay?
l mean, l didn't even see you
at the Arizona contest.
Well, l don't really
skate malls for money, bro.
Hey, Kathy, come here.
-Nice car, man.
-Hey, Stacy.
Hey, Stacy. How you doing?
Hey.
Jay tell you about Sid?
He's sick, man.
What do you mean?
He's always been sick.
No, he's real sick.
That whole equilibrium thing
turned out to be a tumor.
Brain cancer.
What? Are you serious?
Yeah, it's bad.
They operated already.
He's gonna be back home
this weekend.
Yeah, we're all gonna go hang out.
You should come.
Wrong.
We ain't gonna
go see him like that.
Yeah, l can't go.
l gotta go to Florida.
Tony's supposed to be there.
Come on, Jay. You gonna
make out with him or what, eh?
So...
...l'll see you at the mall.
All right, Jay.
l think we should put these new shirts
on sale. What do you think?
-Hey, how you doing? Come on in.
-Hey, how's it going, man?
Do you know when my board's
gonna be ready?
l know my guy started on it already.
Let me go check it out.
Hey, Skip? We got an ETA
on that 6'7'' twin fin?
Yeah, tell the kid he'll be surfing
by Saturday, boss.
Beautiful. Okay. Thank you.
How about Saturday?
At 1 0:30 it'll be ready.
Now, we've got
a wet-suit sale going on.
Dude.
You look like shit.
Let me see that thing.
Yeah, mine's real.
Dang.
lt's pretty punk rock, bro.
l don't have to lift a finger anymore.
l don't have to take out the trash.
l don't even have to
brush my own teeth.
Am l King Tut or what?
Yeah, my doctor prescribes it now.
Heard you were sick too.
Hell, yeah.
So did you get ahold of T.A.?
He and Stacy are off
making their millions.
Sorry, dude.
No big deal.
Hey, if you do croak...
...will you give your house
to my mom?
Only if she lets me see her tits first.
lt's awfully nice of you to bequeath
your star-athlete-like presence...
...among us lower life forms.
Sid, man.
So, what happened to Florida?
The Kona Bowl.
Yeah, l guess l missed my flight.
Won't Larry crucify you for that?
l'm leaving G & S.
l'm gonna start my own company.
l've already got a logo.
Oh, you got a logo?
Man, screw the team.
l mean, you got a logo.
-Sid, l'll just come back later, man.
-No, wait. Stace.
You have to come check something
out in the back, by the pool.
You too, asshole.
Dudes, look in the deep end.
There's a Mexican in my pool,
and he ain't pushing a lawn mower.
Don't make me come up there
and kick your ass, Sid.
Peralta.
You finally got your
shadow back, huh?
What's up, chrome-dome?
What's the zipper for?
Easy access.
He doesn't have to inhale anymore.
He just unzips and pours.
What are you girls waiting for?
My dad said we can trash it.
Oh, my God.
Guys, let's get him in here.
Oh, yeah.
No.
Okay. Wait, wait.
l think this'll be
the first pool session...
...where we don't have to worry
about getting busted.
-You all right?
-Yeah.
Okay.
-Hey, guys. Let's get him in the drain.
-Jesus--
All right.
Lock in, bud.
Sid.
Look, Squid.
l'll let you bang my mom.
You little punk.
-Sid, you okay?
-Yeah.
Hey, Sid. Do you wanna carve?
l'm first.
We got you, bro.
-Squiddles, we got you.
-Man down!
Oh, yeah. You did a kick turn, Sid.
Sid.
What are you doing?
Don't be idiots!
-Sorry.
-Yeah. Sorry.
l'm fine.
Sorry, seorita.
Here. Put me over here.
Can you bring me some herb?
-Oh, my-- You all right?
-Yeah.