Resync: Xenzai[NEF]
Wow...
Looking good...
Oh, yeah, nice to see you.
Hey...
That dress needs dry-cleaning.
- Here you go.
- Thank you kindly, Monica.
Monica, Monica?
Oh shit, Hillary.
Okay...
- Hi, Bill.
- Oh hey Snow white.
Where's 11B?
Bingo.
What did you say
that thing was?
It's time for a little action.
Monica... It's Bill.
I've got some dictation
for you, Monica.
I've got a big secret
for you, Baby.
How did you get up here
so soon?
Monica.
Oh my eyes..
I can't see.
Who let you in.?
What happened...
Where's Monica?
What happened to Monica?
- How did you get in here?
She told me where the key was.
- I can't see.
Did she say it was ok to
dry-hump her roommate?
She said, you would be in the...
library cause you
were a geek...
I am not a geek..
God.
My God.
What was that, mace?
'Eternity', by Calvin Klein.
I gotta be so careful who I
get into bed with from now on.
It would be a big adjustment
for you, wouldn't it?
God.
I do that every time.
I've invented a solution
for that. Seriously.
It is something that
goes around the...
coffee cup, so you
don't burn your hand.
I'm gonna call it
'The Coffee Collar'.
Brilliant idea.
I know all about you.
I know you whole wrap.
- You do?
- Yeah. You're a senior...
who prays on freshmen.
You've slept...
with half my floor.
- Well, half your
floor was female.
Whatever.
And you once met Bono,
which I suspect is
total bullshit.
No, it's true.
He signed my CD.
It's upstairs in my room
with my...
'Coffee Collar',
if you wanna see it.
- Are you hitting on me?
- No. I'm going of your look.
- My look...
- Yeah, doggy bull look.
- Are you calling me a dog?
- No, it's a theory I have.
- Oh, Casanova has a theory.
- Yeah. When a girl...
is attracted to a
guy, she has a look.
It's her tell, like poker.
It's the same look a dog gets,
right before you
put down the bowl.
- You're offensive.
And you're crazy.
No, I'm honest.
I believe honesty is the best
policy.
Alright...
You want me to be
honest with you?
- Sure.
- I'm majoring in fine art.
- Right.
I'm studying the
golden proportions...
of the human face. And you're
nose is bent and...
and it drips down
at the bottom.
A feature that is
accentuated...
by the thinness of
your upper lip.
And your eyes,
are too far apart,
but they have to be...
to accommodate that bent nose.
And I feel sorry for you,
that you have to validate
yourself through...
insatiable-meaning
less-ego-sport-sex,
with insecure girls
like my roommate.
I... Would never have sex with
someone... Like you.
Hey come here.
That was amazing.
- What was?
- The honesty.
That was better than sex
without the... The crying.
- Actually it did
feel pretty good.
Yeah, no one's ever...
been that honest
with me before.
It's called a friend.
I'm Tom, by the way.
- Hannah.
- Hannah? That's a palindrome.
Well, good night.
Good night.
- Your hands, Clammy...
Well, I can see that
you're knocked out.
Tom, is that you?
Can I see your Bono-autograph?
She's all yours, friend.
Monica, get some sleep.
MADE OF HONOR
Subs by: Macco
What time is it?
I'm late.
What are you doing tonight?
I don't do 'back to backs'.
- Isn't that what we
were doing last night?
No, that was
something different.
'Back to Backs' is
seeing each other two...
nights in a row. You
know I don't do that.
- Couldn't you just break
one of your stupid rules?
No.
- For me.
I'm sorry, but I
don't break the rules.
I have a rule about that.
See you next week.
Thanks.
- Excuse me.
- Sorry.
Can I get a grandee drip,
and a decaff,
triple grandee, non-fat,
extra hot, stirred
milk Como Macchiato.
With whip cream,
extra caramel.
Fill that 70% of the way.
Thank you.
Here, let me put a 'Coffee-
Collar' on that.
- Thank you.
I hear that the guy
that invented that...
gets a dime for each one used.
- You're kidding.
I am not.
That could add up.
I think I picked up
yours by accident.
Sorry about that.
- That's alright. Thank you.
- Any time.
Bye-bye.
Gloria.
Morning.
Good morning, Hannah.
Coffee, the way you like it.
Perfect timing. I
just finished...
working on his balls.
That's eh... Yeah.
So I made a reservation.
- So what rule is this?
- No 'back to backs'.
Isn't that the same as the...
'no more than once
a week'-rule?
No, the 'no more than
once a week'-rule...
works Monday to Fridays.
So theoretically
you could have a
Sunday night and Monday
without breaking it.
Exactly, you got it.
Here we go.
Hey, good morning.
Can I get the steamed buns...
the scalloped
steamed ducklings...
and the vegetarian
and shrimp steamed...
- Thank you.
- For what?
You know how much I
love the fried stuff.
You look after me.
Excellent.
So, what did you say?
- She was hurt,
but you know...
But you where honest, right?
What? I was.
I am. Always.
I know you are, but
it's just shocking...
to see how you use
it as a shield.
Maybe I should lie.
Be more like Dennis Philips,
and say whatever it takes
to get a woman into bed.
No, do not be like
Dennis Philips.
- He's so gross.
- He only hit on you once.
At my father’s funeral.
Okay, so he's not known
for his sensitivity.
Oh, God.
Anyways...
- What?
- Nothing.
I know that 'nothing'.
It's not...
nothing, it's something.
- 'Anyway'...?
- Anyway we both know,
you don't need to
lie to get a woman...
into bed.
Gloria.
I don't wanna lose that.
Can I keep that? Thank you.
See there's another rule too.
The 24 hour-rule.
I can't call her for another
24 hours.
Cause then it appears
that I'm too desperate.
You know, Dan sent
me another letter?
Asking you to move to Canada
and marry him again?
- A slice of apple-crumb pie?
- No, we did that last time.
- You guys broke up
like a year ago.
19 months.
- You're counting?
No. He is... It
was in the letter.
Lemon butter cream cup?
Not feeling the
cream cup today.
- Cranberry orange muffin?
Hannah, come on.
You're losing it.
- I know, I know... Okay.
- Think about it.
- Come on. You're
disappointing.
I got it, I got it...
- Yeah.
- Wait, I so have it...
Cream cheese sorrel brownie.
You're so good.
What do you think of this?
I think we should get this.
Tom, I am not going to another
one of your fathers weddings.
Thank you.
Hannah? Please?
Take one of the girls you've
been rubbing up against.
'No weddings or
family events'.
That's right.
I forgot that rule.
- It gives the
wrong impression.
It does.
- Is this made with
real alligator?
Yes, baby-alligator.
- You should be
ashamed of yourself.
Look at you.
Hello there...
And who would you be?
I love you. Yes I do.
I love you.
You're so pretty. Yes you are.
You're beautiful. Yes you
are. Your beautiful face...
I love you, love
you, love you.
You should try saying that to
a human sometime.
What?
A human?
To say it to a human?.
You're sweet.
Love you.
Hannah, please.
Come to the wedding.
He gets married and
I go. I go because...
he's my father and I
care deeply for the man.
And everybody knows
he doesn't love...
them, and they don't love him.
It's pathetic, it
breaks my heart.
I don't know what to say.
You know when someone's
making a mistake...
and it's not your
place to interfere.
You simply say:
'I'm happy you're happy'.
- I'm happy you're happy.
- Yeah.
Okay. I'll do that.
I promise you, this is the...
last time I'll
ask you to come.
And then I'll find
somebody else...
to come to the next funeral.
Hannah, please.
That's cute.
- Last time.
- Thank you. Thank you.
She gets the
apartment in the city,
and 30 grand a month.
Right.
Right, okay.
You get the house in
the Hamptons, she's...
asking for the
apartment in the city,
and 30 grand a month.
- Thirty? But...
Are you still negotiating
a pre-nup?
Now the party starts...
My son is here.
Dad, you’re getting
married in 10 minutes.
Dad, please, I can't breathe.
- Did you bring
the lovely Hannah?
Yes, I did.
You know, if you
don't act on that...
pretty soon, you know
what I'm gonna do?
- No.
I'm gonna make
her my number 6.
Seven...
This is number 6.
- Yeah.
- My God, you are pretty.
Dad.
- I used to be
that pretty once.
Dennis, look how
pretty my boy is.
Yeah, he's beautiful.
They won't...
accept a minimum
of 5 times a week.
- She promised 5, I want 5.
What did she promise
you, 5 times a week?
- 4 times?
- Two.
No, no...
We're not done yet.
- She says 3, with
a bi-monthly BJ.
This is disturbing.
4 and make it weekly.
Wait, no... Driver
go around the block.
We are not even close...
What was that?
Come on.
Come on, tell me.
- Say what you gotta say.
- I'm happy, If you're happy.
No, no...'You're
too old for her dad'.
'She doesn't love you,
this is embarrassing'.
'You're gonna rack up
your fifth divorce'.
- Sixth.
- I'm happy, if you're happy.
- Bullshit.
Go for 4 if you exercise more.
She says you can't gain
any more weight.
- Take it. Deal.
- Deal.
I told her I weigh 10 pounds
more than I do.
- Ain't love grand?
- Sign the both please.
What's he signing now?
His current pre-nup and
his last divorce-papers.
That's just great...
Your good. Thank you.
- Cheers.
- Did you tell your
dad you love him?
I told him I cared for him.
You can't even
tell your father.
- I don't get that.
- It's a 'Guy thing'.
No, it's a 'Tom thing'.
- You're an 'I love you-slut'.
- Are you kidding me?
You say it all the time.
To everybody.
- Oh, this looks so good.
Yeah, it looks
good doesn't it?
I should have ordered
this. this look good.
You always order
better than I do.
It's lemon, right? It's good.
I'm ordering that from now on.
- No, you won't.
- Why?
I need you to order
the chocolate cake...
so I can have some.
- There's my 'son'.
- There you go...
Oh, you're bad boy
I'm gonna spank you.
You know what I would like
to say to you? Is that...
- I want you to
listen to me, Tom.
Yeah.
If you need any advice...
- or you need any advice...
- Right.
Or you got girl problems,
I don't know...
I need you to think
of me how you...
would a real mother.
- Yeah that's
exactly what I...
Look at this beauty, will you?
Hello, Sweety
Drunk as the night I first
met her.
- You are a bad
influence on her.
Me?
- Last shot?
- Thanks.
- I'm stealing you away...
- Last one...
- He does know that he
can just date, right?
No, I don't think he does.
- To mothers.
- To mothers. Cheers.
Careful.
Nice...
Oh God...
Hide me.
- What?
It's my dad’s
patient coordinator.
Yeah, don't look,
don't look...
There... Don't look.
She's obsessed with me.
She's created a website called
'allthingstom. org'.
- A Psycho blogger?
- Yes.
Okay. Come on...
Dance with me.
- Watch yourself.
- She's kind of cute.
- Oh stop it.
- I'm serious...
Keep going.
Here. Right here. Hide me.
back side, side. Go, go...
The last blog was a
2 page description...
of my face.
See, she doesn't think
my nose is too...
bent or my lips are too thin.
- Who said that?
- You did. When we met.
- Well, I lied.
- What?
- I thought you were hot.
- Really?
Well, you told me I looked
like a dog.
That was just cause I was
trying to sleep with you.
Why haven't you since?
Well... I like having you
in my life.
- ...
- Hi, Tom.
- Oh, hi.
- Did you see the new blog?
No, we haven't.
- Who's this?
- This? This is my girlfriend.
Why didn't you tell me you
we’re seeing someone?
Because I don't know you.
But we have a really, really
open relationship...
- Really?
You know? I wanted to
talk to you about that,
- princess.
- Princess?
I... I don't wanna be with
anybody but you.
I don't know if
I’m really quite...
ready to make that
commitment...
- Are you?
- You know my rules...
- I'm bit of an
emotional retard.
Yeah...
I think I need to
start a new blog now.
- That is so scary.
She's psychotic on top of P..
Oh, this is not good.
- Saia da minha frente.
- Ei.
Okay, good... She's gone.
Perfect. Let's go.
Good, come on.
What?
Do you remember that ancestral
home in Scotland,
with those amazing paintings
I told you about?
- It's all I think about.
- Stop it, Tom.
I finally got the board to
sign of...
on making editions to a
permanent collection.
Really?
But they want me to go to
Scotland for an
aquisitionship.
- When are you going?
- A couple of days.
- Couple of days?
For how long?
Six weeks.
That's a long time.
- That's great.
- You think?
Yes, it's a great opportunity
for you.
You're like the
'museum maiden of the Met'.
It's got a good ring to it...
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
Six Sundays.
- That is six Sundays.
What am I gonna
do without you?
I can just imagine.
- Yeah...
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna jump.
- No, no.
- Jesus.
Six Sundays,
how can I live without you?
Can you not take
anything seriously?
- Yeah, I can.
- Get down.
- Let's get you another drink.
I think I've had
too many already.
- Thanks for coming
to the wedding.
It was a ball,
- I can't wait
for number seven.
It's coming up soon,
I have a feeling.
We also ask at this time that...
you turn off all your
electronic devices.
Please leave your
cell phones turned...
off for the duration
of the flight.
- I'm not gonna be able
to play today, man.
If we don't have a
fourth, we are gonna...
end up playing with
'Tiny-Shorts Guy'.
- So?
- Hey, how's it going?
- Need another?
- No, our friend Paul,
- with longer
shorts, is coming.
Right.
No, Jenny signed him up
for some art walk thing...
Art walk? Are you serious?
Tell me something.
What do you think Jenny
did with his balls...
when she cut them off?
Come on, guys,
marriage isn't that bad.
I agree. Without marriage
there would be no divorce,
and without divorce I wouldn't
have my condo in Aspen.
Bingo.
- Good one.
- What is he?
I'm serious, man.
Your missing out on
the best parts of life.
- The most important
part of life.
This coming from the
guy who's wife...
won't let him own porn.
He's gotta wank off...
to the underwear section
of the Sears catalogue.
I thought we weren't
gonna talk...
about that?
What's the matter with you?
You are single and
you've been single,
ever since...
What was her name?
- Sophomore year.
Plim... Pimpkin,
Pimpkin, that's it.
Pimpkin dumped you for him.
Sophomore year, you've
never been the same...
you haven't been
able to sleep.
- Scarred...
Yeah. You have no
idea, how nice it is...
to have someone who
is gonna be there,
no matter what, whatever.
- Snaps to that.
And you don't know
how nice it is...
to sleep with a different
girl every night.
- That's true.
- Nice recital.
You got the best of
both worlds, Tom.
No, it's true.
I can sleep with
whoever I want.
But I still get to hang
out with Hannah afterwards.
- Perfect setup.
Yeah, well maybe
not for Hannah...
- What's that
supposed to mean?
Come on, Tom. She's a woman.
Yeah, I got that.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Tom, she's pushing 30.
You think her idea of...
'Happily ever after' is
coming home to you...
and hanging out after
you got laid?
- Makes you think, right?
- Yeah.
- Hallo?
- Hey.
- Hi.
How's the weather in England?
It's great.
Only I'm in Scotland.
Right, right.
So it's sunny?
It's 3 in the morning.
- Oh, right. Sorry.
- So it's dark.
- Yeah.
Have you seen the
Loch Ness Monster?
- I know, terrible joke...
Was there something important?
Yeah. You'll
never guess what happened.
- What?
- They filled in the pot hole.
- The pot hole?
- On 83rd.
- Terrific... Hey, Tom?.
- Yeah?
- I'm gonna go
back to sleep now.
Ok. Sure.
Love you.
Good night...
Call me tomorrow.
- This stuff's all old...
- Yeah, that's the point.
- Let's go to Fendi...
- Fendi? No.
We're here,
let's just stay here.
I'm not into old stuff.
Why do you talk like
a six-year-old?
I'm not.
The line is too long...
- Can't we just go
somewhere else?
No.
This is the best
bakery in the world.
That's why it's worth
waiting in line.
Come on.
We'll play a game.
- Wanna play a game?
- Yeah, I can play a game.
Okay. Good.
- Tell me what to order.
- Why?
You'll see. It will be fun.
Make a suggestion.
- A cookie.
- No, you have to be specific,
like what type of cookie...
A really big cookie.
Tom, your phone's ringing...
Hallo. Hallo?
Hallo...
- What's wrong?
- Just an important call.
That's because you are
an important person.
Wait. Hey...
We will have...
2 fried dumplings,
2 of the wantons...
and 6 of the fried
'pork-thingies'.
- Yeah. But that's
fried. It's not healthy.
Oh, come on. Have
some of the fried...
It won't hurt you.
Thank you.
Move, please..
God.
This is unbelievable.
- Hallo?
- Hey, hallo?
- Hannah?
- Hallo?
- Hey.
Tom?
Tom is that you?
- Tom?
- Hallo?
Hallo? You're cutting out,
I can't hear anything
you're saying.
Tom? I'm stuck in a
thunderstorm.
I'm surrounded by a world
of cows.
- I'll call you when
I get to the hotel...
I can't hear you.
Tom?
Hallo.
Hallo. Hallo?
Hallo?
I hate Scotland.
- Having a hard time?
- We're having a hard time...
- Oh yeah? Want a hand?
- Thank you, sir.
- Yeah.
- We would love it.
- You'd better sit down, sir.
- ...
- Sit down.
- Sit, sit, sit.
Here we go.
- Thank you.
- No, no, thank you.
- Have a good afternoon.
You were wonderful.
- Desista enquanto pode.
- Here we go.
- Come on, Scott.
- Let's go.
What you got, Gar?
What do you got?
- Come on.
- What do you got, Gary?
Foul. Foul, Tom.
What the matter
with you today?
Ahh... I think I might have
feelings for Hannah.
Come on, come on...
Let's just play.
It's just...
Without her, something’s off,
and it's got me
thinking that maybe...
there's more to life than
just sleeping around.
- I don't understand...
- I'm not following...
Come on, let's just play.
Come on.
- I'll take it out.
I know exactly what
you mean, Tom.
Thanks. Here you go.
I'm gonna tell Hannah.
When she gets home.
I'm gonna tell her that
i wanna be with her,
not marriage,
just be together.
Yeah, that's romantic...
>You have one unheard
message<
Hey, Tom. I'm back.
God, I cannot wait to see you.
I don't care what you're
doing tonight, cancel it.
We're going to dinner.
Meet me at that new
trendy place,
next to the small
Greek place we hated,
that used to be the
Thai-fusion place we loved.
Meet me there 8 o'clock,
I have so much to tell you.
- Hey, what have you got?
Hey Buddy. I'll
find you something.
Alright...
Here's something.
How many do you want?
- I'll take the yellow ones.
- Good choice. Ten bucks.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- Have a good night.
- I will.
- Sorry, is she already here?
- Over there.
Yeah, thanks.
Oh, God.
- Tom, are you okay?
I'm alright. Are you alright?
I think I have a broken rib.
- Your flowers, sir.
They're not mine.
I'm fine, I'm okay..
- I'm okay.
- Are you okay?
- I'm so sorry.
- You alright?
- Here are your flowers.
- What, what...
- You had flowers?
- They're not my flowers.
- They're your flowers.
- I didn't have flowers.
- Hi. It's so good to see you.
- I've missed you.
- Great.
Come here, there's someone
I want you to meet.
Oh good.
It started pouring
and suddenly it...
was just me in
a field of cows.
And, of course we're in Europe...
so there's no street
signs anywhere...
- and it's getting dark...
And then she thought
she was in...
some bad werewolf movie.
'Stay off the moors, Lassie'.
Anyway... all of the
sudden, out of nowhere.
Colin comes riding
up on horseback.
- Can you believe it? A horse.
- Oh...
He asked me if I
needed any help.
You were a 'Lady in distress',
what was I supposed to do?
It was right out
of a Bronte-novel.
So anyway... He shows me
to this charming little Inn.
Were he proceeds to buy me...
the most awful dinner
I've ever had.
It was pretty bad,
even by Scottish standards.
Then we just spend the next...
month travelling
around the country,
getting to know each other,
visiting museums... It was..
- Perfect.
So... When it was time for
Hannah to leave, I just...
I don't know, I just...
Couldn't let her go.
- So I got down on one knee...
And he proposed.
And I accepted.
- Wow. That's
just... Huge, it's...
So the wedding's coming
together very quickly.
- Sounds like it.
We're gonna be
married in Scotland,
- At Colin's
parents summer home.
It's gonna be a
pretty small thing.
We can't expect
too many people...
making the trip over
sea, just for a night.
- The Fourth?
- Right.
- That's two weeks.
- It's crazy, isn't it?
- Have you ever been
to Scotland, Tom?
You know, I haven't.
- You should see the wee
church we're gonna have.
It's the same one Colin's
parent's were married in.
It's pretty spectacular,
just a walk...
from my distillery.
- Distillery?
Colin's family owns
the largest...
whiskey distillery in
Scotland.
Tom.. Look, If you're
getting married
I expect to be
your 'Best Man'.
Tom... Will you be my
'Maid of Honor'?
Your 'Maid of Honor'?
Sorry.
What is it with you, man?
I didn't...
Excuse me... Excuse me.
Did you see that?
'Made of Honor'?
That's fun stuff.
But you're a guy.
Go ahead...
Just get it out.
So, what did you say?
- Did you say yes?
- No.
- No?
I didn't know what to say. I
told her I'd think about it.
You need to think
about whether your...
dress is gonna make
your ass look big.
- Give me a break, come on.
- Okay. Alright, let me think.
- Is she really
in to this guy?
You should have seen them.
Staring at him all moony
like he shits unicorns.
That's not good, man.
I'm thinking you're
gonna have to do this.
You're gonna have to be
the Maid of Honor.
- What?
Yeah, I'm serious.
Think about it,
this will give you
an excuse to be...
around Hannah all the time.
Helping her out, being...
'the man behind
the curtain'...
You'll be her confident.
And you can use that
time to point...
out to Hannah that
this is really crazy.
- And that she doesn't
even know this guy at all.
No, I'm not gonna
do that. No way.
- What?
- No.
Look, I don't know what your
other options are.
You got a better
chance of stopping...
this wedding,
from 'inside'
than from another continent.
And they say that you can...
shorten this and wear
it again, if you like.
Come on man. If you're
serious and you...
really want Hanna
back from this guy.
You're gonna have to
do whatever it takes.
Whatever.
- The dress is beautiful.
- Thank you.
- I am so happy
you're gonna do this.
My pleasure.
For this wedding, I am willing
to do whatever it takes.
- I'm so excited.
- Yeah, me too.
So let me tell you who the...
other bridesmaids
are gonna be.
- Okay.
- Okay. Stephanie...
- Stephanie, great.
- And she loves you.
- Good.
And my friend
Hillary, from camp.
Hillary, I don't know Hillary.
- She's the best
- Okay.
- And Melissa.
- Oh, no.
- I had to, Tom,
she's my cousin.
No, she hates me.
- Well, you broke her heart.
- She broke my nose.
- It was an accident.
- She hit me with her fist.
I was completely
honest with her.
I said: 'Look,
nothing serious'.
And she agreed.
So sometimes our hearts don't
match our mouths.
That's good, you should
put that in your vows.
And, she's been
wanting to be my...
maid of honor since
we were 5 years old,
so now she's really gonna
hate you.
Here they are now.
Okay. Well as your
Maid of Honor.
I promise to keep the peace.
Oh, hi.
Yes. The bride to be.
- Hello, you must be Tom.
- And you must be Hillary.
You look gorgeous.
Stephanie, how are you doing?
So good to see you.
- Are you kidding.
- It's you, Melissa.
Look at that...
- This was great.
- This isn't awkward...
Go on.
I'm gonna be fine.
- Tom, have you met Colin yet?
- Yes.
- Isn't he dreamy?
- Absolutely.
Could someone please pass
me the Splendor?
Could someone who's
not a misogynist,
please pass the Splenda?
- Hallo?
- Thank you, Stephanie.
It's Colin, you guys.
Hi, babe.
Just a sec... Hi.
So cute.
We only have 9 days before
we leave for Scotland,
- so we have to act quickly.
- Exactly.
I've been a 'MOH' 6 times,
so I'll organize everything...
that needs to be
done, even though
I'm not officially
the 'MOH' here.
- What is a 'MOH'?
- M-O-H.
Maid Of Honor.
- Yes.
- Oh, yes. That's clever.
No, it's going great.
Very smoothly.
So we got the bridal shower
bachelorette, dress fittings,
- The 'kilt'...
- I'll do the 'kilt'.
- Okay... perfect.
- Okay.
Shopping for Hannah's
true self...
- That's gonna be great.
So, what is
Hannah's true self?
It's lingerie. For her
wedding night.
How do you expect to be a good...
'MOH' if you don't
even know that.
- She's talking to me.
- No, I didn't..
- You just did.
- Oh, I'm sorry, Tom.
Did I break a rule?
How about we focus on the
wedding part?
- Good idea.
- Just for now...
Okay, I need, dress sizes.
- I'm a four.
- Okay.
- Eight.
- Sorry?.
You know, Hillary...
Do you think that maybe
you'd just be more...
- comfortable in
like a, twelve?
No, it will be fine.
- I'm doing the
Dr. Riverbed fast.
Oh, yeah.
- Yeah.
- What is that?
Water, peach raisin/apple
pectin /shark extract.
And Lowry's Seasoning Salt.
- What about food?
- Look.
I'm going to look
amazing in that dress.
I am going to meet a
Scottish man, and...
I'm gonna be happy.
Write down an eight.
Got it.
What's your dress size,
Made Of Honor?
I don't know. What's your jock
size, Melissa?
That's enough. Enough.
Sorry. But will you guys
look at Hannah, please.
She's happy, finally.
So please, for Hannah,
let's all just get along,
put a smile on our faces...
and pretend
everything's perfect.
- Here she comes.
- Okay. Fine.
- What did he say?
- He's so sweet.
Isn't that great?
How's it going?
- Good, really good.
- Fantastic.
- And it's pretty much done.
- Perfect, really?
- Tom.
- Yes?
- Here.
- What is this?
She does bridal
shower entertainment.
And I hired her for
Stephanie's sisters shower,
and Hannah loved it.
She reads Tarot...
cards and stuff.
That's great.
Thank you, Melissa.
I'm not doing it for you,
I'm doing it for Hannah.
Okay.
Thank you, for Hannah.
It should have been me...
- I'll talk with you tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Bye, Tom.
- Goodbye.
- Bye, Hillary.
- Nice meeting you.
You too, bye.
I just had a very nice
bonding moment with Melissa.
- Can I ask you a favor?
- Sure.
My mother and grandmother are
coming in to town tomorrow.
And I have so much to plan...
I was wondering if you
and the boys could...
entertain Colin for the day.
- Entertain him?
Yeah, just kind of get
to know him and stuff.
- Sure.
- Cool.
So are you more proud of
'Scotch Tape' or McDonald's?
I think they're both American.
- So wait, you invited this
guy to play ball with us?
Yeah, he's the competition.
I need to get to know his
strengths and weaknesses.
I like his green shirts.
Is that like a poly
blend kind of thing?
Yeah, it's my shirt...
- It's your shirt?
- Yeah.
- Looks good on him, huh?
- Yeah, real good.
Why don't you play with him?
Thanks.
Colin, have you ever played
basketball before?
We would call this 'netball',
back in Scotland, it's
more of a woman's game,
so, no I don't have much
experience.
- Hi, I do. Need one more?
- We're good.
Alright.
- Alright, 'girls', you ready?
- Yeah, I am.
Oh.
Use your hands.
- You alright there?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- I'm open. I'm open.
- Here we go.
You gotta hold on
to the ball, man.
Hold on to the ball.
Homos. Homos.
Homos.
Let's get the Scottish girl
out if the tree.
You wanna start a game cause
you didn't get that.
There you go.
Open. Open.
Here you go. That was good.
Good.
Amiga.
Shoot it. Guys.
- I like it.
- I'm sorry.
- Come on.
- Get on the path.
You ok?
Ok, basket.
Put it in the basket.
- You know what I'm learning?
The guy's a chump.
Yeah.
- Wow, 'Fault'.
- There it is. That's it.
That's it. That's it.
We got it now.
Hey, I look good now, don't I?
Here we go.
Put it in the basket.
- In the basket.
- Take a shot, chief.
- Sorry, guys.
- Did you see that?
Probably not allowed to just
stuff it in like that.
- He dunks the ball.
- Sorry. Sorry.
He dunks the ball...
That was awesome.
You can dunk.
He can dunk. That is awesome.
If that's allowed, why
don't you guys all do it?
If we could, we would.
Right?
- Play?
- Guys.
- No.
- Yeah.
- Score.
- Yes.
- Good game, yeah, good game.
My brother.
- Looks like you're
getting more competition..
I know, I know...
I love this guy.
Shit.
- You alright?
- Yeah.
What happening?
My boy's got mad cow disease.
We have got to get some dirt
on this guy.
I got a guy I use
when a spouse...
suspect infidelity.
Everybody's got
skeletons in the closet.
Nobody is squeaky-clean,
- and my guy's the best.
I don't know, it
just seems so cheap.
Don't worry, I'll
charge you double...
because you're rich.
I mean, it's a
cheap thing to do.
- He play's cheap,
you gotta match that.
How does Colin play cheep?
That whole thing with
Hannah, being Scottish.
Making her fall in love
with him in Scotland.
That 'monster thing' of his.
Fine.
Get the dirt.
That's cool.
Van Wyck Expressway
Kennedy Airport 1.5 mile
What's he gonna do,
eat her?
Come on, come on.
Take a breath. Take a...
Thanks, Tom.
- Yeah, have a great flight.
- Right. Thanks, mate.
Come on...
- I love you, Colin.
- Bye.
Bye.
- Yeah...
- My God.
- Need some chap stick?
- Yeah...
So... What church should
we go to?
Grace's Church.
Thank you so much for coming
with me to meet the reverend.
- No problem.
- He is the sweetest man...
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
He married my parents
and insisted...
on coming to Scotland
to do my wedding.
Why didn't Colin stay and do
this with you?
It was more important for him...
to go back to
Scotland to partition
The Grand Council...
so Colin and I
could get married.
I don't know. Grand?
What does that mean?
I'm not Scottish
and his family...
is kind of...
What?
Royalty.
Royalty?
- Royalty? Is he like a King?
- No.. No, he's a Duke.
A Duke?
- Hannah, darling.
- Reverend Foote.
And this must be the
lucky young man...
who is marrying our
beautiful Hannah.
Oh, no.
- I'm not marrying him
- No...
This is Tom,
my 'Maid Of Honor'.
- Maid of Honor?
- Yes.
How about that...
We have many gay and lesbian
members of the congregation.
Welcome.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Reverend.
So...
- Let's talk
about the wedding.
Okay.
I need to get some details
about you and...
- Colin.
- Colin, yes.
I want to work it
in to the ceremony.
Okay. It was such a
whirl wind. Really...
Yes, enlighten me.
Tell me about it.
Hannah, darling.
Hannah, I think it's important...
to dig deep her
for the vows...
and tell the Reverend all
you know about Colin.
- All that you love about him.
- Okay.
And not just the
obvious stuff,
but those unique
characteristics...
that are Colin.
Those things that make you
laugh and say...
'That's so Colin'.
Right...
And then, maybe you
could get some...
information from Colin...
and emphasize
their unique bond,
their shared history.
Off course.
We could talk about
love at first sight.
Well, that's always a
crowd pleaser, but...
Hannah... Elaborate...
Tell me more about him.
How you feel about him.
Where did you meet?
- In Scotland...
- Modigliani.
Your first summer
in New York City,
you were dating a guy who
worked on Wall Street...
and he asked you to move in...
with him and you
weren't quite sure...
And it was right
around that time...
that you 'discovered'
Modigliani...
And became obsessed
with this painting...
of this woman who had this
blue scarf on, holding a baby.
And Hannah said: 'That...
painting captured
the essence...
of that woman better
than any photograph'.
I can't believe you
can remember that.
I also remembered that she...
freaked, because she
said she felt more...
passionate about that painting...
than she did but
'Mr. Wall Street'...
And she wondered if she could
ever meet somebody...
that could make her feel this...
passionate as
that work of art.
That's good.
Modigliani.
Now I know why you picked
him to be 'Maid of Honor'.
Yes...
Come on. Who's ready
to lose some...
money tonight. Because
I'm feeling lucky.
You guys are late.
How you doing?
- How you holding up, champ?
- Stressed.
What the hell is this?
- Hannah's shower's
in the morning.
Well where are we gonna play?
We're not gonna play until
these baskets get done,
and everything else gets done.
- What about this party mix?
- That's 'pot-pourri'.
This is perfect...
- Come on Felix,
take that off...
Have you ever
had one of these?
- That's funny...
- You can't even see.
You'll have to,
to sleep with you...
- Take this.
- You could be like blinded.
No, I'm not playing
with baskets.
It's poker night.
You put 'Bayberry'
with 'Serenity'.
- You don't like?
- No, it's interesting.
Just thought it
was obvious that...
'Bayberry' worked
best with 'Harmony'.
Really? I've been
putting 'Bayberry'...
with 'Tahitian Sunrise'.
- That I like. That's Zen.
- Yeah.
You know what I
like? I like how...
you put the bat ball
right in the center.
I like that so much
that I'm gonna...
see you ball and raise
you another ball.
That's a good idea.
We should definitely
have 2 balls...
- Yeah. Do another ball.
- Hey, Dennis...
Come and curl some ribbon.
I can feel my sperm
dying inside...
of me, one at a time.
Shut up and grab a basket.
Come on, it's fun.
I'm going to a strip club
to eat some meat.
Then I'm gonna
get into a fight.
Call me when you find your
balls, Tom.
Alright, tuff guy.
Or maybe they're
in the basket,
next to the
'Tahitian Sunrise'.
Someone's afraid of his
feminine side...
Look at that... Nice job
with the fluffing.
Look at that.
- Perfect. Perfect.
- What is that, my friends.
- Look at us.
- Come on.
- Can't lose.
- Good work, huh?
Hello ladies.
You look lovely today.
- Tom.
- Oh, Hillary. How are you?
Good. Everything
looks wonderful.
This is the best shower
I've ever been to.
Really? You think so?
You know what, Hillary?
You should really
eat something.
No, Tom. I'm fine.
Fine. I'm okay.
What you ladies would go...
through to fit
in to a dress...
This pretty much blows
your rule out of...
the water about no women
allowed at your place.
What good is a rule if you...
don't break it
every now and then?
I'm very, very impressed
Thank you.
Listen to that.
Gay Gordon's party remix,
just for you.
Hear the horn.
- It's good isn't it?
- No.
Let me turn it up there...
It's...
- It's a little loud...
- What?
- It's a little loud.
- Okay. There you go.
Look at this. Try this.
Haggis pink.
It's pepper, cheese,
chopped up baby...
lamb lung, and cow
pituitary gland.
- How are you?
- ...
It's a Scottish delicacy.
Colin recommended it.
Ladies, ladies.
Look...
What just came,
for Hannah.
It's from Colin, everyone.
Oh wait. There's a card.
There's a card, a card...
For: 'Hannah'.
'Hannah, my love, this
is the extremely...
rare Scottish floral
bud thistle'.
Thistle?
'They only bloom for 4 hours
before they die'.
He must have timed this out
perfectly...
Oh my gosh, when we first met,
Colin promised that
he would roam...
at the countryside to
find me one, and he did.
Sweetheart, that's
the most romantic...
thing I ever heard.
Thanks mom.
Joan, good to see you.
It's been too long.
Easter, wasn't it?
Yes. You slept with our maid.
She told you?
I didn't know she
spoke English.
Yes...
This is grandma Pearl.
You remember Tom?
- How are you?
- Oh, yes, the fornicator.
That's right.
- Okay...
- Tom, this is awesome.
- It's great.
- Good. Thank you.
This is even better than
my sister's shower.
- Oh, really?
- Ahem...
Everything seems to
be doing well. Yes?
Sharon would like to know
where to set up.
- Who?
- The entertainment...
Ah, yes... I mean good.
She should set up over there.
Hello everybody.
Hi, I'm Sharon.
Good to see you all.
Yeah, come on, right
down the front.
This was my idea, you know?
I know how much
you loved her from
Stephanie's sister's shower...
Before we start, I
would like for us...
all to take in
a deep breath...
She wasn't at the shower...
- She wasn't?
- No.
- And now exhale slowly...
- Really?
Good job.
It's very important to
reset our third eye.
And connect to...
the primal inside
of ourselves.
Before I present the
pleasure aids.
Pleasure aids?
Now...
These pleasures are
best used when...
in tantric meditative state.
And today, I'm going
to show you ladies...
how to reach your
optimal sacred Chakra.
All of these aids are
for sale, ladies.
And look what we have here...
Edible panties.
You look hungry.
Try to snack on these.
There you go.
Now ladies, what pleasure...
party would be
complete without...
Glow-in-the-dark
thunder beads?
These are terrific.
And for you ladies, today...
Two for one.
Okay?
There you go.
Wanna try this out, princess?
Where do these go?
From casual writing
to evening wear.
Gorgeous.
Why don't you keep those?
And they match your
ear rings.
Hannah, are you okay?
You know that I've dreamt
of my wedding shower,
ever since I was
10 years old?
No...
Strangely enough, the image...
of my grand mom,
pearl drape...
and glow-in-the-dark
thunder beads...
wasn't part of it.
It's not funny, Tom.
Do you have any idea how
important this is to me?
The Gay Gordon, pink Haggis,
Dildo-sales woman?
Just understand something,
Melissa set me up.
Oh please. There's always
an excuse with you.
I never even should have asked...
you to do this in
the first place.
You don't even
believe in marriage...
for Christ sake...
You know, I might.
I gotta get back.
Melissa's pretty good.
Look, the whole
goal here was to...
convince Hannah
that I've grown up,
and that she doesn't know
anything about Colin...
That I'm the right
man for her.
That did not happen.
Stella. No, baby.
Don't eat buttons, okay?
Yeah, but your still
the Maid of Honor, right Tom?
I don't know. I think she
might have fired me.
How does somebody...
get fired from
being Maid of Honor?
Tell me about it.
- You know what?
I got an idea.
Okay.
To prove to Hannah that
you're the only man for her,
we have to make you the best
Made of Honor, ever.
Right.
- I'm out of loss.
Completely stunned.
Great.
My guy couldn't find any
dirt on Colin.
This has never happened.
This guy's clean.
Glad that happened to me.
You know, he's got
3 Guinness world records?
- Cool.
We don't need to know that...
He's actually got
a Medal of Honor.
That's funny, because we
got the Made of Honor.
Let's stay focused.
Look, the point is,
we're not gonna...
get her off this guy.
Yeah, so we need to make
this not about Colin.
Yeah, we need to
make it about you.
- Good...
- You gotta show her
That you're growing up...
- Finally...
I am changing.
I am growing up.
- Good.. Then this
should be easy for you.
Great...
These are bridal
magazines from...
18 different countries...
each with a feature article on...
the duties of being
the Maid of Honor.
Perfect.'Über Bride'...
I got these guys in
Bangalore that we're...
outsource to, they
translated them over night.
- Great.
Nice 'appetizers'
there, Gary...
- Here's the 'Main course'
- What have you got for me?
My wife Deb is a
A-type personality,
she has to do
everything perfect.
- Sure...
- Love her...
- Hate that about her.
- Right.
Anyway, she rented this when...
she was gonna be
the Maid Of Honor...
for her yoga teacher.
This is 'the goods'.
You're gonna be wow-ed.
12 Steps Down The Aisle
Hi, I'm Elisabeth Hasselbeck
and I'm just so thrilled...
you've purchased this program.
And I'm proud of you...
Because it shows that
you're not happy being just...
an ordinary friend
and loved one.
No. You and I are
gonna work together...
to make you the
perfect Maid of Honor.
When we're through,
you'll know...
everything there is to
know about dresses.
Crockery, nuptial etiquette
and pleasing your bride.
What's the length...
of the bridesmaid dress?
No longer than the brides.
What if you know someone...
won't be able to
attend the wedding?
You got to send an
invitation anyway.
Receiving line?
If there's a receiving
line, it means I've failed,
because Hannah's married.
Right. It was a
trick question.
Who was the runner
up MVP in 1974?
No, these questions all have
to do with Tom...
being the best Maid Of Honor
he can be.
Alright.
I thought we were just
asking like... Questions.
Go sit down.
Basic duties of the
Maid of Honor?
Manage the bridesmaids,
carry the ring, and
support the bride.
Basic duties as You as
the Maid of Honor?
Show Hannah that I've matured,
that I can take care of my
responsibilities fully...
and that I need to destroy
the wedding from within.
- What happens if you
fail at that task?
Colin gets her.
- What are we gonna do?
- Steal the bride.
Steal the bride.
And remember...
Weather it is helping
with the seating chart...
or giving your
opinion on the cake,
the perfect Maid Of Honor is...
with her bride every
step of the way.
You didn't have to clear your
whole day to do all this.
Are you kidding?
Off course I did.
The perfect Maid of Honor is...
with his bride every
step of the way.
A changed man...
I am indeed.
I don't even know
where to begin.
When choosing a china
pattern,
you need to think
about what type...
of entertaining you're open
to, foods you wanna cook...
Look. Now don't be afraid
to mix and mash.
It's important, even with
different styles and textures.
What you wanna do, is stir
up the table.
Make it come alive with color
and tenacity. That's the goal.
Also, at the end of the day...
You will find...
...Connections.
Thank you very much.
Let's go.
If you think I'm
good with plates,
wait till you see what
I do with linens.
- Lingerie, perfect.
- What about the linens?
You'll be able to pick out...
something for the
wedding night.
- No.
Are you crazy? You're the
perfect person for this job.
Who's taken off more lingerie
than you?
let's put your 'whore-ing'
to good use.
Good point.
So how did it go with the
Scottish Grand Council?
Great. Colin got them to
approve everything.
Great.
So, I gotta tell you...
This is gonna
sound funny, but...
- I have to thank you.
- For what?
For asking me to be your
Maid of Honor.
I know this is gonna
sound crazy, but...
You've really opened my eyes,
to the whole idea of marriage.
- Yeah, right...
- No, seriously...
- Have you met someone, Tom?
- No.
Then how can you be serious?
I don't know, I just...
I don't know.
What do you think?
Think Colin will like it?
No... no.
- What?
- It's just...
It's cute.
'Cute'? I do not wanna look
'cute' on my wedding night.
Just put this on.
Cover yourself up.
That's my coat.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Yeah.
Here let me get you
in a cab. Come on.
I can't believe this is my
last day in New York.
What are you talking about?
I've been meaning
to tell you, Tom.
When I leave tomorrow,
I'm not coming back.
I've decided to move to
Scotland, to be with Colin.
- You're leaving New York?
- I am.
It's exciting, you know?
It makes sense.
He's next in line to take
over the family business...
It's a whole new chapter.
- You were amazing
today, you know that?
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. I had no idea you could
juggle like that.
- Yeah, well...
- I mean, women yes, china no.
- Yeah, I know.
- You're always amazing.
Come here.
- See you in
Scotland soon, okay?
Yeah, see you over there.
I'll miss you.
Scotland...
Come, baby.
He likes you.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Nice dogs.
This is Hamish and
this is Callum.
- Callum?
- Yeah.
What kind of dog is that?
- He's a Scottie.
- A Scottie?
That's perfect.
Fuckin Scottie...
I've never felt
like this before.
So hopeless.
So, tell me again, why you...
agreed to be the
Maid of Honor?
To be with her,
make her happy.
Figure out some way to
get her off of him.
Maybe that was all
wrong. Maybe he's...
better for her than me.
He's Scottish, he can dunk,
he's perfect.
Nobody's perfect.
But I tell you,
this whiskey comes
damn close...
It was a gift from Colin.
He made it.
Swell.
I can't go. I can't watch
Hannah marry this guy.
She's moving to Scotland,
I've lost her already.
- Crap.
'...Love something,
set it free'.
Said by a pussy and used
by pussies ever since.
- Casablanca.'Bogie'
put's her on a plane.
Pussy.
- 'Bogie’s a pussy?
- Big pussy.
You know, I've only
truly been in love once.
Most amazing woman
in the world.
She was my best friend.
But I was young, stupid,
and I messed it up.
In my great list of mistakes,
that was the greatest.
- Who was this?
- Your mother.
When I finally
found out how stupid
I was and I decided
to fight for it...
I was too late.
She wouldn't take me back.
She was right.
And then it really
was too late.
By the way...
I'm getting another divorce.
Dad...
Hey... Go and get her,
you pussy.
- What about the dresses?
UPS are delivering
them tomorrow morning.
- I gave you the
tracking address...
I got it.
So, Colin and Hannah are gonna
meet everyone at the house...
- Okay.
- Great.
- Thomas.
- Yeah?
Go get 'em, Maid of Honor.
- Yeah.
Make this the perfect wedding.
- And steal the bride.
- Thanks, guys. Thanks.
Thanks for everything, man.
Thank you so much, alright?
- Alright, baby.
Alright. Alright,
alright. Get out of here.
I'll see you later.
- This is like a fairy tale.
- Hannah is SO lucky.
- I know.
- I wish I was her.
- How has she ever
found such a great guy?
We'll come visit her.
- I know...
- Look at the time.
What's your name?
You're a pretty dog.
I love you.
- That's his house?
No, isn't this
the summer house?
The McMurray's have
homes for each...
season. This summer
home, is their smallest.
They also have an Autumn home,
a Winter home, a Spring...
I know the seasons,
thanks, buddy.
Somebody's richer
thank you, Tom.
I guess you are gonna have to...
invent something
even stupider.
Oh, my God.
The entire castle
was actually build...
in 1220...
- This is
incredible, isn't it?
Yes...Wow...
Grandma Pearl, Joan, this is...
my mother, Diedre
and my father, Mungo.
- How do you do?
Nice to meet you,
Joan. Pleasure.
- Thank you.
- Nice to meet you.
Everyone, I want you
to meet someone...
who is so special
to my Hannah...
and who has been her
life-long friend,
and now her Maid
of Honor, Tom.
- Hi, how is...
Did he just say he's
the Maid of Honor...
He's a bloke?.
- How do you do?
- Very good, thank you.
- Mungo.
- Mungo, pleasure. Thank you.
Definitely gay.
And these are the bridesmaids.
Hillary, Stephanie
and Melissa.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
- Hi.
Nice that you could
come. How do you do?
How do you do?
- So... what do you think?
- I think, they think I'm gay.
Look can we get together,
talk, catch up?
- Tom, do wanna
see your chamber?
Love to.
- Okay, follow me
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Now then... I think
just a few more...
sprigs of jipsoffle
at the front there...
Lovely.
- What do you guys think?
- Oh.. It is gorgeous...
- It is so pretty...
With the veil...
So shiny, and the volume...
Tom... What do you think?
Of...?
The hair. Yeah, it...
This sash will
go on the dress.
- Really?
- Tradition.
What's up with that?
Well...
I'm not.. entirely sure...
Oh no, you see...
It's attached up here...
Tom, you're the Maid of Honor,
it's good to just
be supportive...
- I'm supportive.
- I don't think you are.
- No, I am.
- Listen to me...
You're doing good,
you're good...
Hannah...
Actually, your hair...
Looks amazing.
- Really?
- Yes.
The games will be
starting soon.
Here are your costumes.
- Games?
- Costumes.
- Our costumes?
- What do you mean, games?
The Highland games.
It's a tradition,
in honor of the wedding.
It goes right back to the time
when the groom had to prove...
that he was man enough to
deserve the bride.
If he didn't win, he
didn't get the bride.
No problem for my Colin...
Welcome, one and all
to the Highland Games.
Men have travelled
from all four...
corners of this
great country...
to compete in feats of
strength and agility.
But only one warrior will be
man enough to claim the bride.
One warrior that needs
no introduction...
is our very own
Colin McMurray.
- Isn't Colin handsome?
- And coming up,
here, all the
way from America.
Hannah's Maid of Honor, Tom.
Who I think you can all agree,
is wearing a rather
fetching mini-kilt.
- Who was in charge of that?
- I have no idea.
They're really
giving their all.
And we're running
neck and neck...
A Scottish man against a Yank.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the result of today's
Highland Games...
rests upon the 'Cable Toss'.
The competition is down to
2 competitors.
A tree...
We're tossing a tree?
What a toss.
Way to go, Colin.
Okay, Tom. Let's see
what you're made of.
The whole competition rests
on this throw.
Look at that Yankee..
Alright. Okay..
Come on, Tom.
Oh gosh...
Okay. I can do this.
I can do this. Okay.
Here we go. Great.
Okay. Okay.
Here we go. Here we go.
Here we go, Oh...
Watch out, watch out.
That's gonna cost the Yank
the gold medal.
- What an ass.
And the winner of the
Highland Games is,
our very own Colin McMurray.
That's great.
*For my love is
like a melody*...
*That sweetly
played in June*...
*As fair art thou,
my bonny lass*...
*say deep in love am I*...
*And I will love thee
still, my dear*...
*till all the
seas gang dry*...
*And I will love thee still,
My dear*...
*Though t'were 10
thousand miles*.
Well done, My boy.
Well done.
That was so....
Well done, my boy.
Robert Burns, who
wrote that song,
is Scotland's
most famous poet.
No, no, Auntie. We haven't
had any 'bairns' yet,
so we haven't got
any names yet.
'Bairns' means children.
I'm so sorry, I'm
having a hard...
time understanding
your accent.
- 'Ethel'.
- Excuse me?
It's a name, for the children.
- 'Ethel'.
- 'Ethel'...
Little Ethel.
Yeah. We won't be naming our
child Ethel.
Maybe if he was a teenager...
My mother's third cousin was
the Duke of Ethel.
We're a long line
of 'Ethel’s'.
Maybe... Maybe we'll keep...
it in the mix, maybe
as a middle name...
- So, Hannah, do you
like the venison?
It's delicious.
Colin shot it.
He's a wonderful Shot.
- Stop, mum. You'll
make me blush.
And this is the moment.
I've just remembered.
- What moment is that?
- When Colin killed the deer.
I filmed it.
Right between the eyes.
In fact, everything
we are eating...
this evening,
Colin has killed.
- To Colin.
In your honor, Hannah.
That is so thoughtful...
I'm so sorry, I didn't kill
anything for you...
Gosh...
What did you get?
- Uhm...
- I love chocolate.
Don't... Don't do that.
You want some...
Here. I'll give you some.
Excuse me.
Reverend...
Excuse me, sir. There you go.
Wonderful dinner, by the way.
- Delighted, Tom.
- And your wife is beautiful.
Thank you very much.
- Thanks.
- Cheers.
A little birdie tells me
that Colin personally...
slayed each one of
these reindeer heads...
- Tom...
- Alright.
I say 'a little
birdie told me'.
He would have told
me, but Colin shot it.
Listen, seriously...
Can we go somewhere private
and talk? It's important.
- Yeah.
- Should we go?
Bagpipes...
Oh, My God...
He's been playing the
bag pipes ever since...
he was 3 years old.
Practices every night.
- Every night?
- Never misses.
- What kind of
necklace is that?
They're glow-in-the-dark
thunder beets.
- Hi, mom.
- I have something for you.
- Some evening, huh?
- Yes...
This is so you can
have a little...
piece of home with you.
Thank you.
Look at you...
There's you and Melissa.
You were about 5 there.
Do you remember this?
It was taken at the
lake, when you father...
broke his arm, because of
that silly motorcycle of his.
- I miss dad so much
- Me too, Sweetheart.
I just wish that he could
have been here.
He was always so worried,
I was never gonna meet anyone.
- No, he wasn't.
- That's Paris.
He could be so 'off
days' sometimes...
What?
Well, it's just... He
was always convinced...
that you were gonna marry Tom.
Really?
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Good night, My Angel.
It's pulling off a band aid.
You just have to close
your eyes and do it.
- I just haven't
found the right time.
What are you talking
about, 'right time'?
Anytime is the
right time to say...
'I love you, marry me'.
- Right.
Come on, what are
you there for, man?
Take the shot, win the game
and bring her home.
And stop running up
my long-distance...
phone bill with
these crazy calls..
Right, right okay.
Thanks, Felix.
God, come on. You
can do this, Tom.
What's wrong with
me? You can do this.
- Hey.
I thought we could go for a
walk and work on the vows.
- Good idea. I need some help.
- Good. Okay.
- What do you think?
- I think a lot of things.
I've been working
on them all week...
and I actually think
they're getting worse.
At first I went
for the 'emotion'.
I thought: 'What
if Colin does it'?
Then I tried to be funny...
I don't know if Scots
have the same...
sense of humor as Americans.
So now I am back to
something basic...
and I totally think
I've geared...
off into something boring...
I'm crazy about you.
I think of you
all the time and
I wanna spend the rest
of my life with you.
Really?
Really.
- That's so 'generic'.
- Generic?
- Yeah.
- It totally is.
- How can that be generic?
It sounds like something
you're supposed...
to say instead of what
your really feeling.
Alright. How about...
Nobody in the world makes
me laugh the way you do.
You're my best friend.
I just wanna be with you.
Look, look.
There she is.
Let's go, let's go.
- Hannah, let's go.
- What is this?
- It's her 'taking out'.
- Her... What?
We dress her up and then we...
parade around one of
the pubs in town.
- That's weird...
- It's tradition.
- Really?
Then we fill a
toilet with salt...
and we sell your kisses
for change.
- Sell your kisses?
- Yep.
Come on, it's like a Scottish
Bachelorette-party.
Okay, Okay...
- Okay, come on.
Change for kisses.
Right there...
Instead of Whiskeys.
It's her 'taking-out'.
She's got the
breath of an angel.
One more, alright, alright.
- Another.
Thank you.
This is all I have.
- Oh, my God. My
God, you guys.
Let's go.
We have to get more kisses.
Kisses.
- I can't take it anymore.
- What are you doing?
- Let's do it again.
- No.
- For old time's sake...
- Don't take that off.
- I need to make
this up to you...
Don't... take... this.
No, I'm really unhappy.
- That's fine.
- Tom...
- It's okay. It's okay...
- I'm not happy at all.
- Get up...
- And I am in a really...
confusing place in my life
right now...
- Confusing?
- Listen...
- I have had some whiskey...
- I can tell.
And I need you
to 'service' me.
- 'Service' you? I not
gonna 'service you'...
'Service me', bitch.
- Oh, my...
'Service me'.
- Be quiet.
- You be quiet.
Everyone's sleeping...
- Get down.
- You can't get down.
You can't...
- Be quiet.
- You be quiet.
No. No. Get off.
Wait... Wait...
- Hannah...
- Bring me more whiskey.
Hannah.
It's Tom, let me in.
Let me in.
Go away, Tom.
No. Let me explain.
It's not what you think.
- It doesn't matter now.
- Yes it does. Why did you...
- Just... Go.
I'll go. Just tell me, why...
did you come to my room?
Hannah... Why did you
come to the room?
To talk about that kiss.
Please, don't...
Don't marry him.
- All these years, Tom...
- Don't marry him...
All this time...
- You're doing this now?
- I know...
- How can you do this?
- I'm sorry... Just let me in.
- No. I can't.
- Let me in.
You're only doing
this now because...
you are afraid of losing me.
I need someone who's gonna
be there for me,
no matter what happens.
Someone who truly...
Loves me.
Someone I can trust.
I'm marrying Colin tomorrow...
Tom.
I can't be your
Maid of Honor.
I can't give you away.
I'm sorry, Hannah.
I'm sorry, you and Tom
had a fight.
I'm his best friend.
He's just afraid of
loosing me.
- He'll get over it.
- Ay.
- Suck it. Suck it.
- I am.
- Okay. Suck it
in. Breath in...
- Hold it...
- I'm trying, my God..
- I'll hold it in.
- Okay. Alright, alright.
- Give it to me..
- 1, 2, 3...
- Is it?...
- Oh, My God.
- It fits, it fits.
- It fits.
- Well done.
- Oh no. No, no...
- My God... no...
- Why are we stopping?
- An early flock.
A... What?
Hi, Sweetheart.
I remember you.
Hey.
Hi.
I love you too.
Thank you.
Turn around,
I have to go back.
Oh, no.
Oh no.
Shit... Shit.
- Hey, I need
another ferry-boat.
We only got the one ferry.
- What?
And it's waiting over there
for the ceremony to finish.
- Is there another
way to get there?
You can drive.
- Drive... How long?
It will take about an
hour and a half...
- That's too long.
- You can swim.
- Swim?..
Or you can go on trip
around the shore.
- That will take a wee while.
- Shore, right...
A horse. A horse.
Hey, I need your horse.
- My horse?
- Yes.
- Come down from there.
- I need to get to the church.
What do think you're
planning, you...
great fool? You'll
hurt yourself.
I'll give you 3 cents for...
every coffee collar
used worldwide.
- What?
Do you have any idea
how much money that is?
Good luck to you, then.
Her name's Nancy.
- I'll see you over there
- Thanks. Nancy, let's go.
Stick to the shore... Pass the...
monument, the church
is on the left.
What, in the name
of the wee man,
is a 'Coffee collar'?
Go, Nancy.
This is just what
this nice dress needs...
and it goes across the dress.
It looks really beautiful.
Please, be seated.
We are gathered here together,
in the sight of God...
- Give me your pin...
to witness this
congregation...
To join together this man...
This is a celebration of love.
For Colin, it's
through the memories...
of seeing his parent's love.
- ...As a child.
- It looks very nice.
And for Hannah, it's...
through the paintings
of Modigliani.
Therefore, if any man
can show just cause...
why these two may not
be joined together...
Let him now speak,
or forever hold his peace.
Tom?
Tom.
Tom...
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I think so.
- Tom, what are
you doing here?
I have to tell
you something...
Hannah...
Your hair looks awful.
- It does?
- Yeah.
- What?
- And the sash...
It sucks.
But that hair...
- It's like a co-op
for parakeets.
What?
Look... Hannah...
I pride myself with
being honest...
with everybody.
But there's somebody
I've been lying...
to for a very long
time. Myself.
Because the truth it's...
It's scary.
And 10 years ago I got in bed
with the wrong girl.
She turned out to be
the right one.
I love you, Hannah.
I always have...
And I always will.
Thomas Bailey...
You are the worst Maid
of Honor of all time.
Oh, no.
I'm...
So...
Very, truly, sorry.
I don't expect you to
ever forgive me.
Just so you know...
You are the perfect guy.
Just not the perfect guy
for me.
Goodbye, Hannah.
Colin...
- What did she say?
- She said I should dick you.
Oh yeah, that makes sense...
Arsehole.
- I do.
And Tom, do you take Hannah...
- to be your lawfully
wedded wife?
I do.
Now, this is the moment.
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
At last... You may
kiss your bride.
Oh my God.
- Number six?
- Seven.
You're absolutely glowing
tonight, grandma Pearl.
Thank you. It's very
nice of you to say so.
What are you doing?
I'm just making sure I got
the right girl this time.
You do.
Definitely.
- Oh, Monica...
- Oh, Bill...
Resync: Xenzai[NEF]