Friendship between
Austria and France...
...must be cemented
by marriage.
My youngest daughter,
Antoine...
...will be queen of France.
Mops.
The court of France
is not like Vienna.
Listen closely to
Ambassador Mercy's council.
All eyes will be on you.
Look.
Do you like him?
He has kind eyes.
He's definitely very French.
- Three. Four.
- Six.
- Are we there yet?
- Yes.
We have arrived at Schüttern
for the official handover.
Then you will be presented to the king
and to your fiancé, Louis Auguste.
Your Royal Highness, may I present
your mistress of the household...
...Comtesse de Noailles.
Your Royal Highness.
Madame.
This structure for the
handover ceremony...
...has been built precisely astride
the borders of the two great lands.
You have entered
on Austrian soil...
...you will exit on French as
the dauphine of France.
Now you must bid farewell
to your party...
...and leave all of
Austria behind.
Goodbye.
Mops.
You can have as many
French dogs as you like.
It is a custom...
...that the bride retain nothing
belonging to a foreign court.
An etiquette always observed
on such an occasion.
You're lucky.
Apparently she's quite beautiful.
I'll probably end up with someone
who looks like a dog.
- Or a horse.
I've heard she's really nice.
- Think they got rabbits here?
- Maybe.
Come on.
You notice anything strange
about me lately?
It's so muddy here.
I know. My stomach
feels a little bit sick.
Are you feeling better now?
Are you feeling better, Camille?
- I wonder if our little doggie is sick.
- Feel a little sickly.
Now.
Oh, my goodness, it's so
uncomfortable underfoot.
Come on.
There we are.
How is her bosom?
I have not looked at the archduchess's
bosom, Your Majesty.
Oh, didn't you?
It's the first thing I look at.
The Duc de Choiseul.
The foreign minister who was
instrumental in this union.
I shall never forget that you were
responsible for my happiness.
And that of France.
Please.
Here comes the Austrian.
I hope you like apple strudel.
May I present Madame la Dauphine,
Marie Antoinette.
My dear grandfather king.
Welcome, madame.
Let me present my grandson,
Louis Auguste.
Welcome, madame.
She looks like a child.
Hello.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome, madame.
Thanks.
Hello.
Amen.
To the dauphin and
dauphine of France.
May you have many
healthy children...
...and produce an
heir to our throne.
Good luck.
And good work.
Apparently, nothing happened,
Your Majesty.
Nothing?
- Nothing.
Oh, dear.
Madame...
...at the morning
dressing ceremony...
...rights of entry are given to
members of the high court.
Major rights to princesses of the blood
and mistresses of the household...
...while minor rights to
the valets and charges.
Anyone with rights of entry
may enter at any time...
...so you must pay attention,
to acknowledging properly
each arrival.
And you must not
reach for anything...
...for the handing of an item to the
dauphine is a guarded privilege.
Must go to the highest
rank in the room.
For example,
the Princesse de Lamballe...
...is a princess of the
blood by marriage.
Madame.
Thank you.
- It's cold.
- Yes.
Good morning.
So now the position must
go to the Duchess of Char...
...because she is also
a princess of the blood.
Hello.
So now, as a member
of the royal family...
...your sister-in-law, the Comtesse de
Provence, must have the honor.
This is ridiculous.
This, madame, is Versailles.
So I've heard you make
keys as a hobby?
Yes.
And you enjoy making keys?
Obviously.
She had to let her servants go.
My maid knows the cook.
You know everyone.
Comtesse de Noailles
looks very out of sorts.
I think her husband's been
causing a little problem lately...
...spending far too much
time with his stable boys.
Too much.
Marie Antoinette looks
very pretty tonight.
Yes.
Darling, a new life,
unfortunately.
When you think about it,
this poor Marie Antoinette.
So young, so...
I think she should go
back to her country.
Look at her, so disgusting.
The comtesse is looking rather
dour this evening, don't you think?
Always dour.
Always tragic.
Can't believe they've brought
those ghastly aunts out again.
Where have they been
hiding them all these years?
Oh, really?
This is shocking.
What is she...?
It's so awful, I can't...
Oh, my goodness.
Who is she?
That lady is here to give
pleasure to the king.
That's du Barry,
the king's mistress.
She wouldn't be
allowed at court...
...but the king did some maneuvering
to secure her a title.
The one thing I've learned
about girls from the gutter...
...is they know their jewels.
No way are those fake.
You see that?
Is this the way people
are treating me?
To the stocks.
Nobody treats me
like a lady here.
Now she's staring at me.
It's so awful.
- She should not be sitting at this table.
- I'll have one of...
Did you hear that?
- She just burped.
- Out of the whorehouse, darling.
- I don't know who you're referring to.
- Everyone at this table is for sale.
- Curls.
- What a little tart.
Well, she's not the only one at this
table, darling. Take a look around.
Look at this beautiful
Marie Antoinette. I look like her?
- Don't you think so?
- A long time ago.
Oh, you exaggerate.
She has blue eyes like me.
I suppose she's rather sweet.
For an Austrian.
I think she's delightful.
She looks like a piece of cake.
Be interesting to see
how long she lasts.
Good afternoon, Your Majesty.
How is your grandson,
the dauphin?
He's off hunting the stag.
She doesn't seem the
least bit interested in him.
She is Austrian. They're not
exactly the warmest people.
But it's true. Her brother Joseph
is so cold. He's an awful man.
They say in Austria,
that she was with child...
What a hunt today.
I'm exhausted.
Would you like some meat?
Your Royal Highness...
...handing out cold meats
to a hunting party...
...is not the most becoming conduct
for a future queen of France.
I was just trying to be a nice
wife for the dauphin's hunt.
Surely there's
no harm in that.
And I received a letter from your
mother warning you not to ride...
...as this is one of the leading
causes of miscarriages.
Well, as everyone knows,
there's no danger of that.
And it's not my fault.
Do you realize the consequences of
an unconsummated royal marriage?
That it could be annulled?
Your mother has asked that you
take this matter very seriously.
And do everything
in your power...
...to inspire the dauphin.
I'll do what I can.
Of course I want to please
the dauphin and my mother.
You'll have no influence over the king
and dauphin without a pregnancy.
Madame, you have
the alliance to consider.
Letting everyone down would
be my greatest unhappiness.
I am pleased madame
is taking this seriously.
Oh, is Mops on his way?
I'm working on it...
...but Your Royal Highness has more
pressing matters to attend to.
Oh, and I received this
letter from your mother.
Dearest Antoinette:
It is clear that the heart of
your problems in your new home...
...is your inability to inspire
sexual passion in your husband.
There is no reason a girl
with so many charms as you...
...should be in this situation.
Remember, you represent
the future...
...and nothing is certain
about your place there...
...until the final physical act to
crown the Franco-Austrian alliance...
...is performed.
It's cold.
It is a bit chilly.
Shall I get you a blanket?
No. It's okay.
Are those your feet?
They're like icicles.
Well...
...sleep well.
Thank you.
- Night.
- Good night.
Your hair always
looks so pretty.
- Oh, do you think so?
- Yeah, it's gorgeous.
- It's not what I'm used to. It is.
- It's so nice to be blond.
- Have you been to see Léonard?
- No.
My head is in agony.
- This morning, I think, you know...
- Did he pull it?
Léonard must've been
in a bad mood...
...because he was pulling
my hair so hard.
And I want to tell him, you know, it's
not my fault if he's had a bad morning.
Don't take it
out on my scalp.
That was unnecessary.
Watch it.
I would love to go to
the opera in Paris.
Why go to the opera when we
can listen to the comtesse here?
Must she sing all night?
Can't you do something
about your wife?
Madame, shall we retire
to make love all night?
Four times last night
wasn't enough.
Dear Antoinette:
I am extremely concerned
with your situation.
Fortunately, the king doesn't show
preference for your sister-in-law.
But what if she
becomes pregnant?
Also, I have heard...
...that you are not making
invitations to Madame du Barry.
Snubbing the king's favorite,
in your position...
...is extremely unwise.
- Du Barry is dreadful.
- Dreadful.
The way she dresses.
She thinks she is the queen.
Yes, she does.
And those ridiculous pet monkeys.
Where does she come from?
From every bed in Paris.
You know, we didn't think she'd last
long until she married the comte...
...and then he was conveniently
shipped away somewhere.
She doesn't stay
in the boudoir.
- She's political.
- Very.
And extremely anti-Choiseul.
And I don't want
to say this...
...but I don't think that she has
greeted you with respect.
That's just my opinion.
Ambassador Mercy says
I must pay her a visit.
Well, if we invited you to
tea at the last minute...
...you wouldn't be able to,
would you?
She died giving birth
to her tenth child.
What a pity.
- There was blood all over...
- Here comes our little Austrian.
- Good afternoon, madame.
- Good afternoon.
Good afternoon.
You look lovely.
Oh, thank you.
So do you.
Thank you.
Look at du Barry.
What is she wearing now?
Another one of her
exotic fantasies?
She can't pass a mirror
without seducing it.
Do you think she's wearing
enough jewelry?
Never enough for du Barry.
She's coming.
Oh, I love your shoes, Victoire.
Oh, why, thank you.
I got them from Christian in Paris.
- Oh, I must call on him.
- Yes, you must. He's wonderful.
Madame du Barry would like
to offer you some diamonds.
I have enough diamonds.
Snubbing the king's favorite is publicly
criticizing the king's behavior.
All you need do is say
a few words to her.
Because of rank she is not
allowed to speak first.
I certainly have nothing
to say to her.
Why should I approve of his
cavorting with a harlot?
- Your Royal Highness.
- Well, that's what she is.
Everyone knows she's from a brothel
and that title was bought for her.
Your mother and I
are very concerned.
Du Barry has been complaining to the
king that you will not address her.
And you cannot afford to fall
out of favor with the king.
Especially as your marriage...
...not exactly on solid ground.
Fine.
I'll talk to her.
There are a lot of people
at Versailles today.
Yes, there are.
Those are my last
words to that woman.
The first mechanical locks
were made of wood.
Records show them in use
some 4000 years ago in Egypt.
Any good fans?
That one's pretty.
- Evening or daytime?
- I like lace.
These are so du Barry.
- Do you like these for hair?
- It's beautiful.
- You don't think it's too much?
- Maybe one.
- One feather?
- Yeah.
Or in white?
Can we get these
in white, maybe?
I don't know if I like that one.
I love these.
Do you want these too?
Yeah, but in pink.
Oh, okay.
Two in pink.
Has madame read the brief
on our current situation?
No, I haven't read it yet.
Can you just tell me about it?
Well, the reforms in Poland by King
Poniatowski have led to civil war.
The Russians and the Austrians
have taken over a third of Poland...
...which is, of course,
distressing...
...as Poland is a friend
and ally of France.
Which sleeve do you like?
With ruffles or without?
Have you been paying
any attention?
Your mother is relying on you
to smooth over this crisis.
Where will I be if there's a rupture
between our two families?
Am I to be Austrian or
the dauphine of France?
You must be both.
- Well, I heard that
she bought a boy. - No.
Yes, I heard. She found a peasant
boy by the side of the street...
...and took him in
like a stray dog.
Well, it's not as if she
can have one of her own.
Maybe if she spent less
time with Lamballe...
...and more time
with her husband...
...there wouldn't be a problem.
Well, let's not forget
she is an Austrian spy.
And I can't imagine that's
very warm in the bedroom.
Come, my little truffle cake.
I'm going to ravage you.
- Will you come back right away?
- Yes, my sweet.
Just a quick hunting excursion,
we'll be back straightaway.
I will be humiliated before
the court and the public...
...if your brother's new wife
becomes pregnant before I do.
When I return from Saint-Cloud,
you can be sure...
...that I will resume my regime.
And hopefully everything
will go swimmingly.
I have absolutely no intention of
breaking the alliance with Austria.
I am very relieved to hear that,
Your Majesty.
But what on earth is going on
with that young couple?
It's a disaster.
Send for Dr. Lassonne
to visit them.
Yes, of course.
Do you find your
body responsive?
What?
Do you find your
body responsive?
What do you eat
for breakfast?
Hot chocolate.
Hello?
Hello, Yolande.
How lovely to see you.
Yes. This is the
Duchesse de Polignac.
- Hello.
- Your Majesty.
- We haven't seen you for a while.
- I know.
I've been in St. Petersburg,
where I met Dimitri.
Isn't he divine? Have you
ever been with a Russian?
- No, I...
- They're so bossy.
Look how fat the marquis's gotten.
Hope he doesn't break the chair.
Is he still sleeping with Camille?
Anyway, I must be off.
It was lovely to meet you.
Quiet.
Applause is not usually permitted
at court performances.
Why not?
It was wonderful.
Clap, clap.
Clap.
Dearest Antoinette:
I'm pleased to tell you how wonderful
your brothers and sisters are doing...
...in their marriages.
Maria Carolina is pregnant...
...expecting her
first child in June.
And Ferdinand is enchanted
with Beatrice...
...having made her
his wife at once.
All this news, which should
fill me with contentment...
...is diminished by reflections
on your dangerous situation.
Everything depends
on the wife...
...if she is willing and sweet.
I can't repeat enough...
...the importance for you to
employ charm and patience...
...never ill humor, to remedy
this unfortunate situation.
Remember, nothing is certain
about your place there...
...until an heir is produced.
- Excuse me.
- It's all right.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
- Good night.
Your Majesties are requested at the
delivery of Comtesse de Provence.
Bravo, bravo.
- Oh, wonderful!
- It's a healthy baby boy.
Oh, my God.
How happy I am.
Let me see my nephew.
The new Duc d'Angoulęme.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
It's the first Bourbon
prince of his generation.
He's so beautiful.
It's barren.
What do you expect?
When will you
give us an heir?
I hear she's frigid.
I like the pink.
It's like candy.
This is wonderful.
I love this.
Oh, it's a classic.
Could we get some
more champagne?
Monsieur Léonard.
Ravishing.
Oh, Léonard.
You're the best.
- It's not too much, is it?
- No.
We should all go to Paris
for the masked ball.
We're not allowed to go
without a formal reception.
Well, if it's a masked ball...
...no one would have to know,
would they?
Sorry.
Which way?
Come on.
Excuse me.
Where do you come from,
monsieur?
Versailles.
And has the dauphin
done the deed yet?
What?
Has the dauphin deflowered
the dauphine?
- Excuse me? - I'd love to
do the honors, you know.
Doesn't interest me.
Cheers.
Look at that sword.
I'd like to see what
he could do with that.
Oh, who's he talking to?
Hideous dress
she's wearing.
Pretend you're having
a really good time.
Have fun.
- Do I know you?
- No. I don't think so.
Are you making any
progress with her?
Possibly.
Are you going to tell
me who you are?
Are you?
Count Fersen of
the Swedish army.
Count Fersen.
That's the dauphine.
We must go. It's half past
three in the morning.
No. Let's just stay
a little longer.
- Oh, please. Let's go. Come on.
- Please, please.
Finally.
Do you know of
Count Fersen?
Yes!
Count Fersen, of course.
Beatrice de la Falaise was
with him last summer.
He's got quite a reputation,
you know.
Comtesse de Sevigny.
She was with him too.
Good morning.
- What is it?
- The king has fallen ill.
Is it serious?
Smallpox.
He doesn't have long.
You know, we cannot take his
confession while he has a mistress.
It will be taken care of.
Madame du Barry...
...I'm sick and know
what I have to do.
Rest assured...
...I shall always...
...have the most tender
feelings of friendship for you.
Bring me du Barry.
She is gone, Your Majesty.
The king is dead.
Long live Louis XVI.
Your Majesties,
I am at your loyal service.
Dear God, guide us and protect us.
We are too young to reign.
May God crown you
with a crown of glory.
How marvelous.
Here are two for
me and the queen.
Happy birthday, darling!
One, two, three.
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, darling.
Eighteen. Happy birthday.
Big stakes!
Come on now!
That one.
That one's for me.
What's coming?
Amazing.
Here are two.
So pretty!
Oh, Léonard.
Thank you.
Okay, come round
to the salon.
Speak to le beau Julian.
- First. And then you'll see me.
- Marvelous!
I've heard he
likes men as well.
No. No.
It's not true.
Do you want some cherry?
I love your hair.
What's going on there?
Everything.
- It's fantastic.
- It's full of secrets.
You're winning, I hope.
Madame, it's quite late.
I think it's time for the
dealers to return to Paris.
You said we could play but you
never specified for how long.
- You're worthless.
- I won again!
- Give me my chips.
- How'd you get so good at this?
- Good night.
- Oh, no. Don't go to sleep.
We're gonna watch the sunrise.
Don't you want to see that?
I'd rather get some
much-needed sleep.
Have you ever
watched the sunrise?
When I rise early for
the hunt, my dear.
- That doesn't count.
- It's your turn.
Try not to lose
our whole fortune.
On a roll.
I'm taking off.
That's impressive.
That is very impressive.
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Spin with me!
Wait!
Come along.
Come on. Come on, people.
Move, move, move.
Isn't that the most beautiful
thing you've ever seen?
- Happy birthday.
- Cheers. For the birthday girl.
To the new day.
And the next one.
I think I have a fly
in my champagne.
I would like to plant oaks
all along these paths.
How long will that take?
It will take two weeks to get them,
but they will be quite small.
What if I want
them that size?
It will take at least
three years.
- Three years?
- Yes.
Well, can't they bring
in bigger ones?
Well, I can see.
Your Majesty, you have spent
over 50,000 already this month.
There is nothing left
to go to your charities.
Your Majesty? Léonard is
here to fit your new wigs.
All right.
I'll get the small trees.
And I'll ask Louis for the money
for the Young Mothers' Fund.
The Americans are asking
for help in their revolution.
Well, I can't exactly
see assisting those...
...who are rejecting
their sovereign.
But it would make a strong
statement to England.
Can our finances
take the strain?
Oh, taxes will be
raised slightly.
I recommend we help
our American brothers...
...and show the rest of
Europe our strength.
All right, then.
Send funds to America.
Madame, your brother, the emperor,
is in the salon waiting for you.
He's here?
Thank you.
Have you come
to take me home?
Unfortunately, I can't
kidnap the queen of France.
Is your hair quite
tall enough today?
Maybe you can keep a
pet in there or something.
The emperor of China
sent me this tea.
Watch the flower.
Isn't it divine?
Yes.
It's jasmine.
As your brother, I have to lecture
you about your constant gambling...
...and choice of friends,
like the Duchesse de Polignac.
Do you think she's the proper
lady-in-waiting for a queen?
But she's fun.
She makes me laugh.
And your constant parties.
I mean, they can hardly leave
you enough time to spend...
...alone with your husband.
I'm sure our mother
has worried you.
Yes.
Well, of course she has.
I think I'm gonna
talk to young Louis.
Magnificent.
We have a female elephant
in our Austrian menagerie.
Well, perhaps we could
arrange a marriage.
So...
...I thought we could have a little
talk about the marriage bed.
The doctor said I was fit.
Good.
What goes on exactly?
I understand you have a
certain passion for locks.
Yes.
Well, sometimes when
a key doesn't quite fit...
The problem is only that
the king and queen of France...
...are complete blunderers.
There's nothing really
wrong with Louis XVI.
Everything works,
just not at the right time.
I think after our conversation,
the great work will be accomplished.
Very warm in here.
I can't even believe
she's getting enough air.
Is it a boy?
It's a girl, look.
She's unconscious.
We must get her air.
Please, the queen needs air.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Get back. Back.
Get back, please.
Everybody, please.
Get back.
Oh, he's beautiful.
You are adorable.
It's a girl.
Poor little girl.
You are not what was desired,
but you are no less dear to me.
A boy would be
the son of France...
...but you, Marie Thérčse,
shall be mine.
Come look.
Oh, she's so small.
Look at her hands.
I would like to
feed her myself.
But, madame,
we have the nurse for that.
And you know, it's not a good
idea in your fragile condition.
Madame.
May I present you with your
new retreat, the Petit Trianon.
Thank you.
I want something
more simple. Natural.
To wear in the garden.
Are you getting food for the little lamb?
Let's feed the lamb.
Marie Thérčse, come here.
You do it. You do it.
You feed the lamb.
Little lamby.
Beautiful.
What is this?
It's an egg.
Welcome to my little village.
I love it here.
- Really special.
- It's my heaven.
- Hello.
- Sweet.
Oh, look, the chickens
are out. Fabulous.
Oh, the lilies look
so beautiful.
- It's heavenly.
- Hello.
Come on, you little chickens.
Come on, little chickens!
Oh, look at those little things.
Hello!
That one's named after me.
Oh, this is my favorite, all the
fresh herbs. They smell so good.
You've got to brush the dirt off a bit,
but they're quite clean after that.
Oh, we must do this more often.
I love the country.
Where'd you get this from?
- Wait till you try this milk.
- Oh, what beautiful porcelain.
- How lovely.
- That one's very good.
One of these.
You must try the milk.
Thank you.
Rousseau says:
"If we assume man has been
corrupted by an artificial civilization...
...what is the natural state?
The state of nature from
which he has been removed?
Imagine wandering up
and down the forest...
...without industry,
without speech...
...and without home. "
Let's get a blue flower.
Beautiful.
No, I think perceived austerity
must be encouraged...
...but I'm afraid the queen has a
somewhat artistic temperament...
...which needs nourishing.
May I speak to you?
Yes.
Excuse me, Father.
We have not received any
invitation by the queen...
...which is customary
to our rank.
I'm afraid the queen is not well
enough for formal entertaining...
...but I will speak with her,
madame.
But...
How can we be expected
to live in a place...
...without any certainty
of our position?
I don't understand.
The Duchesse de Char
was very angry.
But this is my escape
from all the protocol.
Raumont, amongst others,
was complaining.
Well, we'll invite them to the
theater for my first performance.
- We'll need an audience.
- Splendid.
Bravo!
And in the end, I don't
know how they go out.
- It's always raining there.
- Not like here. It's always raining.
They are cheerful,
I must admit.
There's someone to see you.
Oh, who?
Good afternoon!
You've come to pay me a visit.
How gallant you are.
- Have you seen Marie Thérčse today?
- She's been married off.
Can't we at least wait
until she's talking?
If you insist.
Come home. We're having a ball for
the soldiers who fought in America.
I will.
I hope there are some
handsome generals.
They've been away from women
a long time, you know.
May I also present Comte d'Estaing.
Excellent victory on the capture
of Grenada. Excellent.
Congratulations.
Your Majesty, may I present
Colonel Smythe.
May I also present Count Fersen.
Count Fersen.
Pleasure's all mine.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
- What is this?
- It's a wild strawberry.
Try it.
It's quite exquisite.
Honestly! "The Marriage of Figaro".
You'd love it.
The servants take
over the house.
It's superb.
The women were carrying the
verses around on their fans.
Best thing I've seen for years.
You enjoyed it, didn't you?
I think we saw it together.
It was over three hours.
Far too long for me.
- Cheers, everybody.
- To the queen.
To our queen.
Have a good evening.
And to Raumont for
bringing the oysters.
To Raumont for the oysters.
And to Lamballe for
bringing the flowers.
For the flowers,
beautiful flowers.
And to Fersen for coming
all the way from Sweden.
- Yes.
- To Sweden.
All the way from Sweden.
That is a very long journey,
I must say.
- How long was it?
- Took about ten days.
Yes, ten days is
a very long time.
Personally, I can't travel
that much myself.
- Far too long.
- I must show you this trick.
Everybody, lick your finger and then
rub it around the rim of the glass.
Beautiful.
- A horrible sound.
- Oh, come on. It's like angels.
- It's like angels.
- It's very pretty.
It is pretty, isn't it?
It's very spiritual,
really, isn't it?
When was the last time
you went to Mass?
- Of sorts.
- I haven't seen it.
Ask another question.
- I can ask another question?
- Yeah.
Am I a male?
- No.
Partially.
That's terrible.
Oh, that's so mean.
My turn, it's my turn.
Am I a woman?
Am I a soldier?
- Do I write music?
- Yes.
Am I a vegetable?
- Yes. Good question.
- Yes.
Am I...
...from the ancient world?
- Am I here?
- No.
No, thank God.
Am I...
...present now?
- Yes.
- Yes, always.
- Am I...?
- You're very talented.
- Am I Alexander the Great?
- Yes.
Is it Mozart?
- You saw!
- You've seen yours.
That's the second time
I've won as well.
- You saw that.
- There's something in the oysters.
Be careful, please.
But you should try
to visit America.
It's beautiful,
very different than France.
Our queen seems rather fond
of looking at Count Fersen.
Then you've not heard of the
Hasselhoff family singers?
No.
Well, he's easy on the eyes.
But don't you think she
favors him too clearly?
Just because it is not you?
Don't you think it would be
unbecoming to our queen...
...when he has quite
a reputation?
He amuses her,
and she likes to be amused.
There's nothing unregal
in that, monsieur.
- You must meet soldiers all the time.
- No, I don't.
You don't?
And then he took it out.
Just like that.
I said, "What do you think
you'll do with that, monsieur?"
Oh, good God,
don't act all innocent.
Please.
I could have told him exactly
what to do with it.
And what is that, darling?
Put it back in his trousers
where it belonged.
Lamballe, ladies and gentlemen,
is what we call a prude.
Better than a whore.
I wish I could go with you.
I should kidnap you.
Of course, you know the
one about the English letter.
Don't you want to go to Paris,
see the opera?
Your go.
I'm more comfortable
just to stay here.
We have everything we need.
I should talk to the priest.
No, that's inexcusable.
It is. It's dangerous
for her safety.
Goodness, a criminal
could come in here.
- Cheat.
- Conceivably her husband.
You know, I heard she's
not even really a duchess.
Yeah, it's all a front.
Her husband's a thief,
and he bought her title.
Is that what happened?
Really?
That's what I heard.
- How much did that cost?
- A fortune.
It would cost a fortune,
wouldn't it?
To buy a title?
Yes. At the court?
She shouldn't be allowed.
She should buy a new dress,
is what she should buy.
yeah, you're right.
Vaguely.
- What are you laughing at?
- Nothing.
May I be excused?
Yes, of course, madame.
I might go and ask her.
That way she'll tell us exactly.
Ask her about her family.
The problem of the debt
is grave, Your Majesty.
The people of France
are hungry.
Sending troops to America is costing
more than what we estimated.
But we can't let England win.
We must show our strength.
We will continue aid
to the Americans.
And when they went to the queen
to tell her her subjects had no bread...
...do you know
what she said?
Let them eat cake.
That's such nonsense.
I would never say that.
And here you're having an
orgy with quite a big group.
I think I'm here
sucking your toes.
Don't they ever tire of
these ridiculous stories?
They say you gave Thomas Jefferson
a special tour of your gardens.
Is Jefferson admiring
the royal bush?
- Oh, that's awful.
- Can't you do something?
I'm not going to
acknowledge it.
The French can be fickle...
...and Her Majesty would do
well to be more attentive.
Life is getting harder
for the people of France.
The bread shortage is grave.
Well, there must be something the
king can do to ease their sufferings.
Tell the court jeweler to
stop sending diamonds.
You don't need any diamonds,
do you?
- No.
- How pretty Madame Royale is.
I'm pleased you find me so.
Say thank you.
She is certainly
a daughter of France.
Oh, I know.
What's the matter?
Your mother has died.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, my brother, I am devastated
by the news of our mother's death.
You alone are left
to me in Austria...
...which is and will
always be so dear to me.
Remember we are your friends,
your allies.
I embrace you.
Madame, you have fulfilled our
wishes and those of France.
You are the mother
of a dauphin.
May I present the
dauphin of France.
What a joy.
The dauphin of France.
Hello. Why don't you hit
the ball over there?
Come on.
You're gonna hit it.
Your Majesty, the Bastille fortress
was stormed by an angry mob.
In view of the hatred felt for
the Duchesse de Polignac...
...thought to be the
queen's favorite...
...I would recommend that she
leave for the Swiss border.
I also must urge all of the princes
and princesses of the blood...
...to leave at once.
Yes, they must go.
I will stay.
Certainly the royal family must
find somewhere more secure.
Metz is one of the strongest
fortresses in Europe.
You will not be safe here.
I will see to it that my
mistresses are off at once...
...but my place is here
with my husband.
Goodbye.
Your Majesty, your immediate
return is requested.
There's a mob of hundreds...
...on their way in demand
of flour from their sovereign.
It would be more secure
to decamp to Rambouillet
- twice the distance from Paris.
- I will not be a fugitive king.
- It is too dangerous here.
- At least send the queen and children.
My place is at the king's side.
- The first of them have arrived
in town. - We will stay here.
Save the queen, madame.
They're coming to kill her.
Celine, don't be frightened.
Let's get the children.
Are you admiring
your lime avenue?
I'm saying goodbye.