If you really love me,
then let's make a vow...
right here, together...
right now.
- Okay?
- Okay.
All right.
Repeat after me...
I'm gonna be free.
And I'm gonna be brave.
I'm gonna be brave.
Good.
And the next one is...
I'm gonna live each day,
as if it were my last.
Oh, that's good.
You like that? Yeah. Say it.
I'm gonna live each day,
as if it were my last.
Fantastically.
Courageously.
With grace.
You don't have to
bubble-wrap everything.
It's not like you're moving
to the north pole.
Oh. That's not yours.
My father gave us that.
This is yours.
Remember this?
Oh, no.
Can we just do this
without any theatrics? Please.
- We should have some kind of ceremony.
- What?
You know, with the boys.
Some kind of thing, so,
they don't forget we were once...
What are you doing?
Richard?
Leave them alone.
- Do I look well to you guys?
- You should be in here packing.
Objectively speaking,
if you weren't my children...
would you think,
that guy looks okay?
He looks like a guy who might
have a wife and kids and stuff?
- Are you mad at us?
- Yeah, totally. I think you look good.
Okay, good.
Space, space, dash.
Is that a Bengal tiger?
I don't know.
Space, space, space.
Dash.
And in the dark of the night,
and it does get dark...
when I call a name...
When I call a name.
It'll be your name.
What's your name?
Never mind.
Let's go. Say it.
Let's go. Everywhere.
Everywhere. Even though...
Even though...
We're scared.
'Cause it's life...
It's life.
And it's happening.
It's really, really happening...
right now.
All right. Now let's kiss
to make it real, okay?
Okay.
So, how is your art project?
- Is it in the museum yet?
- No. That's not how it works.
You know, they have to know
about your work...
I would just march in there
and show it to them, you know?
No one is going to
live your life for you.
Okay. That's not
how it works, but okay.
So, how's Ellen?
Oh, she's wonderful.
I can't sleep at night
thinking about her.
I just wish,
I had met her 50 years sooner.
- Yeah.
- But then maybe I needed...
70 years of life...
to be ready
for a woman like Ellen.
This rug is dirty.
Everyone get a box
on the way out.
Ow. Ow. Stop kicking me.
Ow. Stop kicking me!
You know, some kids don't even have
one home. Now you get to have two.
Think about that.
What I don't get was how angry Pam was.
I didn't hurt anyone but myself.
- It's not like I robbed a bank.
- Yeah, or bombed a church.
Do you have this
in an eight and a half?
- I believe we do. I'll be right back.
- Thank you.
Or bombed a church.
In some cultures, when you burn
yourself it's a ceremony.
It's called self-immolation.
My uncle used to do it all the time.
It was a great trick.
He'd put the stuff on it and light it...
and it would just go out
when he went like this.
Right before I lit it,
I suddenly remembered...
it's alcohol that burns
but doesn't burn up.
Lighter fluid just burns.
And then I thought,
"It's okay. It's better this way."
I just think of it as part
of good service, you know?
No. No, we don't
touch the foot anymore.
If you notice, we spend
a lot of time touching the shoe...
lacing the shoe...
then we just put it on the ground
and watch you try to get your foot in.
We can hand you tools...
a shoehorn, a nylon sock...
but we will never
touch your foot with our hands.
Now, I'll tell you what I can do.
I can press on the shoe
to see if it fits.
- I can go like this.
- Yeah, do that.
- How does that feel on the toe?
- Good.
Good. Why don't you
walk around in them?
- Did you want to try these on?
- No, I'm just driving him.
- So those are comfortable?
- I guess so.
I mean, they kind of rub my ankles,
but all shoes do that.
I have low ankles.
You think you deserve
that pain, but you don't.
- I don't think I deserve it.
- Well, not consciously maybe.
My ankles are just low.
People think foot pain
is a fact of life...
but life is actually better than that.
I'll say.
You should get some.
Your whole life could be better.
Starting right now.
I can't believe I got these shoes.
And they're exactly like my old shoes,
except they're pink.
I don't need these,
and they're not orthopedic.
But you seemed to believe
everything he said.
Yeah. I think he really knew his stuff.
He was very professional.
See, that's how gullible you are.
- You know, you meet somebody...
- Christine.
Oh, God.
Roll down your window.
We have to tell him.
No. If he stops, it'll fall off.
Even if he slows down, it'll fall.
The best thing
for that fish would be...
if he could just drive
steadily... forever.
I guess these are
his last moments of life.
Shall we say some words?
I didn't know you...
but I want you to die
knowing that you were loved.
I love you.
Hey. It was on your roof!
We'll go in front of you!
- Pull in front of him.
- Okay.
We've got to keep him
at a steady speed.
Just keep them steady.
Oh, God. That little girl
is gonna have to watch it.
But at least they know.
At least we're
all together on this.
When me and Pam
were first in love...
we hated to be apart,
even for an hour.
Oh, yeah.
I had something like that once.
- A real fuck-a-thon.
- We just slept.
We loved to sleep
when it was time to sleep.
Not sex.
I mean, we had sex...
but what we really loved
was to sleep like babies all day long.
That sounds perfect.
I don't want to have to do this...
this living.
I just walk around.
I want to be swept off my feet,
you know?
I want my children
to have magical powers.
I am prepared for amazing things
to happen. I can handle it.
Ellen.
Guess who's joining the Olympics?
- Guess who's joining the Olympics?
- Who?
- Me.
- Really?
- How is the love of my life?
- Can I borrow this?
Of course.
Which one is that?
Ohh. My granddaughter
and her boyfriend who won't marry her...
are going to become art.
That's a limited access floor.
You need a swipe card.
Oh. I'll just get off on two then.
You want the offices?
- Actually, are you Nancy Herrington?
- Yes.
Okay. 'Cause I wanted
to show you my art.
I brought this tape
I thought we could watch.
Okay. Why don't
you send it to this address.
Oh, but that's here.
Can't I just hand it to you?
It'll get lost.
It's better if you send it.
But I'm so close.
Okay. Do I need
the thing to get out?
Oh, great, you're here.
Let's go down.
Look at this.
Wow, that's amazing.
Were you able to talk to Patrick
about the maintenance?
Yeah, we spoke this morning.
Well, it really is amazing.
It just looks so real.
Like this wrapper. It looks like
a real hamburger wrapper.
- Oh, that wrapper is real.
- What?
Yeah. I always throw in
a few real things.
Kind of cast a glow
over the plaster objects.
You know, kind of
bump it all up a notch.
Did you do this at the MoMA show?
Were there real things
in that show, or...
Oh, yeah. Course.
This is mine. You got it
from the staff kitchen.
No, I made that.
This stuff is really good for your skin.
It has like all these minerals in it.
- Let me see!
- Let me just finish!
- It doesn't match at all.
- It will. Let me just finish.
My skin is way lighter than yours.
Okay. Just wait. You'll see.
I just have to do your whole face first.
- What are...Where are you going?
- I don't have to come in till 2:00.
- Oh, see you at 2:00 then.
- Okay. See ya.
Guy at 1:00.
Not cute. Say hi.
Hi.
- That doesn't match your skin color.
- I know.
It doesn't.
Do you want me to finish, or do you
want me to leave it how it is?
Are you guys like girlfriends?
Maybe.
You look like
you could be sisters.
- Maybe we're sisters and girlfriends.
- Yeah, that'd be pretty cool.
But that's pretty unlikely.
- How old are you guys anyways?
- Eighteen.
I'm 18. She's 17.
- I turn 18 next week.
- Yeah, I'd really love to believe you.
I really would, because I don't even
have to go to work this morning.
I would love to believe
in a universe...
where you wake up
and you don't have to go to work...
and you step outside and meet
two beautiful 18-year-old sisters...
who are also girlfriends...
and... are also very nice people.
You guys seem
like very nice people.
We are nice.
What would you do...
if you believed we were 18,
which we are?
Well, I can't even tell ya.
- I can't tell you till you're 18.
- That's not true.
What about freedom of speech
and the Constitution?
- What are you talkin' about?
- Free speech.
Okay. Well, I don't know
what you're talking about...
but I can't talk dirty to you...
because then I'd be a pervert...
and probably even
a pedophile too, so...
- No one has ever talked dirty to us.
- Really?
Sounds very appealing.
I'm gonna go inside now.
Okay. We'll wave to you.
- Make sure to look.
- I will.
- Oh, he's probably jerking off.
- Oh, my God!
He is. You can so tell he is.
- How?
- I can feel it.
See that crack?
That's where his hard-on is.
Let's kiss.
Okay.
- Are my little chickies still hungry?
- Yes.
Peep. Okay, worm check.
Open up. Are there any worms
left in there?
You live next door to me.
- No, I don't.
- I saw you moving in.
You have a white dad
and a big brother.
Your whole family lives
in one of those little apartments?
Do you all have to sleep
in the same bed?
My mom lives somewhere else.
You should get a Hide-a-bed.
During the day it's a couch...
but at night it folds out into
a comfortable queen-sized bed.
You want to be a little bird
and get a little worm?
Just lie down and peep.
Peep, peep, peep.
Are you following us?
Yeah, quit following us,
Peter Swersey!
If you don't stop following us,
I'm gonna scream!
If you take another step towards me,
I'm going to kick you in the throat!
Hey, come here.
Ask her if she likes bologna.
What are you putting?
I asked her what kind
of "bossom" she had.
- It's probably a man.
- Why is it a man?
'Cause everyone just
makes stuff up on these things.
It's probably a man
pretending to be a woman.
So picture a fat guy
with a little wiener.
- What's a "bossom"?
- It's a nice word for titties.
- Where's Mom?
- What do you mean?
What do you think
she's doing right now?
I don't know. Screwing
her new boyfriend probably.
- I think she's buying us presents.
- Yeah, Robby.
Right now she's probably
buying us each a car!
- It's a man.
- I think it's a woman. I can tell it is.
What should we write?
"I have a big wiener"?
I want to poop back and forth.
What? What does that mean?
Like, I'll poop into her butt hole...
and then she'll poop it back...
into my butt hole.
And then we'll just
keep doing it back and forth...
with the same poop.
Oh, my God.
I'm going to put that!
"I want to poop...
back and forth."
Oh, God. She's gonna think
we're a crazy, perverted person.
- Ooh! She thinks we're crazy!
- No, tell her like how I said it.
No, she'll never write back. We have to
sound like we're a man, you know?
That's just lame. It's stupid.
But you said I could do half,
and you've done all of them before this.
Whatever. We're probably gonna
get arrested. What do you want me to put?
Like how I said it.
"I'll poop in your butt hole...
and then you will poop it back...
into my butt...
and we will keep doing it"...
- Back...
- And forth...
With the same poop.
Same poop.
Forever.
Wow, look at these beds!
You don't have to make the beds.
I'll make 'em when I get home from work.
Where'd you learn
to make corners like that?
It's just the way we like it.
Really? I thought you preferred
the rumpled, unkempt look.
- We like it this way now.
- Yeah.
At Mom's house,
we have a chore wheel.
- What?
- Nothing.
A chore wheel.
You put chores on it,
and then you can spin it.
There's this metal thing...
and it helps it to spin.
It's spinning from the metal.
Okay. Well...
So, it's just a half shift.
I'll be back in four hours, and
we'll go do something fun, okay?
Okay.
- This in an eight and a half.
- Nothing for Sylvie?
No.
We don't have the coral
in an eight and a half.
So I brought the taupe
and the black.
And this is a similar style
in ivory with a strap.
Oh, I don't want the strap.
I didn't think you would.
I just wanted you to see it.
Yeah, I would just
feel silly with the strap.
I'm a grown woman.
Well, sure. But I'm
contractually obligated...
to at least try to sell you shoes.
How are the boys?
Are you guys all settled in there?
My boys are great.
They're great at being boys.
Kids are so adaptable.
- Am I adaptable?
- Yes.
Yes, well...
they have absolutely no control
over their own lives, so...
But if things were reversed...
you know,
like that movie Freaky Friday...
you can be sure Pam and I would be sent
to our rooms for all our fighting.
Yes, they would give us a time-out...
and tell us we could not come out until we
had really thought about what we had done.
What have we done?
But... there are no time-outs.
There's not enough time
for time-out.
Is the sale just for clothes,
or is it for other things too?
It's a storewide sale.
Fifteen minutes, Sylvie.
How do they feel?
Where are the Braun
handheld blenders...
that were advertised
in the Sunday supplement?
- Is it a classic instrument?
- What?
Is it timeless, or is it likely
to go out of style in the next 20 years?
I would say it's a new classic.
But 20 years is a long time.
I think everything's gonna be
computerized in 20 years.
- Soup won't be computerized.
- Why not?
It's a liquid.
Dude, did you just give her
the family discount?
Yeah. She's my neighbor.
I'm trying to work on my karma.
- Do you know what karma means?
- Yeah.
It means that she owes me one.
I love you.
I'm not following you.
My car's parked over there.
- In Smart Park?
- No, on Front Street.
Oh, I parked in Smart Park.
So, at the end of the next block
we'll separate. At Tyrone Street.
Yeah, the "Ice Land" sign is halfway.
It's the halfway... point.
Ice Land is...
It's kind of like that point
in a relationship, you know...
where you suddenly realize
it's not gonna last forever.
You know, you can
see the end in sight.
Tyrone Street.
Yeah, but we're not even there yet.
We're still at the good part.
We're not even sick of each other yet.
I'm not sick of you at all.
And wow! It's been a good
like six months, right?
What? Six months?
Then the Ice Land sign
is like eight months?
You think we'd only last
a year and a half?
I don't know. I don't
want to be presumptuous.
- I don't know if you're married or what.
- I'm not.
Well, I'm separated.
We separated last month.
I was thinking...
that Tyrone...
was like 20 years away at least.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Okay. Well, actually
I was thinking...
Tyrone is, like,
when we die of old age.
And this is, like, our whole life
together, this block.
See, that's perfect.
- Let's do it that way.
- Okay.
Well, guess it can't be avoided.
Everyone dies.
I could walk you to your car.
Maybe we should just be glad...
that we lived this long,
good life together.
You know, it's so much more
than most people ever get to have.
- Okay.
- Well, don't be afraid.
- Here we go.
Richard! Hi.
Hi. I thought your car
was over here.
It is. It's down there.
You could give me a ride to it.
Doesn't that break
the rules of the thing?
This can be like the afterlife.
You know,
like we're angels or something?
Cute.
What are you doing in my car?
No, I don't know you, and you certainly
don't know anything about me.
I mean, what if I'm a killer
of children?
Yeah. Well, that would put a damper
on things, wouldn't it?
See, you're acting like
I'm just this regular man.
Like a man in a book
who the woman in the book meets.
I'm not doing that.
Did I just invite myself into your car?
Is that what I just did?
- Well, I'm sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- You should be.
Good. Terrific.
Can you get out of my car now?
Okay.
- Did you bring back my photo?
- Oh, no.
I'm not done with it yet.
I'm still in the brainstorming stage.
Well, if you get stuck,
you should enlist Michael.
He's got creativity
just rolling off of him.
Yeah, I always work alone.
I'm a solo artist.
Of course.
She's still brainstorming.
Yeah. It's like this
complicated process that...
So, tell Ellen about the shoe guy.
Did you go back to the store?
Yeah. And turns out
he's a killer of children.
So, oh, well.
What? Why does he say
"the tall one"?
- Because he wants me to do it.
- He's crazy.
You'd leave teeth marks all over it.
You'd choke on it.
He could see that I have
a sensuous mouth.
This is crazy. Someone
should call in the authorities.
Obviously, I would do it better.
We need an impartial authority.
Hey, Peter!
Peter Swersey.
We are going to give you
a "jimmy ha-ha."
- Do you know what that is?
- Yeah.
No, you don't.
'Cause I just made it up.
Don't you want
a warm, wet jimmy ha-ha?
No.
You live there? Cool.
I'm gonna live in an apartment.
Next year, maybe.
- Yeah, right.
- I am.
My sister's gonna get a loft apartment,
and she said I could live with her.
She won't even let you
sit in her car.
- Can we come in?
- Yeah, can we come in? We'll be good.
Go eat it outside, Robby.
Okay! I just need to
put on my jacket.
- Can we see your parents' room?
- My parents are separated.
My dad sleeps there.
He'll be home, like, any second.
We're each going to do it, and you
have to tell us what the difference is.
Like, how it feels different,
when she does it from when I do it.
Exactly.
Thank you, Rebecca.
You're welcome, Heather.
- But first we need a towel and...
- And a washcloth.
Right. A wet washcloth
and a dry washcloth.
And something sweet,
like a cookie or a piece of candy.
- And a CD player.
- And a Cody Chesnutt CD.
I don't have that CD.
Uh-oh. That's our favorite music.
So I guess we can't do it.
Oh, but look.
- I have it.
- Go get the stuff.
Don't forget the towel,
the washcloths or the cookie.
- Or candy.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Hey. Ready to do this?
- I am.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Yeah, we're good.
Okay, here are the rules.
You have to keep this pillow
on your face. You can't watch us.
- Okay.
- You can't touch us.
You can't touch our heads.
And we're not going to touch each other.
And you have to tell us
when you're going to "scooch."
- Okay.
- So, take off your pants.
Okay, I'm going to wash it.
So put the pillow on now.
Now person number one
is going to go.
Might be me.
Might be Rebecca.
- Okay, you go.
- I don't want your cooties. Wipe it off.
Okay. Person number two...
citizen two is beginning now.
Get away.
- Can I have the washcloth?
- The wet one or the dry one?
The dry one.
So, what was the difference?
Yeah, who was better...
number one or number two?
You were exactly the same.
I couldn't tell the difference.
As far as everything goes
with you, Jim...
Are you guys all packed
for your mom's?
Yeah.
- What's that?
- Dave planted it.
What a romantic guy.
I'm in here. Come in.
Okay. Well, I'm off.
I'm just brushing my teeth.
God, I used to
hate that nightgown.
Other people have to look at it,
but they can't read it.
That's the point.
Self-affirming.
Well, so you really need
that written on your chest?
You don't already know it?
No, I don't already know
I'm a precious, wondrous...
special, unique, divine,
rare, valuable, whole...
sacred, total, complete, entitled,
worthy and deserving person.
I don't know that.
Menswear is the other
side of the escalator.
- Over here?
- Yeah.
Hi.
Do you have any glue?
- Oh, we have Shoe Goo.
- Yeah, that might work.
We have to hold this
for one to two minutes.
So, how's the separation going?
Or was that temporary?
Maybe even momentary?
No, we're really separated.
But we have two kids.
Okay. How old are they?
It's a real madhouse in here.
It's 'cause of the sale we're having.
Well, go if you need to go.
How did you do that?
Oh, well, do you want
the long version or the short version?
The long one.
I was trying to save my life,
and it didn't work.
What's the short one?
I burned it.
And when do you get to take that off?
I don't know.
I think when it stops hurting.
Let's give it another 15 seconds.
Do you want to sit down... together
sometime, like with coffee or something?
Yeah.
Well, if you ever feel too old to drive,
just call that number.
I can't hear you.!
Is she of color?
And do you love me?
No. But she's a woman.
Even though I am
sometimes irritating?
And a little bit selfish.!
Oh, her.
Even when I forget to ask you
how your day was?
Yeah, okay. Didn't we already
show a local person this year?
I don't think she's ready.
Let's go to slides.
I really do love you...
All right, what we need
to ask ourselves...
about each one of these is:
Could this have been made
in any era, or only now?
- Are you listening?
- Yeah.
Okay, what does this tell us
about digital culture?
I don't think this tells us
anything about digital culture.
I think you're right.
Let me guess.
This one's about AIDS.
Yeah, it's not really on the theme, right?
And we already have photography.
You know, we have
those photos and e-mails.
E-mail wouldn't even exist
if it weren't for AIDS.
Fear of contamination.
Fear of bodily fluids.
I need a break.
Let's take a break.
Okay. Okay, I'll get him.
Richard.
Why don't you walk around
in those and see how they feel.
- It's Peter.
- Hello?
Oh, no. Really?
Well, did you call your mom?
Oh, right. Damn.
Well, can you make it through the day,
Petey? Are you barfing?
Okay. Okay, let's see here.
I don't get off until 6:00, and we
are just slammed here. It's a sale day.
But don't worry.
Someone will come and get you.
This is why we have neighbors.
We're part of a community, Peter.
Does your mom make you do that?
No, this is my own towel.
I bought it with my own money.
I have the whole set.
See, this is the bath sheet...
and this is the hand towel...
and this is the washcloth.
- Isn't the washcloth cute?
- Yeah.
When they hang on the rack,
they go like this.
I only have one set...
but I think I'm going to get
the other two for Christmas.
What is all that stuff?
When I get married, all this stuff will
belong to my husband and my daughter.
Everything I have here
will be theirs.
All of it. It's my dowry.
This is called a hope chest.
Or trousseau in French.
So Peter was barfing?
I asked the neighbor
woman to go get him.
It's like how they say it takes
a village to raise a child.
If you'll excuse me,
this is a private call.
So Robby's old enough
to walk home alone?
Shit lords!
There's no answer.
Robby loves to answer the phone.
If he was there, he'd be answering it.
Maybe Peter went out
looking for Robby.
Yeah, see, this is why you don't
want a village raising your kid...
because there's sketchy
parts of the village...
and some of the villagers
are junkies and child molesters.
I gotta go. Tell Sven that
Robby's missing and I had to go.
Thanks for calling.
For customer service or furniture
or mattress delivery inquiries, press 4.
For bridal registry, press 6.
- Mann res...
- Is Robby here?
- Mann residence. May I help you?
No. If you didn't know me,
would you think I was really this tall...
or would you think I was
standing on something?
You're here. Jesus Christ!
- Why didn't you guys answer the phone?
- I was online.
Well, no more Internet when I'm not here.
I have to be able to call you.
Maybe you should buy
us cell phones.
No. Just stay off the fucking computer
when I'm not here!
You can't make us stay off
the computer if you're not here.
- You won't be here to keep us off it!
- It's for safety!
- How did you get home?
- I walked.
What is your dad watching?
It looks like Nickelodeon.
- Don't look at my dad.
- Sorry.
If he puts up another sign,
I think we should go up there.
I mean, what else can happen?
Just more signs? Signs forever?
I always thought I'd lose it with someone
who was my boyfriend or something.
But this is better...
'cause it won't matter if we mess up.
And we'll be together.
But I'm trying to change.!
All right.
This song is for you,
and, yes, it is a love song.
Hi, Nancy Herrington.
So this morning, if you remember,
you had asked me to send you my work.
And that was it, what you just
watched. Did you love it?
I'm just kidding.
I can see why you don't do this
face to face. It can be very awkward.
Hi.
And then you'd say...
"Hi. How was your day?"
Oh, me? I had a really
weird day, actually.
And now I'm here...
alone in my apartment.
You're probably in your big house...
with your family...
and your dog.
And probably your dog
has a family too.
You're probably all gathered
around the fire singing carols...
even though it isn't Christmas.
Just for fun.
You will never, ever see this...
because you'll never watch
this far on the tape.
You'll probably never
even watch the tape, will you?
I could do anything right now.
If you are watching this...
then just call this number, okay?
Just call this number,
the number you see on your screen...
and say "macaroni."
Okay? That's all you have to do.
Just "macaroni" and hang up.
No questions asked.
I thought we'd have
breakfast for dinner.
And then maybe sometime
we'll have dinner for breakfast.
Just to mix things up a little.
But there's still
ice cream for dessert.
It's fine with me if you guys want
to continue this silent treatment.
It's like a Zen retreat for me.
- Can I see it?
- I didn't use the book. I made it up.
- What is it?
- It's people seen from above.
From the sky.
See, these are people walking.
That's a person lying down.
And that's a person standing up
next to a person lying down.
This is me...
and you...
and everyone we know.
Where is Dad?
r
i
n
Come on. Come on.
g
We have a whole life
to live together, you fucker!
But it can't start until you call.
- Eldercab.
- Macaroni.
This can't be a regular thing. Tell them
that you can't come in before 9:00.
It's not a regular thing. Last week
I had to leave early one day...
Why did you have to leave early?
Is everything okay?
Honey, go back to bed.
Was it the boys?
No. Jesus! I have
a personal life, you know.
Oh, okay.
So I'll take them for longer next week.
But you have 'em this whole week...
because Dave and I are going
to the coast until Saturday, okay?
- Is that not okay?
- It is, but I might have a date.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Should I cancel our trip so you can go
on the date you might have?
No, obviously you should go.
- What's that sound?
- I don't know, Rob.
- You should be in bed.
- Mom?
That always happens at this time.
You just were never up this early.
It's the lights, Robby.
See these street lights?
They're run by a big computer
that tells them when to go on and off.
That's what that sound is.
So, for the purpose of this role-play,
Shamus is holding a grenade.
The juice is a grenade, so the worst thing
we can do is act afraid.
Because Shamus is already scared,
and he's taking his cues from us.
We will want to exit
in an orderly fashion...
telling Shamus with our actions...
that he cannot get our attention
in this inappropriate manner.
Hey. Hi.
So, do you have anything new in the chest?
You know, the hope chest?
- What's the hope chest?
- It's... nothing.
I don't know,
what you're talking about.
Ellen broke up with me.
What? Why?
She thinks she's
gonna die this week.
No. Out of everyone at Saint Tod,
she is the least likely person to die.
Well, she's usually right.
She's been right about everyone else.
I lived a whole life with a woman
I didn't even really like.
We traveled
all over the world together.
And Ellen and I,
never even left the grounds.
Well, actually I took you
to the IMAX that one time.
Yeah, but I wanted to take her
to the Mayan ruins in Guatemala.
She really wanted to see those.
Yeah, that just seems weird that
she wouldn't want to be with you...
you know,
if her time was coming.
I've long since stopped
trying to make people...
do things they don't want to do.
But she's the love of your life.
You're just gonna let her go?
No. She's just... going.
I can't get you out of my mind.
You're everything I've ever wanted.
Wild dogs couldn't
drag me away from you.
Do you realize he's six?
He said he walked down Burnside.
I don't even walk down Burnside alone.
I am totally and
completely in the wrong.
I'll call you.
When's a good time?
I thought you might be interested
in buying this talking picture frame.
- I love you.
- Yeah, it's really convenient.
You can just
carry it around with you.
And the next time you need to say "I love you,"
you can just press the button.
Yeah.
Could save you
a lot of energy, you know?
But, then, if you're planning
on saying "I love you" a lot...
you might have to change
the batteries.
They're double-A's.
Do you think you can handle that?
- Yeah.
- Good luck.
Fuck!
Fuck you! Fuck me!
Fuck old people!
Fuck children!
Fuck peace!
Fuck.
I'm taking off the bandage now,
if anyone wants to see.
It's so sensitive.
It needs air.
It needs to do some living.
Let's take my hand for a walk.
Talk to me.
So this is it? This is
the end of our relationship?
That makes me sad.
It really does.
Do you have questions
you wanna ask me?
Do you want advice
from your dad?
Ask me for advice on anything,
anything at all. Anything.
Okay, name a song.
I'll whistle it.
Any song.
Any song that I know.
"Every Stone Shall Cry."
- What?
- It's a hymn.
A hymn?
How do you know a hymn?
We learned it at school.
All right, let's hear it.
A stable lamp is lighted
Whose glow shall wake the sky
The stars shall bend their voices
And every stone shall cry
In praises of the child
By whose descent among us
The worlds are reconciled
Come in.
What's that?
It's something for the hope chest.
It's for your daughter.
So you've thought about
where you'll put everything?
Like the interior design?
Yes. Yes, I have, Peter.
If this was the kitchen...
I'd like there to be a little nook
right over there by the window.
Like the booth of a restaurant.
And there'd be an island
right where the light is hanging...
and the island
would have the stove in it...
and a countertop on one side
with tall stools under it.
My daughter would sit on a stool...
so I could talk to her while
I was making dinner or lunch.
What would you say to her?
I'd say...
"Hi, baby girl.
You are a precious treasure."
I'd live up there, if I could.
If there wasn't gravity.
Yeah.
But if you lived up there...
then all this stuff...
all this stuff in my room...
would fall down on you
and crush you...
and you'd die.
Ellen would have been so proud of you.
Isn't it amazing, Ellen?
Yes. I'm so glad
you took me here.
It was a whole civilization.
Two Mayan people in love...
probably stood right where
we're standing now and thought...
"Look what we have built together."
And now they're gone,
and so is the city.
And there's just... us.
I am done.
That was great.
- Eldercab.
- Hi.
- I'm feeling too old to drive.
- Yeah?
I didn't think you were going to...
feel that way.
I thought sometime you might want
to come over and meet my sons.
Can we do that right now?
Now as in "now"?
Yeah.
Oh, good. You're here.
You have to clean all this up.
Come on. Come on.
Go. Go. Go.
Put away all this stuff. All this stuff
needs to be put away somewhere.
No. Wait. You're right.
This is better. More kid-like.
Just play. Do whatever you normally do.
Just be kids. That's great.
Is that gonna fit in there?
No, I don't think so.
Maybe you can put it in there.
I guess not. It looked
like it would fit, but I guess not.
Wait. Wait. I know.
Put it under there.
What are you doing that for?
I'm just passing the time.