Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
CJ Entertainment presents
in association with CJ Venture
Investment Corp. Line Holdings Corp.
In association with Astech Venture
Investment Corp. (Milestone and Partners)
A Zininsa Film Production
Production Funding PARK Dong-ho
with LEE Yong-woo, LEE Jin-gyo
JUNG Jong-wook
Producer YANG Jung-kyung
PARK Sung-gun, LEE Sung-chan
Fund Management CHOI Pyung-ho
Funding planner CHOI Jun-whan
This camera is so old.
It's my father's
- How's your mom?
- Fine.
Can you wait, Jong-hyun?
WON Bin, SHIN Ha-gyun
How long?
Not too long.
The machine is busted.
I will wait.
There's no hurry.
KIM Hae-sook, LEE Bo-young
She was mild and naive.
He liked taking pictures.
They fell in love, got married
and had a baby.
But the birth of the baby
was not blessing.
She stopping going to church.
He stopped taking pictures.
He threw out the baby
without telling her
But she returned with her baby.
Afterward
He became weaker due to illness
and died.
Soon after, she realized that
she was pregnant.
She swore
not to be naive any more.
But to be strong
and raise the baby well.
In the following year
I was born.
Edited by KYUNG Min-ho
Location Editor PARK Kwang-il
Recording Engineer LEE Tae-kyu(BOB)
Sound supervisor KIM Suk-won(BLUECAP)
Music KIM Hyung-suk
Production designer JUN In-han
Title producer, CG RYU Hee-jung(MIX)
LEE Sung-suk, Art KANG Chang-gil(Chung-sol Art)
Illumination director SHIN Kyung-man
Photography director WHANG Ki-suk
Produced by CHUNG Hae-Suk
Written and Directed by AHN Kwon-Tae
My Brother
One, two, three, four, five
six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
This is right.
Don't miss out on payments.
Mom was a moneylender.
She took us around with her
when collecting interests.
I hated that.
Hello?
Du-sik's mom?
Du-sik was retarded.
They complained he
and my brother
gave the neighborhood
a bad name.
I couldn't blame them.
I'm a leech?
Pay on time then!
By next week!
Don't mess with me.
Bitch!
- You stinking...
- Shut your hole!
Let's go!
- Du-sik! Du-sik! Come here!
- Cover your ears.
Don't listen to her crap.
- You're getting us wet!
Nicknamed 'Money Ghost'
she made sure they paid
no matter what it took.
That hard-earned money...
Every penny was spent
on my brother's surgeries.
He's here, Doctor.
Wait for a second.
Not scared, are you?
Afterward
I'll buy you
whatever you want.
Anything you want!
Be brave, okay?
- It's okay.
- Operation is ready.
Don't worry a thing.
Mom.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
Can you buy me new shoes
if I have the surgery instead?
What greeted Sung-hyun
into the world was
a cold syringe needle
not mom's nipples.
It seemed so easy for others
but it took days for him
to nibble on her nipples.
He was hare-lipped.
Medically called a cleft palate
it's one of those congenital
malformations.
You're so silly.
It'll go away in a few days.
- Mother.
- What?
C- Can you m-make this
go away too?
No, I can't.
You know why?
It's a God-given token
for an angel.
It'll stay there forever.
Come here, baby.
My precious!
You're a good boy, Sung-hyun.
You listen to mom well.
You're good in class.
I always felt left out.
He had two more surgeries
afterwards.
As she had wished
we got into the same school.
He was a year older
but we were in the same class.
Die, son of a bitch!
Listen, assholes.
This is freaking tiring.
I'll take you on as a group
next time.
You heard him.
He'll take you all on...
Assholes!
Wait up, Jong-hyun.
Quiet, quiet!
We're from the Lit. Club.
We guarantee opportunities
to hook up with chicks.
Who's in?
Here!
I'm totally with you.
You look like a grandpa.
You sure you belong here?
Hey, you!
You have the look.
Join us.
Chicks are guaranteed.
- Go fuck yourself.
- Quit fooling around.
Who's KIM Sung-hyun?
You won the Essay Contest?
Join the club.
I- I am with another one.
Which one?
God damn it!
You're too noisy for me.
- Stop bullshitting
- I'm not!
Give it here.
What's this?
Trash!
You topped the class again, huh?
I bet that will make Mom
very proud.
You're good at studying.
And I'm good at fighting.
What a pair of brothers!
Knock it off!
Go ahead.
- M-Mother is w-waiting.
- I bet.
For your report card!
Sung-hyun, go home.
Go ahead.
Driver, can you hold a second?
Hurry! Come on!
Damn!
My heart almost stopped.
A knockout, huh? CHO Mi-ryung
from HyangDo Girl's High.
A pie in the sky though.
Why?
Her brother is a crazy ass.
Get near her
and you're done for.
Does Lit. Club ring a bell?
She's in the Lit. Club too?
- He is so cute! Isn't he?
- Yeah I saw him too!
- Isn't he a bully?
- He rules DongSung High.
He's so cute and
bully as well?
It will be so lucky
if I get to go out with him.
Give it a try.
Asako and I met three times.
We shouldn't have met
the third time.
I'm going to Chuncheon
this weekend.
It's breathtaking out there.
I might not be able to
see her ever again.
Missing her all my life...
- Ca... Can... Can't see
- Damn.
I've had it!
You either see her or not.
Who the hell is Asako?
Your squeeze?
It was a kick-ass dream.
I have to dream it again!
Why don't you get me one too?
An amulet that will get me
into college without studying.
This is good.
He's a well-known diviner.
He went to Seoul Nat'I University.
What a wasted degree!
It cost me an arm and a leg.
Try it on.
Here.
Gosh, you look great
with anything on.
So handsome!
- T-This is an expensive brand.
- It is!
I'm not eating!
I wish you had his character.
Hey.
Bring that Burberry jacket.
Jong-hyun, this isn't
the real thing.
I know!
You know what?
Genuine ones look fake on you
but fakes look genuine on me.
You got that?
Where are you going?
You don't need to know.
Hi.
I'm KIM Jong-hyun
from DongSung High.
On this beautiful Sunday
I'm honored to be here.
I hope we make some
kiss-ass memories together.
Especially on this side...
The fourth girl!
CHO Mi-ryung, right?
Mi-ryung.
Nice meeting you.
'Aspirin' by CHO Mi-ryung.
I chewed you, Aspirin
for I was sick.
Hidden in that bitterness is
a true confession.
Oh Head, please don't hurt.
I chewed you, Aspirin
for I had the flu.
Hidden in that bitterness is
a true confession.
It's a killer.
Oh Flu, please go away.
I chewed you, Aspirin
for I had cramps.
Hidden in that bitterness is
a woman's fate.
It's all about feelings.
Poets are mighty.
Mighty!
Look, got any poems
you've written?
No.
You're no help in my life!
Go back to your book.
I am your Aspirin.
Here.
Fair?
Look here.
What's this?
Why don't I get sausage too?
You know what?
You'd find food
on a dirt gravel road!
Jong-hyun!
You are beautiful.
Stop looking at the book.
Look at me.
Don't give me the cold shoulder.
Jerk!
Man, she called you a jerk.
That I am!
Mi-ryung, I know your brother.
He asked me to protect you
from punks.
I know you don't like me
but I like you.
I like you a lot.
I'm crazy about you.
When I want something
I dash like a bulldozer.
Show me what you got.
Damn, it's always Kimchi!
You?
- I got Beef!
- Ah, this ass...
You're a smart ass.
It's impossible to hate you.
Let's eat.
KIM Jong-hyun!
Keep stuffing yourselves
like pigs.
You know Mi-ryung
from HyangDo Girl's High?
Yeah.
So what?
She's my squeeze.
- And?
- Let's get it on.
Pick someone else.
I'm busy eating.
Come on, asshole.
The winner takes her!
- You know what this is?
- What?
I fought off tears getting it.
With the thought of her!
Still not giving up on her?
You live outside your head
don't you?
You asshole!
On this duel
I'm betting everything.
Is that so?
She's yours then.
Okay?
Can't you be more serious?
A duel is no joke, asshole.
Take off your pants.
- They might rip open, freak.
- That's my style!
Asshole!
Fuck!
Fucking tight pants!
Who you calling asshole!
- Ah, fucker!
- You asshole!
Son of a bitch!
Fuck! What'd you say?
Get the fuck off me!
Off me, son of a bitch!
Both of you should be fucked!
- You fucking asshole!
- Let go!
Fucker!
Son of a bitch!
Who told you to butt in?
What are you looking at?
The show's over!
Go!
Get out of here!
Fuck!
Get up.
Do you know
what they're called?
Jong-hyun, tell her.
Brave...
...Brothers.
- That's no compliment!
- Sir!
- You bastard!
You almost...
- killed my son!
- Calm down...
A punk like you should
rot in jail!
Calm down, sir.
How could I?
They beat up my son!
- Sit here.
- Excuse me.
- Who are you?
- I'm their mother.
How'd you teach your sons?
- To be bullies?
- I'm sorry.
But this is too much.
You're over-reacting to a kids' fight.
I can't believe this lady!
Is that how you raise
your kids?
I'm not talking to you.
Bring their father.
No words are necessary.
He's paying the hospital bill.
They...
They don't have one.
So they took after you.
He ran out on you, huh?
- What the...
- Stop it!
We're responsible.
Not our mother!
Say one more word,
and you'll be sorry.
- You son of a...
- Calm down, sir!
Get your act together!
Though he might be a jerk,
he's still your senior.
I'm sorry.
Give me your account number.
Mom!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'M SORRY!
Sung-hyun, Jong-hyun.
Hear me out.
Next time...
when anybody bothers one of you,
you beat him together.
That's what brothers are for.
Understood?
What for?
You're gonna ride that?
You two ride this to school
from now on.
You go to school
and come home together.
Understood?
Always together!
What are you doing?
Get the hell off.
Sung-hyun! This is good.
This is like a literature work,
not a letter of apology.
- Jong-hyun.
- Sir.
Reflection!
You helped me...
to see the light in the darkness.
I hereby pledge my loyalty to you.
That's right.
Jong-hyun! Come here.
What are you, a soldier?
Go clean the bathroom!
And be nice to your mother.
Harelip!
Where's your bodyguard?
Bodyguard my butt.
More like a master!
Hey, Torn Lips.
See if teachers are coming.
What the... Hey!
- Are you nuts?
- What are you doing?
Mopping.
- You're asking for it!
- Hey, Hey, relax
Nothing returns by beating him up
Keep mopping, asshole.
As you are!
Look here, shitheads.
Lose the cigarettes.
Those cancer sticks will do nothing...
but kill you.
What'd you call him?
I'm sorry.
Words won't do it.
- It's okay.
- You stay out of this.
Jong-hyun.
Give me cigarettes.
Give them here.
Hurry!
School is where you study
not smoke you assholes.
Think about...
the future of our nation, assholes!
Out. Get out!
Get the hell out!
Get your asses out of here!
What are you looking at?
Damn, I'm getting dizzy.
Let's take a break.
Aren't you getting
another surgery soon?
No idea.
Can I ask you something?
Aren't you upset
you were born as a harelip?
Were you born
because you wanted to?
You got me there.
I just...
I just don't think about it.
It's not life-threatening.
I read in a book
that everything happens
for a reason.
I'm sure there's a reason...
why I was born like this.
Who wrote that book?
I did.
Shit, I'm getting dizzy again.
Wow, it's awesome.
You can never see this
from down below.
You okay?
- There it goes.
- What?
Du-sik is retarded!
C'mon... C'mon!
C'mon! C'mon!
Let's go.
Hey, KIM Jong-hyun!
Would you mind?
- Who's he?
- Huh?
My younger brother.
What are you doing here?
I heard you fought over me.
Is that true?
No way!
A poem recital is coming up.
I want you to come.
Let's see what she wrote.
Waiting doesn't have to lead
to meeting.
God, she's so talented!
Let the heart ache.
Let the wind blow your smile away.
Days of wandering
for my other half somewhere.
Days of wandering.
I like this part.
She must've wandered a lot.
If i were meant for someone upon birth,
I'd like to meet him now.
What does she want to do
with me?
This is good.
She sure can write.
What? Envious?
Don't be, It's a burden.
You focus on studying.
That's what you do best.
Should I try?
Dear Mi-ryung
I'm your bodyguard.
A bodyguard of love.
Call me if you need my help.
I'm at your service 24/7...
So freaking corny!
Forget it!
Blossoming...
Son of a...
Next is 'Four-Leaf Clover'
by KIM Jong-hyun.
'Four-Leaf Clover'
Don't be so sad
Because you have only
three leaves.
If you had four leaves
they would...
They would've picked you
long ago
Don't be sad because nobody...
pays attention to you.
My eyes are set on you.
Let me be your missing leaf.
Even if nobody sees...
it your way...
you're the most beautiful leaf
for my eyes.
Your existence...
...is so special to my heart
Knowing you...
I couldn't be luckier.
Firecrackers!
$5 for two!
$10 for five!
Firecrackers!
$5 for two!
$10 for five!
Here...
A poem shouldn't be difficult.
It should be easy
to understand.
One that the most ignorant
can grasp.
One that makes...
tears roll down on your face...
That's a great poem.
Got that?
Here, It's for you.
It looks exactly like me.
- Did you draw this?
- Huh?
Yeah, I did
Lean over.
Wow, It's so nice here.
Let's come back.
Sung-Hyun, Go ahead.
I'll stay a little longer.
Okay?
Say... Mi-ryung!
What?
Ki... ss...
Where did Mom go?
Didn't I ask you a question?
Go cook me noodles
What's going on?
- Didn't you hear me?
- You do it.
What?
- What'd you say?
- Cook them yourself!
- Are you putting me down?
- You always put me down!
Want your ass kicked?
- Cook me noodles.
- You do it!
- Cook it
- You do it
- You do it. Asshole!
What?
Are you high on something?
Go cook me noodles.
You do it.
A piece of advice.
Know your place, will you?
Shit!
What... do you wanna be?
Nothing
What about you?
Don't laugh, okay?
- An actress.
- That's a long shot.
I know this agent in Seoul.
He's been asking me
to come up.
Don't get me wrong.
He's just a friend.
Mi-ryung.
I don't think
we're good together.
I came to tell you that.
Jong-hyun?
Let's break up before
I fall head over heels.
What do you mean?
I know.
It might not make sense to you.
But it does to me.
Jong-hyun...
We're strangers from now on.
Mi-ryung.
I'm sure you'll make it
as an actress.
Brother!
What are you doing?
Go get her!
Who the hell are you?
Do you know who I am?
Yes
What's your name?
KIM Jong-Hyun.
KIM Jong-Hyun...
I don't like by baby sister
giving me headaches.
I'd like to live in peace.
Know what I mean?
I don't think so.
Damn.
See you again, Jong-hyun.
Excuse me.
Is Jong-hyun home?
Yes
I need to talk to him.
Can you get him for me?
What's it about?
Just get him please.
Anything wrong?
Go get him, will you?
Tell him I'm not going anywhere
until I see him.
What do you want?
Is that all you have to say?
I think so.
Tell me...
Do you hate me?
Yes.
But why?
Give me a reason.
I don't need a reason
to hate you.
For the last time...
I wanted to see you.
I'm going to Seoul.
Good-bye.
Jong-hyun!
KIM Jong-hyun!
Let's go.
That was the last time I saw her.
Sung-Hyun studied hard
and got into med school
at Seoul National University.
As Mom had wished.
After he moved to Seoul...
things have changed.
I'd never realized his space
until he left us.
As you can see, it's new
with a good location.
Great for business.
Look at the brochure.
This, the interior will be way better...
once completed.
A masterpiece.
Hey, it's going to the 3rd floor.
Take a look around.
You know what they call you
at the cram school?
Burberry Man!
Don't you have other jackets?
Shut up, asshole.
What'd you want?
Neither of us is the academic type.
- Let's make money
- How?
There's a way.
I already talked to my mom.
Her savings account matures
at the month-end.
Let's start a street bar.
That's no money-maker.
You live once.
Try to live with style!
Then again...
your soon-to-be doctor brother
will make money for you.
What's the occasion?
Got a problem I'm being nice?
- Mom
- What?
- You got some money put aside?
- I paid the down payment today.
You're walking on clouds.
You're not a business type.
Didn't I tell you not to do it?
I can't be a moneylender...
once your brother becomes a doctor.
Why don't I start a street bar?
When I have the experience...
we'll open a restaurant like this.
Shut up and keep studying.
You need a college degree
for a doctor brother.
- Let me ask you something.
- Sure.
Where's everybody?
Don't you know?
The company's gone down.
Mrs. SIM!
Mom!
What's the matter?
Jong-hyun...
I think I'm going insane.
What should I do?
Why? Anything wrong?
Fuck!
- Give us our money back!
- What are you doing?
Give us our money!
Asshole!
Son of a bitch!
Give us our money, fuckers!
Assault, property damage...
You have to strike a deal
with the victim.
Or else you are arrested.
What brings you down here?
Just wanted to say hi.
Fuck you snob ass!
You shouldn't have done this.
Come on, it isn't much.
Sweat pants...
- How's business?
- Great, thanks to you.
- Chief.
- Yes?
- What's he in for?
- You know him?
It's me
Be...
nice to Mom.
Otherwise, I'll kill you.
Okay?
Be nice to Mom.
Jong-hyun!
Any word from Mi-ryung?
No.
That bitch.
I'd always wanted
to see you again.
What are you up to?
- I go to cram school
- Cram school?
I didn't know you were a nerd.
Drop by anytime.
Still got balls?
Didn't I say I'd call you?
Yeah, wait to hear from me!
I cant believe...
you ordered only for yourself.
Isn't he your friend?
You're so senseless.
Keep the window open
when you eat!
It's open.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
This is how I live.
I can't trust anybody.
- Young-chun...
- What?
Go ahead.
Feel free to talk.
Think of me as your brother.
Wanna smoke?
It's nothing.
See you later.
Jong-hyun.
Tell my mom
you're lending it to her.
Where'd you get this money?
I've been temping.
Why'd you come?
Don't worry.
I survived without a husband.
I can do the same without money.
Who knows?
May be this is a blessing
in disguise.
That's the spirit.
I'll make money for you.
This is so good.
I haven't had it for a while.
If you had started...
I'm worried about you.
Look at you.
Don't they let you sleep?
Do you eat well?
- Eat, Mother.
- I'm okay.
Tell me.
Have you opened up a person?
I'm in preparatory course.
Not there yet.
I just asked, okay?
Do you have a cold?
Just feeling a bit chilly.
Didn't go to cram school yet?
Where is Sung-hyun?
Beats me.
Where have you been
running around?
What's that?
This?
Herb medicine for your brother.
Damn!
Are you out of your mind?
He needs to stay healthy,
studying so hard.
No words are needed.
So stop it for his and my sake.
My tooth...
Stop worrying about him
and go to a dentist!
My tooth...
Sung-hyun!
How nice to see you!
Long time no see.
You look great man.
What are you doing here?
I came to see my folks.
How have you been?
I've started a street bar.
Wish Jong-hyun helped me.
He quit cram school with me
but changed his mind.
What are you talking about?
Du-sik's Restaurant
Shit, why here?
Look, lady.
If a person walks in,
you say hi.
You consider yourself one?
Watch it, lady.
You borrow and pay back.
Simple as that!
- Get out!
- Shit, you scared me.
Get out of here!
- Get out!
- Stop screaming!
I said get out! Get the hell out!
Or we're dying together!
- Get out of here!
- Mom
- Du-sik stay out.
It's okay.
It's okay, my baby.
Let's go in.
Those bastards!
Punks!
Jong-hyun.
What's that?
Medicine for your cold.
Forget it.
I don't want it!
You go to cram school lately?
I don't, So what?
Aren't you gonna study?
That's your thing.
I'll do what I do best.
Let's stop it.
Mom might hear us, Let's go in.
I don't care if she does.
She's your only concern.
And you're hers.
I've had it, okay?
Stop hanging out with Young-chun.
You know his reputation.
None of your business.
- When did you start caring?
- Jong-hyun!
You don't know?
When will you grow up?
What do you know?
Whom does she suffer for?
You have no right to say that.
So stop preaching
and go back to Seoul!
Stop being selfish for a change,
and take her to the dentist.
Where'd you get this?
Let go.
- You don't wanna upset me.
- Where you get it!
- Tell me!
- Get the fuck off me!
How nice is this?
Why don't you fight?
Go ahead!
I suffered...
...to raise you alone.
And this is what I get?
Gather around the neighbors
and show them a good time!
Is this what happens
without a father?
You're unbelievable.
What should I do with you?
What?
- Why only me?
- You don't know?
What are you good for?
You do nothing but fight...
and embarrass me!
Aren't you use to it?
You make my heart ache!
You got scammed, not me.
Don't take it out on me.
And don't give me that
I suffered for you shit!
Then what?
What have I suffered for?
If not for you, what else?
I never asked you to!
You think I was born
because I wanted to?
What'd you push me out for?
Fine...
Fine.
How could...
he say that...
Du-sik, who's your
favorite friend?
- Sung-hyun.
- Is he?
Sing for Mommy.
Yeah.
I wish I had never known
your family.
Like mother, like son!
Does it run in the genes
to live as leeches?
- Shut up and bring the money.
- That's no way to live!
- - That's no way to live!
- Fuck!
Yeah, go ahead!
Trash the place, for all I care!
Mom stop it, Mom stop.
We're going down together!
How could you!
You asshole!
Asshole! Asshole...
- Jong-hyun!
- Son of a bitch!
No!
Du-sik! Du-sik!
That's enough!
Hey enough!
You Barstard! I said enough!
Enough! That's enough!
Stop it! I said stop!
Mom!
Stop it! I'll pay you!
- You gonna kill him!
- Fucken asshole!
Hey enough!
Take this and get out!
- Let's go, Come on!
- Get out!
Du-sik... Du-sik...
Du-sik, it's okay!
It's okay.
Jong-hyun, let's go
Let's go now.
I didn't expect you
to collect it.
Next month, we will build
a new building there.
Good job, boys.
Young-chun.
What?
I have something to tell you.
I quit.
I will pay back what I owe you.
Son of a bitch!
Look, asshole.
Are you joking with me?
Are you?
I'm not joking.
Do I look that easy?
What the fuck are you looking at?
You know what?
Jong-hyun took a lot
after your father.
It's all my fault.
Raising two sons
without a husband...
One was like a husband,
and the other like a son.
Jong-hyun was strong.
But you weren't.
So I paid more attention to you.
Hi!
They might take pity on you.
But as far as I know,
you have it all.
What do I have?
You don't know?
Mom!
If we were drowning,
who would she save?
You know how to swim
so she wouldn't go for you.
Do you know how much
her panties are?
I do.
She buys two for $1
at the market.
Why would she do that?
So she could save up
for my surgeries.
Do you have any idea
how I felt looking in the mirror
after the surgeries?
I was upset.
What's the point?
It doesn't work.
Why can't she spend that money
on you and herself?
If she had,
I would've lived my way.
So I'm sorry.
To both you and mother.
Forget about me.
Be nice to Mom.
- I'm the skeleton in the closet.
- No way!
She said you were like
a husband figure to her.
She paid me more attention
because I wasn't perfect.
Honestly, we grew up
nibbling her heart away.
If you pour for yourself,
you'll never get married.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You aren't the only one
who worries about her.
I do too in my own way.
I know.
Jong-hyun!
I have a wish only you can grant.
What is it?
Call me 'Brother' once.
Put this on.
It's quite chilly.
Just once.
Jong-hyun!
Call me 'Brother' just once.
- What's up so early?
- Going to cram school!
Is this a dream?
Don't seed that
Seed something that looks good.
- Mrs. SIM?
- Yeah?
I'm going.
I'll film the most truthful
moments on the camera.
My father use to say that to Mom
before their marriage.
That day, Sung-hyun took
father's camera out of the closet.
Move!
Out of the way!
Why take those trays?
Just grab chairs!
You go to SNU?
Yes.
Tell Jong-hyun to stay home.
He doesn't wanna be
seen outside.
I packed some side dishes
that you like.
Share them with your friends.
And don't skip your
herb medicine.
- Do it tomorrow.
- Didn't you say...
You're taking the first train?
Why'd you buy these?
Ah, Ah...
Hurts... Ah...
Guess I'm getting old.
Parts begin to break.
Should I go get medicine?
- I'll be back in a jiffy.
- I will go.
No, I will go.
You stay with Mom.
You won't see each other
for a while.
Chew me up while I'm gone.
Come on, Jong-hyun.
I will go.
You go, Sung-hyun.
What's the occasion?
Happy?
If so, you can show it.
What'd you talk about?
Why didn't you call me?
So you could lament about life?
No thanks!
You're all grown up now,
leaving me out of your matters?
Come on, tell me.
What'd you talk about?
- Curious?
- Yes!
- We've decided...
- Yeah?
To marry you off!
We'll find a good looking
gentleman for you.
Really?
- Mom.
- What?
Going senile?
It's raining.
Did he bring an umbrella?
Damn, it's pouring.
Here it is.
Your mom is so proud of you.
Asshole!
Do whatever you want.
I treated you like a brother
and you go against me?
Calm down, boss
Ah...
Asshole.
What happened to the balls
you once had?
I won't let you...
play with them.
No way.
I'm not scared.
Mom...
Du-sik
I'm sorry.
Fuck!
What... What happened?
Jong-hyun...
What happened?
Sung-hyun!
Anybody here?
Help!
Fuck!
Hey! Open your eyes.
Sung-hyun!
Open them, Sung-hyun!
Hang in there.
Hey!
Let's go.
Get up.
Get up, asshole!
Sung-hyun!
Come on, get up.
Get the fuck up!
I should burn them all.
How could...
he leave me like this?
How! How!
How!
Yeah, burn them all!
Or pull yourself together!
Sung-hyun!
My poor baby...
Hello?
Anybody home?
These are for you.
Happy Birthday, Mother.
It's me Sung-hyun.
I'm sorry I can't be with you
Being away from home,
memories come back.
Do you remember?
Jong-hyun and I would make
seaweed soup for your birthday.
We'd make so much
we ate it for a whole week.
If God sent you us because
he had his hands full
you got yourself
two most troublesome sons.
We basically confiscated your life.
But you know what they say?
Troubled ones pay back later.
I'll be a good son.
If not, Jong-hyun
won't let me get away.
How's Jong-hyun?
I miss him.
You know what?
I think I owe him a lot
because you always put me
before him.
Mother, stop worrying about me
and be nicer to him.
He's the one beside you now.
Mother...
No, Mom...
I always wanted to call you
Mom like Jong-hyun.
I love you.
Be well and happy with us.
I'll always be by your side.
Lots of love, Sung-hyun.
That day, I saw her cry
for the first time.
Remember?
We once got up here together.
Then...
I wanted to tell you something.
You...
You know what?
What?
Nothing.
It's nothing.
Damn, so beautiful.
Say it. What is it?
Aren't you curious...
what I wanted to say?
Back then...
You spoke so well.
You didn't stammer.
Not at all.
You...
You weren't stammering.
So...
You didn't have to practice
with the recorder
every night.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
Damn.
Now I can't tell you this.
No matter how much I want to...
it's impossible now.
I'm sorry, Sung-hyun.
I...
I was a bad brother.
I'm truly sorry.
I'm sorry.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
There weren't many shots taken.
They're great pictures.
Who took them?
Did you?
No.
My...
My 'Brother' did.
I honestly don't think
I can fill in his space.
But I will try hard.
That's the least I could do
as his baby brother.
That's enough.