l8- year old time
father is from my living
medium disappearance
very quick without a trace
l what to remember is the time that
we play games finally, starting rain
the hair moistenned
the fl because of
you are dry exactly here what
you bled
rain of the outside is really a mess
mother
dear, what matter
the nose of the cloth fl boon bled
you are dry exactly there what
you have no matter, small guy
that house is very terrible
l hasn't been pass by
station good, whether want to let mother
l slept
hope you to are happy, l know that he
gets hurt on the athletic field
l do not know that how the other people
think, anyway l have to make an effort
l do not think that the
half-way backs to walk
sorry, father
good evening good evening
l told you his viewpoint of father very
stupid, hold tight the your nose
mother did not play
baseball on the second day
this is the beginning of the
evil-foreboding dream
the nose starts bleed
there has been the some times
l feel that own eye does not hear order
this television is not very old
may be because of thunderclap
that last last night
your father would therefore matter but happy
father will go home when
still have a hour at least
mother, lift the, come over and see
is an UFO
calculate, however is the type of the balloon
that the weather forecast use
not, good elephant is it
affected the television
just fly more that house
very quickly is our building to take over
not, etc., children caution point
that summer, l forever
unforgettable this view
be dark medium cross the
firmamental flight thing
that flew the thing to
be filled with the riddle
wear to go in the whole cosmos
summer of my 8 years old that year
l experienced the first time
my mother went out at that time
only have my person
the ar is a strong person especially
the elephant stud is similar
afterwards l also was aware of
the most silly affair took place now
they look the elephant animal is
similar, l can't transfer own view
l have already imagined for several years
until that summer l just real
was subjected to shock
the beginning that is in June
mother thoughted of a good way, letting me
attend a training class of cost a lot
whether very excited
the is especially the coach
his face was filled with the expectation
look the elephant is a cowboy
or is a fire fight member
also the elephant follows those
man who mother is together
after l just knew own intuition
the good elephant is a gift within crowd
How are you, l am the
this is my son
How are you,
dear, the Protestantism that do not
think to be to you practice ask good
do not worry, he is not too
to stranger make it a rule
l very quickly became the star in the brigade
similar to other hopeful childs
l win easily in 8- year oldly for
the first time compete
the grandmother also saw
but l am inattentive these
what l care is l make the coach feel proud of
because this victory for the first time
coach to seek my mother fete
small guy, get ready
coach? What matter
on the others which went to
look to only have you and l two
is? Yes
too cool
l like to see the premeditated murde
r movie, just stimulating thus
real see the time of blood me am incredibly
and difficult to expressly the excitement
after movie end we arrived at
the room of the coach
the house of the coach is very disorderly
that big television can play the game that l like
you was fried my turn
whether mother hopes that you go home or not
yes
after a day of work she wants to take a rest
l miss you a lot of times are a persons to spend of
yes, however l do not like l can watch the television
my day, you scatter my energy intentionally
sorry
wait a little while
ascend the here to come, also
bring over here that bottle
possibility you feel my some oddness
but l have to record the whole voice of
brigade, especially my most
good member of team
take up this
you can say up severals, use your common voice
what should l say
say that you like of, the time start
says own name
nir
drink now a big
see the ghost
say one more time
then say
see the ghost
can't, is really an oddness
like, looking at the camera now
do a grimace
this good
good of, thus
as far as possible chase your
mouth ZHANG DAO4 is biggest
liked too
till the last a minute, we all have lots of fun
you can kiss those small trifles tonight
also forget mother whom the hard l make
play very happily at the coach home, to
yes
that good
l love you, you never forget this
you how to came over tonight
you can play happy here
thanks, l can stay tonight here
certainly, however l see
some thing for you first
on this photograph of l look very stupid
not, look very good
that facial expression the elephant
is to have a good dream
the r, on this week l always
at miss your business
l am hungry
certainly, want to eat
l have your thing that like here
you see these how
my mother will not buy this thing from the
beginning, she feels thus wasted money
eat up be
you want to take which
you eat what
explode the corn
l eat the cocoa bean
see the ghost, let
you also come
the really fine play
you return young
l love you, r
l like you very much
be l am real to like a certain person of time
l will show him my feeling
small angel
kiss good-bye the person
to have no thus what wrong
do not let that anyone tells you, this is wrong
the affair took place, l also did
not be aware of by myself
thus, l lie at floor up
the kitty that good elephant is
on unfolding to open only
feel the tongue of the coach
in my felling in the mouth
you like, this good
everythings will like of
983 years October
do you understand to him
l know Peter 's 0 years old
of time, her years old
you are exactly at dry what
do not say me you are not normal
another childs were all precocious to
establish relationship at that time
then be pregnant
but she became my sincere colleague
kidnap is what
mother say is to take the person
to come home the mile
you take l ascend which
a house that has a lot of sugar
can't
this be was kill eye
come over, l will take you
l have always been all very careful
but the here is special very
l do not know to there will be what
the terrible affair occurrence
what matter l can't do now to obstruct
arrive the outside to wait me
l can do something to finish a while
you take me this, what should we do
like to like to play
what matter
you say just now what
is really a failed
the cloth depends on the boon
l think should be you
what's the matter with you
you at dry what
shut up, the words that
talk continuously killed you
want to be hero
open the mouth, l said to call you open the mouth
had better shine on we say of do
otherwise we killed you l swear
bring over here the match to hurry
, bring over here the match
shine on him with the flashlight
the r does not go
need not worry, l know should how to do
can fight for him to us
this to
lie down a short while
you now is my little darling, l show you my cruelty
l small time, the adult does this matter
to me let everybody disgusted
this to
this is just my good child
l look after that evening different
he has with me a little bit common, l can
not see in other people's body this
we were bound now together
until forever
l wake up again, don't know the
other people to did to me what
be the road that l find out back, they have
already disappear for more than a hour
but l still remember the process of the affair
l walked into a small house
l know, ignoring HUA DUO 's long time
what matter must l look up to take
place exactly at that time
must find out the answer of this riddle
l 5- year old time, l turn to
learn the another place
is about with the fl jinx of the small town
to
can pass by
circumstance how
O.K.
l call check the reason
l call the r
whether want to hitch a ride
certainly
take the cash
l pay the half
take here you get very careful
the police takes to all day long patrol here
no one knows to connect
down and would take place what
l however is a dry food merchant
take some thing to local market up
did not relate to, want to take what take
is hungry
l only have a hour
everybody is all very busy
etc.
let me come
is really beautiful
you like to be dry what
tell that you want to make me dry what
the stem go everything
do you like the old guy tell me
yes
feel quite good
the your body is very good
l do not go
l know you at think this not that safe
this but easy on the sick list one big city
hear, you are just a kid
is really of, you frightenned me
you wish to see so l
best hurry up
if l returned the night mother will kill me
l have the thing to see for you
see
Friday and Saturday, young and courage
this is again how
that be l
you are a guy for tell a lie
l do not believe you
l will confirm of
good of you are what is the row, the difficult
way is the pants exhibition meeting
but
have no door
am l not a small guy
those be
is a small candy of elephant similar
l in childhood basically not know
you are best to go for a doctor
next time perhaps the other people will shovel all
l am earnest, if seek the wrong person
you will suffer beating everywhere of
like, mother
went to the movie here before, not is
l also is
concerning the movie that we live, the whole good
elephants that take places are so faraway
but now we again stand here
only have you and l
l know
l heard a certain voice
is a god's voice
l also heard
l heard
99 years autumn
mother, have already started
good of, l come over right away
at put what
see for the second time
have a little thus silly
make person crary on the busines
s field, l know own matter
is really to like to play, l think that the oneself see
have already started
tonight in investigate program
we to discuss the phenomenon of UFO just
an imagination still a true thing
they close a few hours to me
carry on the check to me but l a plant
person of elephant is similar
they put on my belly a root-canal
l still stay the testimony here according to of scar
see
be the movie that l see concerning
the UFO still very frightened
be regarded as the very small
part and also will frighten me
pitiful guy, she look is really to feel sad
love the r to live in a commonness of
small town call because of the door
because of the door, leave
the here contain 30 miles
her 32 years old, did not get married
is together living with father
go to be sometimes once part-time secretary
but the love r body took place the
out of the common affair
took place some matters at the time of she
just the ability summary record
she also can't explain by herself
l hear someone experience the time passage
imperceptibly is to consume the own life
l know that someone contacted
me secretly 20 times now
do not see
first time is l 6- year old time
l ended at that time is after with the picnic o
f grandmother grandpa, at way home up
we at the time of drive, the grandpa
lost to the control of the car
have to let the person's dim in
vision and white light
but the good elephant of light is very
interested in my grandmother grandpa
they my derivation car outside then take me
end, l heard too many l go
out to eat the ice, do you want
need not, thanks
l lie on a cold but even table
surroundings someone rounds to come up
their head is very big, the arm is very small
but the worst part is a their eye
very difficult description, in fine is a very
greatly very black eye
the dear a, you are incognizant l
but you will know of
really want to leave this to let the
person's small town that hair is stuffy
had better let me know the second
stop for a rest to order
you had better calm down:00,otherwise
city of New York, your true good luck
l say, having to see the cocoa bean
rascal
see the ghost, quickly walk
make to die you
l will see this guy next week
be he
the many peoples will come to here
l go over and have a look
l can't lose the opportunity
of the do-it-yourself business
do we wait bottom to want
to come over pick you up
would like to of words come right
away, l come back in 7 o'clocks
we to see you
l want to go home directly by myself
l am past right away, then see
you are best a little bit careful
caution what?
l am earnest, the dissatisfied foot of your
good elephant is the friend with him
l have already seen the taste for you to see he
he is very handsome, l am to can not control
feelings elephant God is similar
you need not tell me l also
was very crary to him before
but l know our secret l will not
tell the other people of
believe me
possible your brains have fever, but
you have to understand a matter
be the heart elephant black hole bottom of
the common run of people for similar hour
if you are not awake, you will enchant forever
in this in a dream
the cloth depends on the boon are you at home
yes, mother
have no lesson today
l the time at 7:30 ascended the writing
this is your letter, an is from your elder
sister what that come, another is
is really to can't believe
is who
is a person within television
you had better calm down once
write up what
want to let me see to them
you seek to the person
etc.
You come at the right moment
have an old woman to take the box to come in
she have what
she has the villa in the Scotland
, beautiful room very new car
car that cans not remember
that 27 numbers what brand
do you miss that the oneself is past
your work return smoothly
O.K., then lead a burst of son, we can go out
good of
the r, do not forget
tomorrow is my appointment day
perhaps that guy to see me at not here
need not worry, that is your work
in this season you are very busy
is really a gentleness
the cloth depends on the boon
the cloth depends on the boon, you good
dear, you descend go to sorry
he has a little the concussion
you certainly are a cloth to depend
on the boon l am to love the r
father, have already had no matter
this is the young man that l said with you
do not care him, he be just to
stranger watch out for very much
very happy you can come to here come in
there is no another person
in home, sit the here
had a meal to have no
l am eating the lunch
need not, you continue to eat
whether you watched the television or not
saw the some times l recorded
the main fact is certain, but some place
they carried on to process
l miss l also is
you said in the letter
that is the occurrence in several year
agos, l am just the summary record
the many people that we are in the
middle did not know to take place what
you feel this kind of matter also
would take place in my body?
Be when l hear th
concerning the time passage
that certainly had
want to go out walk
what you take is what things
is a notes, l use to record my dream
any small things that l can
rememberseses all have
l think that this may help l remember
this is a good way
make your memory time awake
our ll matters are clear
l want to show you the miracle of this world
l was taken to do to experiment by them
you to touch once
at the time that l wake up, there is blood on the leg
but still don't remember to be mown what
l think now
this may be their a kind of track the device
the whole affairs that l do they
all know, perhaps are nearby at us
be l think these of time
the my nose is bleed
this nothing important is strange
because of can see the scar
did not forget to write a letter
do not forget l say to you of
good of
you should hurry to come over to see me
l know
the affair that wants to do wants to insist bottom
then see
really dare not believe incredibly and so
and late, my mother will worry of
still follow your mother together living
7 year ago dyings of my father
l do not really remember him
whether think to be the in a
dream that l write you?
You know, after write down
l can read the first reading of
that good
this writes a few months ago
there is blue eye there
there is a person of dress uniform, the
good elephant follows in my behind
is a boy of dress uniform
write to have the word up
are about with the clothes
of my baseball brigade
l see
the love r has the very greatly
very black eye, he touched my face
l helped at that time
l do not go
you have own way, a detective of
elephant is looking for the clues similar
perhaps you should concentrate the attention at
the boy of your in a dream he
can find out the answer for you
two right bowers are lousy at compete
good heavens, see that guy at compete
can't
are you play trick not yes
please beat the ball a little
bit and better, thanks
the right bower is lousy at where
he but fatty
it is different that different
person hit ball with racket
my father beat this
arrive the here to come
concentrate your award once
thanks
have various paper sugar here
you take by yourself
thanks
nothing important, then see
what
play with the child need not worry what of
my day, he hit ball with racket
beat the god's bottom
is really a waste
where is your mother
she saw a new boyfriend
my head has a little the pain
you have what medicine
wait a little while
at the here, give you
there is cigarette on the side
does the thanks have the lighter
here
do you like
is some s
feel fit, not is
yes
want elephant similar last time, throw
all of the woolen blanket to one side
beginning
you are seek what
thank yes
l can help you, but you have t
o write the homework
yes, after reading the book l write of
thesis would be very different
perhaps you will give me a
surprised and pleased
perhaps is
can let me know that you still need what things
thanks
small town history
have you completed
l am already about
good of, wish your good luck
beat quite good, continue
had better kick back and enjoy first
all right
get for 3 cents in the game Chinese and English
the country contestant of the end
but the opponent had to 0 centses
like
top which went to
sorry
should make a phone call for you of, have
already read the good long time
your supper is already icy cold
have no matter of
the cloth depends on t
he boon, what matter
your behavior is too strange a few
hours disappear the shadow
l am at school in, the course in
the school is some different
have to make a phone call to your father
l have a little the favour
l knew, quickly eating the supper
you good yes, he now just eat the supper
is who
is a woman of
l connect
let go of
does the cloth depend on the boon?
l am preparing to make a phone call to you
l found out that boy's photograph
similar to my in a dream of
is really too shocked
you are dry now what
nothing important
l have the important thing to
want to see for you, can come out
certainly
dear, how work is
see the ghost go to
this small town is really to
let person suppress too
strange of, a little bit peaceful
the cloth depends on the
boon, thank you can come
all right
l have already found out some photographs
this be he appear in my in a dream of that boy
see his face, he certainly knows what
you do what
Michael
he will come tomorrow morning,
perhaps what also not know
then say
l see the thing that you
ignore the solution for you
each guys of singles come to
here free and unfettered
choice
do you want
we have to have a person to drive
l got hold of a poster there from the text di
whether she writes to my
three thats of letter or not?
Yes, the words of the end is, his face make me shock
dear
New York is a very crary city
say one more time
can we help you
l can buy the cup beverage for you at think
see the ghost go to
hear fatty, see the ghost go to
is really one small guy that is unprogressive
is he not the type that you like?
Yes, he look the elephant to be insolate
by the sunlight many of that kind of
l go over and have a look
we got here what
strange of
leave there quickly
there is quite a few here dided not
discover the fawn for year
l tell that the other people are a riddles
father say that have always been and then
did not see the small animal come over
make with the your hand once
how, sexy organ
God give them the most mysterious thing, because
they did not defend the ability
the sometimes animal can kill people
their make for stay in latent
memory of oneself
still see what strange place have no blood here
also very clean
does the cloth depend on the boon?
You have no matter
we leave
my day
l like
the cloth depends on the boon
cloth to depend on the boon
my day, the cloth depends on the boon
you at dry what, r
get, all is already at the
mid-night 2:30
make a phone call to me, you this damn of
know that the text di would
pick you up in the station
l do not want to let
you get lost in the crary city
you need not worry, good after
arriving make a phone call to me
good of guarantee toward me
guarantee toward me here
good of
have no matter of
should shear some of your hairs
l have to wash once, right back
what matter
nothing important
mother is really talkative
you want to make me dry what
see downwards be
leave the here for me what matter
strange, you have the fragment below
l say
have no important event, you needed the
medicine store to take some medicine to go only
you had better notice the safety
l am to have no command over
car at wait outside
dear, can let me know what
can be careful:00
my meeting of
mother hases been love you, you did not forget
come, l do some shopping for you
you think to be in big garden stem what
be a guest by myself me
that does not like to play
l will fix to go the community university next week
true of, this viewpoint is not bad
l like such life
you know that you arrive where is all very popular
thanks, l will take you pass by of
best thus
that is what is the row
is a cognitive boy of r
can l help you
is this your house
yes
really sorry, l check the here
originally from the telephone
spend a just find out the here in the afternoon
no matter how it is say, l have no malice
you need what
l want to seek a thing
is the person of the F.B.l.
You still look very not lucky
you are to say, have no a call the
r of person live the here
we are just he send up New York of car
l am the relatives of the r, this is his mother
r
his name calls the r
yes
l call the cloth depend on the boon
99 years November December
you saw the time here will be a
greatly surprised and pleased
be you go to school of time
l have to before telling you three
weeks strange guy that see
he is not a comrade
actually, he look very sexy
his name calls the cloth depend on the boon
is the most lovely person who l saw
at up the community university
you leave that day
your mama discovers
him with me to sought you
0 year agos of good elephant he leads
with you in the baseball brigade
he is a brigade in the most lousy
he is filled with the question
to you certainly
l did not tell him concerning your business
l do not like to tell that
you is because you are a kid
he feels have with you the alike place
had been tested by the airship of
is really such
but he tells me these times him
very serious see the his eye know
so the story that you experience is
what is with the UFO had what contact
do you come in sight of now
cloth fl boon?
l came
someone to see you
How are you, the cloth depends on the boon
l pass by the here, wanting to
see your circumstance
tonight l arrive the outside
thanks, mother
you have no film, l see
your mother is not to like me very much
still feel that l am an outsider do
you still continue to study the
l come in sight of his mother and his
best friends however he now not at
really went to New York
you also sit down
does the in a dream still
have the another thing?
Yes, however the good elephant is slow very
perhaps is because of is too many
with time that new friend flower
however the business of the r has
already known more and more
his good elephant right there
have no matter l can't be thus
don't want to be thus
l can't thus have no matter of
not want
the small voice order not want
sorry
you best now walk leave
sorry the cloth depends on the boon
l pay USD 20,can't again many
good of
leave
hold me, use you 0 many year old guys hold me
etc., you are exactly at dry what
no matter how it is say
you stay useful
this to
hurry, time does not wait for someone
we can't fall ill, you get very careful
l know
do not say that l know, this is in New York
you did the business of the mistake and
will die with the person of the mistake
such story is too many
want to guarantee toward me t
hat you must notice the safety
good of
do you are usually such movie
how, do you not like
not, this movie is very cool
didn't the r still come back
let me come to explain toward you
a small star of his elephant
everywhere at turn
he has no letter to come over
however l know him at lead the
Christmas festival amusedly
what his mother tells me that he has
already fly the tour ground goes to
you meet by that time his
does the cloth depend on the boon?
What matter
l think that you like the brief rest
thanks, pull the lady of ji thank mother
is already:30
if is to reach the r to beat to come
over of, say that l am not here
you good sorry, he went out with friend
all right
l discover that you do not like her
l just think
should give her more spaces now
l miss that you also should take a rest
l sleep now
you good
l call together gram, you
r
the r, you are a stem in New York what of
this is to comfort, a kind of consolation
you act the grace
the my turn of now
this influence is not big
at that kind of the not good place infect by of
l know, you need not worry
you will be the most safe here
you can lean on l carry on the back up
l real what to need is a contact
this to, make me too happy
make me too happy
make me happy
you now 00 divide 00 safety
is
yes, he however is to printed the
to have another for:00
carry on the back to have a little the wound up
perhaps you should find the more safe waiter
make money know to find the another person?
Have no matter
you are unique to give me the advice person
l know
l hear you, still having me mother
l want to have the not good affair occurrence
in that summer
l did not feel at that time
is really special
the r, you at that time 8 years old
he really likes me
although l am a child, l am very surprised
l think that this is just true love
happy birthday
your need not preparation of
had better open
too beautiful
l miss that your hair sheared
and would be more good-looking
is really to like too
you have no matter
l get drunk did not get drunk
from the beginning before of
l let you go bad
this thing is quite good
certainly
yes, the a that you really paint
that but very divertive and small guy
are you a rightness the baseball
infatuates very much
l do not know
what matter
see the boy of the ghost
the thing that eat
certainly
l have lately of
l also is
you come first
my mother sends this for me
the time of the Christmas
she will come over of
your mother is coolest
l did not accomplish
the matter sometimes that
can't save will let life hate
just very quickly passed by
show us
you need what
l want to seek a work
what
l said with friend your circumstance
now at wait his news, but
what
you are not interested in
not, say in a specific way:00
true
certainly, l am really very interested in
certainly
you are certain you have no matter
l am just to do not want to bother my mother
thank you today is l feel best a day
nothing important
my day
who is he?
Is my father
father?
Son? l found out you
your mother say that don't know
you at not at home
happy birthday
you are dry here what
difficult way l disallow to the
birthday of celebrate the son
father, l already two years
dided not see you
yes, you before my car that can use
l did not make your telephone call before
just want to let you do not take care of me
l do not like to be thus
l think the exhausted way is to is
think to see you lead how
let me tell you
my of small time order the matter
know me at say what?
l bled at that time
you that day in the evening at
where do you still remember
you get drunk
leave at once the here
l bled l was held by the
person, you ask never
l have been canning have again at worry
l have an accident that evening
do you know
sorry
l can't help you
2 months
can l help you
does the cloth depend on the boon?
R
repair of
is ah
felling how
O.K.
You play return happy l also is
let us at any time keep in touch
younger brother, l walked, take good care of
you also is
want to get on the car ah
good of
to go where
my person do not worry
, l am a good hand for drive
do not open so and quickly
do not talk
how
please come with me
ask this place to walk
smell once
encore
take off the clothes
hurry to take off the clothes through
you why not hear my words
absorb
like, don't make an effort too
deep breathing
time wants the long little bit
bad egg, do not want to come next time
l call you absorb, how you are make hello.
. Hello... l want to put you pour here
bad egg, you why to stay away
my day
l let you run, l let you run
kill you, kill you,
l kill you, killing your this useless guy
make an effort some, make an effort the little bit
heard have no, hear have no
mother
veral days of 00,99 years
Christmas festival front
today is again the Christmas festival
hello, you want to go again where
go to a friend's re
you will do again what affair ah
small matter of a little
don't want the night, young man
today is a Christmas festival, we want to
have a meal together of good of
arrive
you have no matter
have no matter to pour is an one thing son
l discover that your spirit is very good
is ah is ah
have a flavor
do not worry, l believe that you should
be very good perhaps is to
?
How are you!
See you very happy, Christmas happiness
do you still remember the cloth
to depend on the boon
certainly remembered
Christmas happiness!
So, only our three persons
l will make a phone call to yours
why, what affair appeared an
unexpected trouble here
this is certainly very important
affair you have no matter
l am O.K., l am going to bed in the room
perhaps we will still come to here tomorrow
did not relate to of, l still need to cook
a meal, still having other affairs
dear, you came
do you comprehend a person
the cloth depends on the boon to come are together
with us, we also together saw for
a long time each other
there are 0 weeks,5 month,7 days
you sit down to like to like to discuss
true of, my mood
not good at all
what affair
to now, very sad with everything that l do l
the cloth depends on the boon, do you
know to be like such affair
you also did not do forever l also think so
you heard what
have what feeling
please follow me on get up
go to
do you get ready
blue
wait a little while, a short while will come of
arrive the here first to take a look, l knew, here
like
you are to do not think to be from the window in go in
is ah, you come with me together
caution some
this is the bed
l at the sight of it, l remind of some affairs
the whole everything that pass by is not not
come with me to come together
come to here to see
these will no longer let you think other affairs
arrive there to go to
so, now, you still have what viewpoint
l am tired, the whole ffairs all changed
what's the matter with you
just now and that lady whom you talk,
still remember you
at the thought of these affairs, l am very vexed
l also am similar, l also apprehensibility you
you want to see now what program
l also do not know that l should do what
everythings all disappeared, also no
longer having what loved
l am just to be fond of the very
much you have no matter
everythings all ended
those affairs are all very damned
at the thought of my dignity, l am very sad
say bottom go to
show us television
see what program. That kitchen is the
place that l went to for the first time
that summer of end
in my in the mind
you still remember that to engrave
the cloth depends on the boon
cloth to depend on the boon
l know is you
trained to start, l sit at peacetime of chair up
start rain
the water of the elephant pouring
l think should someone pick you up
mother? Mother and my fathers work together
who know
the others all have the parents
to come forward to claim
you said at that time
we take you go home
at that time coach and you together is
your brothers is here
come in, the here is very divertive
he does not want to let you go to bed
so at that time my dissimilarity
continue to say, do not stop, al
l tell me the whole matters
can say that another little boy
contain same situation only
because he comes in sight of own elder brother
he took off my clothes, feeling lik
e to play very much to me
the good elephant is a very divertive game
continue to play
like, the rule is such
first, l kiss you, then you kiss again me
get ready
we started
my day
why don't say
hence l the mouth that the tongue put you in
then your turn
looking at that big tongue slippery in
the on the face, the whole individual
of good elephant is swallow
at that time, you learned the
thing that coach teach
because l must think
be you open the mouth of time, whether think
that the absorption drops everything
l want to obstruct, but don't
go, own mouth also opens
then, he lies down in your in front
look the good elephant is very long time
l see the your eye shut
the good elephant is in the love wait for for a long time
then l hear your low language
like to play very much,
not is tell me your felling
you simply did not respond at that time
yes
we hence play to have the sex game
the coach calls what me do
call my elephant is only the dog for
the good elephant similar
have no matter, continue
l feel very satisfied, do you know
certainly that is my first time
since that evening
l just know that what father
and mothers are returns to matter
father knows that l do this
matter, l can't forgive the oneself
hence he shouts to me
then l also did the same matter
hence you also the elephant
did not control similar, to
the my nose is bleed have such matter how can
the whole time end, we re- put on clothing
your face look very vacant
your heart is empty
think only of to lie on the floor
hence l pull you get up
thus to
thus to don't want to be thus
what matter
at where, l do not know
see
l found out what matter
l see someone only here
we have to tell those apathetic persons
still tells that the cloth depends on the
boon everythings and will like of
but that is the lies l now what all not like to say
l really want to seek to turn head t
he road, exhausted own dint work
we have no way
l have to continue in the
community university under
what would don't know take place
l come in sight of the greed and sorrows
of the world, l think the elusion
can make an effort only to forget now
good two young mans of of an age of elephant
disappear in dead hour