We’re trying to live in the city
causing no environmental impact...
and I write about it in noimpactman.com.
We're just cutting down too many trees.
We need the trees to save the planet.
And the polar bears.
I'm trying to live a life in line with my values.
Oh, fuck.
People are intent on replacing
the American way...
with wind power and tree-bark burgers.
Like this one New York family, the Beavans...
who are five months into a yearlong quest
to live without impacting the environment.
The rules?
No toilet paper,
no incandescent bulbs or disposable razors...
or magazines or newspapers, television...
planes, trains, automobiles,
elevators, plastic bags...
or shopping for anything new.
They're poisoning our capitalist society.
And here now to defend himself is the
patriarch of these eco-Mansons, Colin Beavan.
Mr. Beavan,
thank you so much for joining us.
Joining us now is the writer and
self-proclaimed No Impact Man, Colin Beavan.
We begin tonight with one man, his family
and a radical experiment to help the planet.
With more than 40%ofthe public now
convinced that humans cause global warming-
I just thought, "What if I actually tried
not to hurt the environment?
What would that feel like?
Is it possible?
Is it practical?"
One of the things
that I as a writer have wanted-
because my last two books were history books-
is to become more of an activist writer.
In some sort of humble way,
I want to have some sense...
that my writing is helping the world.
For the next year, my wife, baby daughter and I
while living in the middle of New York City...
are going to attempt to live without making
any net impact on the environment.
Ultimately this means we'll create no trash,
so no take-out food...
emit no carbon dioxide,
so no driving or flying...
pour no toxins in the water,
so no laundry detergent...
buy no produce from distant lands,
so no New Zealand fruit.
Not to mention no elevators,
no subway, no products in packaging...
no plastics,
no air conditioning, no TV, no paper-
Anyway, so that's-
That's kind of like a summary of the project.
Colin told me what the project would be,
and my honest reaction-
I was really excited that he had an idea
that he was excited about.
'Cause that was, overall,
the most important thing.
I thought, "As long as we're doing all these
things, why don't we throw in...
my two current addictions,"
which are shopping and reality TV.
I'm a reality-TV aficionado,
addict and expert.
Look at her face right now.
It's good.
I've had a really intense
relationship with retail.
Catherine Malandrino sample sale.
Jean Paul Gaultier-So fun.
And I'll see you at midnight,
and then we'll have dinner at 2:00 a.m.
Marc Jacobs is, like-
"I'm married, I'm a mom, but I'm still trying
to work it a little bit."
I'm a high-fructose
corn syrup-addicted, you know...
screen-addicted, meat-eating girl.
I would say that I was not
an environmentalist.
I would say that I was the typical, like,
consuming-
I'm a consumer.
I'm a take-out junkie.
You were scared of not being
able to consume for a year.
Yeah, I was. You're right.
So you tried to do all your year’s consuming
in one week.
I dropped a paycheck.
- Chloe boots. That was a lot.
- How much?
- I'm appalled at myself.
- Can you say how much though?
That's appalling.
That's just-
I can't even- I'm embarrassed.
- This was the last hurrah.
- This was the binge.
- I got you.
- Yeah. That's the bill of the binge.
Yeah, I was laughing 'cause I was just
looking for necessities.
- That was like Custer's last stand right there-
- Okay.
spending all my money on silly things.
I don't care how much you spend.
This particular spending has to do with-
- Your project.
- no impact.
- I thought it was our project.
- Oh, yeah.
It's "No Impact Man."
It's his book, and it's his project.
And he's No Impact Man, but in order-
But the project is. Our family is doing this.
Two weeks ago, on day one of the project...
we stopped using
carbon-producing transportation...
which means no airplanes,
no subways, no taxis and no elevators.
People say, "Well, why get so extreme...
'cause not everybody is gonna get
so extreme," and this kind of thing.
It's to experience
the whole gamut of things...
to see, well, what really
are we willing to give up?
At the end, we'll come out of it and see
what are we willing to keep.
What are we not?
What was too hard? What wasn't too hard?
The paradigm is, "reduce, reuse, recycle. "
So the first thing is, reduce-
Reduce our consumption, right?
Oh, I think to myself,
"You know, of course I can’t do without this.
I can't do without that. "
So the idea is,
"Okay, let's do without it all.”
- Come to see how big the TV is.
- Yeah. Come on in.
They're gonna take the TV away.
And we're just gonna not have a TV.
We're gonna be TV-less people.
- Yeah.
- Mommy's a little bit addicted to the TV.
I'm gonna be 40 this summer, and there
were just so many things about the way...
that I was living my life- especially
with Isabella- that I wanted to change.
I had my blood tested really in depth...
and it showed that if I didn't change
the way that I was eating...
I was on my way to diabetes
and had a low thyroid and-
And then that kind of comingled
with my 40th birthday...
is kind of like that moment in life...
when I think, "Well, what do I want
the second half of my life to look like?"
Since the first half is done.
Tick tock.
The project works in phases.
I'm not a trained environmentalist,
so I'm learning as I go.
Right now we're really working on our trash.
The average American creates
1,600 pounds of trash a year.
We're trying to reduce that to zero.
See that Hawthorne Valley Farm?
Certified organic biodynamic.
I'm gonna see if we can all, as a family,
go stay on that farm for a few days...
and volunteer and stuff.
Is that okay?
Yeah, babe, that sounds like a great idea.
The majority of our trash is
food packaging and food waste.
The good thing about the farmers' market
is that most of the food is sold unpackaged...
so it's easy to shop there
and not make trash.
- No environmental impact?
- Yeah. Causing no environmental impact.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Then you can't have this bag.
- Thank you!
How do I say this
without sounding like a dick?
I get upset to see things
individually wrapped in plastic.
You know what? Are the worm people here?
- What do you need the worms for?
- Well, can I tell you about it after?
Basically, the worms make it compost faster.
Honey, I'm not into that at all.
Okay. We can talk about it.
- Michelle?
- Yeah?
Wanna come see the worms?
See 'em wiggling around in there, Mom?
- Yeah. How do you make sure they don't get out?
- They can't get out.
- Wait. Is there no cover?
- Of course there's a cover.
- Let's cover it up.
- Wait. Isabella's looking at 'em.
Okay. Nature.
Mom doesn't really like nature,
but Dad likes nature.
So, diaper cover-
Made from wool-
Organic wool.
Nicely treated lambs.
I checked into all this.
There's five different techniques.
And there's the bikini fold
and the angel fold, and so whatever.
We're gonna try the angel fold.
There's confusion over...
whether cloth diapers or disposable diapers
are better for the environment...
and the industry-founded studies
suggest that it's the same.
But the fact is that we put 49 million
plastic diapers a day in the landfills.
It's the third-largest source
of trash in the landfills.
Does it feel different, honey?
- It's too fun.
Let's see.
Hey, hey!
Look at you.
- The green-century babe.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
We come here every Sunday
for breakfast, and we love it.
But as a part of our-
Colin- our no-impact project-
with phasing out
everything, including restaurants-
so this is our last supper at Pastis...
and our last supper
in a restaurant together as a family, right?
We're gonna eat food
only from within 250 miles...
so it's not that Pastis,
per se, is a problem, but-
For example, the wheat in the bread...
probably comes from the Great Plains,
way far away...
so it's-
That's what the problem will be
that the food comes from all over the place...
and we're trying to eat locally.
We can eat what we have except for the spices
because the spices would last all year.
Onions are not a problem.
Garlic is not a problem.
Squash is not a problem.
Potatoes are not a problem.
We had leek and potato soup
last week for three days.
I've gone off meat...
but I still have been eating fish,
so last night I started...
no meat, no fish, no nothing.
Out of everything- Out of the stairs
and the scooter and the no garbage-
I've definitely found
the food to be the hardest.
It's still hard.
I just wanna go get a baked good.
Why do you think foods are hardest for you?
Because I can't eat anything
that tastes good.
We're stuck now
with cabbage and root vegetables...
until the winter's over and the spring comes.
Hi, Ryan. I 'm gonna come back
in a little while to get some milk.
I've got too much to carry already.
We'll see ya.
The guy that I usually
give my egg cartons to isn't here.
The transportation of food creates
a lot of carbon emissions.
Here in the United States,
the average piece of food...
has traveled 1,500 miles
from the farm to the plate.
These guys have great apples.
I 'm wondering what your favorite is.
The winesaps'll knock your socks off.
There's also lots of other reasons
for eating local, like preserving our farmlands.
And the reason we're vegetarian is...
worldwide, meat-eating is responsible
for more greenhouse gases...
than anything else, including transportation.
There's no locally grown coffee,
so I have to cut it out...
so today's my last hurrah
with the iced quad espressos.
I'm worried that I'm gonna have a slip,
that I'm not gonna be able to do it...
and then I'm worried
about the wrath of Colin.
Because it really bothers him
when I have slips...
because it makes him feel
like the project is going to pot.
Basically, this is easy for Colin,
and just murder for me-
The food and the caffeine.
That's Mommy's third and last
iced quad espresso.
Prepare for takeoff.
Feelin' good.
Oh, my God. Much better.
Part of eating local...
is about getting to know the farmers
that you're getting your food from.
So we're gonna go see Ronny
at Ronnybrook Farm and all his little cows.
This is the first time
I've been on any sort of...
non-self-propelled transportation for...
more than a month.
So it's kind of fun. Choo-choo.
Every cow has a name.
This is Thelma. Hi, girl.
Is your relationship
with the animals part of why you do it?
That's the reason we started doing it.
My wife tells me that when my son was born,
I had to milk the cows.
I couldn't take her to the hospital.
I didn't remember that one.
Let's talk about organic.
You don't have the "organic" label.
Why don’t you, and what do you think about
the organic label and-
Well, I think "organic" is a good thing.
The one thing that I am opposed to as organic
is not being able to treat your cows.
Right.
That's the only thing
that I couldn't subscribe to.
Which is what? Explain that to me.
Well, if a cow gets sick,
you can't use any antibiotics.
That's the problem I have
is lettin' cows die.
These have been the same cows
for generations.
Wow.
Hi, honey.
So let me ask you this. So everything you're
saying- So let's go to the other end.
People are onboard the organic marketing bus.
The most important thing-
the reason local is important-
is I want to make the food chain legible.
If I’m gonna buy a grape from you,
I wanna go see what you’re doing.
You might not be certified organic,
but everything you do is organic or better.
In milk, it only has to be-
it only has to be local...
and you have to go see
the treatment of those animals.
You gotta go see it.
This is an entirely local-food frittata.
Now, the root vegetables
come from an upstate farm.
Red cabbage- Also upstate New York.
Eggs and cheese-
It's from upstate New York too.
- Did you hear the phone ring?
- I did.
- That was Robin.
- Yeah?
And basically, the deal is that the wanna
try and make this the cover story.
Yeah.
But early Monday morning at 7:00 a.m.,
Robin needs to have the new draft in his hand.
So I'm...
feeling so debilitated
by my caffeine withdrawal...
that I feel like it's gonna affect my work.
- Uh-huh.
- I feel like this is a really important story.
This is what I think.
Why don’t you wait until whenever-
- When are you gonna start doing the work?
- After our dinner party.
Why don’t you wait
till then, and then you can decide.
You've gotta be kidding me.
I feel like my head
is about to pop off my body.
It's gonna help me through the process,
and I feel like it's gonna be stressful...
and so why not avail myself of that help?
Just a second.
What you really mean is,
you want some coffee right now.
- It's got nothing to do-
- I'm gonna take the dog out.
-Juice up.
- That's what you really-
Yeah, I wanna go use. I wanna go on a run.
- Well, I don't care.
- But you do care.
- Well, you know-
- I only eat local food. I don't create any garbage.
- I don't eat anything-
- Wait, wait.
You only eat local food,
but who provides it...
gets up in the morning
and makes you breakfast every day-
- You.
- does your lunch-
- does your dinner-
- That wasn't the point.
- Then washes the dishes when it's all done?
I wash the dishes.
What really happened is, Robin called you up,
and you thought, "Oh, this is an excuse."
So you’re gonna have your-You're mad at me.
And I'm telling you that I'm gonna go
take care of myself.
You're putting words in my mouth.
I never said I was mad.
I am now going to go take care of myself
and get an iced quad espresso, and maybe two.
I don't know.
I don't want to let everyone down,
or let myself down.
I use this spicy olive oil,
and it's the remnants of our olive oil...
'cause pretty soon
we won't be able to use olive oil.
- And you're going to do without power here?
- Eventually.
Well, what about power
in somebody else's apartment?
If somebody were to invite us
to watch TV at their house, we'd say yes...
'cause it was a social occasion.
I'm not begging, but close.
- Clothing?
- Used clothes are allowed.
No new materials, but Michelle,
I think, wants to go cold turkey.
For the whole year.
I'm not gonna buy anything all year.
It's been really great letting it go,
'cause I've been able to rethink everything.
What do I use? What don't I use?
'Cause Colin's out of style anyway.
We're the superficial friends.
Second syllable.
Good job.
At first, because it was our habit
to watch TV, we missed it.
And now that space is filled...
with being in the moment,
with friends and each other.
I 'm making cornmeal porridge...
which we have a lot, even though Michelle
doesn't like it that much...
because there's not that much
we can get locally.
So cornmeal porridge is what it is.
My apple.
- Okay, give Mommy a kiss good-bye.
- I love you.
I'll see you later, okay, honey?
I'm gonna go to work.
And I put a post on the blog
called "How We Avoid Making Trash."
"No Indian food in throwaway take-out tubs.
No Chinese food in plastic throwaway tubs.
No Italian food in plastic throwaway tubs.
No soda cans. No water in plastic bottles.
Canceling our magazine
and newspaper subscriptions.
Putting an end
to the junk mail tree killing."
I'm calling up the companies...
to ask them not to send them to us anymore.
"Returning egg and berry cartons to the
vendors at the farmers' market for reuse.
Buying milk in returnable, reusable bottles.
Carrying my ultra-cool,
reusable cup and water bottle...
which is a glass jar
I diverted from the landfill.
Using baking soda from a recyclable
container to brush my teeth.
Switching to real- meaning cloth- diapers.
Shopping for food only from the bulk bins...
and from the local farmers' market,
where food is unpackaged and fresh."
If I want what's inside this box,
why do I need the box?
And inside the box, there's a bag.
"No throwaway plastic razors
and blade cartridges.
Using old clothes for rags
around the apartment instead of paper towels.
Keeping a worm bin
to compost our food scraps...
into nourishment
that can be returned to the earth...
instead of toxins
that seep from the landfills."
Here. Look at this.
They're gonna eat, I think you told me,
three pounds of food material-
A week. Yeah.
Before the project started, we took four days
where we saved all our trash.
There was 90 gallons in four days,
which is kind of disgusting.
This is our combined trash for a week.
- Okay, so, we've done the trash phase.
- Yeah.
- And we've done the local-eating phase.
And now we're moving
into the sustainable consumption phase.
But what about transportation
and all the other stuff we’ve done?
Yes, but those
aren't part of the phases.
- So now we're moving into-
- Okay.
Making sure that we don't have any environmental
impact through purchasing, basically.
So the first rule is,
don't buy new products. Okay?
But we can borrow, rent or buy used.
Do you have to go to the potty?
Do you want some toilet paper?
Actually, we're out of toilet paper.
Honey, do we have any toilet paper?
One thing that's really, really hard
is for a consumer...
to figure out what's okay to buy
and what's not okay to buy...
and what should be disposable
and what's not disposable, right?
- Yeah.
- So that research is really, really hard to do...
- and nobody can do it all.
- Yeah.
But if you just cut out
consuming the things you don't really need-
- Yeah.
-you've already done it.
- Yeah!
- You don't have to do the research.
So if you discover that really you don't
need toilet paper, you can just reuse cloths-
- Yeah.
- Yeah. You don't have to buy toilet paper...
and you don't have to do the research
about toilet paper.
You get it?
- Yeah.
- Do we really want to be this graphic?
'Cause-
The thing about it is,
is you don't know until you try.
I feel like I'm gonna lose my job.
The public health mockery of us
is just gonna be-
- It's a one-year experiment.
- Right.
Isn't it making you,
No Impact Man, so fringe and wacko...
that you’ll just be discounted
as a fringe wacko?
I'm just asking rhetorically.
But if I tried it,
and I found out that it works...
and it's environmentally better
and it's no problem...
and it can be done just as hygienically,
then I don't see why it would cheapen it.
But if I don't try it,
I won't know at all.
- You see?
- Oh, Frankie.
What's bad about toilet paper?
We need our trees to absorb carbon dioxide...
but instead we're cutting 'em down
to make toilet paper.
So part of our experiment is just to ask...
do we have to be a disposable culture?
Right? And toilet pa-
And it's extreme, because we're looking
at every angle of that "disposableness."
Because the throwaway culture itself
is really a big problem.
And actually, if we were-
Maybe we can get away
from everything that's throwaway.
Tonight I was, like,
"Okay, well, if you’re gonna ask me to do this...
then I should be getting a prize, a coupon
or a voucher, redeemable for something."
But I don't really want anything.
And then the next thought was-
I felt this sadness for the wanting part
of me kind of dying a little bit...
and it felt like there was just a hole there.
So what is left?
- What's that?
- It's all the stuff that we're gonna give away.
From cleaning out the closets.
Okay, ready?
This is called "inventory reduction."
I've never, ever been here before
where there's been a Marc Jacobs bag.
- You already have that exact same bag.
- No, I don't, honey.
- You don't?
- Honey, I have the white Sophia.
- And what's that?
- That's not white.
It's a kind of taupe,
and it's a totally different bag.
Maybe ours was a little bigger.
I don't know.
But, anyway, it just reminds me of our TV.
You're on New York public radio,
WNYC, FM and AM, New York...
and wnyc.org.
Mostly sunny skies in Central Park at 10:00.
My first guest today is No Impact Man.
Colin Beavan just walked
up 24 flights of stairs...
accompanied by your host, who is not proud-
or tired- to avoid consuming
electricity in an elevator.
For those of you who happen to have
the New York Times around...
take out section F,
the House and Home section.
There's a big, green-tinted picture
of Colin Beavan's apartment...
with his wife and daughter and everything.
One of the biggest pictures I've ever seen
in the New York Times-
of one of the littlest apartments I've ever
seen in the New York Times.
I rode home from The Brian Lehrer Show,
and I thought...
"I'm gonna go see if any of my friends saw
the New York Times story...
and e-mailed me to say congratulations"...
and there was 150 e-mails.
The subject line says things like
"Greetings from The Today Show.”
Hi. This is Mary Knowles.
I'm a producer for Bill Maher.
At first I was excited...
but then when I saw how many requests
there were, and I didn't know what to do...
I went from excited to scared out of my mind.
Hi, Colin. My name is Celia Converse.
I work with the Discovery Channel.
Hi, Mr. Beavan. My name is Abian Agradge...
and I'm calling from Al Jazeera in English,
based out of Washington, D. C..
People contacting me
from Australia, Colombia, Germany, Italy-
Time Out Kids is doing a story
about families that live in New York-
Sort of eco-effective,
environmental green families.
- Can you turn yourself more towards me?
- Oh, my God-
You see?
Not to mention, like, Italian television,
Japanese television.
Interview request from a newspaper in France.
Before we started this project,
Michelle and I-
Sir, you were talking about the philosophy.
What's behind No Impact Man?
I kind of am always thinking
about collective action.
What we as a society should do.
The laws that should be changed.
But one of the things I've always been
weak on as a liberal is individual action.
Why do I have to wait
for Congress to do something?
Why do I have to wait for big business to do
something? Why don't I do something?
The Times, though, makes it sound like
part change the world...
part gimmick for your next book.
- Do you cop to that?
- Yeah, I totally cop to that.
I am who I am. This is what I do.
But If I can take the energy
of who I am as a person...
and point that energy in a direction that-
I say this most humbly-
and point that energy in a direction
that can help the world...
then it's better than pointing it
in another direction.
This is what the New York Times reporter
says about the project at the end.
"It may seem at best like a scene
from an old-fashioned situation comedy...
and at worst an ethically murky
exercise in self-promotion"-
So she wrote basically that
the range of possibilities...
was that it's bad, or it's really bad.
To a reader it was really funny.
From my point of view, it undermines
the opportunity to cause people to think.
What if we called it "The Year I Lost 20
Pounds Without Going to the Gym Once"?
Or "The Year We Didn't Watch TV and We
Became Much Better Parents as a Result"?
Or if we called it
"The Year We Ate Locally and Seasonally...
and It Ended Up Reversing
My Wife’s Pre-diabetic Condition"?
There are actual benefits
to living environmentally.
So this is the readers' opinions, right?
379 comments.
Apparently it's a huge number of comments.
"Sacrifice now or sacrifice later.
I'm already doing a lot,
but plan to do a lot more."
Then there is this one.
"I can't wait to wipe my ass with this book."
This one says, "DTMFA, Michelle."
Which I'm guessing
stands for "Dump the motherfucking asshole."
Gawker is a site that kind of parodies
and sends things up that are in the media.
"Colin quietly weeps on the toilet
too moist to move, and too proud to wipe."
That was great. But the comments-
"My first impulse
was to rake these people with Uzi fire...
while screaming,
'Is that enough impact for you?"'
I started-
I doubted myself for a little while.
I think I'm doing something worthwhile,
but maybe I'm not.
Maybe one, it's philosophically wrong.
Because I've also got e-mails
from some environmentalists that say...
"Crazy people like you
give the rest of us a bad name."
Could I potentially be making
completely the wrong decisions?
Yeah, but-
I'm just trying-
I just try to ask myself
to do what my cons-
I try to follow
the dictates of my conscience.
I know that I can't back out now,
and I'm not gonna back out on you...
but it's making me not want to do it.
I think that it's create-
We've been reading the blogs and stuff like that.
One person at work has come up-
Who I really like.
She's a friend of mine, but I guess she-
Everywhere she goes,
people were talking about it-
Basically how we're
bourgeoise fucks and crazy...
and she spends all her time defending me.
Then one guy said...
"My wife has instructed me
to never, ever shake your hand."
And she went on all night
about the hygiene and-
I understand why people would criticize.
I just don't get why they hate us.
- I don't think they hate us.
- I don't get that.
Completely coincidentally,
Colin and I were invited to brunch...
by this woman Kerry,
because she's a food writer.
And it turns out, at the end of the brunch
that I discover that-
She comes clean with the fact
that she had written negatively about us...
and had been
one of our haters on the Web.
She claims that she's
changed her mind about us. I don't know.
Let me see if I can pull this up.
I have been dreading this moment.
I was afraid you were gonna ask.
You're a sport.
Oh, God.
"No Impact Man is, in fact, having an impact
but probably not the one he intended.
Once upon a time, virtue was its own reward.
Now a vow of voluntary simplicity is just
another entrepreneurial enterprise.
The fact that No Impact Man's
ostentation embrace of all things organic...
did not come about in,
well, an organic fashion, is what bothers me.
While No Impact Man runs around air-drying
his ass for posterity...
less flamboyant folks are leading lives
of quiet inspiration."
- Yeah, I questioned his sincerity and his motives.
- Yes.
And there was a "gee whillikers" quality to
the posts that rubbed me the wrong way.
Your criticism,
in the context of the criticism...
is very, very mild.
I didn't quite get why people hated us
or why it was such a-
- I have a theory.
- I didn't quite get it.
Based on my own experience with this kind
of thing, to a much lesser extent...
but I think that a lot of this really
touches a nerve for people.
Aside from making people
feel guilty and defensive...
about their consumer habits...
people are very traumatized...
if you suggest that
they should make do without something.
The notion of going without-
- The notion of "I need it."
- Yeah. I need this.
Or I don't need it,
but I want it, and why shouldn't I have it?
This is being a good American.
Part of local foods about connecting
with the way the food is grown...
so I talked to the local community garden...
and the waiting list for having your own plot
is long, like years and years.
But it turns out that there is only one person
in the community garden who grows vegetables.
Everybody else grows flowers.
And he was actually willing
to take me on and to mentor me.
You gonna help us in the garden?
- Yeah.
- You wanna grow things?
That's my friend Mayer.
Be careful. That's a rosebush.
That has thorns.
That has sharp things.
- Let's talk about what we hope to do today.
- Yep.
This little plot is gonna be parsley.
Just kind of broadcast it
over this rectangle.
And cover it to the depth that it says to,
and whatever else.
Want me to tell you what I'm doing?
We're gonna put some plants in there.
So I'm breaking up the soil
so that the plants can grow.
I thought gardening
was supposed to be hard work, Mayer.
It is. I did a lot
of the most labor-intensive-
- When you spread the manure?
- Yeah.
- Right.
- When I dug the whole fuckin' place up last fall.
I'm takin' these seeds, right?
And I'm gonna put 'em in the ground.
Mayer, we're going to go spend
four days up at Hawthorne Valley Farm.
There whole thing is that everything
on the farm is recycled.
- Yes.
- It's all self-contained.
Yes. I called them up, and the whole family-
Me and Isabella and Michelle-
It's gonna be our holiday.
- That's great.
- Yeah.
I feel like we should talk
about having another kid.
But I know that you don’t want another kid...
so I feel like that means
we're probably aren't gonna have another kid.
When we had Isabella,
I felt like you really wanted a baby...
and what I wanted for my life could have-
I just couldn't keep that from you.
And I was willing to take the leap with you
from that because I felt like-
Also it's funny 'cause we have this history.
I was scared to get married too, and I would
say to you, "Are we doing the right thing?"
And you said yes, and I trust-
I trusted you,
and for me, it's totally the right thing.
But when I think about
having a second child-
Whose career is it that's gonna get-
Whose work's gonna get sidelined?
'Cause you’re totally riding high at work.
If we were to have a second child,
are you willing to give up that work?
I don't have to-
That's so-Well, that's so-
I don't have to give up my job
to have a second child.
I don't know why you’re bringing-
I don't really feel like
my work has anything to do with it, really.
It does.
Because the point is I wanna know
if we were to have a second child- Right?
I don't particularly want a sec-
I don't want a second child. Right?
But before we even begin to consider it...
there is not much flexibility
in our schedules, right?
So what I'm asking you is,
where is the flexibility gonna come from?
It'll come from me.
Okay. I've collected all the cleaning
products we have in the house already.
Standard cleaning products
contain all sorts of chemicals...
that aren't good for us, and they're not good
for the environment either.
And they end up getting flushed down
our drains and into the water supply.
What we're looking at here...
are a lot of things that are marketed...
as natural and not harming
the environment already...
because we've been
on the project for a while now.
They do not allow you
to refill the bottles...
and for the purposes of this project,
we don't use disposable products.
And people say, "Well, what about recycling?"
But the fact of the matter
is that plastic recycling...
is not as good as it's made out to be.
It's better than nothing,
but it's still not perfect.
So the people call it "down cycling"
rather than recycling...
'cause it goes down in quality every time,
and then becomes toxic.
As we've been running out of stuff, I've-
We've save the empty bottles
so that we can...
put our homemade cleaning products
in the empty bottles.
All our cleaning products
can be made from these things-
White vinegar, baking soda...
castile soap...
and borax.
How do you tell if it’s really clean?
But it feels like it-
It feels the same
as though I'm using a regular cleaner.
Hey, poop, you know
what I'm doing right now, right?
- I'm gettin' rid of all the cosmetics.
- My cosmetics?
- Well, aren't we supposed to do that?
- You mean my makeup and stuff?
Well, I thought so, but I don't know.
What are you doin' about your makeup?
What are you doing?
You're gonna throw all that stuff out?
Well, no, I wasn't gonna throw it out.
I was gonna put it in this box
till the year’s over.
Okay. Just let me know.
We have to put all this stuff in this box.
Can you help me?
- Honey?
- Yeah?
Leave that bottle that says "fresh" on it.
I'll take care of it.
I already left that for you.
Okay, empty.
- It empty.
- I know. I need that.
'Cause you know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna
make shampoo and put it in there.
A few days ago I blogged about the fact...
that we were gettin' rid of the electricity,
and I asked for suggestions.
And I gave a list of all the things
I needed help with...
and one of the things was laundry.
And somebody e-mailed me and said that they
used to do their laundry...
in the bathtub,
and they would just walk on it.
And that sounded good to me.
You wanna do it too?
Now we go backwards.
Mom?
We're doing the laundry.
I wanna do it myself.
You wanna do it yourself?
But I'm worried you'll fall over.
Don't fall over.
What are you cleaning these clothes with?
Castile-
I told you not to fall.
- What's in there?
- Castile soap and borax.
- What's borax?
- It's natural.
It's all natural laundry stuff.
- You wanna get in?
- Yes.
- A laundry.
- You're doin' the laundry.
When she goes to college,
she's gonna be-
You made the water so cold.
- Well, they've been soakin' for three hours.
- Well, this isn't fun.
Come on. It's like crushing grapes.
Come on, get it clean, kids.
- I see something troublesome.
- Troublesome? What?
- Okay. That's all right.
- See? Always lookin' for trouble.
- A laundry.
- We're all doing a laundry.
Don’t your friends think you’re insane?
And I'm trying to imagine-
When they come over
for supper at your house...
for parsnips or whatever it is
you have lying around.
What do your friends say about this?
With no napkins and no toilet paper.
Could you do it?
Nobody has to do what I do.
That's not the important thing.
What I'm doing brings attention to the issue.
But all of us should just learn
to do what we can do.
You're now-What? Five and a half months in.
Next step is to get rid of electricity
and live by daylight alone in New York City.
Saturday-There's a switch in my apartment...
which is the circuit breaker
for the whole apartment.
We're having a little party for our friends,
and we're gonna click the switch off, so, yeah.
We should let everybody know
we're gonna be following Colin...
throughout this long year.
I was gonna get some spinach...
but now that the electricity's going off,
I realize I can't buy a lot of stuff.
I gotta just buy for the next couple of days
because everything will just spoil.
Tonight we're switching off
the electricity...
and I haven't really thought about it,
but I actually feel-
We're moving into the sixth month...
and I'm starting to really
get into the dividends...
and the benefits are really
starting to pour in...
so I'm actually kind of excited,
but I'm sure that-
Talk to me in a day,
and I might be just miserable.
Let's just talk a little bit about
what it's gonna be like.
Well, there's gonna be a transition period
that's hard like everything else.
Hi. Hi, baby.
- How are you?
- How's it goin'?
- Hello! How are you?
- Hi.
"Composed of post-consumer
recycled materials.
Help us help the planet."
Is that not good enough?
Tell me what’s wrong with it.
- It's a disposable cup.
- Yes.
- Non-recyclable top.
And the jacket, and then the-
And then you have two cups, in fact,
it looks like.
- You've broken every rule.
- Every rule there is. Okay.
Have you guys seen our new refrigerator?
- You want one, don't you?
- What's the story?
- What's it called?
- It's called a pot in a pot.
It was invented for use in Nigeria.
And the idea is that the-
The water evaporates from the-
The sand in between the two pots is wet,
and the water evaporates...
and the energy of evaporation
is taken from the inner pot...
which causes it to cool down.
And, for example, a tomato-
which would only last
in Nigeria two days after picking-
in this thing would last three weeks.
And there's a glass of water in there right now,
so we're gonna see if the glass and water-
See, I thought that was part
of the refrigeration.
No, the glass of water’s
in there 'cause we're gonna see...
at the end of the night,
if the glass of water’s cold.
I thought that was like
the nuclear core-
that drove the whole thing.
- Nuclear energy.
- It's not. Okay.
- I got the gist of it.
- Oh, yeah?
And are these from the farmers' market?
Yes.
Okay, here we go.
-Just sit.
- We're fine.
It's colder, but it's not that cold.
Futz with it, I suppose, and see
if there’s a way to make it a bit colder.
This has become my Four Seasons.
I have my lights.
Somebody comes in, empties my garbage.
And there's, you know...
plenty of heat and electricity
and air conditioning.
So now my huge treat has become...
the ice. I'm gonna go show you.
Technically, the ice
shouldn't be allowed either...
but I...
allow myself the ice.
It's really good.
It's tap- New York City tap.
So it's just as good as bottled water.
Probably cleaner and better
than a lot of bottled waters.
It's good to get the ice- But to get it
really cold, you have to wait a little bit.
You guys, I wanna run a story by you.
Basically, I got a really good,
juicy inside dope today.
It's kind of like a "what went wrong" story.
They focused on their weaknesses.
They totally neglected
and under invested in their strengths.
At this point, I just have to just report
the thing to death, right?
And then see what we have midday Monday.
- This is a very big story.
- I know.
This is the first story where I didn't even
think about having to do it without caffeine.
I'm making some progress.
Honey?
Do you remember where you put the matches?
Wait. Hang on. Hang on. Here they are.
I got 'em.
It's kind of really our first
night without the electricity...
'cause last night we had people over, and we
had the electricity for most of the night.
Are you down?
Are you mad at me?
What is it, babe?
It's stupid.
- What, the project's stupid?
- Well, the going without electricity.
Who's gonna go without electricity?
That's dumb.
So that's what's really bothering you?
You're afraid that-
I just think it's gonna be-
I feel like it's a pain in the ass.
It kind of is.
- Can't argue with you there.
- I don't know.
I just feel like
the whole project's a curio-
maybe a curiosity...
but not-
Everybody will have moved on by the time
the book comes out, and-
It's just gonna be another irrelevant book.
Let's just say it turns out
that it's totally stupid.
Right? Okay, I don't think that.
But just worst-case scenario.
So we had a ball.
We've had a ball doing it so far.
It's been hard, but it's been fun, hasn't it?
Yeah, it's been fun.
New York Public Radio,
WNYC, FM and AM New York and wnyc.org.
And the heat index issue
is not just a warning.
The heat is here.
It's already 84 degrees,
and it's only six minutes after 10-
That's gross.
I got home yesterday,
and there was flies all over the apartment.
There was a bunch of flies
reproducing in my worm bin...
and every time I opened the worm bin,
more baby flies flew out.
Oh, my God. Look at 'em.
Oh, my God.
By the way, look at this.
It's all earth. See?
I didn't think that it would work.
It just doesn't work, okay?
There's a reason why
people have refrigerators.
The truth is I'm just mad because I'm-
I'm just devastated about that Google
information about getting pregnant.
The statistics are so low,
and I'm basically turning 40-
and note the gray hair-
and I just feel devastated about it.
And I feel in a sense that somebody like me
would have a five-percent chance...
Iike in any given-
It's gonna work out your way anyway
because the chances are so low.
I totally hear that you're sad,
and I totally understand...
but it feels like a reality show for me,
discussing this issue on camera.
I thought that you wanted
to know how I felt about the pot in the pot.
Well, that's- I totally wanted to know
how you feel about the pot in the pot.
This is how I feel about it.
Our whole thing was that we were gonna
totally support...
who the other person wanted to become, right?
We were gonna kind of be onboard
for each other's dreams.
This is important to you
that we don't have a fridge.
Right?
I'm onboard with that,
and then I feel really bummed...
because I feel like we're
putting all this energy on your dream, right?
And then I'm like-
I'm totally willing to work with you
and talk to you...
about the prospect of having another child
and see where we get to in talking.
But if you’re connecting it
to the project, I-
It's tied together for me.
They're totally connected.
So if they’re not connected for you, then-
If I've got this right, you feel as though
you support me, but I don't support you.
I don't support your dreams.
I feel like this is my biggest,
most important, most precious thing.
- Right.
- And I feel like-
Yeah, you don't wanna do it, so-
So it's kind of like no. The answer's no.
Well, I want to want what you want.
But I don't feel like
it would be good for our family...
for me to just say,
"Okay, you want it, so I'll do it"...
when I have such strong feelings about it.
Do you wanna move this out then?
That's okay, honey. We're just gonna leave
that there just for now, okay?
Okay.
The pot in the pot has been moved out.
And this is our latest refrigerator.
To keep it cold,
I mooched ice off of my neighbor Hilary.
Do you need to come and get it every day?
Or how do you wanna-
I think this will last
a little while in the cooler.
Yeah. I hope so. I think so.
- Okay.
- Can I carry the bag?
Yeah, yeah.
You can carry the bag. Let's put the freezer-
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
- Say thank you to Hilary, honey.
- Thank you.
Bye. You're welcome. Bye, sweetie.
Okay. Perfect.
We're gonna take the ice pack
and put it right on top...
so that your milk stays nice and cold.
And you wanna just drop the cubes on there?
Drop 'em? One by one?
One by one.
The refrigerator is my bottom.
The pot in the pot. And now the-
I don't know what I hate more-
the pot in the pot or this.
I'm not sure.
Just mooching power and ice cubes.
So I kind of don't get it.
I'm kind of like, "What?"
Say, "Bye, wacko fridge."
Bye, wacko fridge.
Who cheats more-you or Colin?
I'm sure I have to cheat more.
Like this.
I tried a vegetable dye at home,
but it was a disaster.
- Right.
- He doesn't really cheat.
He'll bend the rules a little,
but that to him wouldn't be a cheat.
There's no trips this year
because we can't go anywhere.
So he decides that we're
gonna make an exception...
and we're gonna go up to the farm
where they grow all our food.
We walked to Penn Station with our luggage.
This is when the slip started.
I go to Dunkin' Donuts.
There's this huge line.
I give the lady this huge tip, and I'm like,
"Could you refill this glass twice?"
I get two huge decafs,
and I knock them back at Dunkin' Donuts.
- Hooking you up.
- And there's 10 people behind me.
But I gave her such a good tip
that she was just my girl for a while.
But I was like-
I don't wanna be putting our energy
into the pot in the pot.
I wanna be having another kid.
I don't wanna spend my vacation on a farm.
When we got married,
I was like, "Look, Colin, I'll marry you.
But there's one thing. I don't like camping.
I'm never going camping with you."
But now our whole house
has turned into a campground.
And also I don't really like nature.
And now for our vacation,
we're going into nature.
We're gonna see and work with all the food
that we eat from the farmers' market.
This is the farm where it comes from.
Hi. A cow. Cow.
- You can put your hand out and touch him.
- Hi, cow.
Thank you so much for having us.
- My pleasure.
- We're having the best time already.
We've only been here for an hour.
As you work to steward this land...
you are growing a very vital...
dynamic being...
that's in balance.
It's a closed-loop system.
The cows eat the grass.
They give you milk,
but they also give you manure.
The manure's composted.
It becomes the fertility.
We make about 400 tons of compost per year.
And smell it.
Yeah, it just smells like earth.
It smells like my worm bin, actually.
You say though a lot that this kind of is
the realization of his values?
- Yeah.
- Do you-
How do you feel about it now,
six months into that?
- Do you still-
- I feel like there's no going back.
There's no going back. Right? Right?
This is for our family.
It's not just about the project.
- Where are you from?
- I live in the city.
I hope to be more of a help
than a hindrance.
Let's go!
That's Henry. That's the Bull.
Come on, Henry. Let's go.
It's good to escort Henry into the barn.
The night before we left, the farmer and Colin
were having a conversation.
They were talking about how the valley once
was populated with sheep.
And they were also talking about how people
could devolve into animals.
And I just felt so transported
by this conversation.
And we went to bed that night
with the beautiful farm air...
and the beautiful farmhouse
with the beautiful people...
who treated us like we were family...
and I dreamt that I was one of the sheep.
It's weird, 'cause
my grandparents were farmers.
They were homesteaders.
And I started feeling like-
I feel like my family...
left something back there.
And I was like,
"I feel like I'm going back to get it."
When I listened to the farmer
talking about the herd...
and how sometimes that something will happen
to one of the cattle but the herd goes on...
I just felt like I woke up.
I felt like I got
to reconnect with something.
A company loaned me
this solar panel for the project.
I can't change the way that electricity
is delivered to my house.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
The solar panel will provide
just enough electricity...
so that I can power my computer
and write my blog.
But what's really interesting
about this phase...
is that it's the first time
that I've realized...
that it's not about using as little
as we can possibly use...
but finding a way to get what I need
in a sustainable way.
And that's what we need to do
with my electricity, with the solar panel.
But that's also what we need to do
with our systems.
We just need to figure out
how to get people what they need...
in a way that doesn't harm the planet.
Tell that guy to get out of the bike lane.
Do you wanna know what I gave her
for her 40th birthday?
No birth control. You know what I'm saying?
We call it Russian Roulette.
Now the question is, is
it click-click or bang-bang?
If it's bang-bang, I die, she lives.
Watch out on your right for a lunatic.
My blog post today was about
opportunities in the crisis.
Imagine if we made the city nicer to live in.
So the two comments on the post so far are:
"Let's be realistic.”
You can't make
a city nice, so forget it.
There's such a lack of idealism.
But I think realism’s got us where we are.
You know what I'm saying?
That helps.
You okay, Michelle?
- Watch out, honey.
- I know. I know.
- It's so quiet.
- I know.
- That's Fort Tilden over there?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God. This is like the Hamptons.
- It's better than the Hamptons.
- 'Cause there's no one here.
Oh, my God. How radical is this?
And this is still New York City.
We're in New York City.
Bug!
Will you go swimming with me?
To me, it's amazing how resilient nature is.
There's sandpipers on this beach,
and everybody's trying to survive.
And there's these sand crabs,
and they're in New York City.
- You see the two of ‘em?
- Yep, I see it.
Yep. I see.
People keep talking about,
"What's the hardest thing?"
"Are you depriving yourself?"
As though all these aspects
of the project are hard.
But it's not about deprivation.
It's not about not taking care of yourself.
It's the opposite.
It's about seeing is it possible
to have a good life...
without wasting so much.
Colin met this amazing woman at the
farmers’ market who loaned us her tricycle.
We can roll. It totally changed our life.
We have no TV, no lights,
no electricity, no air conditioning.
These were all the things
that kept us inside.
We're kind of forced
out of the apartment all the time now.
The days feel like they just last forever.
- What are those?
- They're fireflies.
They light.
- You playing gin rummy?
- Playing gin rummy.
Now, I wanna show you something, okay?
This is what you call "kicking Dad's ass."
Okay?
We're coming from vastly different spaces.
No one is ever gonna be as naive-
naively hopeful and naively optimistic
as we were in the late '60s.
But I think there might
be something kind of similar...
but more muted that's happening now.
Not in the same way at all.
But I feel like there's a certain...
quiet beginning of a rebellion happening.
The other thing is to point out
is this on the garlic.
This is called a scape-S-C-A-P-E.
I would suggest you take home
one or two of those.
- Okay.
- These are the beans.
You can see how they're
grabbing the pole.
- And see this?
- Yeah.
It's starting to make tomatoes.
Are you overall optimistic about humankind,
or skeptical?
I'm of the belief that it's always 50/50.
Right.
- That, in fact, some things are getting better.
- Right.
Some things are getting worse.
Yeah.
Every time you try to do something right,
no matter what level you're on-
- Right.
- there are unforeseen results.
My hesitation about your work...
is that it enables people
to fool themselves-
that all they have to do
is change the light bulb-
and recycle their plastic bag.
Well, as long as they feel that way,
no politician will pick it up.
And I feel that it's completely true,
that it's both.
You need to have-
I think that there's a tremendous-
If you have a political stance...
then there's a tremendous integrity to living
in a way that reflects that political stance.
- At the risk of being too personal, but-
- Right.
It's not. It's just the facts.
- Michelle writes for Business Week.
- Yes.
Millions of trees are cut down
on a regular basis...
in order to promote the thoroughly
fallacious propaganda...
that American corporate capitalism...
is good for the people- good for you and me.
Now, if it’s your contention...
that she makes up for it, that evens out...
because she doesn't take the elevator
in your Fifth Avenue co-op...
I have to say you’re
either dishonest or delusional.
There's definitely an irony...
or a paradox involved in that, but-
Where did all this crap come from?
American corporate capitalism did all of it.
If anybody really thought...
that you were gonna have an impact there...
you wouldn't be getting
the attention you're getting.
And here's our No Impact Man, Colin Beavan
in the No Impact S.U.V.
Wait a minute. I got to check this out.
You may be on my show, but I'm not here
to spread your particular gospel.
'Cause I think what you're doing
is extremely dangerous, okay?
Oh, there we go. That's good.
- Now I've got you all set up so I can see you.
- I can see a little bit.
- A little bit.
I'm gonna hold something up
for you to see more.
- It's disgusting.
- No, it's not.
It looks like shit from here.
Yeah, it is shit. It's worm shit.
I think that my only connection
to food before the project was eating it.
I really ate all my food
pretty much at restaurants...
or out of take-out containers.
I never cooked it. I never prepared it.
I never thought about it.
I never composted it.
I never thought about the waste.
Now that I go to the farmers' market,
I know all the people who grow our food.
I kind of have this little desire
to take it to the next level.
I'm seeing today as just the first succession,
the first lesson.
So we're gonna just make some-
I'm just thinking
of a few things that we can make.
So start with the green beans.
Just snap off just this end.
- So snap off the kind of uglier end-this end.
- Exactly.
See? Here are the dandelion greens.
I'm gonna just snip the ends off.
- I'm just gonna cut off the end. Okay?
- Okay.
- Great.
- Nicely done.
Preheat it to 375, but honestly,
I might turn it up a little towards the end.
I'm gonna make coffee, but I
know you don't want any, right?
Oh, yeah. I'll have a little.
Yeah. I can have just a little bit.
But there's a reason
why I can only have a little bit.
I wonder if you guys can guess the reason.
-Just have a little bit of coffee.
- Are you pregnant?
Oh, my God. You are?
- Oh, my God! That's so great!
- I know.
Oh, my God.
I'm so happy for you.
- I wanna go out.
- Dad's gonna take you out, love.
Dad's gonna take you out.
I'm just gonna put them on.
I love tomatoes.
I'm making dinner tonight,
and I've actually never made dinner for us.
Do you want me to show you
how to get that oven to get to 350 or 375?
It's a little tricky.
- Why don’t you just do the oven to 350, 375?
- Okay.
Yep. Yep. Okay. That's a good trick.
Okay, and then if you wanna be sure,
there's a thermometer down there.
- Oh, that's nice.
- It tells you what the temperature of the oven is.
- We really love our eggplant.
- We really love our egg.
It might not work out,
but you have to learn and grow.
Tonight, I'm just focused on trying to learn
how to roast the vegetables.
Bye! Bye.
I feel a little performance anxiety.
I wonder if I should cut these off or-
I feel really nauseous.
My whole life I've been looking for gurus
or this program or that thing or-
I've always been kind of like looking
for something.
I feel like we're looking for that thing together,
and we're kind of like finding some of it.
I have to admit that there were times
when I was this asshole.
I had a lot of moments.
Now I think what he's doing is so cool.
I get a big kick out of him.
I just think he's, like-
Not quite done yet.
- Madame and monsieur.
- Oui.
- More cheese on my bread, please.
- More cheese on your bread?
Just the idea that you can park with
other things besides cars.
The idea is, why are we dedicating this land
to cars instead of people?
Could you imagine if this extended
all the way up to Seventh Avenue?
We started the positive
impact stage of the project.
The idea is no net environmental impact.
So that's reduce our negative impact
and increase our positive impact.
And it's not meant to be scientific.
It's just meant to be philosophical.
Can I live on this planet
doing more good than harm?
I've been helping with a research project...
to do with putting oysters back in the Hudson
River, which will filter the water.
I went cleaning out tree pits in the Bronx.
I was, like, "What a crock of shit
No Impact Man is as a project."
There's this network of people
who have been working on this stuffforever.
Once you no longer live in the ignorance...
that when you throw something away,
it actually goes away-
It's just a really difficult thing...
because, yes, your piece of trash comes
to a community like this where it's processed.
Most people, as they consume...
don't understand what the real costs
of those goods are.
The pollution that was created to make it.
The health effects
that were associated with it.
We're the point sources
for all the greenhouse gases...
that everybody's trying to curb right now.
I think that we should
be spending more time...
recognizing that people's lives
are being compromised every single day...
and have been for decades.
1 2,000 trucks a day
go through that neighborhood.
The diesel particulates in the air
are causing asthma in kids...
causing brain damage in kids.
When I started this project, I just thought
I was just gonna make less garbage...
not travel so much,
and "wouldn't I be a hero" sort of thing.
And I-
I guess I wasn't so clear
on how many issues it was gonna open up.
I'm not talking about the polar bears.
I'm not talking about the people
in faraway island communities...
who are gonna be hurt
when the ocean levels rise.
I'm talking about people
who already are living with the effects...
of our over-consumptive society.
If you’d asked me nine months ago...
would I ever have my baby be on a bike,
and I would say no.
Absolutely not. That's insane.
And I remember going off
on the bike messengers.
"Those fucking bike messengers.
They're fucking insane."
And "Anybody who would
ride a bike in New York is fucking insane."
And "They're making it really unsafe-
the bikers- for us car people...
Iike SUV renters, they're making it
really fucking unsafe for us."
And that's my world view.
And now my world view
has completely flipped on its head.
The streets have totally been taken over,
and they're not for people.
And then the rapacious consumption
for consumption's sake...
and the coma that that induces.
I'm just rethinking everything
in terms of what’s important.
Do you feel that moving forward...
that you’ll somehow-
You feel like there's some other way
of considering your decisions?
Yeah. I mean-
You know, well, now-
What am I gonna do,
just say, "Well, I don't care"?
Fixing it so that we get the most...
sun that we can.
A big question at the center
of the No Impact experiment...
was whether one person can make a difference.
One of the things
that I really get worried about...
when people talk about the fact
that individual action is not important...
is that the thing about individual action
is that it causes people to be engaged.
Our society is not set up
to live sustainably.
We need more mass transit,
higher-efficiency vehicles...
no more coal-burning power plants.
These are hard changes.
The International Panel on Climate Change...
says that we need an 80% cut
in carbon emissions by 2050.
That's huge.
As your constituent,
the first thing that I wanted to do...
was I wanted to thank you
for sponsoring the energy bill, because-
- You're welcome.
- that gives us a good-
Good solid bill.
Using less is a start, but it's not enough.
We need to demand that our systems
become sustainable.
You can rock here. Let me rock you, okay?
Do you wanna rock while you look at Frankie?
We told Isabella...
we thought Michelle had a baby in her tummy,
but we were wrong.
She didn't actually.
I guess it was the second time
we went to the doctor.
The first time we went to the doctor,
everything was fine.
And then the second time
we went to the doctor-
- Well, it wasn't that every-
- there was no heartbeat.
Yeah. The second-
There wasn't one. There was no heartbeat.
Where are you going?
From the perspective of the story, it would
have been the perfect ender of the story.
I finally kind of cross over into No Impact...
and really embrace it,
and that's what Colin really wanted.
And then I got pregnant,
and that's what I would have really wanted.
And then the project winds down.
It's all kind of in this really great bow.
And it's not a bow.
It's a big loose end.
So it's a loose end.
It's a narrative loose end
and a spiritual loose end.
Just a loose end.
A lot of loose ends in life.
I think we’ll probably try again.
They're like rainbows.
Is that like rainbows on your feet?
Rainbows on my feet.
The official swan song of the garden
is when you turn the soil over in the fall.
That's the official end of the season.
It's kind of interesting,
because we're coming back...
to the food that we were eating
when the project started...
which is squash
and root vegetables and stuff like that.
And, similarly, the garden is getting turned.
So you actually-You kind of-
It's not like you turn the calendar page,
and you can tell that a year has passed.
You feel that a year has passed...
because you’re recognizing
something about the Earth.
We're so disconnected, I think, in the city
from the natural rhythms.
I didn't know this before, but it's actually
a great pleasure to be connected.
It's freezing in here.
It's November 7,
and we're almost done, and I'm cold.
So a lot of times what I do is I-
See, I've just got home from work.
I'm wearing a suit.
But I come in here,
and I get in the covers.
I spend a lot of time
under the covers when it's cold.
We don't talk about it ending.
It's funny because we're gonna be
separated when it ends.
Because when it ends, for me, I'm getting
on a plane to go see my parents...
who I haven't seen in a year.
And Colin will be here,
and I'm taking Isabella.
So we- It's funny.
We haven't really talked about it.
But everybody on the outside
asks me about it.
- Hello?
- What's up, sugar pop?
There's not any light in here.
I can't see.
I'm looking forward to reading
in bed with Isabella...
with ample illumination.
Ample illumination.
You're not tired, are you?
Next week,
there's this school thing happening at NYU.
Something like 200 NYU students
are gonna try and live No Impact for a week.
I think that's so cool.
So on Sunday, I go, and we have kind
of a workshop about how to do it.
And then the following Monday,
I go and I give a big talk.
Room 206.
And this week, as you experiment, I think
you're gonna see that it's not so bad.
My experiment only lasts two more weeks.
As I come out of the extreme, some of this
stuff that we've given up, we'll take back.
But that fact is
that the balance will be there.
We are gonna be substantially
causing less environmental impact...
and without adversely
affecting our happiness.
The fact of the matter is that if only I change,
it's not gonna make a difference.
But the hope is that if each of us
as individuals change...
it's going to inspire everybody to change.
So I believe the most radical political act
there is, is to be an optimist.
The most radical political act
there is, is to believe that if I change...
other people will follow suit.
The reason why I'm here
is because a first-grader called Olive...
wrote to me on my blog
and asked me if I would come.
People ask me, "If I can just do
one thing, what should it be?
Not use plastic bags
or not use plastic cups?"
I would say if there
was only one thing to do...
it would be to volunteer
with an environmental organization.
Part of the reason for that
is because there's community.
I believe very strongly that a lot of the
environmental problems in our planet...
have come because
of the breakdown of community.
Because without community,
none of us feel accountable to anybody else.
All of us are interconnected
on many levels.
If you’re religious, then you
understand that at a religious level.
But even if you’re just practical,
you can see that we're interconnected.
If I splash a puddle and you're
standing next to it, it splashes you.
If I make pollution,
you have to breathe it in.
My mind wants to tell me that I'm
the only one that's important, you know?
So I have to keep teaching myself over and
over and over again that that's not true.
And then when you turn the light on,
are all the lights gonna go on?
Most of them. I tried to set it up
so most of the lights come on.
As soon as you do that,
they're all gonna go on?
No. I have to do a few flicks.
'Cause there's more than one circuit breaker.
So you have to hit three circuit breakers,
and then they all will be on?
- Yes.
- So we should light this. Okay.
It's been-
Well, it hasn't really been a year...
because the electricity phase started
around month six.
So it's been six months
since we've had electricity.
So it's gratitude for small pleasures.
There we go.
I have to say I was really skeptical
about a lot of things in the beginning.
And I thought they were insane
and really stupid.
And I hated and resented you,
alternatively, for them.
But I really, really wanna keep the biking.
I wanna keep as much
as we possibly can the no garbage.
And I really, really
wanna keep the farmers' market.
I wanna be a vegetarian, but I wanna be-
I wanna have a hot dog now and then.
I would be a vege-
a "vegehogian" or a "vegedogian."
I'd like to not have TV in the house,
but I can't wait to go to the movies.
And when we're on vacation, that thing is on.
- There are some things I have some issues with.
- Yeah?
Why can't we take those worms back?
Because they do make
"Lord of the Fleas" in the kitchen.
And also there are some things that we're
just not gonna be able to do maybe...
and that might be one of them.
'Cause I get to make
some decisions around here.