PeG@SuS
Resync by : kang Dadan
pilemhade.blogspot.com
ALAT ELEKTRONIK MURAH & BERKUALITAS :
GPS, Kalkulator, Telepon, Perkakas, HT/WT, dll.
handycom-it.blogspot.com
Belanja Barang Murah & Original :
https://www.bukalapak.com/pegasus_bl
https://www.tokopedia.com/unicorn-shop-bdg
Way to hustle, Toby!
Wait! Look to pass!
Look to pass.. look...
Melissa's there.
Pass to your teammate!
In Del Rio, Texas,
saturdays were all about soccer.
Fresh cut oranges,
- screaming parents,
- Defense.
cheecy uniforms...
- teamwork and winning.
- Good goal, nice goal.
I used to live for those games...
and then one day,
I just stopped caring.
That's alright. Good game.
Good game, girls.
- It's okay Toby.
- No, it's not.
It's just a game.
You can't always believe
everything my dad says.
He might pretend it's...
all about how you play the game,
but trust me
he likes to win.
Hey, get your gringo hands
off my cousin.
Casper. Oh girls, this weeks practice
the sheriff's gonna bring pizza.
Shh.
Acting sheriff.
Hey, good game today, hombre.
Yeah, they...
they played well.
But you know,
we'll get them next time.
What do I owe you?
Hot dogs are ready!
Oh, coach, this is on me.
Oh.
Thank you.
You're a good man, Hector.
Here we go.
Hot dogs all around.
- Where's Toby?
- Uh... I don't know...
I don't know,
she's around here somewhere.
- You want me to find...
- No, I'll find her.
Oh! Sorry.
Sorry about that.
Girls are gonna go
all the way, coach.
Regionals, nationals,
mundial.
Well, we, uh... just gotta get...
we just gotta get through the season.
Toby, get away from there.
You will never ever
come back here again, okay?
Dad, this stuff
is kinda cool.
Trust me, that stuff
is anything but cool.
But Melissa says you can pray
for anything there,
even for things you'd
never ask the Virgin for.
Hey!
Anything you wanna talk about?
You are a young woman.
Your mother in heaven
would be so proud of you.
Toby, you in there?
- Y... yeah, Dad.
- Okay.
After today,
nothing in your life
will ever be the same again.
- You both in there?
- Yes.
What are you guys doing?
Jack, sweetie,
give us a minute, okay?
- Alright, alright.
- God, dad.
Period.
- Nice shot.
- Thanks.
Well, at least
you still play video games.
Dad, no.
Okay, I'm sorry.
No.
Okay, fine.
Go.
The witch is coming.
On nights like this,
my father used to say...
Which means?
It's so foggy
that even the ghosts...
need candles.
I hope Toby
remembers me that way.
She will.
Some things
you never forget.
Yeah.
That's not what I meant.
That's what I meant.
I love you, mommy.
Good night.
Eye on the prize, baby.
Eye on the prize.
So as we look at
this years budget,
I'm reminded
of a little credo...
we follow here at
Del Rio Savings & Loan.
As Yogi Bear used to say,
A nickel ain't worth a dime anymore".
- It's Yogi Berra.
- Oh, dad, same thing.
It's okay, honey,
it sounded really good.
- It did?
- Yeah.
It sounded really good
at breakfast.
It sounded really good,
last night.
Dad!
- Take it off.
- No no. No, dad, it's just lipstick.
Yeah, and the next thing you know,
it's just a nose ring.
Jack!
Sorry dear, you're gonna
have to stick to lip gloss... for now.
- See? That's better.
- For you, maybe.
I'll see you at practice.
Anyway, as Yogi Berra used to say,
"A nickel ain't worth a dime anymore".
Yeah, well,
I think that's it, so...
let's, uh... stop yapping
and start mingling.
Thank you.
Come see me at the bank.
Hey!
Sorry I'm late.
Hey, coach.
What's going on?
- It's Toby... we can't find her.
- What?
We were kicking some balls around
and she lost hers over there somewhere.
When she didn't come back,
we looked for her a long time.
Jesus, I told you, you gotta keep
an eye on the girls, when I'm not here.
- I know, I know.
- There must be some explanation, Jack.
She's probably gone home,
because she doesn't feel well.
Yeah, well, we've been looking.
- We went all the way down to the river...
- Where's Melissa?
- Melissa's right over there.
- Okay.
Well, she might have
gone to Heather's place..
- Look, Jack...
- Hang on, hang on.
There's no answer at home.
Hey, Jack listen,
look, we found the ball...
Where exactly
did the ball go over the fence?
- Right over there.
- Okay, thank you.
- Now look, maybe we...
- She's gonna be fine, Hector, okay?
We had a little spat this morning,
she's probably just hiding down here
to pay me back.
Yeah, my Carmen's the same way.
Alright, just keep going down!
I'm going back to the parking lot.
Toby! Toby!
Wade across to the other side!
Hey, look at this!
Gracias.
If somebody's taken her, I don't know
what I'm gonna do. I just don't know.
- Sweetie...
- She wouldn't just disappear like this.
- Not for this long.
- It's only been a couple of hours.
Toby will be okay.
That's easy for you to say,
she's not your daughter.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that.
- I just...
- I know.
- I just, uh...
Any... any footprints?
Two sets.
Dogs tracked them up...
to the parking lot,
then they disappear.
- Forensics is checking it out now.
- Okay.
Right, uh...
um... keep me posted.
Sheriff, Department of Public Safety
returning on line two.
- Sex offenders.
- Oh.
Hey, uh... Navarro here,
I was wondering if you all could...
fax over an updated list
of the registered sex offenders in, uh...
in like a 100 mile radius?
How about I send a file.
- Great, thanks.
- No problems.
What... what is all this?
What am I signing?
This is the department's
press release,
And this next one... is an official
request for additional deputies.
Sir, they're here.
Hey, Mindy.
what would, uh... Sheriff Fernandez do
in a situation like this?
You're doing fine, sir.
- How old is Toby?
- Eleven.
- She'll be twelve in April.
Gray sweatpants
and a T-shirt.
- What?
- I think it was pink.
Why would she run away?
Any history of drug
or alcohol abuse?
- Toby? No, never.
- Are you sure?
- What about her friends?
- Toby doesn't do drugs.
- How do you know?
- How do I know? She's my daughter.
- That's how I know?
- What about Toby's mother.
- Does she have a family?
- She's an orphan..
When she was a baby.
Toby's biological mother died of cancer.
- She's dead.
- Casper introduced us.
- We've been married three years.
- Toby was our flower girl.
She was born at Saint Margaret's.
It's in Oklahoma City.
Do you have a criminal record?
- No.
- Bar fights?
- Anyone you might have pissed off?
- No, Not... no no. Nothing.
- Ever fight in front of your child?
- Do you ever hit your wife?
What the fuck?
- What about Toby? You ever hit her?
- Do you ever cheat on your wife?
- Ever cheat on your husband?
- No, I don't cheat on my wife.
This is Karen De La Rosa
from the Victims' Assistance Unit.
Hello.
Now, before we head up there,
you should know...
that if somebody did take Toby,
whoever that is
may be watching this broadcast.
It's important to be clear
and mention specifics.
- Mr. and Mrs. Bishop, did she run away,
- Now I know this is...
- hard to face.
- or do you think somebody took her?
Toby, if...
Toby, if you are watching this
right now...
we love you,
come on home.
Please, uh... whoever you are,
if you have our Toby, just...
just please
send her home to us.
Please, God, find Toby...
and lead her
back home safely...
to her loving family.
- In the name of the Father...
- Honey, you there?
Sorry.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
- Amen.
- Thank you all for coming.
- Thank you.
- God bless you.
- Thank you, father.
Gracias, Padre, and thank you
for organizing the prayer chain.
It means a lot to us.
I want you both to know
the church is here for you.
Padre, I...
we feel so helpless.
Is there anything else
we should be doing?
Trust in the Lord.
Whatever happens,
its Gods will.
Yikes!
What is that?
Jess Lien's work?
No sir... Jess was strictly boys,
if you know what I mean.
What about old Fred Walker.
No, he's still
serving time upstate.
These girls here are victims
of Redd Holden.
He's registered
in Lone Eagle.
Should we visit him?
That's him.
- Hey, Redd.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Long night?
- What I that now?
Yeah, just top it off.
That's good.
Hey, Mary Alice,
what's going on in there?
Now, Roy, you know, you're not
gonna get anything out of me.
Come on.
Rooted in Tupeto
a slum of Mexico City,
Santa Muerte is a centuries-old mix
of pagan rituals and Catholicism.
Mexican police say it is popular
with prostitutes and drug dealers.
Several recent revenge killings
have been connected to the sect.
The Catholic Church condemns
Santa Muerte as devil worship.
But despite the Church's best efforts,
the cult is growing.
So, what do you think?
No alibi,
a rap sheet a mile long...
what do you think I think?
24-hour surveillance?
Right.
We have to know
Any news?
No.
There's this old woman
just across the border in Mexico.
My grandma used to take me
to see her when I was little.
She sees things.
- Come on, Amaya.
- Come on what?
These... these people,
they just... they just...
they just tell you
what you wanna hear.
How do you know?
Have you ever actually
gone to someone like that?
- No.
- Well... what if she can help?
I mean...
What have we got to lose?
I'm just... You know, I'm just gonna
leave this conversation right here.
Hey, wait, wait.
Let me get this straight.
You want to leave this to God's will,
like Father Salinas said?
Or do you want
to do something about it?
Oh, no no!
Madre will see you now.
She said that
I'm not Toby mother.
What?
That's it?
She wants your hand, sweetie.
Gracias, Dońa.
Gracias.
- That was a waste of time.
- Honey, she saw something.
Whatever she saw,
she didn't see Toby.
God damn it,
I can't even park in my own place...
As long as I've got
two men coming in...
Come on!
- Casper.
- Jack, um...
this is the special agent Wilson,
special agent Nakamura.
They're gonna take over
from here on in.
- What about you?
- We're still on the case,
it's just that the FBI is gonna be
spearheading the investigation.
Sir, uh... what can you do
what the sheriff can't?
Well, ma'am,
agent Nakamura and myself...
have over 20 years combined
experience in these type of cases.
Now...
we have a few questions.
To look at her, you never would've known
Toby's mother was even sick.
She was very pretty.
We understand that
the last time you saw Toby...
you were arguing.
- I mean, she's... she's 11.
- But she left angry?
Yes, but that's not unusual.
I mean, you guys have kids, right?
Then you know what it's like.
What about work? Anyone that you
may have denied a loan to?
You can't approve every loan,
but I think the system's
more then fair.
I mean, I can't...
I can't imagine anyone, no.
So there's... no one you can think of
who might have a vendetta against you?
Well, if they do,
it's news to me.
Hello?
They found something.
We just got this in this morning,
one of the parents had a video camera.
Does anything look unusual to you?
No.
No, that's Heather's dad
and Peggy's mom.
What about that big guy
in the back there?
No, he's fine...
Melissa's uncle.
Could you back it up,
um... please, sir?
There...
that white van
in the parking lot.
Didn't Redd Holden drive a white van?
- No sign of the girl!
- Who's Gomez?
You are?
You were told to have this place
under 24-hour surveillance.
Serously, I was only gone,
or like 5 minutes.
That's all it takes, asshole!
- Wilson!
- What?
You gotta see this.
Great, check it.
I... I don't understand,
how could this happen?
- Jack.
- No, no, no.
How... how could you just
let him go like that?
He was supposed to be
under 24-hour surveillance.
Unfortunately, mistakes
were made on the local level...
- before we got here.
- Oh, you can say that again.
A real sheriff
wouldn't let that happen.
That's not fair.
Casper inherited those deputies
when Hernandez died.
Besides... we don't even know
if this guy has Toby.
Oh, this is the guy
that took her.
This is the guy that has Toby,
I know it.
Look, I can assure you both, we have
everything we need on the suspect.
He won't slip through
our fingers again.
I have one more question.
We're having a hard time finding your
first wife Katie's death certificate.
Do you happen to have a copy?
No.
Do you remember the name
of the hospital where she died?
- Saint Margaret's.
- What about the funeral home?
Uh... give me a sec, um...
Do you remember
where she was buried?
No, uh... no.
You don't remember where
your first wife was buried?
No, I... can't...
can't you just look it up?
We tried.
Well, I don't know what to say,
um... try harder.
Bueno.
Josefina, telefono!
Josefina!
Bueno.
Si, Josefina.
Come on!
Go!
You know this guy?
No, why?
We missed it the first time,
I took a second this morning.
Nobody seems to know who he is.
You know,
I have seen this guy before.
He was at the town aqoare
a couple of days back...
playing loteria
with some friends.
- You saw him?
- Yeah,
he made some joke about the girls
going to the World Cup or something.
He talked real fast,
sounded like a Yaqui.
- Yaqui?
- From Sonora, Yaqui Indian.
Yeah, I know who they are.
I'll get this printed up.
I'll fax it down
to a buddy of mine in Mexico,
see what he can dig up.
10 dollars on number 12.
Ho-ho! Awesome ride
you got there, dude.
My old man used to have one
just like it.
What's that,
a Tradesman 200?
Ernesto Huerta...
better known as Calvo.
Our guy's got quite a record.
I may need to cross the border,
you wanna come with?
Just the two of us?
Yeah, well, the FBI's got a lot
on their plate right now.
Besides... they don't have
any pull where we're going.
You know, that was
a good call back there...
you know,
the Yaqui thing.
Especially for a guy
who doesn't speak any Spanish.
Anita from the bank,
her, uh... husband's Yaqui.
Yeah?
I thought he was Guatemalan?
Nope, Yaqui.
Alright, alright, Lumi.
You gotta go before
I write you another citation.
Adios, Chief Detective.
Hey, oh, this is my, uh...
cousin's husband, Jack.
Ah, si, si, I'm sorry
to hear about your daughter.
Casper tells me that you're looking
-for a Yaqui from Calvo.
You've come to the right place.
Can't toss a dwarf in Acuna
without hitting a Yaqui.
Come on, follow me.
Roberto?
Ha sido un tiempo.
żComo estas?
- No, yo no hablo Espańol.
- Yo estoy Carolina,
- from the house in Tempe...
- I'm sorry, I... I don't know you.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna need two
for like, later on, alright?
They're ready.
- Ah, Detective Sanchez.
- Canta.
My American friends here
are looking for a girl.
Uh, uh, uh, you know
we don't sell girls here.
- Not that kind of girl.
- His daughter.
She was kidnapped
a couple days ago in Del Rio.
Oh, kidnapped.
She's pretty.
And this...
this is our suspect,
Calvo Huerta.
Doesn't ring any bells.
Well, I'm gonna leave it here...
in case any bells
start to ring.
Hey!
Does anybody work here?
Hello!
Suspect in the apduction
earlier this week...
of the 11-year-old Toby Bishop.
The suspect is a
convicted sex offender...
Be right there, bud.
He was last seen
driving a white van,
- licence plate number 6-7-0...
- Hey, that's 5 dollars, thanks.
...U-H-D.
We now return you to our
regular scheduled program...
already in progress.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You want any, uh...
ketchup or hot sauce with that?
No.
PeG@SuS
Translated by : robbinsan
pilemhade.blogspot.com
ALAT ELEKTRONIK MURAH & BERKUALITAS :
GPS, Kalkulator, Telepon, Perkakas, HT/WT, dll.
handycom-it.blogspot.com
Belanja Barang Murah & Original :
https://www.bukalapak.com/pegasus_bl
https://www.tokopedia.com/unicorn-shop-bdg
You all have so many
cute pictures of Toby,
but I haven't seen a picture
of Jack when he was little.
Or even you
for that matter.
Don't you get a day off?
Usually Mondays,
but the county does let me stay
with the families, as long as I'm needed.
And I also wanna make sure that I'm doing
everything that's necessary, just...
Karen, give us a minute, please?
- Oh, yeah, of course.
- Thank you.
What the hell is this?
I picked it up in front
of the place downtown.
- You know, that old bakery?
- Yeah.
What were you doing down there?
Everybody at the rosary
was talking about it.
And I just... wanted to see
what it was all about.
So much of this suff...
is about revenge.
Hey...
you don't wanna get
mixed up with that stuff.
Have you ever thought
what you'd do...
if you were face to face
with the people who took Toby?
Face to face?
I'd kill them.
Where is she?
Who?
Where's who?
- I didn't do anything.
- Yeah,
how'd you get those fuckin'
scratches on your face?
Cover me.
Does...
does this look familier?
No.
No, I don't think so.
But Toby's always
trading things with Heather.
It could be hers.
Is that... is that blood?
We do not know, I'm gonna send it out
to the state lab and get it tested.
They're pretty fast.
We should know someting
by to... by tomorrow.
Keep moving.
Jack!
Right this way.
Wrong answer.
I told you, I ain't never seen
that girl before in my life.
- I told you...
- You remember these?
The last time you were
a guest of the state, your, uh...
your buddies beat you so bad,
you spent 6 months
in the infirmary.
You know that one call from me
will put you right back there, right?
When the DNA comes back,
we're gonna know everything.
So if I were you,
I'd, uh... come clean now...
and safe youself...
another serious beating down the road,
you know what I mean?
Alright...
I picked up a girl...
at a rest stop.
She was a runaway.
She was...
pretty high on sometin'.
And we had some fun.
Then things got outta hand.
She scrached me,
then she run off.
But I didn't fuckin' kill her!
We need to talk.
And I sure as hell
never seen this girl here.
Carolina?
Carolina.
Come on.
Come in here.
Tell mamma everything.
Hey! Quero.
This won't take long.
Thank you all for coming.
As you know, we are here tonight
as a community...
to send a message of hope
to our...
Isn't it funny
how people get all religious...
when things go wrong?
guide our beloved Toby
back home...
A vigil... with candles
and prayers was a nice idea...
but what they didn't know...
was that there really are some things
you can't ask the Virgin for.
Thank you.
Um... uh...
First... I'd like to say that my
husband and I... are very grateful,
for the huge... outpouring
of love... and support...
- we've received these last few days.
- Guys...
please, we're in the middle
of a vigil.
This won't take long.
The hospital you told us about,
Saint Margaret's,
burned to the ground
five years ago.
Not a sigle record left.
Never could find that death certificate
of Toby's mother either.
You must have spelled
the name wrong.
Well, then we must have spelled
your name wrong too...
because couldn't find
your birth certificate.
No high school records,
college, bar taps, gas bills,
- not even a library card.
- We moved around a lot.
Well, according to our research,
Jack Bishop didn't even exist...
until about 10 years ago.
- I don't know what to say...
- Am I under arrest?
- No.
- Not yet.
Then if you'll excuse me.
I think my husband
should say some words.
Jack?
- What was that all about?
- Just more questions.
Hey everyone.
I know Amaya... said it before,
but, uh... thank you so much
for coming out.
It... it means
so much to me...
that my family is in your hearts
and in your thoughts...
and in their prayers.
Toby says I talk too much, so...
tonight, uh... Toby's
gonna do the talking.
This is a little something
she wrote in 3rd grade.
"Life is like a soccer ball"
by Toby Bishop.
Life is like a soccer ball.
It sometimes gets scuffs...
- You can't play to rough...
- Navarro here.
- Casper.
- Oh, hey, what's up?
Listen, amigo.
I have a lead your gringo cousin
should check out.
You want me to come down?
No, it'd be great if you, uh...
both could come down.
I'm kinda tied up right now,
we'll get there as soon as we can.
- Mm-hmm.
- You know,
- in a couple hours.
- Well, the sooner the better.
Ah. Come on, come on.
Sorry about that.
Hey, Jack, do you remember...
the youg lady that approached you
at La Paloma Blanca the other night?
- No.
- A working girl.
I'm sorry.
No, she said she knew you
from somewhere.
Well, anyway,
she's dead.
Earlier this evening,
Carolina Sandoval was stabbed to death...
in an abandoned church
on the edge of town.
What are you saying?
Well, were you in that church tonight?
No.
No, no, no, my husband...
was with me in Del Rio...
at the vigil for Toby.
I have a witness who says
she saw a gringo...
matching your husband description...
inside Saint Dismas Cathedral tonight.
No, no, no,
it wasn't him.
Okay?
She's in the other room,
Why don't we just ask her?
Hey, Quero.
Do you know that woman?
Amaya, I have never
seen her before in my life.
You see? You see?
He doesn't know her.
Oh, no, no, you so sure about that, Jack?
What about this, huh?
You ever seen that before?
Alright, I was there.
But I...
I don't know no Carolina.
What?
- Can I go now?
- Si, Lourdes, gracias.
Sorry, Papi.
You didn't meet Carolina
for the first time the other night.
You knew her and I think you came
down here... wanting to see her.
And then... something happened
and you killed her.
- No, that's not true.
- Isn't that right, Jack?
- That is not the truth.
- Oh?
That is not what happend.
I did not kill her, okay?
I did come down to meet her,
but I did not kill her.
I... I swear... I swear to you,
Detective Sanchez, I didn't...
- Amaya, please listen... Listen...
- Don't touch me.
- Please, listen...
You gotta listen to me, Casper.
Listen, my ass,
that's my cousin, Jack.
Why don't you just start
from the beginning, Jack?
Arrested?
He didn't do it, it's one of those...
wrong place, wrong time kinda things.
Guess the Mexicans
beat you to the punch.
Oh hey, gringo!
Do you want some soup?
Hey...
pretty lady...
Hey, no touchy.
He left early.
You sure?
Yes. He has to do books
in the morning.
You want to give him
a message?
Give him this. Tell him
I'll be at La Pantera Hotel.
No, this is not my husband.
I'm afraid it is, ma'am.
Navarro.
You're telling me
this Robert Wyley person...
- Wyler.
- Whatever.
This Roberto person...
was born in Oklahoma,
but grew up in a casa
de putas in Tepito?
- A debt collecter?
- Yes.
No!
And a contract killer
for the Mexican mob.
I don't care what your
Mexican informants say.
This man is not my husband,
I know Jack Bishop.
Jack Bishop doesn't exist.
Looks like you guys are gonna
have to wait a little longer.
Jack just escaped from jail
30 minutes ago.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Can I get a room?
Ma'am, I need a room.
10 dollars an hour.
I'm gonna need it for the whole night.
Twenty.
Hey, Coach, I hear
you're looking for me.
Where's my daughter?
Who do you work for?
I said...
who do you work for?
No one.
It's just another contract, gringo.
Where is she?
Fuck you!
I said where is she?
Okay...
I'll tell...
I'll tell you, okay?
Your little daughter's
gonna be a slut.
I was gonna safe her
for myself.
She's... she's right here.
The lighthouse...
at the top of the hill.
You know what they do up there?
It's a whorehouse.
Roberto...
where's Lorena?
- You tell me, Katie.
- What're you talking about?
You kidnapped her.
The only kidnapper here is you.
Don't fucking lie to me.
Nobody gets to speak to me
like that in my own house.
- I know you have her.
- Stop saying that.
I woke up one morning
with no husband, no daughter,
not even a fucking note.
I did what I had to.
Yeah, you're a real saint.
I didn't want her
to see the things I'd seen.
Poor Roberto... you're still
that whiny little gringo...
who's junky whore of a mother
abandoned you in Mexico.
Just give me my daughter
and I'll go.
- You're serious?
- I spoke to Calvo.
Calvo?
Calvo told me you hired him.
- I don't know any Calvo.
- You're lying.
Oh, that's good
coming from you.
Santa Muerte.
You're not...
get out.
I mean it,
please just go.
Just go.
- Give her back to me.
- I don't know where she is.
- I don't have her.
- Where is my daughter?
Check every room in the house,
she's not here.
You don't have to do this.
No, please.
You don't...
have to do...
this.
Don't...
Seńora!
żEstás bien?
You're bieng played, mi amor.
żPuede abrir la puerta,
por favor?
Seńora!
żestán bien allí?
Amaya said that...
on my wedding day,
my mother's spirit
would be right there beside me,
as I walk down the aisle.
I wasn't actually getting married.
But that night...
I knew in my heart...
that my mother was with me...
every step of the way.
Oh, death,
glorious death,
do not let me be
without your protection.
Santa Muerte is one of us.
She walks with us,
she protects us.
She will vanquish my enemies.
I'm so proud of you, Toby.
And now it's the time you know
the truth about your mother.
Dońa.
Oh, God.
Forgive me.
Show me.
Please show me the way.
I don't think the ghosts...
will need candles tonight.
Amaya.
What're you doing here?
Taking the light...
Fire in his eyes,
darkness in your heart...
a crucifix falling.
- The red curtains.
- This is Dońa story.
The cord...
strangling the lifeblood
from his body.
Why are you telling me this?
There was someone else
there that night...
a little girl.
Look at the darkness in the eyes,
face to face and tell me what you see.
I see nothing.
He was a gambler...
but he was all she had.
And the girl...
was forced to watch...
while you and your bitch Katie...
collected his debt in blood.
No.
I was there, Roberto.
That's not me,
I am not that man.
Pues...
I am that girl.
You messed with
the wrong family, hermano.
You're being played.
You hired Calvo.
You took Toby.
You took my father...
the only man I ever loved.
What did you do to her?
And now... I'm taking
the one you love.
No.
Eye on the prize, baby.
Eye on the prize.
- Hey.
- Hmm.
My dad thought
we were lucky to escape the fire.
But Amaya had told me that...
neither of us was gonna die that night...
and that one day,
when it was too late,
he would know everything.
Some people spend their
whole lives starting over...
new towns, new jobs,
new friends.
But no matter where you go...
or what you do,
some things
you can never forget.
And some things...
you can never forgive.
Santa Muerte
will vanquish my enemies...
help me find
my mother's killer...
and avenge her senseless death,
however long it takes,
however...
hard it may be,
conquer him
who is conquering me...
like Jesus conquered
on the cross.
PeG@SuS
Translated by : robbinsan
pilemhade.blogspot.com
ALAT ELEKTRONIK MURAH & BERKUALITAS :
GPS, Kalkulator, Telepon, Perkakas, HT/WT, dll.
handycom-it.blogspot.com
Belanja Barang Murah & Original :
https://www.bukalapak.com/pegasus_bl
https://www.tokopedia.com/unicorn-shop-bdg