{\move(10,10,190,230,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000&\3c&H00FFFF&}anoXmous
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&HFF0000&\3c&H00FFFF&}https://thepiratebay.se/user/Zen_Bud
[ Choir ]
♪ Sanguis bibimus ♪
♪ Corpus edimus ♪
♪ Tolle corpus ♪
♪ Satani ♪
♪ Ave ♪
♪ Sanguis bibimus ♪
♪ Corpus edimus ♪
♪ Tolle corpus ♪
♪ Satani ♪
♪ Satani ♪ ♪
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
[ Man's Voice ]
The child is dead.
He breathed for a moment.
Then he breathed no more.
The child is dead. Dead.
[ Fading ]
The child is dead. The child is dead.
I'm afraid it will kill her.
My God. She wanted a baby so much...
for such a long time.
What can l tell her?
What... will I say?
You could adopt a child.
She wanted her own.
If I may suggest, it even resembles.
Your wife need never know.
It would be a blessing to her...
- [ No Audible Dialogue ]
- and to the child.
Are there no relatives?
None.
The mother died—
as your own child—
in the same moment.
You said it—
It could be ours, but—
On this night, Mr. Thorn...
God has given you a son.
- Oh.
- Here's your boy.
My, what are you
doing home so early?
- Just came to start packing.
- What?
We can't waste any time.
We're leaving in the morning.
- Buongiorno, Carlo.
- Buongiorno, signore.
- Please, Carlo.
- Oh.
- What are you talking about?
- l am talking about London.
I am talking about the ambassador
to the Court of St. James's.
- Well, what about him?
- You're married to him.
I'm what?
Uh, it's me. I'm— I'm appointed
ambassador to Great Britain.
Oh! Darling!
- [ Chuckling ]
- Oh!
- [ Door Closes ]
- I've already told them yes.
- I loved it the minute I saw it. Huh?
- Uh, it's a bit much.
Well, nothing's too much for the wife
ofthe future president ofthe United States.
- Oh. You know, you're pushy.
- [ Chuckles ]
Come on. Wait till you see this.
- Now, this they call "his day room."
- His day room.
- So, how do you like it so far?
- Oh, um, yeah. Yeah.
- It needs some books to warm it up.
- Couple of books.
- Cozy it up.
- Warm it up. Yeah.
Hmm.
Something in mind, Mr. Ambassador?
Well, why don't we have a little look
upstairs, hmm?
- Well, there's no furniture up there either.
- Oh, hmm.
You know, you could be too sexy
for the White House.
- Oh, l'm gonna miss you so much.
- I won't be long.
- Well—
- We don't have that much to talk about.
Ha. Since when did two old college
roommates not have much to talk about?
[ Affecting Southern Accent ]
Since one ofthem assumed...
the awesome burden
ofthe presidency.
- Well, give my regards to the first lady.
- I'll do my best.
- Why don't you change your
mind, fly over with me?
- Hmm, nah.
I better stay here
and fool around with Damien.
Mmm.
- Where is he?
- Hmm? He's right behind us.
Damien?
- Damien?
- [ Shouts ] Damien?
Damien!
Damien? Damien!
Oh, my God, Robert. Dami—
Robert, where could he be?
Damien!
Oh!
[ Sighing ]
Oh, you little monkey.
Don't you ever do that again.
- You gave us a scare. Oh!
- [ Damien Crying ]
- There, there. Oh.
- [ Cooing ]
Go.
- Hey!
- Good boy.
- [ Together ] ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- ♪♪ [ Children Join ]
- ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Damien ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪ ♪
- Run out offilm?
- Just saving a bit for his canonization.
- How's that?
- I don't know ifwe just got...
the heir to the Thorn millions here
orJesus Christ himself.
Want a bite, Daddy?
Having fun?
- Here you are, son.
- [ Photographer ] Lovely.
Nanny, give him a big, big hug.
[ Nanny ] Come on, Damien.
Smile. A big birthday smile. It's your day.
- Come on. Smile. Come on.
- Holly!
- I'll take him, ma'am.
- No, no. I'll take him.
Come on.
Let's go.
- [ Children Squealing, Chattering ]
- One, two, three.
- Whoa!
- Let mejump on it, Daddy! Let me jump on it!
- Hold on!
- [ Shouting ]
[ Nanny Calling In Distance ]
Damien! Damien!
Damien, look at me.
I'm over here.
- Damien, l love you.
- Look, there's Nanny.
Look at me, Damien.
lt's all for you.
Go, Tom.
Good morning, Mr. Ambassador.
Read the papers today, sir?
- [ Thorn ] No, I haven't.
- There's an article on the suicide.
Your nanny, the one thatjumped—
They say that she left a suicide note, sir.
Not true.
Mr. Ambassador,
did you know she was on drugs?
[ Thorn ]
Would you mind?
- Mr. Thorn, did she use drugs?
- Not that I know of.
- Mr. Ambassador, the article said—
- [ Sighs ]
I don't care what the article said.
l'm sorry.
l am sorry.
Will you, um,
send me a bill for the damage?
That's all right, Mr. Ambassador.
Let'sjust say you owe me.
Corporal.
Okay. Outside.
- [ lntercom Buzzes ]
- [ Thorn ] Yes?
[ Woman On Speaker ]
There's a Father Brennan to see you.
- Who?
- A priest named Father Brennan from Rome.
He says it's a matter of urgent,
personal business.
- Never heard of him.
- He says hejust needs a minute.
Something about a hospital.
Donation time.
- All right. Send him in.
- I didn't know you were such a soft touch.
On that trip to Saudi Arabia—
Why isn't it the right time?
Well, it's personal, Tom. l just, uh,
don't feel like leaving home right now.
Mm-hmm.
Yes, Father.
We haven't much time.
You must listen to what I have to say.
All right.
What is it?
You must accept Christ as your savior.
You must accept him now.
Forgive me, Father, but didn't I
understand that you have a matter...
ofsome urgent personal business?
You must take Communion— drink the
Blood of Christ and eat his Flesh.
- For only if he is within you can you
defeat the son ofthe devil. - I see.
He's killed once.
He'll kill again.
He'll kill until
everything that's yours is his.
- Father, would you mind—
- Only through Christ can you fight him.
Accept the Lord Jesus.
Drink his Blood.
I've locked the door, Mr. Thorn.
- [ Woman ] Yes?
- Would you send for a security guard, please?
l beg you, Mr. Thorn.
Listen to what I have to say.
- [ Intercom Buzzes ]
- [ Woman ] Ambassador Thorn?
l was at the hospital, Mr. Thorn,
the night your son was born.
I witnessed the birth.
- [ Intercom Buzzes ]
- Sir?
- l beg you.
- [ Intercom Buzzing ]
All right.
Stand by.
- What do you want?
- To save you, Mr. Thorn, so Christ will forgive me.
What do you know about my son?
- Everything.
- And what is that?
I saw its mother.
- You saw my wife.
- I saw its mother.
You're referring to my wife!
- lts mother, Mr. Thorn!
- [ Knocking ]
Ifthis is blackmail,
come out and say it.
- What is it that you're trying to say?
- His mother was a jack—
- Everything all right, sir?
- You sounded strange. The door was locked.
- I want this gentleman escorted out of here.
- Okay. Let's go.
Accept Christ each day.
Drink his Blood.
- Just get him offthe grounds.
- All right, Father. Come on.
- Father.
- [ Shutter Clicks ]
Thank you.
- [ Knocking ]
- Come in.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, Mrs. Horton.
Mrs. Baylock is here.
She says she's the new governess.
Well, that's a start.
Show her in.
- Come in, please.
- Thank you.
Ambassador and Mrs. Thorn.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
I, um— I know it's
a difficult time foryou...
so l'll not intrude on your grief.
I'm here to take away some
ofyour troubles and anxieties.
We'll soon help your little boy
to forget what's happened.
l'm afraid, sir, that, uh...
some of ouryoung nannies,
they get homesick...
or they have boyfriend problems.
I left all that behind
a long time ago.
Well, now, if, um—
Ifyou'll let me see your boy?
Well, yes, of course.
He's upstairs.
- I'll show you where it is.
- Why don't you just leave us alone at first?
Let us get acquainted
in our own way.
- Well, he's shy with new people.
- Oh, no.
Not with me he won't be.
- Well, I— l don't think—
- I think it'll be fine.
Go on.
Give it a try.
All right then.
Mrs. Horton?
- This way, Mrs. Baylock.
- Excuse me.
- Well, I like her.
- She seems all right.
Where'd you find her?
- Where did / find her?
- Yeah.
I didn't find her.
l assumed you found her.
- 'Round that corner to the right,
and it's the door facing you.
- Thank you.
- I'll have your things sent up in a moment.
- Oh, Mrs. Baylock!
- Yes, ma'am?
Uh, I'm sorry,
but we're a little bit confused.
- Oh? Why is that?
- Well, we don't know how you got here.
Oh. Oh, the, uh— the agency.
The agency?
Well, yes. They, uh—
They read in the paper about the—
well, about your first nanny,
so they, uh—
They sent you another.
- Oh, that's it.
- Well, I'll call to confirm that.
Oh, um, here are my references.
Well, thank you very much.
Well, if, um—
If I could see your boy... now?
- Yes, of course.
- Thank you.
Have no fear, little one.
I am here to protect thee.
- Any minute, Horton, I think.
- Very good, sir.
- Kathy.
- I'm coming! Mrs. Baylock!
- Mrs. Baylock!
- Yes, ma'am.
Where's Damien?
Ifyou don't mind, ma'am,
I think he'd rather go to the park instead.
- To the park? I told you
he was going to go with us.
- He's too young for church.
- He'll cause a fuss.
- Mrs. Baylock, you don't seem to understand.
It is my wish
and my husband's wish...
that Damien accompanies
us to church.
- [ Robert ] Kathy!
- I'll be there in a minute!
Now, please have him
dressed at once.
Well, uh, excuse me
for speaking my mind, ma'am...
but do you really think
a five-year-old will understand...
the goings-on
ofan Episcopal wedding?
Will you have my son dressed and in the car
in five minutes. Thank you very much.
What's the matter, Damien?
Oh, it's just a church.
That's all.
What's the matter?
- Robert.
- Something wrong?
He seems— I don't know.
Hejust seems scared to death.
Is he ill?
No. He's just—
No. He'sjust trembling all over.
[ Choir ]
♪ Tolle corpus Satani ♪
- Mr. Ambassador. Welcome, sir.
- Good morning.
- No!
- [ Kathy ] Damien, wait!
- [ Damien Shrieking ]
- Stop! [ Screams ]
- Don't! Damien!
- [ Robert ] Damien! Stop it.
Damien, stop.
Let's go.
No!
- Horton, drive on.
- Help!
Help! Help!
Are you sure that
you don't want to call a doctor?
- ♪♪ [ Continues ]
- No, no. It's just a couple of bruises.
- Be all right in the morning.
- No, I— I mean for Damien.
Oh, no. He's fine. He's—
He's sound asleep.
- Oh, just—just to have him examine him.
- Well—
Well, he's perfectly all right.
Never been sick a day in his life.
- Yeah. He never has, has he?
- Nope.
Isn't that a little strange?
- ls it?
- I mean, no measles or mumps or chicken pox.
- Not even a cough or a cold.
- So?
Well, I just think
it's a little unusual.
Look. He's a perfectly healthy boy.
I mean, we— We have
nothing to worry about with him—
not physically or-or otherwise.
He just...
had a bad moment.
You know, like a— a fright.
- [ Knocking ]
- Yes?
I'm leaving now, ma'am.
Is there anything else you wanted?
- Nothing, thank you. Good night.
- Good night.
I think the best thing to do with a bad day
like this is end it and to go to bed.
I'll be along soon.
Quiet now. [ Chuckles ]
This is the master ofthe house.
- What is this?
- Sir?
The dog.
Beautiful, isn't he?
We found him outside.
Who gave you permission
to bring a dog in the house?
I thought we could use a good
watchdog, sir, and Damien loves him.
Gave you a fright, did he, sir?
- Yes.
- Well, you see how good he is—
as a watchdog, I mean.
l think you'll be grateful
on your long trips away, sir.
Mrs. Baylock, we don't need a dog.
And ifwe do,
I'll pick him out myself.
Damien's taken
quite a fancy to him, sir.
Tomorrow morning,
you'll call the R.S.P.C.A.
Tell them to collect the dog
and find him another home.
You understand?
[ Quietly ]
Sir.
Come on, boy.
[ Woman On P.A. ]
Welcome to Windsor Safari Park.
- Mummy, this is going to be a lot offun.
- Animal compound to your left.
- Now, you roll up the window.
- Parking for refreshment
and zoo area to your right.
When driving through
animal compounds...
please keep all car windows closed.
Thank you.
[Choir]♪ Sanguis bibimus
Corpus edimus ♪
♪ Sanguis bibimus
- Come on, darling. Let's go see the monkeys, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- Good morning, Horton.
- Good morning, sir.
[ Woman On P.A. ]
Baboons bite. Keep all car windows closed.
Keep all car windows closed.
Baboons are dangerous.
[ Squealing,
Screeching, Hooting ]
- [ Roaring, Hooting ]
- Mummy! Mummy, help!
- [ Kathy Screaming ]
- Help, Mummy!
No!
[ Screaming ]
Mummy! Mummy!
- You all right, Kathy?
- Yeah.
You're so...
silent this evening.
Just tired, I guess. Sorry.
- Damien all right?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- You're sure?
- Yes.
lfthere were anything...
wrong, you'd...
tell me, wouldn't you?
Wrong? What could be wrong
with our child, Robert?
We're the beautiful people,
aren't we?
There is something wrong,
isn't there?
Kathy, is it so serious?
Robert, I— I— I want—
l need to see a psychiatrist.
I— I h-have... fears.
l have such fears.
What kind offears?
What kind?
Oh, if I told you,
you'd put me away.
Kathy, I love you.
I love you.
Then help me.
Find me a doctor.
I will.
Ofcourse I will.
[ Man ]
Keep that scrum tight! Get down low.
- Come on! - Get down!
- Hoist it upon them!
- Let it go! Let it go!
- Speed! Speed! Speed!
- That's it! That's it!
- Come on, lads! Come on, Evans!
- Come on! Come on, Pip!
- [ Man Shouting ]
- Get onside! Get onside!
- [ Chatter Continues ]
- Heel, heel. Heel!
Get in there, you boys!
- Come on! Come on, move!
- Break! Break!
Get it down then!
Down to the ball!
Bring him down!
- [ Whistle Blowing ]
- Well done!
Don't know what you're clapping for.
You'vejust lost a bet.
- Oh, that's right. 27-3?
- Right. That'll be three quid.
- I thought it was two.
- Rate of inflation. Haven't you heard, old boy?
Well done, George.
Great stuff.
That was a good game.
Look. Robert, why don't you go
and have a quick drink with the lads?
- That'll give me time to make
sure everything's set up.
- All right.
Tomorrow, half past 2:00,
Bishop's Park.
Five minutes, and you'll never
see me again. Your wife is in danger.
She'll die unless you come.
- Father?
- [ Shutter Clicking ]
- Thanks again.
Get on with it.
Say what you have to say.
When theJews return to Zion...
and a comet rips the sky...
and the Holy Roman Empire rises...
then you and l must die.
From the eternal sea, he rises...
creating armies on either shore...
turning man against his brother...
till man exists no more.
The book of Revelations
predicted it all.
I'm not here to listen to a sermon.
lt is by means ofa human personality
entirely in his possession...
that Satan will wage
his last formidable offense.
- You said my wife was—
- Go to the town of Megiddo...
in the old city ofJezreel.
There see the old man Bugenhagen.
- He alone can describe how the child must die.
- Look here—
He who will not be saved by the
Lamb will be torn by the beast!
Will you stop?
l'm here because you said
my wife is in danger.
She is pregnant.
You're mistaken.
That's nonsense.
He will not allow
the child to be born.
He will kill it while
it slumbers in the womb.
What in God's name
are you talking about?
Your son, Mr. Thorn—
the son ofthe devil.
He will kill the unborn child.
Then he will kill your wife.
And when he is certain
to inherit all that is yours...
then, Mr. Thorn, he will kill you.
- That's enough.
- And with your wealth and power...
he will establish
his counterfeit kingdom here on earth...
receiving his power
directly from Satan.
- You're insane.
- He must die, Mr. Thorn!
You asked for five minutes,
and you've got five minutes.
Go to the city of Megiddo.
See Bugenhagen before it's too late.
Now I've heard you.
I want you to hear me.
I never want to see you again.
You'll see me in hell, Mr. Thorn.
There we will
share out our sentence.
[ Choir ] ♪ VersusCristus
Ave Satani ♪
♪ Versus Cristus
♪ Versus Cristus ♪
- ♪ Ave Satani ♪♪
- [ Strains ]
[ Screaming ]
No!
- Mrs. Baylock!
- [ Continues Loudly ]
Anything wrong?
I just can't stand that noise.
- [ Damien Continues ]
- [ Chuckles ] Oh, it's not all that bad.
- Good morning, Damien.
- Good morning, Daddy.
- What are we gonna do?
- Hold my hands.
- Right.
- [ Kathy ] Mrs. Baylock!
- Yes, ma'am?
- Would you take him out of here, please?
But he's only playing.
[ Loudly ]
Would you just get him out of here, please?
Yes, ma'am.
Come along, Damien.
Excuse me, sir.
Come along.
Darling, l don't know
what's the matter with me. l just—
I just don't seem to be able to—
Ah, I don't know.
Kathy, I love you.
Ifthis is what the doctor's
doing to you...
don't you think it's time
I had a talk with him?
Yes, you should.
There's something he wants
to talk to you about anyway.
Oh?
Robert, I—
I don't ever want
to have any more children.
All right.
Then you'll agree to an abortion?
I'm pregnant, Robert.
I just found out this morning.
Yes?
Yes, this is he. Who?
Who? But—
- [ Line Clicks, Dial Tone ]
- Hello.
Hello?
- [ Handset Settles In Cradle ]
- Something about the newspapers.
She knew how much you wanted one.
Now she can't cope.
She searches for reasons
that won't make her feel inadequate.
She has these fantasies.
She fantasizes that your child is alien,
that your child is evil.
She thinks that the child is evil?
The point is, at this time,
another child will be disastrous.
Well, in what way evil?
Now this isjust fantasy.
She also thinks the child isn't hers.
The most important thing foryou to do
is to agree to an abortion.
No.
I'd like to know your reason.
It was foretold that this pregnancy
would be terminated.
l'm going to fight
to see that it's not.
- Forgive me, Doctor.
- No, please don't leave, Mr. Thorn.
l'm sorry.
I must get home.
- Ow!
- ♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪ Ave Satani ♪
♪ Ave
Tolle corpus Satani ♪
♪ Sanguis bibimus
Corpus edimus ♪
Corpus edimus ♪ ♪
Oh!
[ Yelps ]
Damien! Damien!
No! No! No! No! No!
No!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Reporters Clamoring ]
- Mr. Ambassador, can you help us, sir, please?
- Are there any new developments,
on the state ofyour wife, sir?
- Can you give us a statement, please, sir?
- How is your wife, sir?
- Please, sir, could you furnish
us with a statement, sir?
- Any news, sir?
- Ambassador Thorn?
- Yes. Doctor?
- Yes. My name is, um, Becker.
- Is she... all right?
Well, she will recover.
She's in there.
Bed by the window.
She has a concussion,
a broken humerus...
and, uh, well,
some internal bleeding.
- Internal bleeding?
- Yes.
- But she's pregnant.
- No.
- [ Whispers ] She's lost it?
- Afraid so.
You know, you've got a lot
to be grateful for.
She's still alive...
and, with proper care,
she can still have children.
[ Woman On P.A. ]
Dr. Jones. Dr. Jones.
Robert.
- Robert.
- Shh.
Shh, shh, shh.
Don't let him kill me.
Kathy. Kathy.
- [ Moans ]
- Kathy.
Kathy...
it's all right.
Kathy.
Yes?
[ Man ]
I'm sorry to botheryou, Ambassador Thorn.
- Who is this?
- My name is Keith Jennings...
the photographer whose camera
got smashed at the embassy.
l wonder if it would be possible
to have a word with you here at my flat?
- lf it's about the camera—
- No, it's not about the camera.
lt's about you, Mr. Thorn,
and the death ofthe priest.
Oh?
Go on.
Do you notice anything unusual?
No. Sorry.
At first, I thought this was
just a fault in the film.
It was a strange coincidence.
Then it happened again.
Interesting, don't you think?
And this...
I took on the day that you
were at the rugby match.
- Same thing.
- Only it's more pronounced this time...
and it's actually making
contact with the body.
And the rest, ofcourse— history.
I can't explain it.
And that's why I started digging.
The coroner's report shows that
he was riddled with cancer...
high on morphine most ofthe time.
- Injected himselftwo or three times a day.
- He knew that he was dying?
Apparently, yes.
He said that he wanted to be
forgiven by Christ.
Externally, his body
was perfectly normal...
except for one small thing in
the inside of his right thigh.
- What is it?
- Three sixes.
666.
- Concentration camp?
- That's what l thought.
But the biopsy says
it's a birthmark.
The best is yet to come.
Pages ofthe Bible—
thousands ofthem.
Every inch ofwall space covered,
even the windows.
He even needed to be
close to his church.
There are 47.
l counted them.
I think he was trying to keep
something out. Don't you?
The police thought he was insane,
so they didn't mind me coming here...
and rummaging around
to see if l could find anything of use.
The first item...
is a diary.
It didn't say anything about him.
It's about you—
what time you left the house...
where you went,
what restaurants you had your lunch in...
what time your speaking
engagements were.
The last entry says that he was supposed
to have met you in Bishop's Park...
and that was dated the day he died.
But the really important
items are here.
lfwe're to get to the bottom ofthis,
we've got to start here.
This first clipping is from
the Astrologer's Monthly.
It reports
an unusual phenomenon—
a comet changing shape
into a glowing star...
like the Star of Bethlehem
2,000 years ago.
Only this one was on
the other side ofthe world—
the European continent—
five years ago.
The sixth ofJune, to be exact.
Does that date mean anything to you?
Yes.
Then you'll recollect
this other clipping.
It's a birth announcement
from a Rome newspaper...
also dated the sixth ofJune,
five years ago—
the day your son was born.
Sixth month, sixth day.
Was your son born at 6:00 a.m.?
Yes, I'm sorry. I'm just trying to work out
this birthmark— the three sixes.
My son is dead.
I don't know whose son I'm raising.
lfyou wouldn't mind, Mr. Thorn,
l'd like to help you try and find out.
No. It's my problem.
No, sir, you're wrong.
It's my problem too.
When l came here with the police,
l took some photographs.
I happened to catch sight
of my own reflection in that mirror.
I know you must think I'm crazy,
but I'm so frightened.
Don't be afraid.
You'll be all right here.
You'll be perfectly all right.
Oh. Some all right.
What about Damien?
I'll speak to Mrs. Horton.
She'll look after him.
Mrs. Horton.
Mrs. Horton?
- Mrs. Baylock.
- Sir?
- Where's Mrs. Horton?
- Gone.
- Gone out?
- No, no. They've gone. Theyjust got up and went.
They left an address foryou
to send their last month's wages to.
Didn't Mrs. Horton say anything?
- Didn't Horton leave any explanation?
- No.
But don't worry, sir.
l can manage.
- I'll look into this when l get back.
- Just as you wish, sir.
- And, Mrs. Baylock.
- Sir?
Last night, I saw that dog
in Damien's room.
- I clearly told you—
- He's gone now, sir.
They took him away this morning.
No. No.
This is the right address.
Apparently, there was a terrible fire
and the old hospital burned down.
Five years ago.
- [ Italian ]
- Okay.
Well, surely the fire
didn't destroy everything.
- There must have been some records.
- [ Speaking ltalian ]
I sorry. I think everything
was destroyed.
Isn't it possible that there were
some papers stored elsewhere?
- I do not know, signore.
- Sister.
This is most important to me.
I adopted a child here.
l'm searching
for some records of-
- There were no adoptions here.
- There was one.
- No, signore.
- It wasn't an actual adoption.
- You are "mistake."
- Wait.
Birth records.
- lf l gave you a date, an exact date.
- No.
- lt's no use.
The fire started in the hall of records,
in the basement.
All the paperwork was there—
went up like a torch.
Shot up the stairwells.
The third floor became an inferno.
- The third floor?
- The nursery and maternity wards.
- Nothing left but ashes.
- You will excuse me, uh?
- What about the staff?
- Hmm?
- Surely some survived.
- Sí, some.
There was a tall man,
a priest—
dark eyes, piercing eyes.
Ah, sí!
Padre Spiletto.
- Yes.
- Hewas principale.
- Yes, he was in charge. Is he—
- Yes, he is alive.
- ls he here?
- No.
- Where?
- He's in a monastero in... Frosinone.
Many were taken there.
Many die.
Perhaps he is die since,
but he lived through the fire.
I remember. People say
itwas un miracolo.
Frosinone?
Sí. Il Monastero di San Domenico.
- Mille grazie, signora.
- Prego.
- Here we are.
- What is it?
- "When theJews return to Zion" —
- That's it— the poem.
"When theJews return to Zion."
And there was something
about a comet.
Yes. That's here too. The shower
ofstars and the rise ofthe Roman Empire.
These are supposed to be the events
that signal the birth ofthe Antichrist—
the devil's child.
[Jennings ]
It's making more sense.
TheJews have returned to Zion,
and there has been a comet.
And as for the rise
ofthe Roman Empire...
scholars think that could well mean
the formation ofthe Common Market.
- The Treaty of Rome.
- Bit of a stretch.
Well, what about this?
ln Revelations, it says...
"He shall rise from
the eternal sea."
Well, that's the poem again—
"From the eternal sea, he rises...
creating armies on either shore"—
That was the beginning of it.
And theologians have already interpreted
the "eternal sea"...
as meaning
the world of politics—
the sea that constantly rages
with turmoil and revolution.
So the devil's child will rise
from the world of politics.
Looks like this is as far as we go.
Let's have a look.
Found him?
His mind is active, but, since the fire,
he has not made a sound.
We feed him
and take care of his needs.
- And we pray for his recovery
when his penance is completed.
- What penance?
"Woe to the shepherd
who abandons his sheep.
May his right arm wither
and his right eye lose its sight."
He's fallen from grace.
Can you tell us why?
For abandoning Christ.
- How do you know he's abandoned Christ?
- He told us.
But he doesn't speak.
There is some movement
in his left hand.
He was able to write it down.
You will notice the curved line
over the head.
This indicates the hood
ofthe monk— his own hood.
- The three sixes.
- Six is the sign ofthe devil.
But why three ofthem?
We believe it signifies
the diabolical trinity:
the devil, Antichrist
and false prophet.
Father, Son and Holy Ghost, huh?
For everything holy,
there is something unholy.
This is the essence oftemptation.
Father Spiletto.
My name is Thorn.
There was a child.
I want to know where
that child came from.
- I am afraid this is—
- You confessed to them. Now confess to me.
- What happened?
- Please, signore.
You said you knew its mother.
- Where is she now?
- I must insist that you do not—
I beg you.
Where is she?
Answer me!
- Answer!
- [ Bell Tolling Loudly ]
Excuse me.
"Cervet."
Please.
Does it mean something to you?
Cerveteri.
It is an old cemetery
from Etruscan times.
Cripta Sant'Angelo.
lt is nothing but ruins.
- Where is this place?
- But, signore, there is nothing there. Only graves.
- Where is it?
- You will find it on the map.
It is perhaps 50 kilometers
north of Rome.
Robert. Over here.
"Maria... Scianna."
My God.
"June 6."
Five years ago.
"Bambino Scianna."
Infant boy.
Same date.
"In birth and death,
the generations embrace."
Is my son...
buried here?
This woman could be the mother
ofthe child you adopted.
Why here...
in this terrible place?
- [ Exclaims ]
- My God.
- The other one.
- No.
Let's get out of here.
lf it's an animal, too...
then maybe my child...
is alive somewhere.
They murdered him.
As soon as he was born.
Murderers.
- Murderers.
- [ Growling ]
Come on.
Robert!
- [ Barking ]
- Don't run.
It's only the smell ofthe graves.
Run!
[ Groans ]
Robert!
- Hello?
- Hello.
Kathy?
Hello.
Robert, is that you?
Oh, l'm so glad you called.
Kathy, darling.
Now listen to me very carefully.
Do just what I say.
I want you to leave London right now.
What do you mean
leave London, darling?
- I don't understand.
- l've put through a call to the embassy.
Tom Portman will meet you at the hospital
and bring you here to Rome.
Robert, what's happened?
What's wrong?
Please, darling, just—just do it.
Get ready to leave.
Robert, l don't think
l can move very well.
Kathy, do it.
Okay. Y-Yes, all right.
l'll— l'll try to be ready
by the time he gets here.
All right, darling.
Who is that?
Is that somebody there?
Tom, is that you?
♪ Sanguis bibimus ♪
♪ Corpus edimus ♪
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- ♪ Tolle corpus ♪
- ♪ Satani ♪♪
- [ Glass Shatters ]
Yes?
Yes, this is he.
Tom?
Kathy?
Tom...
I can't...
talk now.
Robert?
I found out about
the town of Megiddo.
It's derived from the word
"Armageddon"—
the end ofthe world.
It's underground,
about 60 miles south ofJerusalem.
There's some excavation
going on there.
If only you could remember the name
ofthe man you're supposed to see.
It's Bugenhagen.
He was an exorcist.
I read about him.
That was his name,
and l remember the poem.
"When theJews return to Zion...
"and a comet fills the sky...
"and the Holy Roman Empire rises...
"then you and l must die.
"From the eternal sea, he rises...
"creating armies on either shore...
"turning man against his brother...
till man exists... no more."
Kathy is dead.
I want Damien to die too.
[ Man ]
Hello, Mr. Thorn.
I am Bugenhagen.
[ Robert ]
What is this place?
The city ofJezreel.
Town of Megiddo.
The place...
where Christianity began.
The little priest, is he dead yet?
Yes.
Come along, Mr. Thorn.
We had better get to work.
Oh, you will excuse us.
This is for Mr. Thorn alone.
All right.
It must be done on hallowed ground.
A church.
His blood must be spilled
on the altar of God.
This first knife...
is most important.
It extinguishes physical life...
and forms the center ofthe cross.
The subsequent placings
extinguish spiritual life...
and should radiate outward...
like this.
This is not a human child.
Make no mistake.
- Is there proof?
- Oh, yes.
He bears a birthmark—
a sequence of sixes.
So, says the Bible,
do all the apostles of Satan.
- He doesn't have it.
- He must have it.
I've bathed him.
I know every inch of him.
lf it is not visible on the body...
it will be beneath the hair.
Remove it.
You must be devoid of pity.
- And the woman?
- She is an apostate of hell.
She will die before permitting this.
Look, I want to know what he said.
I have a right to know.
Robert, I want to know what he said!
l'm notjust some bystander!
l was the one that found him!
I'm the one that's
supposed to kill him.
These are knives.
He wants me to stab him!
- He wants me to murder a child.
- It's not a child.
How can he know that?
Maybe he's wrong.
It's insane!
I won't have anything to do...
with murdering a little boy.
He's not responsible.
I won't do it!
Well, ifyou don't do it, I will.
- ♪♪ [ Choir Chanting ]
- Oh, God!
Run, Damien! Run!
Uh!
[ Screaming ]
No! No!
No! Damien!
Hold it. Hey!
Panda 4 to Control.
[ Woman Dispatcher ]
M.P. to Panda 4. Come in, please.
- [ Engine Starts ]
- Panda 4 in pursuit.
- American ambassador. White estate car.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
Heading north,
Seven Hills Road. Over.
- [ Chattering ]
- l've got a shout.
- I'll be back later, all right?
- [ Man Chattering On Police Radio ]
[ Woman ] M.P. to Zulu 7.
You are requested assist Panda 4...
in pursuit white estate car,
north, Seven Hills Road.
Possible diplomatic incident.
[ Man On Radio ]
Zulu 7 to Panda 4.
We have taken over
your pursuit. Over.
No!
[ Man On Radio ]
Zulu 7 to M.P.
Heading west on Old Church Road.
No! Please, Daddy, no.
No, Daddy! No!
God... help me.
Police! Drop!
Drop, or I'll fire!
And so to their final rest
do we commit these two...
and entrust them unto our Lord.
In the name ofthe Father
and ofthe Son...
and ofthe Holy Ghost, amen.
Detail, atten-hut!
Present... arms!
- ♪♪ [ Taps ]
- Ready, aim, fire!
Ready, aim, fire!
Excuse me, Mr. President.
When you're ready to leave,
your car's right over there.
- In a moment.
- Yes, sir.
[ Choir ]
♪ Sanguis bibimus ♪
♪ Corpus edimus ♪
♪ Tolle Corpus ♪
♪ Satani ♪
♪ Ave ♪
♪ Ave, ave versus Cristus ♪
♪ Ave Satani ♪
♪ Sanguis bibimus ♪
♪ Corpus edimus ♪
♪ Tolle corpus ♪
♪ Satani ♪
♪ Ave ♪
♪ Satani ♪ ♪
© anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.se/user/Zen_Bud