Paprika (2006) Sub ENG
It's The Greatest Show time!
There's no doubt. He's here.
Who?
Be careful. He's a traitor.
There's someone who keeps looking at you.
See?
It's okay, he's a friend.
Please turn your attention to this gentleman!
Now ...
One... two... three!
There he is! Get him!
Grab my hand!
I let him get away again!
Aren't you the one who got away?
One more time!
Take that!
But what about the rest of it?
You were in my dream.
Everyone is startled at first.
The DC Mini.
It's the scientific key that allows us
to open the door to our dreams.
It can even do all this?
It really is a dream machine.
To tell you the truth,
the DC Mini is still incomplete.
Once complete, we'll be able to
enter your dream even while awake.
You said he was a friend.
We used to work together.
Why did he put you in a cage?
I don't know.
He's not the kind of person who would trick me.
Why are they all me?
That was really disturbing.
This is Tarzan, right?
This looks like a scene from a spy movie?
The fighting was rather fun.
REM sleep, that occurs later during the sleep
cycle is longer and easier to analyze.
If earlier cycles are, say, artsy film shorts,
then later cycles are like
feature-length blockbuster movies.
Then that makes you... a dream movie star.
Do you not like movies?
It's not that.
What is this?
The victim in the homicide
case I'm working on right now.
I haven't been able to catch the perp,
so maybe that's why I...
Your anxiety neurosis.
Do you think this is the source?
No need to rush.
The treatment's just getting started.
Take care, Captain Konakawa.
When can I see you again?
I'm in a bind.
I can see that.
No, it's not that.
I was on my way to see you.
It's not that! The DC Mini!
It was stolen? The DC Mini?
We found out this morning.
Three samples in Dr. Tokita's
possession were stolen.
But why?
We'll worry about the reason later.
We need to find them now.
Do you think it's internal?
Unfortunately.
We'll talk about that later.
- Foundation for Psychiatric Research -
Meet me in my office.
We'll figure out a plan...
...before the chairman finds out.
Yes, we have to protect the DC Mini.
It's too bad it was stolen, but all we
have to do is make another one.
You should know better than anyone
what can happen if it's misused.
You invented it.
I make it, but how it's
used is your job, At-chan.
Don't call me At-chan.
There is one more problem.
Good grief.
I hadn't programmed the access
controls into the DC Mini yet.
Translate that for me.
It means that the person
who stole the DC Mini...
...can connect to a psychotherapy
machine at any time, from any place...
...and use it to intrude into the
minds connected to that machine.
- Chief's Office -
I see. We have to hurry.
It is man's responsibility to
control science and technology.
Chairman.
Sharing in another's dream. It is quite
literally a technological dream...
...but, in time, it can lead to violence.
It was an invention that never
should have been created.
This discussion again?
The DC Mini represents the hope that shines
on the new horizons of psychiatric treatment.
It is taking control over dreams.
Your overconfidence will bring weakness.
It is not about control.
We are simply pursuing
a deeper connection with our patients.
The terrorist who stole
it won't see it that way.
But it hasn't even been misused yet.
Thieves are not always wrong.
Paprika.
I hear there's a woman who's been using the
psychotherapy machine for unapproved treatments.
Are you going to believe...
...such groundless rumors, chairman?
Discipline calls for a search of the DC Mini,
rather than Paprika's bikini.
This is true happiness.
Discipline?
Even the five court ladies danced in
sync to the frog's flutes and drums.
The whirlwind of the recycled
paper was a sight to see.
It was like computer graphics!
That I don't support Technicolor parfaits,
and snobby petit bourgeois
is common knowledge in Oceania!
Now is the time to return home to the blue sky!
The confetti will dance around the shrine gates.
The mailbox and the refrigerator will lead the way!
Anyone who cares about expiration dates,
will not get in the way of the glory train!
They need to fully realize
the lives of the triangle rulers!
Now, this festival was decided,
by the third grade class
with the telephoto camera!
Move forward! Come together!
I am the ultimate...
...governor!
Chief!
Now!
Right now!
Take me in!
He has the dream of a patient
planted into his brain.
How's the chief doing?
His breathing and pulse are stable.
I guess it could've been worse.
Dr. Chiba, here are the chief's medical records.
Thank you.
He was probably using the therapy
machine to treat a patient...
When someone used a DC Mini to intrude.
And the dream was projected into
his subconscious without him knowing.
But for that to happen...
The culprit has to be watching this nightmare too.
What a desperate terrorist.
All terrorists are desperate.
The sun during midday will
light up the dark night.
Night dreams of day.
Light dreams of darkness.
But the ignorant sun...
will chase away the darkness,
and burn the shadows,
eventually burning itself!
Himuro!
The shade of the tree with the
flowers that bloom at night...
... is where the residents of darkness rest.
Why is Himuro in there!
The people of daytime are nut allowed!
Where is Himuro?
He's been out for the past few days,
but I didn't think too much of it.
Himuro tends to abandon everything else,
when he really gets into something.
Like doctor, like assistant.
How could we have not seen this coming?
I thought he was my friend.
A genius produces a lot more than he realizes.
More clearly, please.
Himuro was jealous of Dr. Tokita.
Even I feel bitter towards
you sometimes, Dr. Chiba.
No matter how hard I try,
I'm not as good as you.
I feel powerless.
It's open.
You mean you opened it.
This is illegal, you know.
I'm not as bad as Himuro, though.
Welcome home. Welcome back.
He can't be serious.
This is dangerous.
This isn't your cue.
Anaphylaxis?
Like an allergy?
I can't think of any other reason.
I got stung by a jellyfish when I was a kid...
...and even now, I have allergic
reactions at the sight of one.
It didn't occur to me until now.
Here you go.
Who had the udon set?
But the DC Mini uses a transmission formula...
...within the natural width
of the body's energy level.
Who had the jumbo steak set?
Depending on the frequency of use,
the body might adapt to it.
And as a result, Dr. Chiba, who has had the
most exposure was more susceptible to invasion...
...even when she wasn't connected to
the DC Mini, nor was she asleep.
Who had the paella?
I think you have a problem too.
Like overeating.
I can't fight on an empty stomach.
Fight?
Implanting dreams into other
people's heads is terrorism.
At-chan, you said that Himuro and I were alike.
I think so too.
All the more reason this is unforgivable.
Hello?
We'll be there immediately.
Chief! Please, come back!
Wake up! Chief!
The delicious left brain is getting older...
...and drifting to a faraway island.
Himuro, give him back!
I, who stand before you,
am the protector of your dreams.
I wonder what kind of punishment
will befall the ignorant commoner...
...who tries to enter this sacred dream?
You're the feisty country
girl I saved some time ago.
How are you?
If he was not home when
I passed by around 7:30...
...then he probably disappeared
into the instant noodle soup.
Thank you for saving me.
I have come to show you my appreciation.
Is it a square?
No.
It's round, like this.
I can feel it.
Paprika.
Do you remember me now?
I'm going to be a little rough.
Paprika, what are you doing?
Now, now, stop that.
Welcome back, Chief.
I wonder where that parade was going?
A place of no return, most likely.
I felt like I was really close...
...to controlling the entire world.
That was a dream of a
severely delusional patient.
While you were in there,
your brain waves and body deteriorated...
...almost to the point of death.
That's why Paprika came.
Thank you.
You haven't changed since the time you
treated my depression two years ago.
I'll let Paprika know.
But to think that that
honest Himuro was responsible.
What should I do now, Dr. Chiba?
Please don't do anything.
What?
The chairman will probably halt the development
of the DC Mini as a result of this incident.
But with you, a board member, in the hospital...
They can't have a meeting.
Hello? Oh, Konakawa.
How was the? You know.
I would have asked sooner,
if I had known that it would be this good.
Remember, you can't tell anyone.
I want to keep it a secret all to myself.
Paprika's existence cannot become public...
... until the psychotherapy
machines gain public approval.
She really is a woman of your dreams.
Women of dreams are busy these days.
You look tired.
Want me to look in on your dreams?
I haven't been seeing any of my own lately.
Welcome. We were waiting for you.
Good evening.
What is this place?
A counseling room.
A meeting place. A date spot.
Don't you think dreams
and the internet are similar?
They are both areas where
the repressed conscious mind vents.
Here you go.
Have you found anything?
In regards to my dreams?
You're so impatient.
Do you work at the research foundation?
It was Shima who introduced me, after all.
Where do you know Mr. Shima from?
He's a friend from college.
We got along pretty well,
so we always hung out.
Drinking and watching movies?
No, movies don't interest me.
I love them!
Paprika?
Put it on my tab.
Hey, Paprika!
Which one do you want to see?
I'm sorry, but movies really aren't my thing.
Come on, hurry!
I don't like movies!
Hey, Tsumura, stop...
Breaking news!
The widow who tells fortunes
in the shade of roof tiles!
The response is sunny!
The sign is good fortune!
The ceiling fan brings a
message releasing epithets!
The maiden who sleeps under
the veranda has a pulse!
This is the way out!
The secret of this view is deep
within the 10-year loan payment!
They are new victims.
I am stopping development.
But the board meeting...
The culprit won't wait for
a board meeting to happen.
I am forbidding all use of the DC Mini
and the psychotherapy machines.
This is retribution.
Science is nothing but a piece of
trash before a profound dream.
Are you okay?
I heard the parts are non-recyclable.
But that's an important piece of equipment.
I'll just have to make it again.
He's a genius.
He's a mysterious one, all right.
You're giving him too much credit.
He's just a kid inside.
- DREAMLAND -
- DREAMLAND - It was a small
theme park, but I liked it as a kid.
It was a small theme park,
but I liked it as a kid.
I used to talk about it with Himuro.
Do you really think Himuro is here?
If I knew, I wouldn't be searching.
You're so cold, At-chan.
You should act more like Paprika.
I know, I know.
I have a feeling he's near.
Keep quiet, both of you.
Watch out!
Himuro?
That's...
A DC Mini.
The high pressure holds the grab bag
and looks a lot like milk.
The dense forest turns into a shopping district.
The 24-bit eggplant will be analyzed.
Su youre saying both of them were attacked by
way of the DC Mini which broke their psyches.
And the culprit, Kei Himuru, was also disturbed
by the nightmare and tried to commit suicide.
Is that right?
It's not because of the DC Mini!
It's just a little incomplete.
Himuro knew that.
I'm not refuting your invention.
She's the head of the DC Mini development team.
I'm Chiba.
This is Mr. Konakawa from the police department.
Yes?
Isn't it wonderful?
The ability to see a friend's
dream as if it were your own.
To share the same dream.
Yes, it probably would be
a wonderful experience.
You understand, right?
It came to me during a brain scan I was doing,
using a computer image processor.
And you can use it to treat illness.
That's exactly right!
The nonlinear waves created by
surges in the bioelectrical current...
...can be applied to create new synapse
connections by adjusting the BTU output.
To use a person's body for
energy is a remarkable idea.
Exactly!
And the reason why I focused...
You are talking with Dr. Tokita, right?
That's her, isn't it?
Paprika.
So what do you think about this case?
Well, I think it's an accident.
It's hard to build a case against a dream.
"Isn't it wonderful," eh?
The bulky one.
To think such a silly thought
would lead to such an invention.
He's a kid trapped inside the body of a genius.
It's an adult's responsibility to steer
that genius in the right direction.
Chairman.
There is always conceit and
negligence behind misconduct.
You have it hard too, I guess.
Good grief.
Where did I go wrong to end up here?
I want to go back to our college days,
back to when we used to talk about our futures.
I want to go back to our college days...
... back to when we used to
talk about our futures.
But what about the rest of it?
It's too dangerous!
Himuro went in and he's not coming back.
If the same happens to you...
There are still two DC Minis out there.
Our only lead is inside Himuro.
And besides...
The chairman has already prohibited
the use of the therapy machines.
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
Don't worry.
The genius boy is here for backup.
Dr. Tokita again?
I know that you two established this field...
...so that's all the more reason for you
to place your trust in him,
but...
...his immaturity is th
cause of all these mishaps!
That's why we'll make him take responsibility.
Besides, is there anyone else?
This isn't the time for that.
There are people in the world that understand.
That cop.
He has a mind for science.
He doesn't seem very smart, though.
Now, all I have to do is set the filtering
program for external access and...
What was that for?
Do you really think it was Himuro?
He's your assistant, and he knew
the risks involved with the DC Mini.
He knew what would happen,
if he exposed himself for that long.
What did he have to gain from it all?
He was jealous of me.
Even Osanai says so.
He might be a victim too.
That's like a line from a mystery novel.
If so, then it's still dangerous.
We need to confirm...
No more talk.
What I need to do is finish this.
You guys really are alike.
At-chan?
You and Himuro.
You get preoccupied with what you want to do,
and ignore what you have to do.
Don't you understand that your
irresponsibility cost lives?
Of course not.
Nothing can get through all that fat.
And now what? "Isn't it wonderful"?
"A mind for science"?
Don't make me laugh.
How can a mad scientist know
what a human mind is?
If you want to be the king of geeks
with your bloated ego...
...then just keep up all this and
indulge in your freakish masturbation!
And where is Mr. Konakawa now?
At a hotel. It's all here.
I'm counting on you.
There's no doubt. He's here.
You've crossed the line of action.
Be careful. He's a traitor.
You need to narrow the exposure.
This is Panfocus.
Now...
one... two... three!
There he is! Get him!
Welcome.
What floor?
The guy, I'm after him.
Of course. The 14th floor.
Fourteenth floor, the adventure section.
Fifteenth floor, the suspense section.
Sixteenth floor, the romance section.
One more time!
Seventeenth floor, the special section.
No!
I don't need to go there.
Encore!
I... killed... myself?
That's like a line from a mystery novel.
It was a rush job, but I put
an access function on it.
Morals, responsibilities...
I don't really get that adults' stuff.
But let's talk it over again.
We're friends, right?
Oh, jeez.
Was making them not enough?
You had to become a doll yourself?
Why did you steal it?
Do you hate me that much?
Or was it not you who did it?
Even with an access function,
it's not one person's dream anymore.
That's right!
The DC Mini was both our dreams!
The crossing of two dreams,
creates many more dreams.
That's right!
The entire development team
dreamt of its completion.
This is a foolish place to be...
...to inquire about the master of this dream.
The conceit of the daytime residents,
is what the nighttime residents want.
To come in carelessly is
like a moth to a flame.
You're not Himuro, are you?
What's the line of action
that clown was talking about?
It's an imaginary line...
...that connects the subjects on camera.
If the camera crosses that line...
...the cut is awkward.
That's why it has to be like this.
I see. How about Panfocus?
It's a camera technique...
...where you narrow the angle
to get the entire screen in focus.
So you did like them.
Movies.
Are your dreams in Panfocus now too?
Have you solved the mystery
of why you killed yourself?
I've never... thought of suicide.
Maybe it's someone a lot like you.
Like me?
Or another you.
Another me?
Paprika, is the inside of
my head this messed up?
The dreams are merging.
Tokita.
He got started without me!
Wait! Tokita!
Paprika!
Why are you here?
The ecstasy that blooms in synapse
is Paprika-brand milk fat!
Five percent is the norm.
Tokita! No!
The safety net of the ocean is nonlinear,
even with what crabs dreams of!
Let's go!
Wake up!
So you're saying...
...the dreams of Tokita and Himuro
merged into Konakawa's dream?
The anaphylaxis of the DC Mini
is expanding exponentially!
Just meet me at the lab.
They're not dreaming?
But they're in REM sleep.
It's as if...
their conscious itself has been taken away.
I guess this calls for Paprika.
I'll dive into Himuro's dream.
That's the only way to save Tokita.
Chief, can you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you loud and clear.
Any abnormalities?
This dream is very dangerous.
If anything happens to Atsuku,
use the awakening apparatus.
Of course.
But is it really safe? Tokita is gone
because he went into Himuro's dream.
Who du you think I am?
I'm sorry to have doubted you.
There they are!
Himuro isn't there.
But it's his dream.
Osanai?
Be careful.
Leave it to me.
Himuro.
Wake her up!
Chief! Hurry!
That's not Himuro's dream anymore.
So he was a victim too.
He's an empty shell.
He was invaded by a collective dream.
A collective dream?
With no access restrictions the DC Mini can
be used to invade any psychotherapy machine.
Every dream it came in contact with
was eaten up into one huge delusion.
And that delusion belongs to...
This breath seethes in the joy of life.
I will not allow arrogant scientific
technology to intrude in this holy ground.
Return Dr. Tokita to us.
The dreams are horrified that their
safe refuge is destroyed by technology.
Are you going to punish
him like you did Himuro?
In a world of inhumane reality it
is the only humane sanctuary left.
That is a dream.
That parade is full of refugees who
were unwillingly chased out of reality.
You are collecting those
with stolen technology.
Do you plan to take over
the world of dreams?
I am protecting them.
I am the guardian of dreams.
My duty is to mete out justice
to terrorists like you, Paprika.
Don't make me get rough with you.
This is a dream too, huh?
Paprika, wake up! Paprika!
Wake up, Chiba!
Chiba! Paprika!
The sphinx look doesn't suit you.
An intelligent researcher by day,
the chairman's humble servant by night.
Is that it?
Shut up!
I have many faces. That makes me human!
Oedipus is the perfect look for a man
completely controlled by the chairman!
Shut up!
That's right, keep running.
There are nu boundaries to dreams.
The spirit will be freed from the constraints
of the body and gain limitless freedom.
Including me!
I will also be free!
The dream continues from here.
No! Paprika!
It's a trap!
Chief! Wake her up!
Please hurry!
What a lovely sight.
Osanai!
What is this? Let me go!
But I finally caught you.
Where is Tokita?
I have no interest in such ugly things.
Of course, because you're not.
You were Himuro's idol after all.
Shut up! Just shut up!
You sold your body for the DC Mini, didn't you?
Don't remind me!
You coward!
Stop it!
This is my sanctuary, and you'll do as I say.
I'm a special person.
Yes, hand-chosen by the chairman.
Osanai, you used to be smarter than that.
You don't know its true power!
The DC Mini was, in a way, complete.
No, better than complete.
We can now go back and forth between dreams and
reality even without the DC Mini, while awake.
You were the one who set up
Atsuko at Himuro's place.
It was just a friendly warning
to a terrorist threatening dreams.
You're just like an old baldy I know.
We are the chosen ones,
assigned to protect the sanctuary...
...threatened by technology
that has lost its philosophy.
You're just twisted.
You should understand.
Dreams are so sacred,
they cannot be controlled...
What would you know? You're just a
little man controlled by jealousy.
You really think you can beat Tokita?
I warned you, don't make me get rough.
You should call it a night.
Don't worry, I'm drunk.
The fact that I know I'm
drunk is proof that I'm sober.
This isn't a real bar and this isn't real
alcohol, and you're not a real bartender.
Right?
I'm sober...
...even if odds and sods go around in my head.
Paprika will come, right?
Do you not like the number 17?
The conspiratorial 17.
You're familiar with movies,
as if you've made them before.
I did.
Shot an independent on an 8 mm.
It was child's play.
When you were in high school?
When I was 17...
It's a silly cop story.
Two men who used to be best friends,
are now fugitive and cop engaged in a chase.
They just keep running...
...and flashbacks of their
past play throughout.
Very experimental.
That guy...
How could I have forgotten
about him until now?
He was always one step ahead of me.
He was smart and popular with the girls.
I could never catch up with him.
I was frustrated at myself,
for not being frustrated with him.
He really was a good guy.
We talked about making movies together.
But I gave up.
I didn't have the confidence.
I left the unfinished
movie for him to deal with.
And that friend now?
He died.
He had just gotten accepted to
film school, but he was sick.
He didn't tell me.
I betrayed him.
I was his partner.
I was his counterpart.
He was the other...
The other me.
But what about the rest of it?!
Wait!
Stop!
Why do you dress like a girl?
Paprika!
The real you is more befitting of me.
Stop, please...
...you jealous, perverted prince!
You have a bad habit of trying
to manipulate people with your words.
And you think you can
manipulate people with power?
In here, yes.
I love you.
I love you as you are.
I will show no mercy for those who defy me.
Chairman...
You cannot hide anything from me.
Chairman, not her. Not her!
Can you not control
even one sensual desire?
Please! Please spare her!
Why won't you obey me?
You are nothing without me!
But I love her.
Paprika!
Are you okay?
I knew you were Paprika.
What are you doing? You will obey!
Disgusting.
You fool.
Swayed by a mere woman.
I'm too anxious to dream!
Konakawa?
Shima? Is that you?
Konakawa.
Why are you in Chiba's dream?
Why are you a monkey?
What's going on?
I'll explain later. Just go!
Go where?
To your dream!
Don't get in the way of my dream!
This is my dream. You get out!
I am justice!
Freeze!
How's that for traumatic?
What about the rest of it?!
It's coming up right now!
This time, I'll end it!
That hurts.
It's over.
Chief.
Is this really the real world?
I think so.
See? It hurts a lot.
But why was Konakawa in your dream?
That's right,
Paprika was saved by Mr. Konakawa.
The chairman and Osanai...
Tokita!
What about Tokita?
Osanai! What's wrong?
Osanai!
No! No! Osanai!
You can't go!
That body is mine!
I will not allow you to act on your own!
My noble spirit needs that body!
When the two become one, I will be complete!
Something's wrong.
Not just Tokita, but what
just happened with Osanai.
Don't worry.
We just need to get the mastermind.
A happy ending is right around the corner.
But that mastermind is
lost in his own delusion.
No problem.
We have backup.
Mr. Konakawa.
The number you called fur
assisting young children...
... is not available because of
crowded lines in the Pacific Ocean...
... starting at 7:63 a.m.
The battle has ended.
Now...
...it's showtime!
Todays weather is dreamy and will clear up
after a sunny, sunny, sunny, sunny, sunny day.
The dream I had yesterday and today.
The happy and mundane world
will vent their anger.
The dreams will grow and grow.
Let's grow the tree that blooms money.
It's most valuable while it's still a bud.
That's right, so we shall
preserve the memory forever.
If there is no flower,
there will be no fruit.
If there's nothing,
then I won't do anything.
If you're unhappy,
please put a vote in this eyeball.
Who would give up this throne?
I am the emperor,
chosen by the lord himself!
I didn't choose you!
God and Buddha will change religions.
The happy and mundane world
will vent their anger.
Am I still dreaming?
Yes, the whole world is.
You forgot this.
Thank you.
Now, let's go.
Where?
To clean up this mess.
Dreams and reality are merging?
Is this because of the DC Mini too?
Chief! Hold on!
Paprika?
No time for questions. Hurry up!
Why are you here?
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
Is this reality?
Hurry! We have to get the mastermind!
It's as if we're in a dream.
Hurry!
Don't get ahead of yourself, Paprika!
Don't think you're always right.
Tokita.
Let's go, Atsuko.
I have to help Tokita.
Leave that irresponsible fatso.
Why don't you listen?
You're a part of me!
Have you ever thought that
maybe you are a part of me?
Do as I say!
To think that you can
control yourself and others.
You're just like an old baldy I know.
Let's go.
We need to stop that old
baldy and his excursions.
Now!
No!
I can't just leave Tokita because I...
Because what?
Chiba!
She's become true to herself, hasn't she?
An overweight spirit needs no diet!
Go forward, superhero,
to anywhere you please!
Tokita, wake up! It's me!
The one I've been waiting
for since historic times!
Your flute's melody is
a sound for sore neurons!
Yes, try to remember.
Atsuko, the one you like!
It's me, At-chan!
A fragrant fat is a first class lunch!
It needs a little more spice.
Maybe a little paprika?
What is this?
A big hole.
I can see that!
It's connected.
To the other world.
The other... You mean?
What should we do?
Run?
You think so too?
Well-rounded achievement is missing a spice.
Paprika found!
Hey!
Paprika! Shima!
Are you two okay?
Mr. Konakawa!
Konakawa.
Chiba?
I'm in a bind.
I can see that.
It's not that!
Sorry.
You're such a slob.
I know.
You're fat, slow and sloppy.
It's not the outside that counts,
but there's a limit to that too.
Yeah.
To think, a food disposal like you
is the genius of the century.
I swallow everything.
I know.
You're so much fun.
Atsuko is dreaming.
What is that?
Our chairman!
I feel great!
I am reborn!
Look! I am standing!
With my own legs!
I am perfect!
I can control the dreams, and even death!
Now, to make the cosmos complete...
...I shall heal all deficiencies!
Way to go, Lord of Darkness!
Light and dark. Reality and dreams.
Life and death. Man and?
Woman?
Then you add the missing spice.
Paprika?
Bingo.
Paprika!
The new cosmos begins with me!
Who is eating up my dream?
Is that Paprika?
Well, it's a girl.
Why won't you obey?
Have we awoken from the dream?
I just had the best dream.
I had a good dream too.
The first in a long time.
I guess I've been dumped.
You mean you were serious?
But Paprika is a woman in your dreams.
That's true. I'll see her
in my dreams again someday.
How are your dreams going?
I almost forgot about it.
Did you find out what was causing it?
The cause...
You didn't do anything wrung.
You just lived out our movie in real life.
That's why you became a cop.
It's truth that came from fiction.
Always remember that.
Yeah, all the truths and the fiction.
Welcome.
I have a message fur you from Miss Paprika.
I heard you caught the perpetrator in
that homicide case. Congratulations.
I also have an announcement:
Atsuku's last name will change to Tukita.
P.S.
The movie "Dreaming Kids" was very good.
I recommend it.
- Dreaming Kids -
One adult, please.
Paprika.2006.720p.BluRay.x264-IMF
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0851578/
Frame Rate: 23.976Fps.