I think the biggest misconception about Break Dancers, or B-boys...
with people out here in the world is that,
They're not dancing.
That everything they're doing is just happening at the moment
and they don't know what they're doing
they're just doing it, they're just going crazy.
Breaking is a legitimate dance, as legitimate as any other dance that has existed.
Planet B-Boy
Break Dance does have a history
And a lot of heroes that no one is ever going to know
If you look at the socio-economic
situation in New York in the late 60s and early 70s
you could see how
something like Hip Hop could spawn itself
because there wasn't that much happening at all.
So, there's all this energy in a young person,
and then these elements of expression are around
and you want to draw to them.
Hip Hop is not Rap.
Hip Hop is a culture, that consists of 4 elements.
It's B- Boying,
DJ ing,
Mc ing,
and Graffiti writing.
What it did was that it gave an option,
in which each individual
chose on how to express themselves.
And that is the truest form of what Hip Hop is.
With Hip Hop
the rules were being made on the spot.
We can call a move whatever we want to call it on the spot.
Or an individual thats empowering
that's something that, wow, you definitely want to be a part of that.
B-Boy comes from the terminology, Beat-Boy.
Because we danced to a specific beat, to a record.
It's a gesture of a fight, without actually touching someone.
But with the same intensity of a battle of a gang.
The battle is what the B-Boy is about, he lives for that battle.
There's nothing else.
Other influences in B-Boying, Kung-Fu movies,
gymnastics,
and then the music with James Brown,
and certain steps that he did.
It was a mesh, to create
one specific dance.
The USA B-Boys, like in the early years,
were our heroes in Europe.
We tried to grab every little bit
of Rock Steady Crew, New York City Breakers
And they were our great heroes.
If I could describe Kenny in one sentence,
He's the last true B-Boy of his generation.
A lot of dances stay exactly the way they are.
They're not allowed to evolve, or use anything else.
Breaking its just unique,
the way that it's all put together.
It's like the ultimate dance.
Because you can take from everywhere.
But you just have to put,
B-Boy flava on whatever you took from.
In the late 70s, Bboying
basically branched out.
And that's what caught the media's attention.
The Culture of Hip Hop, visually,
was brought out to the masses, out to the world
Because of the movie Flashdance.
Because of Break Dancing.
Not because of a Rap record.
In Germany, Break Dancing came first.
And then of course with Break Dancing
came the music,
But, nobody was really interested in Rap Music at the time.
Everybody sees it and it becomes
really big.
And especially with young people,
they are going to try it right when they see it.
There was that famous scene
Showing backspin
and backsliding.
Moves I'd never seen before.
It struck me like I'd been
hit over the head.
We only went to the movie, not to see
Jennifer Beals, not to see that love story
Everybody just went into the movies
to see Rock Steady dancing on the street.
When I saw that guy
spinning...
It was like destiny saying
"This is for you."
"You are the movement of life."
It is very personal and emotional
for me.
In the 80s what happened was,
it got exploited.
It was just... a quick fad.
These guys here,
they don't know what it's really about.
They don't understand that all of us
that we are much better than what these guys are doing,
and that they don't have a clue.
It was ugly
it got really bad.
And that was the end of it, you know,
to where they said, you know, we've sucked everything we can out of it
these last two years
and then we're done.
Germany 1990
Something really interesting is happening in Hanover.
It's the first international Break Dance competition.
And we have the founder in the studio today.
Tell me, how did you come up with this idea?
I started "Battle of the Year" in 1990,
because at that time
it was dead.
I wanted to show the public that,
wow, Break Dance is still here.
It's changed a lot,
that to us, Break Dancing was more than just a fashion.
So in the early years
it was really, really small.
The audience was only 500-800 people.
But the longer we did it,
the more popular it got within the Break Dance community,
then more and more nations
joined the "Battle of the Year".
If it wasn't for
"Battle of the Year",
B-Boy in Europe
definitely wouldn't have been what it is today.
The aim was also to show,
it's a culture on a really high level,
They have love for what they are doing, they invest energy and time
seven days a week to practice...
For me it was always so hard,
to see how hard those kids worked on their skills,
But finally it always ends up,
that's it.
And this is so stupid, in my opinion,
so I thought, ok,
I have to do something,
I have to show the way to perform in theaters for example,
or to show,
how to perform on comercials
like exhibitions, to make their living.
The "Battle of the Year" is an annual event,
and each year, in the beginning of the summer
there are "Battle of the Year" eliminations
that take place in 18 countries throughout the world.
Each country gets to send just one team
to Germany, to the world finals at the end of the year.
Japan Eliminations
Each of the countries
where we have "BOTY" eliminations,
the top crews come together
and in the first round, they put on a show in front of the judges.
For a good show
the criterias to judge on are like...
theme and music, choreography itself how its built up,
if the crews are dancing syncronized
and also the stage presence.
Considering the aspect of choreography,
The Japanese dancers, they always had
better ideas than any other B-boy country in the world,
they are always very innovative.
French Eliminations
The general reputation of
French B-boys,
is that they are really good dancers,
Their expression is really positive
and at the same time agressive
and these are basically all aspects
forming a perfect B-Boy.
The French, they were doing some really intracate,
daring dancing.
USA Eliminations
So the top 4 crews from the first rounds
are qualified for the 2nd round.
Which is the "Battle" round .
So in a Battle, you have two crews on stage,
one on the left side, one on the other side.
And then the dancers are coming out,
dancing against each other
like attacking the other dancers from the other side.
So it is also possible, that
the whole crew
or let's say 2-3 dancers of one crew
are coming out with the choreography,
or you can call it "Commando",
attacking the whole other crew,
then has to react the same way.
So it happens in an exchange.
He's giving me something, that I
can relate to, and I have to answer
with something that he can relate to
so we can continue this battle.
So we can continue this exchange.
The dancers more or less have to improvise
with the music,
which is played spontaneously by the DJs.
And the judges are looking, closely
at how the dancers work this out with the music.
The battle is what, the American B-boy
is about.
You eat, sleep,
and think about a battle.
The USA B-boys, they are mostly known for having
a lot of good individual skills for battleing.
You have really, really complete
unique characters in the USA B-Boy scene.
South Korea Eliminations
Korea is a B-boy phenomenon country,
because they developed their skills
in such a short time.
What Germany or France did in 15 years,
they in a way,
managed this in 5 years.
They came out of no where,
bringing the level of powermoves
on a completely new level.
Doing powermoves, no one
has seen before,
They got so popular in
Europe and all over the world.
On a technical level,
there is nobody that could touch the Koreans. Nobody.
USA Eliminations
Japan Eliminations
The winner is...
South Korea Eliminations
French Eliminations
PHASE-T
French Champions
This battle represents
my childhood...
and what I've been dreaming
of for such a long time.
It's what pushes me to train.
KNUCKLEHEAD ZOO
USA CHAMPIONS
When it comes to a Jam like "Battle of the Year",
You train
your whole career for it.
"BOTY" is one of the first videos I ever saw,
and I said, I want to go there.
LAST FOR ONE
SOUTH KOREA CHAMPIONS
I've been working toward this...
and we've reached the pinnacle.
Battle of the Year is the summit.
ICHIGEKI
JAPANESE CHAMPIONS
It's hard to say what it means to me.
It really is the biggest goal of my life.
Japanese education stresses homogenization.
which is reflected in the proverb...
"The nail that sticks out gets hammered down."
KATSU
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
I think the B-boy style...
that exists in Japan
is related to "bushido",
the way of the samurai
You're not a true B-boy...
until it becomes more
than just a hobby.
NON MAN
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
QUIK
After I started Breakdancing...
I became more aware of my
identity...
and open to other ways of thinking.
Since I was young,
I always lacked calmness.
CATCHER
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
The reason I dance...
is to explode
and feel free.
KATSU
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
I've been B-boying for about 8 years.
I also DJ as a hobby.
I work at my family's green tea store.
I think Djing is fascinating.
It's sharp and has a lot of speed.
PRINCE
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
Most people focus
on the athleticism...
but there's also the artistry...
and a B-boy's job is to
express them both with the music.
KOUSUKE
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
I don't believe there's any
natural-born talent in breakdancing.
What's most important is your drive to improve.
SHIN
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
I'm broke and have to quit
my job to go to Germany.
Honestly, I think I am on the borderline...
of being the worst father!
SHIN-OSAKA STATION
JAPAN
ICHIGEKI REHEARSAL
ICHIGEKI they have been at "BOTY"
2002 already,
and I was very happy to see them again,
in the elimination in Tokyo.
One could see that,
they improved their skills,
they got older
and they are one of my favorites for this year's finals.
In 2002 we represented Japan...
at the "BOTY" finals...
but the results were awful.
"BOTY" 2002
I can remember everything.
It was a tough year for us all.
We argued within our
team the most that year...
just because we wanted to win.
We even performed moves
we didn't really like...
just to win.
We didn't win anything.
We were really ashamed.
This year...
it's not just about winning.
There are more important things out there.
Good. Thats it. Come on!
Great. Really good!
KATSU
ICHIGEKI/JAPAN
It feels good to know...
that I have Ichigeki around.
My father died about three years ago.
They found a cartenoid tumor in his liver,
My husband wanted him to finish High School...
then go on to college...
and keep dancing as a hobby.
Honestly, when he was
in the hospital struggling...
we didn't get along very well.
While he was critically ill...
I was dancing.
He didn't understand me
and we didn't talk to each other.
My father simply wanted me to grow up.
He continued to dance after his father died.
When we were on stage once
I told him...
"Battling can help release emotions."
"It would be nice if the passion
you feel for the dance"
"was channeled to your father."
French B-Boys, man
they have such a nice sensitivity for music.
I think that the French B-Boys
they dance more beautiful then the rest of the world.
CLAUDE
PHASE-T/FRANCE
When I discovered this artform...
I knew it was the best outlet...
to satisfy my thirst for creativity.
LIL KEV
PHASE-T/FRANCE
There's nothing more
important to me than dance...
so my goal is to win
Battle of the Year...
and become World Champions.
ANNE
PHASE-T/FRANCE
Everytime I come out of a practice or a battle,
I have a rush of energy,
that I've never felt in any other way.
If I don't dance for 3 days,
I get crazy.
CRAZY MONKEY
PHASE-T/FRANCE
When I was little, I was nicknamed
"the monkey"...
because I jumped around a lot.
Then people started telling me I was crazy...
so I called myself "Crazy Monkey."
I think it suits me because
my moves are a little crazy.
Your strength is the dance!
ZOUBIR
PHASE-T MANAGER
In Germany, Phaste-T will
represent France of course...
but we will also represent our town...
Chelles.
LIL KEV'S MOM
We live in Chelles.
We are 25 kilometers from Paris.
Chelles has a population of 45,000.
There are a lot of...
North Africans and black people.
CHELLES COMMUNITY CENTER
Phase-T's image is based
on our spirit as a team.
They spread a message through their dance.
To laugh, to be warm.
To bring back a warmth that B-boys have lost...
especially at BOTY!
There's a good ambiance.
The guys are like brothers to me.
At first I didn't know what it was.
His father and I were a bit against it.
because they're all 6 feet tall...
and black, black, black.
And he is very small for his age...
and blonde, blonde, blonde.
SKWALL
HIP HOP PROMOTER
Hip-Hop often has a negative image...
because people see it as
"gangsta rap" or something.
.
Frankly, I didn't like it before.
I was a lot more racist.
It's true, I was.
-Whatever.
People should transcend the prejudice
they have against Hip-Hop...
because there is a lot more to it.
CLAUDE  BEE-D
PHASE-T/FRANCE
We're heading to the mall...
where we practice with the kids...
The ones who inspire us.
So many different people came together
under the name of Hip Hop,
that Hip-Hop changed music, arts, completely.
Hip Hop changed the world view,
on, how we are together.
We come from so many backgrounds in France...
the phrase "French culture really doesn't apply.
We like France for what it is...
but we can't say the flag
blue, white, red really represents us.
Our flag is Hip Hop.
Whether you're DJ ing, MCing, Bboying,
you're coming from deep inside yourself,
and you're just really
you know, enjoying
the ability to express yourself, but there's a lot of freedom in that.
PHAX
Slow-Mo Dancer
The art in Hip Hop, is
when you're dancing, you're discovering also yourself.
And how to put your motions on
on the movements,
to find more self confidence, to be able to open,
to really feel all the feelings you have all around in life
and it gives you also a chance
by your own ways of life.
The most important thing
is to show the whole world...
that people coming from nowhere...
who grew up with a minimum, really a minimum...
can accomplish a maximum.
He wanted to be a fireman before...
and I would be pround if he became a fireman.
-Get over it.
Hip Hop is New York history,
and we know that you have a lot of
Bboy crews in California.
But now all of a sudden, since a couple of years ago
Las Vegas
is more or less one of the
capitols of B-Boying in the USA.
I'm really happy and excited to see
how a crew from Las Vegas
out of the desert, will make to the "BOTY".
B-Boying fills this gap in my life
that I mean
I can't even really explain.
You know, It's almost like a spiritual thing.
that it fills, and I just can't let go of it.
The best feeling you have ever felt,
times that by 2.
That's kind of the feeling we get.
DO-KNOCK
KNUCKLEHEAD ZOO USA
I love to just go out there,
and dance
and just having cats
like, "wow, you're amazing, bro".
Las Vegas is a good training ground
no matter what you do.
Everything is so readily available
at 24 hours a day.
Like, Vegas has culture,
but it's entertainment culture.
It's a different culture, to probably
any other city in the world.
- It's culture is, that there is no culture.
- Exactly.
I'm down with Bboying because of the battle.
And business, to me, I treat the same exact way.
It's a battle, you're actually battleing people
For what you believe in.
With Hip-Hop the Mcs have been doing it,
the Djs have been doing it...
And even different aspects, the Graffiti artists up coming now are doing it.
Now it's time for the Bboys to take steps to control
our own future,
instead of, letting someone else do it for us.
Omarion, Justin Timberlake, Usher.
Always had a B-Boy
right there teaching them.
And they never get respect,
and they never give a name.
The mainstream dancers look down on
Bboying because,
it's such a new dance.
They go out there and they're doing all this choreography,
took them several years to learn, they all look the same.
Then we can come out there with our own technique,
and do something that's just amazing, and people go crazy.
There is no limit,
you can do whatever you want.
As long as you're dancing
and you got that Bboy attitude, it's all good.
Winning the BOTY,
is really about respect.
When you come back and people say -
I heard those guys are the best in the world.
I wanna see them.
Before I do a battle, before I do a competition
or something like that, he tells me to
"Just go out there and rip that shit"
CHRIS' PARENTS
- That's the way he says it.
- That's the way I say it.
Number one is seeing my son succeeding,
and he's made me very proud.
He's done it on his own,
him and his friends have put together
a crew that's just awesome.
The majority of us
were freinds before we even started dancing.
It's not like a team where we
recruited a bunch of different members
it's like, family, you know.
Pretty much everybody in the crew
is Latino.
It wasn't like it was planned out or anything,
it was more like
we were just homies
and we happened to also be Spanish you know.
Ricky is Bboy diva.
You know what I mean, he loves that attention
Ricky's out there like he's modeling.
Do-Knock is an entertainer.
Oh, this guy is hype!
What Mikey brings to the dance floor
is just smoothness
Mikey gets the ladies,
Mikey has never had a problem with that.
And he's a really good person, bottom line, Mikey has a good heart.
Fonzie's dance style is very explosive.
Fonzie is definetly a character.
Either you love him, or you hate him.
I'm half Venezuelan and half black.
Spanish, is more like where I get the cool flava
the black is where I get a lot of the explosiveness,
why I just fly through the air
But I can keep it nice and cool and controled.
Battle of the Year is what I train for all my life.
When you know you are going
that's when everybody backs up and
looks at it from the outside
and they're like... Wow!
And then you kind of put it into perspective, and you're like -
"We're, representing the USA".
It started out in the Bronx.
It's an American culture right here.
We gotta bring it back to the USA.
I mean we created this thing, you know what I mean?
Everybody grabbed a hold of it
but we are the creators.
The last time the USA won
it was 1998
Man, that was a long time ago,
that was almost 10 yrs ago man.
The 38th Parallel
The line that divides South and North Korea
Korea right now, we're basically
still at war.
Right over there, right over those mountain tops,
We got our Korean brothers in the North,
that have about 3000 missles,
pointed at us right now.
So every Korean man in the last 50 years
have had to go to the army for a minimum of 2 years.
You have no choice in that matter,
the only choice you have is to go to jail.
That's a bitter hard truth, that you have to swollow
at a really, really young age, you know.
Dancing is not allowed in the army. Period.
So we're willing to go to the extreme
before we get drafted.
You lose everything you worked for
when you go to the army.
Like any professional athlete...
if you take a break, you lose all your skills.
GAMBLERZ REHEARSAL
So the Gamblerz are the defending champions
from last year.
Gamblerz represent mainly the style of dancing
or B-Boying
everybody expects from a Korean crew.
Like powerful dancing
very acrobatic styles, clean executions
This is what makes Korean dancers.
Gamblerz, they would not be satisfied with doing moves,
that everybody could do.
They want to technically to be so sofisticated,
and so advanced
that it would at least take a regular B-boy
2-3 years to do.
B-boy Darkness is hardcore.
He's just powerful you know, he's a beast.
Laser has spent 5 or 6 years...
solely spinning on his head.
That's how he became the best
headspinner in the world.
He can't do other moves that well.
Yo, they are just really good at that
one thing
Right now Korea is just spawning
new super-hero killers.
They're just inspiring a lot of people
to go rediculously crazy.
We start practice at midnight...
and go home by 5:30 or 6am.
unless we have a performance the
next day, which means we don't sleep!
Get up!
We decided there will be no days
off before BOTY.
WAL JANG BUDDHIST TEMPLE
I'm a B-boy whose been in many battles..
but I believe this is the first time in history..
a battle has been hosted by a Buddhist temple!
After the Gamblerz became World Champions...
the way people treated us totally changed.
I'm embarrassed to admit it
but our fees went up a lot.
We're booked for more events...
and gained media exposure.
Commercial Starring B-Boy Bruce Lee
Our biggest challenge...
is to win the Championship two years in a row.
No team has done it before...
so we want to make history.
So since the Gamblerz get a free pass
as defending champions,
The second crew from Korea
was qualified through BOTY Korea Elimination,
will represent their country together with Gamblerz at BOTY.
LAST FOR ONE they represent
part of the new generation of Korean Bboying culture.
They still have the good powermoves,
but they are one of the first crews,
showing on an international levelì,
that Korea has more to offer than just
power and dancing machines.
I've been addicted to this dance for so long.
It feels like a shadow following me wherever I go.
We're proud to represent Korea...
to be the face of Korea.
Last For One, the whole crew is
from down south
They only come up for certain events, you know every now and then,
so they really haven't had a chance to get really looked at
JEONJU
South Korea
They just kind of get dissed on,
if you're from out of Seoul.
They look at you as if you were,
a country bumpkin, you know.
Not much happens in Jeonju, compared to Seoul.
Older people, even my own mom,
have no idea what B-boying is..
They think it's just
a bunch of guys spinning around...
like we're cleaning the floor or something.
B-Boy Joe's Father
The truth is many parents
in Korea still don't get it.
Is it tap dance or something?
It's hard for us to understand.
In a capitalist society...
you can't do anything without money.
I would have preferred for him to become...
a professor or a doctor.
so he could contribute to society...
while securing a stable future.
Mr. Byun
Last For One Manager
Older members have to enter the army...
so they see this as their last chance.
They are giving their all this time around...
because winning BOTY
is their ultimate dream.
Preparing for the competition...
we left home to train in Seoul.
Our whole crew is from the countryside...
so before we moved up to Seoul,
we said, "Lets be unified as ONE in spirit"...
"and dance together until the very end".
So we're LAST FOR ONE.
Korean B-boys seem very powerful...
but within the structure of Korean society...
they are actually weak.
These guys know dance
as the only way...
to experience joy in their lives...
so they desperately just want to dance.
Last For One, they're very like
Happy-Go-Lucky family type kids
They really know how to work with each other.
They've only been up in Seoul for a couple of months,
and they're trying to make something happen.
We have to win this year!
Right now I'm not dancing to make money...
I want to make money to dance.
Since Last For One just
moved here from the countryside...
there's not a lot of work.
The team as a whole is in a very difficult situation.
It's gonna stink like an ol' bachelor pad.
At least break out the Febreeze!
Their accomodations are very bad.
We couldn't get one big house for all of them...
so we rented two small studios
with four members in one...
and six in the other.
They are all poor...
and a few are from families
that would be considered...
to be in extreme poverty.
As a father...
I'm not on a path to earn
money like a businessman.
My job is to establish our national identity
by promoting the Korean flag.
I distribute and hang flags
in people's homes for free.
Since I'm in social work...
I don't have the financial means
to support his dream.
He didn't have a mother growing up...
and as a single father...
I couldn't always prepare his
meals or buy him clothes.
That frustrates me.
I want to help him.
I want to talk and drink with him, too.
I promised myself I would..
...but I haven't followed through yet.
Braunschweig, Germany
Braunschweig is not really a big city.
Once a year really, they have international jams,
that's during the BOTY
We have 19 crews from all over the world.
And the town was so kind to offer us
a high school.
Is this a school?
It's an elementary school.
We're in the 4th grade guys!
Welcome to school!
It's a school....
This is awesome!
Works for me.
Each crew gets a bathroom,
we had to buy mattresses, linens everything,
make it good for them
because we didn't want them sleeping on the floor.
The gave us one mattress,
one blanket, one pillow
and told us to sleep on this.
It's no Holiday Inn.
There are only four showers. Four!
You didn't say there are only FOUR showers?!
I gotta go down there to take a shower?
-On my mother's life!
Is that the shower?
For reals?
I need to go buy some swimming trunks.
Wow, graffiti everywhere
-I'm hungry
That's the cafeteria.
I want sushi!
And that's the gym for practicing.
I hope there will be a positive atmosphere in the school.
Wow!
Shocking!
I don't like this.
Is this grape tea?
What the hell is this?
It's rather delicious.
I don't understand why you guys can't eat this.
I was shocked.
They told me to drink this.
It's chocolate sauce. You eat it with a spoon.
How do you say "tastes good" in English?
Yo, don't eat too much kimchi.
Let's try to make it last, ok?
I can't stand the thought of
not having anymore kimchi.
Oh, my back!
Hip-hop is so big in Cape Town now
Because it's bringing so many people together,
so many cultures and religion
You can see Ubuntu is a mix of
many different people.
And no matter if you're black, white or colored
we are still going to do this, it brings us all together.
It's my first experience out of the
USA.
I've been craving this for so long,
just to come out overseas.
That really inspires me to be around all these people
especially when I'm doing something that I love.
Hey, the American guys are practicing.
The American guys are practicing!
Hey, they're good at basketball!
You're crazy.
Don't forget I'm black.
Being American doesn't matter.
They don't know.
The French think they are just
as badass as we are.
Bottom line, just as bad as us.
So when you get those same mentalities
in a circle, you'll get a heated battle.
The American mentality
doesn't make it easy because...
Americans are number one everywhere.
-That's a self-imposed position!
I remember we went to France,
and we had a USA flag.
And we got booed! The crowd went "Boo!".
We didn't vote for Bush!
Calm down people!
I'm not sticking around to stare at them.
Most of the crews don't talk to other crews the days before.
You can feel a big tension.
The guys in red are Japanese. In red and black.
In red and black...
The damn Japanese!
What kind of show will they come up with?
We greet each other and
ask how things are going.
We also eat together at the dining hall.
But during rehearsal we are more weary.
We don't speak the same language.
but we communicate with our eyes.
I'm warmed up. It's war time now.
Check out these steps!
Looks like they have a sponsor.
Maybe not, their sneakers aren't nice.
When Korea and Japan face off in soccer...
people get really into it.
If we go to the finals...
I want to battle Japan!
If I could choose our opponent for the final battle...
it would be Korea.
They are amazing...
but their dance doesn't touch my heart.
You can't fuck with history, you know?
No disrespect to the Japanese B-Boys,
or Japanese youth,
because they're hella cool, I have a lot of Japanese friends,
yo we got history.
We may forgive, but we never forget.
We don't have to beat them.
But we can't lose.
We cannot lose.
Damn, that was nice.
It's hard to tell, yeah,
because no one is doing anything full out.
We're not nervous.
I was nervous in 2002,
but not at all this year.
The first time we came to BOTY...
my father told me, "I'm very
proud you're representing Japan."
It was the first time he ever
complimented my dancing.
I cried my eyes out...
and I will remember it forever.
I think that was the last time
we talked to each other.
Day of Battle of the Year
K-H-Z.
You'll see that on stage.
Stay focused.
Bro, how's my hair?
We're positive. We have faith.
Here we are!
The BOTY for the last 5 years
took place in the Volkswagen Hall.
We are the biggest Bboy event worldwide.
We will have like 8,500 people at the venue.
Very, very international audience.
We have people traveling from Japan, Korea, from the USA
Go Ichigeki!
In a way, of course Im proud
that today the Bboy world is watching
Bboys on a big stage
not the Rap artists.
The stage looks perfect.
We're performing here again!
I'm going on the stage
I've admired since childhood...
which is really special for me.
It's like I've bet my youth on this one shot.
Crazy Grandma
66 years old - Sweden
This man is gonna do it tonight!
It's Mike Murder!
TRIX
Host
We're finally here,
Everybody's here.
Battle of the Year!
19 crews,
all qualified to be here today!
One day to find out,
who is the best in the world!
The first crew from Thailand!
At the BOTY, we have two rounds.
In the first round all the crews have to show
a coreography in front of the judges and the audience.
Each show, 6 minutes.
It's important to have, like
stage presence.
Theme and music.
The dance synchronized.
And then you will have a ranking of all crews
and the top four crews of the ranking, go further, into the battles.
Hey man, Gamblerz is up next, right?
Everyone's checking out the Koreans...
because we weren't players
until a few years ago...
when we came out and beat everyone.
I want to beat the Gamblerz, honestly.
They got this hype around them, and
I just want to come and...
The Gamblerz aren't a problem for us...
because we both have technique
AND dance skills.
Nobody scares us.
Shit, we've done this for two years.
Nothing to worry about.
We won Battle of the Year last year...
but we're not done and content.
We'll battle like it's our last time.
We will win to make Korea legendary.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the defending champions of
BOTY...
from Korea...
Gamblerz.
"The History of Korea" is our concept...
We are split into two...
symbolizing North and South Korea.
South Korea is expressed
through the style moves...
while the powermoves represent North Korea.
They wage a war then reconcile...
and try to live in peace.
Eventually they are reunified.
You know, I thought they could have been
a little more on point,
but when you are doing moves that difficult,
you can't always be 100%.
Precise,
so, I'm mad confident and our show is just a different feel.
So, it's just a matter of how the people will react to it
and how the judges see it.
Hopefully they'll want something different this year
instead of a bunch of amazing shit.
How was it after the headspin?
-It fucking exploded!
I'm a very competitive person.
I admit that I like to see him at his best.
He likes to win for his team.
They are compelled to
come together in order to win...
and can't win alone in Hip Hop.
We realized that Hip Hop
was completely different.
They took him under their wing...
like their little brother.
We became more comfortable with it.
Now I won't pass judgement
on someone I don't know.
It's not easy but you learn
to get to know people first.
We'll be France's ambassadors
of its Hip Hop culture today...
and we will do our best to represent.
The last four French crews at BOTY...
have all reached the finals.
So that's the challenge we will undertake...
to reach the finals, Allah willing.
It's you, you, you!
Everything with your heart!
You're gonna make it!
In our show we'll try to wake up the audience...
and feature our musicality, that's for sure
To show that France knows how to dance.
That's it!
You should have seen Storm's face...
and the other judges.
They were in a trance.
Kevin's the one who inspires us.
I called my dad from the airport and said...
"I'm going to Germany now."
He said "Take care of yourself
and I'll see you later."
I remember coming home
one night after rehearsal...
and hearing my father crying...
in the room next door.
The next day I saw my father set his own table...
eat his meal and wash the dishes alone.
My heart just broke.
I got drunk one day and fell asleep.
When I woke up...
I found an envelope next to my head.
There was a $100 with a note inside that said...
"Father, I'm offering you
money for the first time.
Please use it as your pocket money.
Men should not cry."
I was so moved,
I felt tears running down my face.
What I do makes him worry.
But when I succeed in my work
I want to say to him...
"Dad, I am doing what I want to do"
"and making a living."
I want to start all over with him.
Get ready!
We're up next.
Make sure to take three
deep breaths before we go on.
It's OK if you make a mistake.
Everybody does.
1, 2, 3 lets go!
Our crew has a coreography...
that combines the music
and technique of the dance...
adding our own style and
showcasing our teamwork.
In Germany, we're gonna show
what the dance is all about.
We Gamblerz pursue bigger action moves..
or moves that are more technical.
They'll take moves that aren't so difficult...
and package them well.
Good Job.
I messed up here.
Right?
No, it's good.
Everyone had great expressions.
I kept smiling.
I did too.
Here, I kept fucking smiling.
Fucking great job.
When you see that prize
in front of you, and you see what's at stake
and what's possible,
it brings you together, it's like a certain bond
You all have your eyes set on the same prize.
And the only way you are gonna get it,
is if you work together.
Do it 'till the fucking day I die, dog.
Everybody remember that.
When I look at BOTY,
I think about, you know, the aspects of why I started B-Boying.
You were in some little gym,
battling for a $100, you know, or something like a trophy.
All that stuff, were just building blocks
as far as to getting to this point of our lives,
this is surreal,
now we're all here in Germany
doing the same thing we did,
back then.
The theme of our show is Knucklehead ZOO.
That's all the influence from all the casinos, all the lights, our city,
where we live. We're from the city of entertainment
We'll bring white tigers to the scene.
I want him to be strong mentally.
I think my brother is incredible...
and I'm proud of him.
I want him to express his love of dancing...
without thinking of winning.
Without greed.
If he thinks about winning
it will show in his dance.
I never imagined how much my mom...
related to my dancing and understood me.
I'm really fired up now for Germany.
I feel their love.
Nothing is stronger than my family's bond!
The best part about BOTY...
is that regardless of the outcome...
we can put our true selves out there.
It's the best stage for that.
It's gonna be so much fun!
It'll be great!
To get in front of all these people
and do a show...
it's going to be fun!
We're a little nervous, but not out of fear...
it's more out of excitement!
The set-up is that the whole
crew forms two turntables...
and each produces a song.
We create music through our dance.
Ichigeki is a threat,
just because of their energy.
When they're out there,
you can see their passion for the dance that they have.
Well done!
It was unbelievable!
Truly unbelievable!
Wow, amazing!
I was completely absorbed in it.
It felt good.
I think I brought the 10,000 audience...
into my world.
I had the best time dancing with you...
and we're not done yet.
The Japanese...
They were radical.
They must have climbed mountains
to put that show together.
This coreography too, is not just about
which dance forms you do or which dance steps.
You should not forget
that there are other parts like,
using drama, you know like, how you use those,
where's the climax
The top 4 crews from the first round
are qualified for battles.
The highlight of every BOTY
is the final battle at the end.
So, we will have one battle for third place
and we have one battle for first place.
Yeah, judges making
a decision.
I think we'll battle against france.
Whether it's first or second,
or third or fourth, I don't know.
Now let's focus on our combinations...
and assume we've made it
to one of the two battles.
Come on, no one is telling us anything.
Being selected for the third place battle...
means absolutely nothing.
We have to be selected for the 1st place battle...
to have any chance at winning the BOTY.
Let's go, let's go
battle for third place.
Is between...
Let's go!
- It's embarassing.
and
Hey guys, we battle for 3rd place.
For real?
Yeah, 3rd place.
- Motherfuckers.
It's ok guys, it's fine.
You battle against Gamblerz.
- Gamblerz?
Gamblerz are third, so France and Gamblerz.
For the next 30 minutes
stretch, just in case.
France is in the house! Phase-T!
Korea is in the house! Gamblerz!
Battle for third place!
Right now the Koreans are percieved...
to be better than the French.
So when we face the Koreans...
it's a real battle!
We're not friends anymore
You're our worst enemy...
as if you burned down our house or car.
We want to show the Europeans...
that Korea is still a force in Bboying.
That's the message we want to send.
Hip Hop can be peace, love and unity.
But during the battle...
Peace and love, no! Fuck you, no peace and love! FIGHT!
A Bboy crew can be like a soccer team...
where each player has a specific role.
There's a dancer who is good with powermoves.
There's a dancer who focuses on style.
If you see any offensive player coming...
you need a strong defender to stop him.
It's the same with dancing.
If we see the opponent is better at powermoves...
we have to create something to stop him.
It's the guy against you who provokes you...
and gives you rage to do even better.
30 seconds, you got 30 seconds
Hasn't the ranking come out yet?
We come to the battle.
1st place...
The 1st crew...
Ichigeki
Really?!
And the next crew is...
Last For One.
What are your feelings about Last For One?
Dok Do island is ours!
What makes BOTY different
from all the other competitions,
is that it really shows, whether you are
a group or not.
This time I want to win
as a result of enjoying ourselves.
I want to have a great time dancing.
while competing to win.
We should have brought our
white tiger.
We should have called up Seigfreid
Should have brought out the animals.
We just didn't throw enough dynamics in the show.
And we have the dynamics to throw
in the show, which fucking sucks.
Our biggest concern is the future.
If we win BOTY...
we expect great things to come.
That's why we are working so hard.
To have a better quality of life.
For me the art of Bboying,
clearly is, individuality
It's how a Bboy takes that music
and adapts to it.
The music is basically that.
Blood, pumping through your veins.
And it's allowing you to release yourself.
Bboying is different than any
other dance.
Because individual
interprets things differently.
There is no specific format
for individuality.
It's a self interpretation,
on how they want to express what they're feeling.
Through the music they're hearing.
This is where the spirituality comes from.
Before leaving Japan, I visited my father's grave.
I shared all my emotions with him.
I told him I would enjoy every moment here.
I feel like he is looking after me.
Ichigeki is precious to me.
When my father passed away...
they were sad as if my father were their father.
In Korea, they say a man who brags
about his own son is a fool.
In the end, we don't take wealth with us when
we die, but we do go with our honor.
My son is taking a lonely path like his father.
It's a contribution to the development of Korea.
I'm proud of my son.
I feel like I'm following in my father's footsteps...
in pursuit of honor.
I want to win for my father.
The prize money we give away,
for BOTY
is all together 2 500 euro.
Which is around 3,000 dollars.
But, we split this amount of money into
1st place, 2nd place, third place and best show case.
So you can see that more or less
the prize money is absolutely not important for the crews to join BOTY.
Our philosophy is to promote
Bboying culture
and hopefully, they will have a lot of opportunities
after they appear on stage at BOTY
If you make it at BOTY,
Then you can definetly make it with your show
in the normal world
and you can make a living off of it.
The judges have made their decision...
"Best show"
The first award is given away
for the crew with the best show and coreography.
"Best show" goes to...
Ichigeki
The show case that Ichigeki
did, that was amazing.
They scored so high,
that was crazy.
And then we have two more awards,
one for the winner of the battle for 3rd place.
Applause for....
GAMBLERZ.
And finally the big one for the winner of the battle for first place.
Give it up for 1st place...
Last For One
Last for One they seemed more like
the open guys,
that want to party with you,
and they learn through joking around.
And it showed in the battle, and in the show already,
like some of the gimicks they were pulling out.
Honestly, we're happy
We represented. We gave the best we could.
We made a great impression
People loved us and that's what we wanted.
I had so much fun!
I was able to show my own dance.
I was able to stand on stage with these guys...
and receive the Best Show award.
I had a blast.
I'm sure my father is watching me from up there.
I miss my dad.
I don't usually call him after a battle
I could wait to get back to Korea...
but I think I will call him today.
Hello? Dad, It's me.
I'm in Germany.
Dad, we won the competition.
Yeah, we won.
Listen dad, it's crazy over here right now...
so just go back to sleep.
Bye.
Good Morning.
You're drinking now?
I drank two already.
In the first 10 years of BOTY
my aim was to get more and more crews,
from more and more countries,
to get more and more spectators together to see it...
But then, more or less
I reached everything
we had like 10, 000 people in the audience already,
and we had crews from all over the world.
- You want a beer?
- Yeah man, lets go drink some beer, this is the time right?
And then in the last years I
learned what makes for me,
the BOTY, is the little things.
Happening the week before or
the days after,
like people staying together before BOTY, eating together
and practicing together,
exchanging a little bit more hopefully than just
talking about dancing.
Once these rival crews,
once they stop dancing
then they will find out, it wasn't really about competeing,
it was really more about being together and jam in one place.
The sucess in Hip Hop worldwide is that,
no matter what language you speak,
you can communicate with Hip Hop culture.
It's a serious way to unify,
youth.
The admiration they have for each one another
Is the admiration for the dance itself.
And that is the biggest key.
Looks like you'll be busy
when you get back to Korea.
I'm excited to think we'll be busy.
We should be, now that we're winners!
We're gonna get busy!
There's so much more we want to accomplish.
One year later.
I used to worry as his father.
Now I can only watch him.
And I watch him proudly.
My wish for him is to shine even more brightly.
Once our dance has found its place in society...
it will help us make a living out of it.
To make a living with what we love...
is the dream of all dancers.
Phase-T went on to win several Bboy championships
across Europe. They continue to teach Bboying through
the outreach program in the community of Chelles.
The Gamblerz continue to compete and
perform year-round in Asia, Europe and the USA
Knucklehead Zoo have gone on to peform for the
troops in the Middle East and several NBA shows
They also continue to work the circuit in Las Vegas.
The members of Ichigeki retired the crew to focus
on life outside of dance, but they vowed to remain
Bboys forever. Many considered their final show
one of the best ever performed at BOTY
PEACE, UNITY, LOVE AND HAVING FUN! HIP HOP LIVES! PEACE!
Translated and subtitled by Bboy Spazmatic, Floor Spiders Crew USA
Contact: saide_david@hotmail.com
So, the first part that people are gonna try
Is just this, draw, turn the hips...
My  name is Buddah, I'm from Ottawa, Canada
I started the Canadian Floor Masters,
23 years ago
And danced consistently from the early 80s
But I also am a social worker, I went to school
and I did a Masters in Social Work
And I combined those two things together
To try and come up with a package that
speaks to young people, and youth at-risk communities
and aboriginal communities in the far north of Canada
Whether its the South Bronx, or whether it's a poor community
in the Artic in Canada
There's some similiarity in the conditions, that young people
may not feel they have a voice
and we sort of give them these categories, of art,
of music, of dance, of fashion, of attitude
of ways of expressing yourself, in a way that
they can have pride
In their culture, and bring in their own elements
and explore ways that they can,
sort of reclaim a voice
They've got to get some self-confidence,
and believe that they have value and that their life is important
And to me that's the starting point
This is what we want we wanted to accomplish this week