I hate surprises.
-Yeah?
-Yes.
You didn't mind when I surprised you
with my promotion.
Well, that wasn't a surprise,
that was earned by my genius husband.
Good answer by my genius wife.
See, l thought you only liked me
for my body.
l do like you for your body.
What are we doing?
Surprise.
l don't understand. What is it?
-lt's a house.
-Yes.
Yes, l can see that. Thank you.
-Also known as a home, sanctuary, dwelling.
-Yeah?
Or, if you like, you could just call it ours.
Ours?
Where would we get the money?
l mean, how do we
get into something like this?
Oh, l don't know.
Maybe with a key.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, are you kidding?
lt's a classic.
1 920s, wood-frame.
Three bedroom, one-and-a-half bath.
And the old owners even left us
a brand-new swing set out back.
Oh, well, l think l'm a little big
for swing sets.
We have to fill up those spare rooms
sometime soon, right?
Thank you.
-l love you.
-l love you, too.
Let's go home.
Mommy?
When's Daddy coming home?
-What, baby?
-When's Daddy coming home?
Today, baby. lt was just an overnight trip.
Why couldn't he take us?
Because it was work and we couldn't go.
But how about a, "Good morning, Mommy.
-"Nice to see you."
-Good morning, Mommy.
-Mom, you gotta get dressed.
-Sweetie, we got plenty of time.
-We're gonna be late for school.
-Oh, no.
We're not gonna be late for school.
Better get going or we'll be late for school.
Bridgette, are you okay
with your spelling words?
Yes, Mom.
Hey, hey, hey, don't forget your lunches.
You got it? Here. Got it?
Give me a kiss. Bye. Bye.
-Come on, Megan.
-l am!
This isn't dirty.
Hey, girl, what's going on?
I can't beIieve it's Thursday aIready.
Tell me about it.
l have no idea where this week went.
God, l wish you were here.
l am having the hardest time
trying to pick out my dress for tonight.
What about you guys?
You have any big plans for the weekend?
What, besides jetting off to Acapulco? No.
Yeah, right. Okay, l gotta go.
l gotta figure out
what l'm doing with my life right now.
Oh, yeah? what's his name?
His name?
Well, the name is really bad. lt's Harry.
But, you never know, he couId be the one.
Bye.
You have one new message.
First new message.
Linda, Iisten, I need to teII you something.
I meant what I said in front
of the girls the other night, and...
I just...
I just want you to know that
and to please remember it.
Damn it. Someone's calling. Hold on.
ls that you?
End of messages.
lf you leave a message,
l'll get back to you as soon as possible.
Hey, it's me. l got your message.
l don't know when you left it,
but just call me when you get mine.
Okay? Bye.
Mrs. Hanson?
Yes?
Linda Hanson?
-l'm Sheriff Reilly.
-Yes?
l'm sorry to tell you this.
-Your husband, Jim...
-Yeah?
...was in a car accident.
He died on the scene.
-When?
-Yesterday.
No. No, it's impossible because l just...
l just heard his voice
on the answering machine, so...
Well, l'm sorry, ma'am.
We couldn't get to you any sooner.
The other driver was in a truck. A semi.
They're certain it was instantaneous.
lt jackknifed. 220.
He was on the highway,
around mile marker 220.
The truck driver was killed as well.
l'm very sorry about your husband.
Ma'am, is there anything that l can do?
Ma'am? Mrs. Hanson? Ma'am?
Can l call someone for you?
Let me leave you my card. Okay?
lf you have any questions, you just call me.
What's wrong, Mommy?
Mommy?
What's wrong?
lt's about Daddy.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
He's had a very bad accident.
What kind of accident?
When is he coming home?
ls he okay?
No, baby, he's not.
Come here.
Wow, l'm impressed.
You guys got this far all by yourself?
Yeah.
That's really amazing.
Hey, it's Annie.
Leave a message at the beep,
and l promise l'll get right back to you.
Hey, Annie. lt's me.
Could you please call me
as soon as you get this message?
Thank you.
Wow, you girls are doing so great.
Daddy's better at puzzles.
He was going to help us.
-Hi, honey.
-Hey.
l think l finally got them to sleep.
Oh, l should say good night.
No, don't do that.
They just fell asleep. Leave it.
Okay.
l was thinking about everything
we need to get done.
Tomorrow we should probably
start looking into funeral arrangements.
And then, you know, just see
where you are in terms of insurance.
l'm not ready for that, Mom.
Nobody's ready for any of this, dear.
But you'll be surprised
at how strong you're gonna be.
-You know when l lost your dad...
-l can't stop thinking
about our serving platter.
-What serving platter?
-You know, the big one on the top shelf,
the one that his folks gave us.
l can't reach that.
Jim... Jim does that for me.
Well, nobody expects you to get
everything done in the first few days, dear.
l... l'm pretty tired.
-l'm gonna go lie down in the den.
-Okay.
l'll get some sheets out of the closet.
l'll be right up here if you need me, dear.
Mom?
Jim?
What's wrong?
l don't... l don't know.
l just had... l just had the...
l just had the strangest...
What? What is it?
Okay. l guess it's nothing.
lt's nothing, it's nothing.
Mom, we're late.
Three times and we get detention.
And how is that
a good way to start the day?
How about, "Good morning, Mommy."
-Good morning.
-"Good to see you, Mommy."
Good morning.
All right. l gotta get going.
Monday morning meeting.
l got hugs for everybody.
All right, l gotta get going.
l gotta train this new assistant manager.
l packed their lunches. Ready to go.
Are you okay to take them to school?
Okay.
-You girls have fun at school now.
-Bye-bye, Daddy.
See you, honey.
-You okay with your spelling words, Bridge?
-Yes.
Hey, you guys, don't forget your lunch.
-Come on, Megan, get out of the car.
-l'm coming.
You have no messages.
Oh!
Oh, shit.
-That was quite a stop there.
-Yeah, l just... l was totally...
Yeah, l just, l got comp...
l just, l was totally just distracted.
Let's just take it a little easy out there, huh?
Sure.
We don't want anyone getting hurt now,
do we?
l'm trying to figure out, should l call him?
l mean, l really feel like l wanna call him,
but then it's kind of like
l think that's breaking the rules.
l think it's better if l just wait.
What?
-Did we talk yesterday?
-Yeah. We talk every day.
No, l mean, did l leave you a message?
l don't think so. Why?
Wait a minute, hang on.
l'm the one with the crisis, okay? Are you...
-Are you sure you're all right?
-Yeah.
Everything's cool with you and Jim?
Yeah. Everything's exactly the same.
Oh, God.
So, how was everybody's day?
lt was okay.
-Kind of boring.
-Thank you.
Yeah, kind of boring.
-Boring, huh?
-Yeah.
Jim?
Jim.
What the...
Lithium?
l...
Thanks for coming.
Here's your coffee.
-You never know.
-Here she is.
Hi, honey.
-Did you get some rest?
-What's going on?
Hey, how you feeling?
Why don't you go upstairs
and let's get some clothes on.
You wanna go upstairs and get dressed?
-Where are the girls?
-The girls are fine, dear.
The girls are fine, honey.
Don't worry about the girls.
This isn't right.
-What isn't, sweetie?
-No, everything's fine.
Do you need to go upstairs
and get more sleep? Or...
No, no, no, l don't need any more sleep,
and l don't need to wake up, either.
Everything's gonna be fine.
-No, Mother, everything is not fine!
-Okay.
-Something is really, really wrong.
l'm...
He's not dead.
Hi, baby.
Hey.
Hi.
Sorry l wasn't awake when you guys got up.
Grandma said we had to let you sleep.
No, baby. You can always wake me up.
What's your sister doing?
-Swinging.
-Yeah?
-l think she's sad.
-Yeah.
We're all a little sad right now.
Hi, baby.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, baby.
Baby, what happened to your face?
Baby, talk to me.
How did you get these cuts?
Who did this to you, baby?
-Did what?
-The cuts! The cuts on your face.
There's no cuts, Mommy.
What are you talking about?
She's perfect, like a beautiful princess.
Oh, God, come here. Come here.
Just hold onto me.
lt's gonna be okay.
lt's gonna be okay. Come here.
lt's gonna be all right.
Everything's gonna be all right.
-Mommy?
-Yeah?
What was it like when Daddy died?
l don't know, baby. l wasn't there.
So how did you know he died then?
Are you all right?
What if this is a mistake?
What do you mean, "a mistake"?
People just don't die one day
and are okay the next day, that's all.
lt's not a mistake. Jim's...
-Okay, Mom, did you see inside the casket?
-No, l didn't see, dear, but it doesn't...
Okay, well something is seriously
fucked up with this situation.
Linda? We need to go in the church now.
Come on, dear.
No, you need to take the kids inside.
-Well, why don't you come inside with us?
-Just take the kids inside.
Go ahead, go ahead with the kids. Linda.
Linda?
Here she is.
Hello, Mrs. Hanson.
l just want you to know
that everything's on schedule.
l need for you to open up the casket.
No, no, l don't think
that would be a very good idea.
Open up the casket, God damn it.
Open it up! Open it up!
-Open it! Open it! Open it!
-Mrs. Hanson!
-What?
-l beg you to let this go.
-Don't do this to me.
-Mrs. Hanson, l have to warn you.
-There was a problem with the body.
-What kind of problem?
They didn't want to tell you the way he died.
The didn't want to tell you.
-What about the way that he died?
-There was a deep cut, a severing.
-What kind of severing?
-Well, it...
-Oh, my God.
-No! No!
Get out of the way! Stop it! Let go of me!
Let go! Let go of me!
No!
Jim left this world a beloved person.
His friends spoke about his kindness,
his laugh,
his graciousness,
his helpfulness and consideration
to everyone around him.
But his greatest devotion was to his family.
His "girls" as he liked to refer to them.
His lovely wife, Linda.
His precious daughters,
Megan and Bridgette.
Mom?
What?
-Who is that?
-And what better tribute is there to any man.
-Who?
-Her, that woman.
Than the reflection of his own love
in the hearts
-of the loved ones he left behind.
-l don't know, dear.
-And so, dear friends...
-Linda?
-lt's okay. lt's okay.
-...let us pray.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Wait. No, please, wait. Wait.
-l'm sorry.
-Stop.
-How do you know my husband?
-l just thought that after we talked and...
-We talked?
-Well, yeah, yesterday when...
Yesterday, l...
-You don't remember?
-No.
l've never met you before in my life!
-l'm just gonna go, okay?
-Please, talk to me.
You have all my sympathies,
and your girls, too.
Who are you? Please. Don't just...
"Lithium carbonate. Take two tablets.
No refills remaining.
"Dr. Norman Roth. Do not take with alcohol.
"Drowsiness and..."
"Dr. Norman Roth."
Dr. Norman Roth.
Mommy?
Hey, why don't you guys go downstairs
and visit with Grandma and Aunt Annie?
No.
l'm sure it'd be fun.
What are you looking for, Mommy?
Mommy needs someone to talk to, baby.
Why don't you talk to us?
Baby, l love talking to you,
but this is grown-up talk,
and Mommy needs some help, okay?
Come on, baby, please go downstairs.
Thank you, baby.
Thank you for being so good.
All right. Physicians.
Dr. Roth.
You've reached the offices
of Dr. Norman Roth.
we are currently closed.
Our office hours are Monday through Friday,
9:00 a.m. to 5:30 p.m.
lf this is an emergency,
please hang up and dial 91 1 .
Do you guys want some tea
or coffee or anything?
Can l get you something?
Maybe we ought to think
about getting the girls to sleep, huh?
-Oh, yeah.
-Been a long couple of days.
Yes, it has.
All right, girls.
Come on with Auntie Annie.
We're gonna go upstairs
and we'll get yourjammies on, okay?
Then l'll read you a story?
Yeah?
Make sure you brush your teeth.
Come in.
Good evening, Mrs. King.
Hi there, Annie.
Hello, Linda.
Hello.
l'm Dr. Roth, remember?
No, l don't. l...
Annie.
-Okay, girls, let's go upstairs.
-Mom? What's going on?
Let's say good night to Mom.
And get ourjammies on.
-Honey, please don't be angry.
-No!
-Please. Please don't be angry with us.
-Mommy!
Wait a second. Annie.
Annie, what are you doing? Annie!
Linda, your family is worried about you.
Your family cares about you,
about your situation, about the girls.
What are you doing?
Mom, what are you doing? Annie. Annie.
-Honey, what else could we do?
-What?
Just tell us what happened
to Bridgette's face.
Mom, l don't know what happened
Don't you see? That's what l mean.
Mom, l would never do anything
to harm my child!
-For the girls' sake.
-Get away from me!
Baby, it's okay. God damn it!
l didn't do this. l didn't do this!
-Linda, stop it!
-Get off of me!
No, you can't do this to me!
What are you doing?
-Baby, it's okay, baby!
-Mommy's all right!
No, no, baby! No, no!
lt's okay, baby! lt's okay!
God, look at what you're doing!
Stop it!
No, it's okay, baby!
Mommy's sorry! Mommy's very sorry!
Stop! Stop it!
Mom! Mom! Stop it!
l'm sorry.
Sir! Sir! Sir!
Obviously, she's never
been committed before.
The husband
was in a fatal car crash on Wednesday.
l told her about it on Thursday.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on.
Wednesday?
That's strange.
She showed up in my office on Tuesday
claiming he was already dead
or was gonna be.
She said he was gonna die
before the accident?
Yeah.
Are you sure it was an accident?
Hello, Linda.
Please don't do this.
l just wanna go home to my girls.
Please, just let me go home to my girls.
-Please don't do this.
-We'll have time to talk about that tomorrow.
Please, don't do this.
Please, please don't do this. Please.
Please don't. Don't do this.
Everything is gonna be just fine.
Jim?
What?
-You're okay?
-Come on, Linda,
you're gonna get yourself soaked.
Just give me a minute.
Just one more minute.
l can hear your heart beating
and it feels so good.
Hold on. Hey, hey, hey. Hold on.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Come on.
-You promise?
-l promise. l promise.
What is it, honey? Tell me what's going on.
l don't even know how to explain it.
-l gotta get going. l gotta get to work.
-Just give me a minute.
Just one more minute.
l gotta... No, l gotta go.
l'm running late for work. l gotta go.
Girls?
-Morning, Mommy.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Mommy.
-Hi.
Hey.
Hi.
Oh.
Oh, you're so beautiful. Do you know that?
You are. You're so beautiful.
You're both beautiful.
Oh.
All right, babies, listen to me.
l need for you
to be very, very careful today, okay?
No playing at recess.
l don't want you running around, okay?
-Ma'am, you're holding up the line.
-Sit quietly, promise me.
-Ma'am.
-Okay? Just give me a second!
-Just promise me. Promise?
-l promise.
Okay, baby.
You gotta promise me, too, okay, honey?
-All right.
-Good girl. Okay. Here you go.
You guys be good.
Ma'am, come on. Please.
You've got Mrs. Lynne at 3:00
and then you're free until 5:00.
Yeah, that's right. l...
-Keep that open for me.
-Okay.
-Who's this?
-Mrs. Stevenson.
Mrs. Steven...
-Can l help you?
-l'm Linda Hanson.
Hello, Linda. l'm Dr. Roth.
Do you know me?
Should l?
l wake up and he's dead.
l wake up and he's alive.
Different things around me all the time
that l can't explain.
Things that l've done.
People talking to me.
People who know me but l have never met.
-People like me.
-Yes.
-Seems a little complicated.
-Tell me about it.
What about the lithium bottle?
l don't know. lt's... lt's...
l don't know. l misplaced it somewhere.
l don't know.
Look, l can't explain it,
but l thought if somebody was trying to...
Trying to drug you?
-Why and who?
-l don't know. You tell me.
-l didn't prescribe it.
-But your name was on the bottle.
-Why do you think l came here?
-To get some help.
Obviously, you're dealing
with some inconsistencies.
Well, yeah. l wake up every morning
to find my husband has died again.
l think that goes
just a little beyond inconsistent.
How do you feel
during the times he's dead?
What?
l mean, what kind of emotions
run through you?
-ls it sorrow? Resentment? Relief?
-What are you saying?
Well, it's a pretty common daydream
to imagine people being dead.
l'm not daydreaming, okay?
l wake up and he is dead.
Except for today.
Do you have any history
of mental illness in your family?
No.
What about yourself?
Any episodes of psychosis?
Memory loss?
Judgment lapses?
l don't want him dead. lt was a car accident.
Well, there's no crime imagining something.
l'm not imagining it. He's dead.
Well, it is a little odd
-that the prescription was for lithium.
-Why?
Because that's probably the best thing
for you right now.
lt'll help you cope.
Do you think you can make it in
to see me here tomorrow?
Hey, look who's here!
-Hey, Bob. ls Jim here?
-Yeah.
How come you don't come by
and see us anymore?
-Honey?
-l need to talk to you.
What is it?
What's going on?
l know l've been acting strange,
but there's something wrong.
There's something very wrong.
-What is it, the girls?
-No, no, no. They're fine, at least for now.
Can we just go somewhere? Just us?
Let's just take the girls. Let's go, just go.
Linda, l can't go anywhere. l have to work.
-Please! l really need you. Can you just...
-Linda, l need to go to the sales meeting.
Excuse me. Jim, we're waiting for you.
l'm sorry.
Who are you?
l'm Claire Francis. You must be Jim's wife.
Yeah. Linda.
l've seen your pictures.
lt's nice to meet you.
Claire's our new assistant manager.
Your husband's been really helpful
the last few weeks.
Guys! we're starting.
Excuse me.
We can talk about this later.
Who killed Cock Robin?
"l," said the sparrow,
"with my little bow and arrow."
Who saw him die?
Oh, Christ! Girls!
-Hurry! The laundry's outside. Grab it!
-Hurry!
Start taking stuff down.
l'll meet you guys outside, okay?
Bridgette, no! Bridgette! Bridgette, no!
Baby! Okay, l'm right here. l'm right here.
Megan, go get me some towels. Please.
-Mommy!
-l got you. l got you.
Here, baby. lt's okay. lt's okay. lt's okay.
lt's okay, baby.
She's still bleeding, Mommy.
-Somebody! Somebody, please!
-We need a gurney right away, please!
l'm Dr. Norman.
Can you tell me what happened?
She went through the glass door.
-Any allergies that we know about?
-She's allergic to codeine.
-Codeine.
-Codeine? Okay.
Put her in 14, please.
Ma'am, l'm gonna need you to wait out here.
-Can l go with her?
-No, ma'am. We'll take care of her.
-Everything's gonna be fine.
-lt's gonna be okay, baby!
-ls she okay?
-Yeah, they just took her in.
-They just took her in.
-You all right?
-What happened?
-She just... She was running.
l had to get the laundry and she was...
She just went through the glass window.
-Honey.
-lt's okay.
lt's okay.
What are you doing, Mommy?
We are gonna
forget about mirrors for a while.
Till you feel a little better.
ls Bridgette gonna have ugly scars forever?
-l don't want any talk about scars.
-All right.
Because as far as l'm concerned,
there are no scars.
And l don't care
what anyone tells you, okay?
You understand?
Because you're beautiful.
Like a princess?
Yeah. Like a princess.
My two princesses.
l thought you were gonna put up stickers.
l did.
l don't know. Maybe...
Maybe l thought l did.
Christ, Linda.
What?
What are you blaming me for this, now?
l've asked your mother
to come and stay while l'm gone.
What? Why?
-Just to help, you know.
-l don't need any help.
-Help take care of the kids.
Look, you can take a break.
You know, get some time to yourself.
For what? Time to myself for what? What?
So l stop acting like a crazy person?
What are you talking about? l never...
You are not separating me from my kids.
l'm a good mom.
God!
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
Sunday. Monday. Tuesday. Wednesday.
Thursday. Friday. Saturday.
Okay, Thursday, find out Jim died.
Find out Jim died.
Monday, Jim alive again.
Again.
Funeral's on... The funeral happened when?
Saturday.
Funeral and what else? What else?
What else? We have...
Lithium is on Saturday.
Tuesday. Tuesday.
We have on Tuesday... We have...
Except for today.
Meet Dr. Roth on Tuesday,
and l am... Oh!
Committed Saturday
by Dr. Roth.
Bridgette's cuts happen on...
Bridgette! Bridgette!
Mommy.
Tuesday.
Friday and Sunday are still open
and Wednesday.
You have one new message.
-When?
-Yesterday.
Oh, God.
Jim dies
Wednesday.
What you doing?
-Jim, don't go on this trip, please.
-l have to.
We waited a year for this interview.
Besides, it could be good for us, you know?
Take a break from each other.
Well, it might be a bigger break
than you bargained for.
What if something happens to you?
Something could happen to me
on my way home from work.
-Should l stop working?
-Jim, l'm begging. You want me to beg?
l will beg. Please, just don't go.
You have children and you have a family.
Why are you saying that?
You think l've forgotten that?
-No, l haven't...
-Because l haven't!
l realize that.
l didn't say that you've forgotten.
-All right. Good.
-Just listen to me.
-l need for you to listen to me.
-No, just stop it.
-No, just listen to me.
-Stop it. Stop it.
Just do me one favor.
lf tomorrow's Wednesday,
just please wake me up before you leave.
-lf tomorrow's Wednesday?
-Just... l know it sounds crazy.
Just please wake me up, okay?
Jesus.
Promise me.
l promise.
Okay.
Oh, that guest bed is just awful.
Mom.
That's right. You stayed over.
-Did you forget l was here?
-No, no, no. No, l remember.
l remember, now.
So that would have to be Friday.
Friday morning. Friday morning.
All right. All right.
Okay. There's two days left.
This is Sunday and there's Friday.
How do we know that? Shit! Shit!
-Are you all right?
-Shit!
Claire. Claire Francis. Who's Claire Francis?
Who's Claire? Who's Claire?
Who's Claire Francis?
-We taIked?
-Well, yeah, yesterday. You don't remember?
Claire. Claire. Yeah.
Mom, l have to go.
What? You need to be with the girls.
You had the shock of your life yesterday.
Tell me about it.
ls there something
we should be talking about?
Something involving my husband?
Who told you?
l think you just did.
He was gonna cheat on me.
He what?
Well, wait a minute.
How do you know? How did you find out?
Because l talked to her.
She told me everything.
-When?
-Today.
Oh, hon, l'm sorry.
-Are you still in shock?
-No.
No, l passed up shock a couple days ago.
The whole thing is bad.
The accident, the other woman, it's a mess.
l don't know if it's so bad.
You know,
maybe it was supposed to happen.
What do you mean?
Even though he didn't do anything yet.
The damage that it would have caused us,
the girls.
Maybe it was enough that he was going to.
Are you listening to what you're saying?
We were roommates, Annie.
We were roommates with two girls,
and my roommate was a liar.
Well, as far as your mortgage
and your daughters' education,
it should all be taken care of.
And with the annuity Jim left you,
you should be pretty much set
income-wise, so...
You know, Linda, l have to tell you,
the timing on all this...
Timing? What do you mean, timing?
Jim stopped in to see me
Wednesday morning, right before his trip.
-Wednesday?
-Yeah.
And he seemed very anxious,
like he wasn't quite sure of things,
and he kept talking about you and the girls,
and he said that,
no matter what happened,
he wanted to make sure you're all okay.
And then he tripled his death benefits.
l mean, it's not a problem.
The police reports
all confirm it was an accident.
So, l'll just get this cleared
through the main office
and l should have a check for you
fairly soon.
Nice view, huh?
Yes, very.
You have a family?
l have two daughters but...
lt's no big deal.
Happens to a lot of people.
They drive by here just like you did.
See the houses by this beautiful lake
and suddenly say to themselves,
"What a great place to start over."
l moved here after my divorce.
Really?
Yeah, it's great.
lt's like a whole new life.
This moss pink velvet is very nice.
l believe l would like that for the showroom.
And...
Miss Dwight, l'll have to call you back.
Thank you.
Hello.
l'm Dorothy Quinn.
l know.
Got it?
-Hi, honey.
-Hi, Mom.
Hey, you.
-One for you.
-Cool.
-Thanks.
-And one for you.
-Thank you, Mommy.
-You're welcome.
You know how much l love you, right?
-Linda?
-Yeah.
l don't want to upset you.
What is it, Mom?
l know this is very difficult,
but l really do think we need to
drive out to the funeral home, dear.
-l'll go with you.
-Oh, it's done.
-What?
-l already made all the arrangements.
Oh.
Well, when were you thinking
of having the...
The funeral is tomorrow.
lt's all set.
-Saturday?
-Saturday.
-That soon?
-Yes, that soon.
You okay, hon?
Hey, Mom?
lf l let Jim die,
is that the same thing as killing him?
Honey, Jim's already dead.
Good night, dear.
With silver buttons, buttons, buttons
all down her shoe, shoe, shoe.
She asked her grandma, grandma, grandma
for a hundred dollars, dollars, dollars
to see the bunnies, bunnies, bunnies
jump over the house, house, house.
They jumped so high, high, high
they reached the sky, sky, sky.
Girls, can you keep it down, please?
lt's Sunday.
All day long.
Hey, why don't you take the girls
out for a while? You know?
You guys should spend some time together.
You can go have some fun.
Yeah. Okay. That's a good idea.
You girls want Daddy to make you
some pancakes for breakfast?
Yeah!
Hello, Father.
Linda.
lt's been a long time.
l'm scared, Father.
l want another piece of bread!
Come on, green head! Get it!
1 632, Dutch trading colony
off the coast of Carolina.
An hysterical midwife claimed to have
walked through the aftermath
of a terrible hurricane
that hadn't happened yet.
-So, what happened?
-They hung her for being a witch.
Two days later,
the entire town was wiped out
by a gale force hurricane.
That's awful.
l'll skip ahead to the 20th century.
Boston. 1 91 8.
At the height of the influenza epidemic,
a father told friends he'd been to the future
and seen the graves
of his two small children.
He went insane and shot them both
to spare them the disease.
Oh, my God.
The autopsy showed
the children were never infected.
He shot himself a week later.
Who are these people? Why did it happen?
You see,
history's full of unexplained phenomena.
Nobody knows why.
Some people thought they suffered
from what the ancients called
Blasphemare absens fides.
The dangers of the faithless.
The faithless?
lt's the notion that nature abhors a vacuum,
even a spiritual one.
People who've lost their beliefs,
they're like empty vessels,
more susceptible to having their lives
taken over
by forces bigger than themselves.
Almost like a curse.
Or a miracle.
Yeah, well, l don't believe in miracles.
Every day we're alive
can be a miracle, Linda.
Well, it doesn't feel that way.
Not for me.
Father, something bad is going to happen.
l need your... l need your help.
l need your direction. l need faith.
Faith is just
believing in something beyond yourself,
something you can't feel, or smell, or touch,
like hope or love.
l believe l've let that all go.
Maybe you should try
and get it back again, huh?
But if it's too late...
lt's never too late
to realize what's important in your life,
to fight for it.
l don't know what to fight for.
He was on the highway,
around miIe marker 220.
Mrs. Hanson?
Ma'am?
who are these people? why did it happen?
History's full of unexplained phenomenon.
Bridgette! No, Bridgette!
Nobody knows why.
Open it up! Open it up! No!
Obviously, you're dealing
with some inconsistencies.
No!
Dangers of the faithless.
I'm CIaire Francis.
Your husband's been really helpful
the Iast few weeks.
Jim.
How do you feel during the times he's dead?
we don't want anyone getting hurt now,
do we?
If I Iet Jim die...
It's never too Iate.
...is that the same thing as killing him?
Inconsistencies.
The same thing as killing him?
-Did you guys have a good time?
-Yeah. Yeah.
We had a great time.
Good.
Let me help you with that.
Smells good.
Oh, good girls.
Night.
-Night.
Good night, baby.
Come here. Give me a kiss.
Hey, why don't you girls go give
your dad another hug, nice and tight?
-Okay.
What's this all about?
-Mama said to give you extra hugs.
-Yeah.
Extra hugs?
Oh, how about extra hugs and extra kisses?
Now, off to bed. Go brush your teeth.
Hey, girls, why don't you tell Daddy
how much you love him?
-Love you, Daddy.
-Me, too!
Well, thank you, ladies.
Aren't you gonna tell them?
-Tell them what?
-That you love them.
You do love them, don't you?
Of course l do.
Then tell them.
You girls know how much l love you, right?
Huh? Right?
l love you more than anything
in the whole wide world.
Mom, too?
More than anything?
l do love your mom.
l love her very much.
Linda!
What are you doing out here?
Honey, let's go back inside.
How did we get here, Jim?
l miss you!
l miss us!
There's still an us.
lt's just different now, that's all.
-Why? Why is it different?
-l don't know why.
-What did you expect us to be like?
-Just the way we used to be!
Linda, look at us. We're married.
We got a house, a mortgage, two kids!
Why do we have to talk about this now?
Why can't we just go inside?
Because we're running out of time!
Watch out!
l'm sorry.
l'm so sorry.
What?
You have that look.
What look?
Like you want to tell me something.
l had a dream you're gonna die.
That was only a dream.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Hello.
Annie! Annie, what day is it today?
lt's Wednesday, it's Wednesday.
What's the matter?
Shit!
Girls? Girls? Jim?
Jim?
Shoot.
"Took the girls to school.
Be back tomorrow."
Answer the phone.
Hi, this is Jim Hanson.
l can't get to your call right now,
but if you'll leave a message,
l'll get back to you as soon as possible.
Thanks for calling.
l should be able to take care
of this right away. No problem.
Thanks, Doug.
-Hey.
-l just got to the room. lt's really nice.
l can't wait for you to get here.
Jim? ls something wrong?
Yeah.
l'm sorry, l can't.
l can't do this.
Do what? The interview?
Us.
Jim.
Pick up. Pick up, Jim. Pick up.
Hi, you've reached the Hanson residence.
You know what to do.
Listen, Linda, l need to tell you something.
l meant what l said in front
of the girls the other night, and...
Well, l just, l want you to know that
and please remember it.
Damn it. Someone's calling. Hold on.
ls that you? Linda?
-Jim?
-l love you, honey.
l need to tell you something.
lt's all right, l know about her.
l know about Claire.
-You do?
-Yeah.
l have to explain it, but it's...
Honey, honey, honey, listen.
l thought that's what l wanted, but l don't.
l just...
l want to make things better, you know?
Between us.
Whatever it takes.
l see you. l see you.
l'm coming up right behind you.
You are?
l'm pulling over.
Thank you. Thank you.
l can see you, honey.
Oh, no.
-Jim, do you love me? Do you trust me?
-Of course I do.
Then turn around now.
-What? l don't understand.
-Turn it around.
Jim.
Are you okay?
Jim!
Jim. Baby, are you all right?
Jim.
Can you hear me? Are you okay?
Baby, can you hear me?
Sorry, l dropped the phone.
l love you.
Let's go home.
Okay. Hold on.
Stalled it.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Jim. Jim, get out of the car.
Jesus.
Jim! Jim! Get...
Shit.
Get out of the car.
Oh, my God!
Jim, get out of the car!
Jim!
Baby!
Mommy, they're here.
Oh, baby, l must have fallen asleep.
-The moving truck is here.
-l know. l heard.
Healing so nicely.
Why don't you guys go downstairs?
l'll be there in a second, okay?
-Okay.
Faith is just
believing in something beyond yourself,
like hope or love.
lt's never too late
to realize what's important in your life,
to fight for it.
l don't know what to fight for.
Every day we're alive can be a miracle.