It seems our little secret's out.
- They're opening up everywhere.
- All over the world.
This is it, we're about to make history.
Stop him. Do whatever you have to.
See, I know that you think
you're doing the right thing,
but you couldn't be more wrong.
New Dawn kills everything.
There are dinosaurs roaming the streets.
- That's what the ARC's for!
- The ARC has failed.
Yes! I'm in.
- It's Connor.
- Get him down from there.
Come on, April.
Don't give me an excuse to fry you.
Philip! You've got to
listen to me, I've seen this!
You're going to kill everything.
Philip, no!
Auxiliary power activated.
Cheer up, Matt, it's working.
- No!
- Connor!
No!
We have to go after Connor.
Philip, at least let me go after him!
No one is going after Connor
until this anomaly is stable.
But you can't control this!
You have to listen to me!
No, you listen to me.
This machine is already generating
more power
than the entire National Grid
and this is only the beginning.
Did you ever even care about him?
That kid worshipped you!
Of course I cared for him.
And if he is dead, it'll be your fault.
Because he wouldn't even
have been up there
had you not poisoned him against me.
Look around you, Matt.
The world didn't end.
You were wrong.
This machine is a force for good.
My work, Connor's work.
I know he would have been proud
of what he has achieved.
You were wrong.
You.
Get him out of here.
Emily, I have to go after Connor.
I have no choice.
- I'm going to get him.
- No, no, no, I'm going to come with you.
No! I'm going to go and I'm going to
bring him back, I promise.
You're going to stay here because
I need both of you here, okay?
Abby?
Connor, do you read me?
Anyone, do you read me?
No, not here.
Connor!
It's growing too quickly.
No. That can't be right.
Run those tests again, will you?
It's all right, Ray, I expected this.
Connor!
Matt!
Connor.
Connor. Connor.
I can't breathe.
Okay, on three
we're going to move, okay?
- I don't think I can.
- You're going to do it, mate.
You're going to do it.
Move back, we've got to move back.
Get up. Where's Emily?
Distracting the guards.
Matt, it's coming again!
Okay, follow me. Come on.
These winds are toxic.
We'll be safe in here, help me.
Connor, get in.
Abby, go, go!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Where are we, though?
Okay. Here, sit him over here.
He needs water.
You just keep breathing and that pain
is going to pass, all right?
Just keep breathing.
Hey.
What is this place?
Our only hope.
My lungs are burning.
Hello?
He needs water.
Okay.
How did you know this place was here?
Water. There must be water.
This is my time.
But I'm guessing later. Or close to it.
You actually lived out there?
Nothing can survive out there, Abby.
Except those ugly freaks.
Oh, no.
It's clean, it's clean! Here.
Okay. Drink this. Okay.
It's okay.
The storms are erratic
and hard to predict.
We're going to have to
time this carefully.
You lived underground?
Yeah, we moved from shelter to shelter,
tried to avoid the storms,
fought the predators.
When I got to your time,
I thought it was the Garden of Eden.
Where is everyone now?
Everyone is dead, Abby.
Have a good look.
This is what New Dawn did to the earth,
turned it into hell.
What is wrong with you people?
Can't you see that I'm actually
quite busy here?
They might be dead now because of you.
Take her away.
You have to stop Burton!
Listen to me! Let me out of here!
- Malfunction. Emergency.
Anomaly expanding.
Check the magnetic field brackets.
What are you doing? Where are you going?
I need you!
Primary reactor offline.
Emergency, emergency,
emergency, emergency,
emergency, emergency...
Helen won.
And I helped her.
All I ever wanted to do was to prove
to Cutter that he was right to trust me,
and I ended up just betraying everything
that he even stood for.
It's okay.
Are you okay? What happened?
Could Philip not afford to pay
the electricity bill?
There was some kind of electrical surge,
everything went dead.
We're on emergency power.
The system is fried,
the detector's offline
and I can't get through
to anyone on comms.
Okay, we'll just get someone to fix it.
Everyone is out in the field.
And I don't think the power-out
is restricted to the ARC.
Philip's infernal machine.
Now I've seen it all, mobile phone
reception when you really need it.
It's Becker.
The electricity is out
all across the city.
It's as if someone set off
a huge electro-magnetic weapon.
- What's Matt say?
- We've lost touch with him.
Get to New Dawn
and find out what's going on.
Try that.
We're on our way.
Good man.
Every second we stay here
New Dawn gets stronger,
we need to go and we need to go now.
You two go on ahead.
I'll catch up with you
when I feel a bit better.
Don't even think about giving up on me.
I'll slow you down.
Never.
Whatever we do, we do together,
that's the deal.
I need you to stop that machine,
I can't do it.
Come on, nothing's finished yet.
Connor, forget about Philip
and the machine.
You have to go back.
Why?
Because...
- Really?
- Yeah.
Stop messing around and help us.
Come on.
The wind's died down.
We doing this or what, then?
It's clear, hurry.
Let's go!
Matt!
Matt! Matt!
It's expanded too quickly,
it's not safe inside, come on.
You will find a way.
Our hopes rest on you.
The future is in your hands
and there's no doubt you will do it.
The future is in your hands.
Philip. Philip!
- Connor, you're alive!
- I need you to help us.
I know this is what Helen wanted.
I just don't understand why!
The anomaly has grown so powerful.
Give us the code
so we can shut down the system.
- It's too late, it's too...
- Stop lying to me, Philip!
Otherwise I'll drag you
through that anomaly myself
and I'll show you what you've done!
Listen to me.
I know your intentions were good
and I know you were trying to help...
This is what Helen exploited,
this is what she always exploited.
Humanity.
Your humanity.
She didn't exploit my humanity, Abby.
She exploited my ego.
Give us the codes,
we can still fix this!
It's no use,
the EM surge would have fried the data.
We can't just quit the programme.
Unless...
There is a way. There is a possibility.
Connor, I need you to crash
the computer in the turbine room.
- Do it.
- Then find Emily, I'm going with Philip.
Come on.
Any news?
No.
What if they've failed
and this is the beginning of the end,
just like Matt said?
What if they're all dead?
They're not dead, Jess,
and it's not the end of the world.
If it was, someone would have
sent us a memo.
You know what my father used to say
when things got rough?
"Where's that ruddy whisky?"
Oh, no!
Don't tell me you're teetotal.
There's...
Don't...
Don't make a sound.
Okay, how do we do this?
I can shut this machine down,
but when I do,
there won't be much left
of this building.
You need to leave, Matt.
Can't we shut it down
and then make a run for it?
As soon as I take
the last system offline,
it'll be like slamming the brakes
on an aircraft
travelling at 500 miles an hour.
Everything in here will be vaporised?
Anomaly expanding at critical level.
Including you, Philip?
Matt,
I'm the bad guy.
Primary reactor overloaded.
Emergency, emergency,
emergency, emergency...
- We've got to get down and override it.
- But it isn't safe!
I know, I know, just do it, Abby.
Shutting it down now.
Then what?
We need to get out of here!
Where... Where's Philip?
He's not going to make it.
He wants to do the right thing.
No, no, we don't have to...
He's locked himself in,
there's nothing we can do.
Well, we can't just let him...
Connor, Connor,
if this is what he wants.
Come on, we're leaving.
We have to get out of here.
- Come on.
Get clear of the building,
I'll find Emily.
Emergency. Emergency.
Emily!
Matt?
What took you so long?
Self-destruction sequence initiated.
Five seconds to self-destruct.
Four, three, two, one.
The anomaly is too powerful,
it doesn't need the machine any more.
There's no way we can stop it now.
What are you doing?
Texting Becker.
What is it?
Almost out of power.
We've got one shot, maybe two.
It's not going to be enough.
Okay, we're going to have to
get to the armoury.
Shouldn't we stay here? Becker will
get the message and he'll come.
There's got to be something
we can do about this.
- It's over.
- There's nothing more we can do.
Won't the anomaly close
on its own eventually,
just like they always do?
This one's manmade. It's stable.
It was designed to stay open forever,
to provide it like an endless
energy source, it's unstoppable.
Okay, so plan A was rubbish,
what about plan B?
We're working on it.
Jess said all the anomalies
had disappeared,
how the hell did she miss that?
Maybe it overwhelmed the system.
It's from Jess.
There are future predators at the ARC,
her and Lester are trapped.
Predators? How can there be predators?
Your anomaly, the one in your lab,
it was the prototype
for this one, right?
Yeah.
So, essentially, it's the same anomaly.
It must have re-opened, which is how
the predators got into the ARC.
There's a way to destabilise
the anomaly,
by merging the prototype with this one.
Where is everything?
All the teams are out in the field,
but I thought there'd be
more than this left.
There's no power.
Power packs.
There.
This?
Oh, God!
Hey, hey, hey.
Over here!
Jess, you're all right now, we're here.
Abby, keep a lookout.
Okay, let's get a drip in him
and seal him in the medical bay.
That's all we can do for now, right?
Jess. Jess, how many were there?
Um, four or five, maybe more.
Becker, check the car park.
James?
Internal video system is down,
everything is.
Connor.
I need to get to my lab,
I need to get to that anomaly.
Okay, James. Come on. Up you get.
Okay.
That's it. All right, let's go.
One, two, three, take a deep breath.
Just breathe.
Look after Jess.
Hey.
We're all going to die, aren't we?
We're all going to die.
Of course not.
Jess,
have you got a laptop here?
Yeah. Yeah.
Good.
Don't worry, I've got an idea.
It's going to be okay.
Listen, we have beaten
these creatures before,
we'll beat them again. Okay?
Will it hold?
Yeah, yeah, he'll be safe for now.
Okay. You sweep through this way
and we'll meet you at Connor's lab.
Okay.
Your secret weapon is sound?
Not exactly. But disruptive sound
should seriously mess them up.
They work on sonar,
it means they pick up infrasound,
low-pitched noises
way beyond our hearing.
I'm going to overload
their nasty little brains.
Will it be enough to kill them?
No, but it should slow them down
enough for us to shoot them.
Just access this file...
Why did it go?
Wait here.
Out! I'm out!
That's the first one
I've managed to hit.
Thank you.
Becker!
Nice plan, Abby.
All right, it's safe.
Okay, Matt, when I...
When I tell you to close it,
do it in one fluid movement, all right?
Good luck.
Cheers.
Close it.
That's good.
We're locked.
Okay. Ready?
One, two, three.
Easy. Easy.
If we damage the sun cage in any way,
we might lose the anomaly.
Okay, got it.
Yeah?
Look, no offence, but do you
really think this is going to work?
Well,
we've got three options.
One, we merge this
with Philip's anomaly,
it makes the big one unstable,
it closes and the plan's worked.
Two, nothing happens
and it doesn't change a thing, right?
Right.
So far, I prefer option one.
What's option three?
It makes the big one even more powerful
and it accelerates the whole apocalyptic
end-of-the-world type thing.
Basically, not good.
Right, let's find out.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Okay.
We're good.
I'm going to go and rig the car.
Okay.
You're going to drive it yourself?
It's the only chance we have.
You know what I have to do.
It's all about this.
If you fail,
you die.
If you succeed,
if you change the future,
you might never even have existed.
You could just...
- disappear.
- Hey.
It's okay.
- Ready?
- Ready.
You just need to secure
the steering wheel with the seatbelt.
Okay, I've got that.
- What are you doing?
- Matt!
- Stop it!
- No!
- No! No!
- Matt!
Matt.
Matt?
Hey, hey, hey!
- How did you survive?
- I have no idea.
It's so good to see you.
Do you think we did it?
Do you think we changed the future?
Yeah.
I think so.
Matt, what about my truck?
No.
Oh, well, I guess we'll just
walk back to the ARC.
Yeah.
- How's Lester?
- He's going to be okay.
He's already threatening
to sack the medics.
Hey.
- Abby, could I just have a word?
- Yeah.
Um...
I wanted to,
you know, the...
whispered thing?
Whisper?
Well, yeah.
You said that when we were back
and, you know, all this was...
all this was over then,
well, you said you were going to...
You know, you...
You said you...
Great, you don't remember.
Connor...
- Yep?
- Temple...
Will you marry me?
- I'll have to think about it.
- Forget it.
Yes.
So yes.
Oh, please, for goodness sake,
stop fussing.
I'm perfectly capable of
walking by myself.
Here we are.
How are you feeling, Lester?
What an idiotic question,
how do you think I'm feeling?
It's so good to see you.
- I take it this means we've won, then?
- Here we go.
You did it.
I guess this means
we're stuck with you now.
I guess it does.
I think we should keep
the whole "man from the future" thing
just between ourselves, don't you?
The Minister's confused enough as it is.
Well, this is turning into
a surprisingly good day,
with us, you know,
saving the world and...
Well, I suppose that's the end
of the anomalies.
It is possible
Philip's machine might have
closed the anomalies forever.
It'll be really weird
being normal again.
Ah. Only two people
have got that number,
one's the Minister
and the other's my wife.
Either way,
I think I'm in for an earful.
James Lester.
Understood.
So much for being normal, Connor.
A train just left Kings Cross,
disappeared into thin air.
Sorry, does that sound
familiar to anyone?
Anomalies? Chop-chop!
Yep.
Everyone grab a black box,
I'll get the system up and running.
Right. Let's go.
Well, Parker, don't just stand there,
get back to work.
Emily, comms are still down.
I'm going to get my phone.
Hello?
Go back.
You have to go back.
Matt?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm fine.
We're ready to go.