With this crime
was show the...
Once again it was clear
today is prosecutiom
Regendary responsible
for over 200 runner.
Just away againts one day behind blood
for the witness as the judge from...
the case was gun down
just the few hours over!
Punisher WarZone
What is make up for you?
Alright.
You know so the captain shouldn't
show me out the 34 menthol race plenty
get out joke party.
Is there just like
start care with you.
Oh make about the night.
So matter fact does
pretty show is show up.
And the what did
you know with those.
I wanna bring you in?
You know, you kill me so, let's
just say you can let this happen!
Why would you?
He does those bastard that where
you can only find the side about
He didn't know the screen.
- Sure things pop.
Hey, get out just
take it easy, ok?
Thank you.
What can i do?
Can you guys on attack?
Well, Billy.
You would like to
win this situation.
You was think it.
Go swear, uncle Jimmy
You regret?
Here I do, that she
did by oh chist sake ink
Major took to the Ken right?
You can do this
suprised that mind.
Don't look the dark.
- Right that, crystal do it.
Now here you just
sacrefied the wood.
You don't bring any shipment.
Nee dto say important.
Other way my customer great
sigment to be on that night
William boys could
roll that cast ten mile
Is won;t break a straight.
Feel the crystal ship.
- I don't know
Somekind of biological package!
- Biological package!
I fucking hear you!
Put them go up
to raket and queen
Is too guarantee this city.
We go to touch
that kind that shit!
In case your memory is go
along with Western body function
I was top memory about he is!
I'm not stupid.
Well is cheers out
cretive your brother.
I should run that
book to you look away!
One more word about my
brother I wanna christ up..
You know what, he
make pretty fuck!
Hey, let's just see
calm down here, ok!
Now put on the bitcher
that out of here!
So come on everybody!
Pick up with!
That fucking idiot is
shit bag, you understand?
Please, pull me a trick!
Right that, right that!
Hey, what is so fuck?
Alright, then switch up
we should wait for back up
Listen, Frank Castle
is getting away.
So we move over!
Can I heat down the dog first.
Shit! That hurt!
What happen with you?
The punisher, he did saw me and
gun point then shot them right
And where the
hell are you huh?
I know where he come,
where is your statement?
Come on, Cesare, tell
me, tell me that...
How to go down? Huh?
Are you share the same.
Over, maybe spome
blashing on the sky!
The kind for take over the
great way, that's a punisher!
That will make my
fucking hand dirty!
There's your problem!
What the fuck he doing here?
- Relax!
Ask him to calm!
Why not! Hurry, John!
What the fuck he fellow.
Here, look at in Call it.
Now very very...
Get to the Raymond no
mountain to way in the river!
Too deep!
Alright, alright... enough!
Here you get me some money!
Time to go apart!
What did we need bos?
Please pick up the educate,
when the fuck inside
To hear the monet
that pussy cat land
I can tols him remember?
Tomorrow, you gotta bus
Yeah, 20 way the hundred to
grandy and counter, as for the port
be the monkey thing that security
things hand out the money!
Hey, what up you going?
We will be alright! for the
move we still have a job!
Whatever!
You fucking see!
Fuck!
What the fuck with that?
Agent down, agent down! Fuck!
What you gonna push?!
Pop!
- No, to care with
Take that guys!
Nicki
Fuck!
Come on, Franks!
Fuck you, Frank! Fuck you...
Help me! Help me!
FBl, don't move!
Shit! Shit!
You not understand!
Don't move!
Get down!
We go to line that!
Billing the build.
Nothing more, huh?
The more is can
passing the know.
Show too anger
in rich and mercy.
He does not truth the cause into
scene no repay according to our false
That parent had
compassion on his children
The Lord had pity
of those here.
We all here be is walk in here
he remember that here in dust
And for us it be as a glads
With flower with
the flower to funeral
When it blow it were going, you
will place never see us agian
I'm so sorry for your lost.
- Thank you.
The problem that
I try to tell you
Calm down for the out
skill wasn't anybody false.
No of us can fight case the
punch decease of whole straight.
Come on!
Look! How did you
send the message?
Is there something
big is gonna happen.
He just the homeland security,
with the 24 hours surveillance on..
And that just to find
what the fuck is happening?
Gonna tell you got
shot believe me!
No one will piss
off about that I am!
How which we not alone
over Frank Castle?
Because we having real national security
Frank and realize that don't check
That top try that
unto crazy landy.
Go!
Hey!
I better get this guy in.
I promised you.
Where have been
the baby sitter?
These are.
- What use some freak?
Still wanna work with this
We have sitting right doing
things specially you go with this?
Right go the mess
murder was one believe!
4 years, the punisher
is making happen.
And you have watch
out the break!
Only the deep and
shit out of here!
You punisher here appear to
the city under somekind of task
You all can see that the man
that you know what I means.
That what I need you find out what
you need Cally to came across...
Maybe you fear allow to know the cop
in your under cover once you were are
All is couldn't
been voice that.
Withg all due
respect, Captain!
Is bullshit!
Why you let your
man lying there? huh?
And pull of in the blood?
You crispy queen mother fucker will
be pint down every door in the city
Captain! Captain!
You know what?
You almost tell force
could use the extra man.
No!
On basement!
Ah, Agent Death, Paul
Budinsky, make it that right?
Captian Ross told
me you coming in
Now go the punisher
the test for it.
I'm Detective Martin
Soap, pleasure.
And you the servent arms?
- We have agree the phycologise
Suprised, that
ok, people right.
So, where you actually do it?
Here!
This is ground zero!
I show that every step
the last five years!
I done many thing every
murder they finish profile
My collecting and intelligent
all know the sociated.
Take the look at this.
Six years ago,.
Frank Castle was a
special forces inspector
And to see the family man, would
be take his wife and kids and pinic
And by chance is all fit and
you will not to believe it
That is March exercution!
When they just dicover.
The Castle just right.
Since then, he's been taking down
one crime family after another.
Oh, is really
closed, Budiansky
What is get in my
way should by luck.
I afraid that
about the danger.
Like the way is so in regular.
Being so in the case file.
Get the lay of land I get the supply
from Melano is peace of the city
With drawer?
- What?
The land punisher murder.
All of them.
What did you want, Michael?
You heard that
Johadibrother. com?
The push is a warm had to be warrior
take the crap in the case to be lover
If you can screw
couple of luck for..
What did you want?
I'm the senior one
Get you some trips. is
gun shot evening virginia
No back group check no profile
That too much Frank.
Call me the retire package.
Now with the pathetic robe inside that
doesn't means you pack up here tend
We all make the mistake Frank!
Is find the new one.
Does this things ask for slip things
the ring you get the way with this
With any work this clous old
damage that you know that?
Get old damage?
They kill the agent in
field. He was a good guy.
And his family.
I fuck up Mike!
No please! Just
leave me alone!
What the folk Ricky?
He ah.. he didn't make it.
- Ricky was the fucking right
For the friend.
Where is my money?
Where you wentto this
place until is apart?
I sun in the city
the positive in often!
Was he got the next to him?
So what you gonna carry
on the family name?
People say something
wrong way for a little gilr
Good. Let's move there.
Hey, Rock! Where
have you been?
My pleasure to see you!
At that is, to see the
fucking rossa the clean
Must to brought that
fucking ray in the internet!
How gonna I do in
the free clinic?
You sure that I
miss the pay me.
Can you fucking believe that?
Yeah, before we do this,
I hope you understand.
This will be ranger
when you go out here.
You shouldn't be find this.
Where I am here, Doc?
I have the best plastic
surgeon in New York.
Tissue mussle, tenton, bone
struction everything will destroy...
Is just wasn't just
see the where the skin.
Leave in tack.
Just taking off already.
Ok, let do this!
Now I need you sit for it.
Alright.
Ok!
I need you place
this out of replace.
And just bring
back this all...
I need to talk to
my daughter alone
Ok, of course.
What the matter with you.
Get fuck to control yourselve.
You know how sensitive
about his lost son...
Sorry Pop, if you have seen that is
been so... -Just shut up! Fuck off!
What have you post?
Much better things.
I'll be in the court.
No more distractions.
We need to focus on my goals.
One.
We need to get my money back.
Two. We gonna get
rid of Frank Castle.
Well...
He took out like
30 of us. I mean-
How are we gonna kill
him before he kill us?
My brother will
take care of that.
Loony Bin Jim?
- Shut the fuck up.
His name is James.
Not Loony Bin Jim.
Not LBJ, James.
- I'm sorry.
It was a good
idea I mean. It is.
Don't mind him.
He doesn't think
before he talks.
Just like his mother.
Sorry about that Billy.
Billy is dead.
From now on, you
call me Jigsaw.
How are we doing
today, Loony Bin Jim?
Yummy yummy.
So good.
What?
Got an ambassador. Open op.
Yes, doctor.
Billy?
Is that you?
It is.
You look fantastic, brother.
Ink, cut these off. Now.
Put all the force
in the real assault.
We need everybody
out at the front door.
Sure thing, Billy... Jigsaw.
I'll take care of this guy.
Oh no brother. Fatso is mine.
Of course.
I'm gonna get my
apple sauce back.
Did you know...
Kidneys in apple sauce
are a delicacy in Sweden?
Did you know that? Yes.
Yummy yummy yummy,
my tummy tummy tummy.
We've seen worse.
Still mind it for him?
What for?
These corpses do
not feel so good.
He's doing just great.
You're in my light.
When the next time
someone kiss on your lips.
Stay the fuck away
from my little girl.
Mom! That's attached on.
- Go inside, Grace.
You're messing with the wrong
family on the wrong day, asshole.
You... You are...
What are you doing here?
What makes you think
you can come here?
You scared the girl.
- Shut up.
Just shut your mouth.
I'm sorry.
- I said shut up.
What's this?
Something to help out.
- No.
No, you don't get to do that.
You don't get to shoot my
husband in cold blood...
and did stuff with the ATM.
It's for your daughter.
This is what you deserve.
What you did to me.
Who punishes you?
He taught you how to shoot.
Good edge to keep
his family safe.
He could always be here.
Took the act to the range.
Showed you what to do.
This... is what you do.
Squeeze.
Now pull.
I can't find my red pen.
Mom? I need it.
Take it.
The Sebous.
Nice brother.
Is it yours?
I checked.
Old Chessarate used
to rent it to hookers
Let's go inside before I
free my fucking Perosaline.
What's the matter?
Just when I think I'm Ok
and see my reflection...
I look horrible.
What has he done to me?
Oh no... don't cry, brother.
Everything is
gonna be alright.
I promise you two things.
One, I will find Castle
and I will kill him.
Slowly and painfully.
And two, you will never ever have
to look at your reflection again,
as long as you're with me.
Such a delineate.
9 trillion of renew
anymore crystal.
We don't talk them play.
It's the Russian, Mr. Volage.
My men is concerned.
If Punisher can do
this to your face,
what might he do to our deal?
The tongue stretches further
than most people think.
Ask your men how he's
gonna talk that shit,
when I pull it from his mouth.
Or you'll what?
Enough!
The Punisher's my problem.
Rock's mine.
My look have nothing
to do with this.
Everybody.
From local security to
international custom's in my pocket.
Quite frankly. This job
doesn't get done without me.
What's most for the blame?
It's too precise. And
she wants you have it.
Sure thing now.
Shit!
I'll go inside.
My most sincere apologies.
My father always say
never insult your host.
Sounds like a reasonable man.
You don't know my father.
Three days.
There have to be 12 million.
Maybe when you get it
all done, we'll both know,
that this biological shit you're
bringing in is ruining the city.
You're selling it to
the rednecks and queens.
The porchers are crawling
in suits from homeland.
And it take a lot of
pills to keep it quiet.
I always knew you'd
be a good boss, Billy
Latin kings.
Let him go, Frank.
You know this piece of shit?
Next piece of shit.
- Yeah.
The regular hard boy.
Fuck you, cracker.
- Language.
It's a genius racket.
You know how the cops
always run the guns by back?
Except they never work.
Because work banner is
gonna trust the cops, right?
Well, these drive by whack
jobs, they just love Carlos here.
That with one look at that Ink,
and they know he's for real.
We can get the guns
of the streets to you
Everyone seen a banger look
to quit. Too fucking stupid.
He's straight, Frank.
Hey ma! Frank's
here. He says eat up.
How is she doing?
Yeah well...
As long as she got her
cooking shows, she's good.
It's the only
thing she notices.
But hey that's
something, right?
Listen. I-
I just came around to tell you
I'm going out of town for a while.
Out of town?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I never thought of the Punisher,
you know taking a long weekend.
I'm not planning
on coming back.
So I take the things didn't go
so well at the Donatelli home.
Did the Billy
Russoli survived?
I heard.
But the cops did caught him.
You might know they
got nothing on him.
Their hands are tied.
This is when the
Punisher comes in.
This is why I believe in you. Why
I supported you all these years.
You want me to tell you about
somethings happened to...
Mrs. Donatelli
and her daughter?
Because that's
what's gonna happen.
You don't think he's
gonna go for revenge?
It's not important it's
just a matter of when.
Pull a couple of brisk.
- For what?
3, 2, 1
Russoli is the last one.
Then I'm done.
For your own lips to Ganzier.
You know where I can find him.
I don't have a fix on him.
You worked out all the
associates that amount to me.
So much to the new guy.
The leader was black.
Dreadlocks.
There's some kind of
acrobatic stuff over the roof.
That's the DNA
servant free for gain.
He's a mean motherfucker.
He's on a constant method.
Welcome home.
You want to find
the sky or not?
You boys playing with us?
I've been looking for you.
Sure yes. Take your load off.
I need to go see Castle.
Where do I find him?
- Brats, you know.
He just left.
Wait...
You know what I like to do.
I like to sit in my car and listen
to CB Radio and follow the crime.
I don't mind just indoor.
But there's no work
for me in front of this.
But I'm not the luckiest
guy in the planet, you know.
Let's get to the back door.
I didn't knew these boys are gonna
hit the store of 15th in 40 seconds.
Suspects are armed
and dangerous.
I repeat. Suspects are
armed and dangerous.
Let's do this.
Really?
Let's try the car.
Come on! Run!
Don't kill me.
Russoli, where is he?
Yeah Jigsaw, I
was just with him.
He was suppose to give
us some dope for a joke.
But time's up.
He don't come here anymore.
He forgot he have Porch do
that or he'd be like bastard.
So you wanna go see him,
you need to tell him this,
we hate you bitch.
Take your part.
Soul for soul,
Mr. Punisher, sir.
So when did Donatelli
ordered a hunt?
We were partners in that cart.
Unfortunately,
most of them had
been confiscated.
Ended up in my mouth.
Until the traders tried
to wrap me and Nicky out.
He wouldn't.
They sent him undercover.
He's dead because of me.
So you still skin your lobes?
No. That's in the past.
Shit!
I'm on the grab. Meet
me on the other side.
Move.
Hello, Mrs. Donatelli.
We will live in your
place from now on.
What do you want from us?
Looking for my money.
About the rat your
husband stole from me.
But we don't have
it. I swear to God.
How about you, sweet cheeks?
Would you also dare to swear
on your imaginery friend?
Make sure they don't move.
I'll look for the money.
- Come here kid.
Freeze, asshole.
You're under arrest.
Stay out of my way.
Listen to me.
Russoli is headed to
the Donatelli house.
He's probably already there.
You'll have to let me go.
You have the right
to shut the fuck up.
Good evening, officers.
Is everything Ok in there?
No. Everything is
not Ok. Follow me.
Officer.
No... don't!
Well...
This day was about to come
sooner or later, wasn't it?
Did you hear from
the patrol car?
So...
I tried it a couple times.
There was no answer.
Listen.
We gotta get out of here
before more pigs arrive.
Where the fuck is the money?
My husband has a safe
upstairs in the bedroom.
I don't know if it's there but
I can give you the combination.
10-12-1965
Oh how cute.
Is that your dead
husband's birthday?
Let me out of here.
Get him to the station.
- You bet.
Let me out.
You know, Frank.
You're throwing your tip
to no one against one thing.
Password to the crime base is
sure but letting you go, so-
Fine.
How you doing?
19.
What was that?
Go check it out.
What the fuck you
waiting for? Christmas?
Now.
Hey!
- You sit down.
I'm calling this out.
Put your hands behind you.
You asshole!
Where do you
think you're going?
Hands up!
I repeat, dispatch.
We need back up.
Billy! Go get him.
Get him the fucking out.
Stay where you fucking are.
We did it.
You mind explain it to me?
How I have the criminal escaped
from the back of your lock?
The case was a slippery one.
You'll be safe here.
We can manage on our own.
Just until you know
Russoli's been arrested.
Grace.
Grace, you listen, honey.
She's smart.
Go ahead. Open it.
It... belongs to my daughter.
Here.
Wow!
Was... This was
her favorite toy.
She got so angry when her
brother used to hide it from her.
Does she care to
fight with him?
No.
You gonna file for
killing two of my officers.
I wanna warn you.
- Go get your fucking line up.
No lie is gonna get
you out of this one.
Like a piece of shit.
Agent Miller. What
are you doing here?
Russoli.
What's he gotta
do with the bureau?
Pierre's gonna tell you
what he's working on.
He says he got some
intel to make a deal for.
Anyone know where
he is right now?
He's on his way
to the reservation.
Good.
Yeah.
Cameraz. Agent Miller
with the bureau.
I believe you've been informed
we're taking over this.
This perk killed
all my officers.
And terrorize a woman and
child with your agents.
You keep that in mind, Miller.
You're lucky I came
to you with this.
But then I look
patriot just like you.
I shit in red white and blue.
The reason you came to me
is because you got caught.
Say that to someone without
the intelligence, Ok?
You tell me what you know.
If it's any good,
I'll recommend
life without parole.
This deal is
going down tonight?
I know when and I know where.
So you're gonna give me and my
brother the immunity and the money.
Or you're gonna have to explain
the war to fucking Witzer.
Why you had a lead on the thing
that killed half of the fucking city,
and you didn't do a
goddamn thing about it.
I'll be right back.
Oh and Miller.
Just that one
other little thing.
Happy?
Shit! You bastard.
You're a fucking dead man.
My father will kill you.
My father said you'll hear
the fucking silver plate!
Agent Miller.
It's agreed.
The other conditions
of our agreement?
Clear the air.
I hope when the guy finds you,
you'll get what you deserve.
How long was I-
A long time.
You should eat.
Yuck!
- Grace.
What is it?
Egg and cheese and Oris.
That's all I have.
What's the name Oris?
Meal. Ready to eat.
Military food.
It's great for
people who can't cook.
Look, Grace. This is
gonna come with chuckles.
It's the best one I get.
Not exactly a
balanced breakfast.
Out of practise.
Not one more step.
Where's my girl?
His mother is in
the feeding room.
He didn't want to leave her.
Damn it.
I need to talk to her.
This is Carlos.
He's... a friend of mine.
He's gonna help me take
care of some things.
Hi Carlos. I'm Grace.
Hey little darling.
We're gonna be homies, right?
Yeah. we're gonna be tidy.
This all will be over soon.
Then you can go.
Don't go.
I need you on alert.
Don't make me regret this.
That was fun.
Now let's go kill Castle
and his miserable whore.
No, not yet.
We're gonna have ourself
a little fun with this.
Next time you guys defend
source in the fucking army.
Where do we get the army from?
Just like golden Sam, bro.
We recruit in
trouble blade boys.
Offer a hundred grand towards a
college education you'll never get.
Promise nobody's gonna
be asked to go to Iraq.
Just as long as I
get to kill Castle.
Don't worry brother. You will.
Just making damn sure this time
he don't come back breathing.
Hold it.
Hello swordsman.
How are you today my friend?
Run! Get out of here!
Hey! I asked you a question.
Wrong answer.
Guess I'll have
to ask it again.
Here I come.
Good.
Bring him upstairs.
Bring him back down here.
I'll see if we can talk these
bastards into signing up.
Where are they?
I shout. I swear I shout.
Goddamnit! Don't die on me.
What do we do now?
I see him shooting for her.
Shut up kid. You're
gonna be fine.
The hurt is real bad.
Hurt is real bad, Frank.
Don't let me die on this, man.
Not like this.
See you in hell.
I see you anywhere near
hell, I'll kick your ass up.
I haven't seen
you in ages, Frank.
Whatever it is, it
must be pretty bad.
Maybe I'm just here
to see an old friend.
Yeah right. I haven't
seen you since-
A few month ago. I know.
I've been reading about you.
You've been a long way from
the seminary, my friend.
I don't really remember
that part as in my life.
Why do you do this?
Somebody has to
punish the corrupt.
For the same way you judge
others, you will be judge.
And with the measure you use
here will be measured to you.
Matthew. 72.
I'm Ok with that.
God be with you, friend.
Sometimes I'd like to
get my hands on God.
Interested trust
for me to place.
Didn't take you for a
religious man, Castle.
Yeah well. An eye for an eye.
If I remember then I'll call
to attend your suggestions.
Besides he's got
Angela and Grace.
Doesn't matter.
Or maybe if you put her in
protective custody like you should,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
A locking touch, Castle.
Told you in community.
Unless you gotta take
Russoli as you take him.
Can't even give him
a parking ticket.
It's a fucked up
system you're sworn to.
I never said it was perfect.
It was being
exchanged for that.
I need to secure the trade.
Ok.
I'm on this private poke.
Where do you think
they're going by huh?
I took them host, Castle.
We're lost.
- No official police procedure.
You wanna come along?
Leave your badge at home.
I have to think about it.
Throughout this ticket.
Gentlemen. Gentlemen.
Relax.
We're looking for
a few good man.
And we'd like to offer
you the opportunity...
to be all that you can be.
Now we've all suffered, lost,
at the hands of the Punisher.
And because we don't
look like everybody else;
and because we don't
act like everybody else;
nobody does a goddamn
thing about it.
Well I say, he ain't the only one who
can take the war into his own hands.
So if you're as sick of
this cocksucker as I am,
raise your armies.
You'll be well paid.
You'll be well armed.
And at the end of it,
the Punisher will be dead.
Hey it's the booty ansky.
Just in time for happy hour.
You need to come with me.
Where to?
Your partner, Frank Castle.
He needs help.
Partner is a little
bit exaggeration there.
How did you know?
Usually I'm the
arresting indeed.
And no one could
escape that easily.
You know you're not
as stupid as you-
Who are we looking for?
Mr. Farm.
I don't this is a good idea.
What?
We're looking for
Tiberia. Cristu father.
Who are you?
If I were to burial,
I'd probably wanna find the man who was
responsible for sending my son to prison,
and I might took his life.
And how would you do that?
I tell you when and
where to find him.
What do you want from me?
I don't like him. I
want him taken care of.
No worries my friend.
Oh boy!
You get it!
- Fuck, you get it!
I get it.
Who are you looking for?
I'm here to see the Jigsaw.
- You have the luck.
I'm here, for the punisher.
This room man, this
cost your father.
Old country just side maniac.
Figure it stuggle on force.
Cops the only way to
push the fire work start.
We won't worry about that, I
call the name that explosive.
Instruction, everything
need try my ball...
So, what's the plan?
I going to get them.
You already in plan.
So I make.
I'm going with you.
Never took the time to
think where I head it.
I fine that grory!
We not go like that.
Oh Jesus! Thanks Frank!
You don't need to take out
of me where you wait hope?
Here come fire! For
long in the five minute!
The girl is not here!
Set in wood!
Hit target!
James, be careful.
Oh for fuck sake!
Make that place
that son it caught.
Who are in the cruel?
Early in the cave...!
You should be seen in
both right in pal...
That would be a tough...
James!
Go!
Welcome! Welcome! Welcome!
Please help us!
- Shut the fuck up!
Frank Castle, don't be shame.
Put down your gun!
Died you bastard.
- No, James
that's not where
punisher punishment.
Nice shooter!
Catch, put that your
place! What did you said?
You go wrong one
right and dead.
You shot one of this
two I let you all go..
What did you said, Frank?
Who that you be, the
fat friend right here?
Or nice gress over there?
Burn the hell!
- Ok
Frank!
She and the kids
should make it.
Ok, fuck, kill her first!
- No!
Stop!
Is ready to decision!
Now we can two go
for you, fat Soap
We have the switch, Castle!
Two
Don't fear things, my dear.
God!
Frank!
Get out!
Fuck you!
Let me put you
out of my business!
This is just the begining!
You're ok?
Where is Castle?
- Still inside
And Michael?
Are you ok?
We better get out of here!
Yeah, Frank, I
buy you a drink!
Wait! Wait!
My husband Ricky,
we talk about you.
Agree about you.
He said you are
one of the good guy.
No body make this
time equiment huh?
I means he must get
tired this right?
Now thinking about
the creepy this town.
Mr. Audio left find
this consider politician
And we can't track
the people can't change
Just wanna saying is I'm
just person family that else
Frank?
Where are he go?
Oh hey, give me a fucking
wallet motherfucker!
Carring right? Do I
look like fucking caring?
Give me your wallet!
Frank?
You wanna died?
Last time, give
me your wallet!
THE END
Subtitles by: