[BUZZING NEARBY]
What have you got there, Matthew?
I got speed, Joseph. I got speed.
Speed, huh?
Afraid we don't have much use
for more speed these days.
Things are moving fast enough down there
as it is.
Well, but the...
- Get it.
- Damn. Oh, I shouldn't have said...
I got it. Oh, fast little bugger.
I didn't mean to say "bugger" either.
- Well, put it on the shelf.
- Could we just toss it down and see if...?
- Speed is gonna have to wait.
- Could I just put it right there?
VOICE:
Wow.
JOSEPH:
What have you got there, Pedro?
Uh, it's a voice.
[LOUD MUSICAL SHOUT]
That's a big voice.
- Oh, yeah.
- Very big voice.
And soft and sweet as any aria...
...but strong and powerful
as anything before.
Can we send that one down?
Send it right down.
- Easy, easy. Matthew.
- I'm sorry. He's listening.
That voice is an incredible gift.
And with a great gift
comes great responsibilities.
- Yeah.
What?
There are rules that must be followed.
Oh, the rules, the rules.
- Yeah.
- Rules, rules. Um, um...
Never lie.
Always be fair.
Never break a promise.
Yeah.
Those are tough.
Well, wanna drop one?
Ugh, to those who much is given,
much is expected from them.
Him.
Well, it's time.
Let her rip.
[EXCLAIMING]
[CRYING]
[ELLA SINGING]
[SINGING]
Dream big, reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith
A whole lot of luck
And some love to see you through
Dream big and it just might come true
CHOIR [SINGING]:
Dream big, reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And some love to see you through
Dream big and it just might come true
Dream big, reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just fly, fly, fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big and it just might come true
Dream big
Reach high
Dream big, reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big and it just might come
True
Hallelujah. Yeah.
- Something wrong?
- No.
Billy Connelly is a big fat idiot.
Bobbie, be fair, never lie...
...never break a promise.
- Never break a promise.
But he said I was too poor
to have a mommy...
...that my daddy didn't want me.
Oh.
Honey...
...I told you, your mommy's in heaven.
But what about my daddy? Where is he?
Well...
...you're old enough to know now,
so I'll tell you the whole story.
Your daddy was a rodeo cowboy.
He rode into town on a big, white horse.
He had a smile that could make
the sun come out...
...and eyes that could calm a wild mare.
He met your mother
and there were fireworks.
They had a beautiful,
wonderful love affair.
And then the rodeo moved on.
So he climbed back up
on his big, white horse...
...and he rode out of town.
And that's it.
Your daddy was a rodeo cowboy.
Wow. A rodeo cowboy.
[SINGING]
You left me for her
She left you for him
Now you're back again, begging
Saying it was a moment of weakness
Couldn't help falling
But now your love for me is rock solid
If your love was a rock
I'd throw it through the window
Skip it 'cross the water
Watch it sink to the bottom
I'd crush it with a hammer
Then glue it back together
Just to roll it down the mountain
Hope it never stops
If your love was a rock
You know it's true
That's what I'd do
[CROWD CHEERING]
Thank you all very much.
Now get ready for some hard riding...
...as we welcome you to
the 25th annual Cloverton Rodeo.
[GASPS]
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]: Give a big round
of applause to Bobbie Thomas and her band.
You all right?
- Yeah.
- Heh.
Thanks.
I really enjoyed your singing.
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]:
Ladies and gentlemen...
... welcome to the annual
Cloverton Rodeo and Stampede.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Thanks.
WESTON:
Bobbie, I am so very sorry.
I'm not sure what happened.
Listen, I'm just glad you ain't hurt. Heh.
You ain't hurt, are you?
Bobbie?
Hey, you all right?
Honey, did you hit your head?
Do you like my singing, Wes?
Of course. Yeah, yeah, I love it.
I think you sing as good as the people
that sing in the Grand Ole Opry.
Uh, better.
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]: Let's give
a warm welcome to the Cloverton flag girls.
About tonight,
you should wear something special.
Special? For what?
Well, because it's gonna be
a real special night for us.
Oh, my God.
Ella?
- Ella.
- What are you screaming about, child?
[BOTH SHOUT]
At least I stay home when I look like this.
What happened to you?
Ella, I have a problem.
Yes, you do, child. Come here.
- What do you think of Wes?
- That he's a nice boy.
Do you think I should marry him?
- Did he ask you?
- No.
But I think he's going to.
- Tonight.
- Do you love him?
I don't know.
He's the best catch in this little town.
Except for...
- Do you believe in love at first sight?
- I believe in everything.
But how do you know
when you're in love?
- What's it feel like?
- Oh, that's easy.
When you're in love...
...it's like the sun rises and sets
on that person's smile.
They can make you fly higher
than you've ever soared...
...and sink lower than you've ever sunk.
You feel like you don't know
what you're doing half the time...
...but you know exactly what's going on
the other half.
It's the most beautiful feeling
in the world.
It's like taking a bath
in warm tapioca pudding.
Yeah.
Have you ever been in love?
Nope. Never took a bath
in pudding either.
Now go take a shower.
Gee, thanks.
- Hello, Weston.
- Hello, Ella.
Uh, ma'am.
ELLA:
Huh.
- Don't you look fine tonight.
- Oh, well, thanks. Heh, heh.
Do I?
Well, come on inside.
Bobbie's almost ready.
Okay. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Um...
You're welcome.
Well, just have a seat here.
She'll be down in just a bit.
- Can I get you anything to drink?
- Nope. No, thank you.
How about a napkin?
I'm sorry?
Uh, oh, oh. No, thank you.
I'm just a little excited tonight.
Not excited, you know, but anxious.
Anxious.
- I'll get you that napkin.
- Okay.
Poor child.
Okay, I'm ready.
Hey. Heh, heh.
- You all right?
- Uh, yeah. Yeah.
- Wow. You look great.
- Thank you.
Yeah, sure.
- Here's your napkin.
- Napkin? For what?
Uh, nothing, ha. You ready?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Thanks, Ella. Ma'am.
Close your eyes.
Step down.
BOBBIE: Why are your hands all wet?
- Shh, shh. Just a little bit further.
- You sure you can't see?
- I'm sure.
WESTON: Okay, step down.
Just keep going. There you go.
This needs to be perfect.
BOBBIE: Where are we going?
- Shh, shh. Just a couple more steps.
There you go. One more.
Okay, here we go. All right. Now face me.
- Don't peek, okay?
- I'm not peeking.
Okay, you can open your eyes now.
[CHUCKLES]
Isn't she perfect?
- A pickup truck?
- Yeah.
No. Not just a pickup truck.
I mean, it's a automatic, four-wheel drive.
It's perfect.
- That's what this is about?
- Oh, yeah.
- Our special night?
- Yes. Yeah. Yeah, why?
What did you think? Ha.
I mean, look at it, it's gorgeous.
Yeah, she's beautiful. Oh, man.
Yeah, l... Wait, wait. Bobbie?
- Where are you going?
- A pickup truck.
That's what was so important.
He bought himself a pickup truck.
I'm out of here.
WESTON: Bobbie?
BOBBIE: Tell him to go away.
I can't believe this. What an idiot I am.
A pickup truck.
I can't believe I lasted as long as I did in this
dumpy, little, nothing-happening, old town.
- Going somewhere?
- Yes.
I'm going to Nashville, Tennessee...
...and I'm gonna be a huge
country music star.
I been singing my whole life...
...time to see if I'm any good at it.
Because I've had it
with this stupid little town...
...and all these stupid little people in it.
Except for you, of course.
Of course.
How will you live?
I have saved $237.50.
Bus fare is only 87 bucks.
I'll get a job when I get there.
Waiting tables or something.
Done it my whole life.
I'll be fine.
[SIGHS]
I just feel like
I'm meant for something else.
Something bigger.
And it's not here in this little town...
...working at the diner...
...playing rodeo gigs on the back
of some stupid, old hay wagon.
Ella, do you think
people will like my singing?
I do.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you too, baby.
Now, just because you're going to
a big city, don't you forget the rules.
- Never lie.
- Always be fair.
[IN UNISON]
And never break a promise.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
I love you.
Here.
I have something for you.
- It's beautiful.
- Open it.
It belonged to your mother.
What's this?
That is a reminder.
No matter what happens,
however tough life may get out there...
...remember, you can always come home.
Thank you.
[MOUTHS]
Bye.
Here we go.
Hey, hey, hey, that's all right.
Hey. Hey, what's your name?
Hey, come on, talk to me.
Oh, man.
Jesus.
[HUMMING]
[SINGING]
Don't ever be afraid
Spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith
A whole lot of luck
And some love to see you through
Dream big
It just might come...
Good morning.
Oh, God.
No, just one of his many workers.
I'm sorry. I just needed a place to sleep.
I'll leave right now.
- You new in town?
- Uh, yeah. I just got here last night.
I haven't found a place to stay yet
but I'm sure I'll find one today.
It's just different than I thought.
You, um, gonna drag those around
with you all day?
I have to. I don't have anywhere else
to put them.
If you like, I'll keep your bags here.
You can come get them
when you find a place to stay.
That would be a big help. Thank you.
- Here you go.
- Hey, great.
Let's see here.
BOBBIE:
I actually just got to Nashville yesterday.
I started with my Aunt Ella at Jake's Diner
just about the day I started walking.
That's right around the corner
from my house.
When I got out of school,
I started working full-time...
...but I had learned
the whole restaurant business...
...by the time I was 8 years old anyway,
so it wasn't that exciting for me.
But that's not
what I wanted to do with life...
...so I thought I'd come to Nashville
and I try my luck as...
A singer?
- Yeah. How'd you know?
- Just a hunch.
I don't have an address
or a phone number...
...because I just got here, you know?
Yeah, um...
Why don't you give us a call back,
like, when you get a phone.
Should I come back tomorrow?
We'll see what happens.
Oh.
Okay.
Thank you.
Can I get you anything else, hon?
Just some more water, please.
- You new in town?
- Mm-hm.
- You a singer?
- Yeah.
Me too.
Only don't tell the manager. He only wants
professional waitresses working here.
You get a lot of bigwigs in here.
He doesn't want people bothering them
and giving them music...
...and stuff like that. You know.
Uh-huh.
How long you been working here?
A while.
But as soon as I get my record deal,
I'm gone.
[WAITRESS HUMMING]
- Hi!
Hey.
- Can I help you?
- Yes.
I saw the sign outside, "waitress wanted,"
and I'd like to apply.
You're a very beautiful girl.
Wonderful and pretty.
Well, thank you very much.
Does that mean I get the job?
Ha-ha-ha. Good sense of humor.
No.
First, ask questions.
- Name?
- Bobbie Thomas.
Good grip.
My name Morita, owner Sushi House.
- Nice to meet you, Morita.
- Pleasure mine.
- You have experience?
- Yes.
Twelve years at Jake's Diner
in Cloverton, Kentucky...
...where I been working
since I was this high.
- Because it was right around the corner...
- Plenty, plenty. Good, good, good.
Very pretty.
- Look like movie star.
- Thank you.
So...
...are you a singer?
Nope.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
Oh, no. She lied.
What's all this about?
- She lied.
- Yeah, I know. I heard.
That's one.
It's so sad when they lie.
Oh, now don't cry.
You'll cause a flood down there.
He takes it so personally.
Okay, you get job.
But I run business here.
Need people to work at business,
not music.
Must be serious about sushi.
Can you start now?
- Sure.
- Congratulations.
Thank you.
MORITA:
Where all that rain come from?
- Raw fish?
- Hai.
- People eat this?
Sushi very good.
Hey, how long you been singer?
Well, my whole... Uh...
Hey, they're waiting for sushi.
Excuse me.
Raw fish and hot wine.
Everything okay, Mr. Haskins?
Morita, if it were any better,
I wouldn't able to stand it.
[BOTH LAUGH]
- Say, who's the new acquisition?
- Her name Bobbie.
- First night tonight.
- She's a beautiful young lady.
Hai. And very good worker.
BOBBIE: Thank you.
- No problem.
Bobbie, very good job tonight.
- You good worker.
- Thank you.
- Jimi.
- Hai.
Please, make some sushi
for our new worker.
- Hai.
- Oh, no, no.
You don't have to do that.
In Japan...
...you no accept gift, must kill you.
[LAUGHING]
Morita make joke.
You should know what sushi taste like
if you sell.
Hai. Good night.
Good night.
Don't we have a hamburger
or something?
What?
No, it's a sushi house. We make sushi.
Try it. It's cool.
- What happened to your accent?
- Oh, that's our sushi accent.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
It's okay, just use your hands.
Not bad.
- Here's a song.
- A song?
You're a singer, right?
Uh, well...
[HUMMING]
[GUITAR PLAYING COUNTRY RIFF]
- You're a band?
- We, are:
[IN UNISON]
The Rising Sons.
I thought Morita only wanted
professional restaurant people.
No musicians?
Well, that's gonna be a bit tricky...
...considering everyone in Nashville's
a musician.
- You ready?
- Ready for what?
- To sing.
- Sing?
Here we go, fellas.
One, two, three, four.
[SINGING]
The country smells like
Flowers in the spring
The city smells like urine
Oh, but here's the thing
Sometimes I'm hard to understand
That's hard to take
But if you'd simply take my hand
You'd love me anyway
You can love me anyway
Ha-ha-ha.
That's great. You guys are wonderful.
- Wow.
- Miss Bobbie, you sing like an angel.
- Thank you.
- So what do you think of my song?
- You wrote it.
- Yep.
Well, the music is great.
Yes. See, guys. I told you.
But the lyrics could use some work.
That's what I'm talking about.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
It's okay, man.
[SINGING]
The country smells like
Flowers in the spring
[HUMMING]
If I'm...
If I'm just a girl
Would you love me?
Just one against the world
If I can't be like everybody else
So I walk away from a dream
I never even wanted for myself
Would you love me anyway?
If I'm not strong enough
Would you love me?
And if I need you too much
If I run to you when I wanna cry
When I'm gonna break
And you can't understand why
Would you love me anyway?
Baby, I need to hear you say
That you know me, you really know me
And you love me anyway
If I want to fly
Would you love me?
And hold me while I try
Because you love me?
If I wish to live among the stars
Where I can touch God's face
Would you let me go that far
And love me anyway?
Would you love me anyway?
Baby, I need to hear you say
That you love me anyway
Ooh
That's beautiful.
[MORITA CLEARS THROAT]
Hai, very beautiful song.
Jimi, pour some sake for everyone.
- Morita, I can explain...
- Jimi.
Pour sake.
I would like to propose a toast...
...to Bobbie Thomas
and the Rising Sons.
- How'd you know about the Rising Sons?
- It is my job to know everything.
That is why
I will become manager of the band.
You will all become very famous...
...and I will drive a Cadillac.
[LAUGHING]
[SINGING]
Would you love me anyway?
Solo the vocals for me.
[MUSIC STOPS]
That you love me anyway
Put this on tape for me, Lester.
Janie, how you doing, darling?
It's Keith Haskins.
Yeah. Is the grouch around?
Hey, Charlie, how you doing,
old buddy?
Yeah, well, I only called you because you're
close and I won't have to get in my car.
Now, I've got something you need
to do yourself a favor and listen to.
No, no, no, not tomorrow.
Tomorrow it'll be on the radio.
Now, this company is hot right now.
It would be a great place
for you guys to be.
BOBBIE:
Yeah!
Now, I've known the old man
for a long time, so he trusts me.
Now, let me do all the talking
when we're in there, all right?
Man, I hate this alley.
Always smells like urine.
JIMl:
My lyrics, exactly. See, guys. I told you.
PUDGE:
Your lyrics stink worse than the alley.
ISHl: You got it right, dude.
JIMl: Not true.
I write very powerful lyrics.
[MEN LAUGHING]
- Charlie?
- Yeah?
I want you to meet Bobbie Thomas.
Oh, the little girl with the big voice.
Welcome to
the Bobcat Entertainment Company.
Keith, we'll finally see
what kind of manager you are.
Hey, good of you to come.
Gotta run. Thank you.
What just happened in there?
What just happened in there
is I just got you your first record deal.
[ALL LAUGHING]
The train is pulling out and you are on it.
Let's celebrate, you all.
Morita, Sushi House?
Hai. Drinks on the house.
Guys, guys, guys,
I need to talk to Bobbie...
...so, uh, we'll meet you there later.
ISHl: Cool, man.
[BAND CHATTERING]
Let's go, kid. This train is rolling.
When you're ready
for some T-shirts, hats...
...Good Old Boy Merchandise.
That's the place you go.
- We'll call you.
- Keith's a very good guy, by the way.
He'll make you a really good manager.
I thought Mr. Morita was our manager.
Bobbie, Mr. Morita is
a good restaurant manager...
...not a manager of talent.
This is a whole different world.
But he brought us to you,
made the whole thing happen.
He gave me a job
when I really needed it.
It isn't fair.
Now, don't you worry about Morita.
He's being well taken care of.
All right, great. We'll see you then.
MAN: Hey, Keith.
- Hey, buddy, how you doing?
MAN:
Great.
I'd introduce you
but I don't remember his name.
Can't be that important, huh?
- Does that cell call long distance?
- Absolutely.
- You wanna call?
- Could I?
Sure. Dial away.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello?
- Aunt Ella, it's me.
I know it's you, child.
No one else would call me at this hour.
It's good to hear your voice.
It's good to hear you too.
Sometimes I get so homesick,
I can hardly stand it.
You can always come home.
I know, but I'm doing pretty good now.
I got a job serving sushi and I met
some guys at work who have a band.
We wrote a song together
about my daddy...
...then Mr. Morita,
who owns the Sushi House...
...and knows everyone in the business,
introduced us to Mr. Haskins...
...who's, like, a really important manager,
and he introduced us to Mr. Bunch...
...who signed us to a recording contract
at Bobcat Entertainment...
...and we're gonna cut a record.
- What do you think?
- I think you need to take a breath.
Heh, I guess I'm just a little excited.
[PHONE BEEPS]
- Your phone's beeping.
- Oh, it's another call.
- Call waiting.
- I gotta go. He's got another call.
- I love you, Ella.
- I love you too, darling.
- Remember, be fair, and...
- Never break a promise, I know.
- Bye, darling.
- Bye.
Hello?
Ha-ha-ha. How you doing, buddy? All right.
I'm good, I'm good.
What about "never tell a lie"?
What?
Well, yeah. Yeah, I've been waiting.
- Leon, how you doing, buddy?
- Good. How are you?
Bobbie, say hi to Leon.
He's your new lawyer.
- Bobbie, Leon. How are you?
- Hi.
- Good to meet you.
- I never had a lawyer before.
Boy, you got one now.
Why don't you two step into the vocal booth
where you can hear yourselves think?
Hey, Charlie.
- You get her John Henry on the contract?
- Leon's doing it right now.
- How's the band?
- Amateur night in Dixie.
Sorry looking bunch. Get rid of them.
They're not the right image.
She's not gonna like it.
CHARLIE: This little girl is gonna be
the home run hitter...
...if we don't screw it up.
Get her a hot band.
Pam, send Tony down
with 2,000 in 20s. For Keith.
All right, you're the hotshot manager.
You make her happy.
LEON:
I can't wait till you're on the road.
It's a pleasure.
- Glad to represent you.
- Thank you.
- How you're doing, darling?
- Great. I think.
Things seem to be happening so fast.
[SIGHS]
Bobbie, this is your very first lesson
in becoming a star.
Making difficult decisions.
And you gotta make one right now.
There's a problem with the band.
What kind of problem? I'll talk to them.
Unfortunately, that won't help.
Truth is, they're just not very good.
We're gonna have to replace them.
But they can get better.
They'll work. I know these guys.
They'll work.
Darling, I would love to be able
to dunk a basketball...
...but no matter how hard I work,
it ain't ever gonna happen.
But it's not fair.
I wouldn't be here without them.
Kid, I'm sorry.
That's the way it's gotta be.
You are the real talent here.
This isn't charity work.
This is the big time.
I know, but maybe we can...
- Hey, is this a bad time?
- No, not at all. Come on in.
Bobbie, Tony, your accountant.
- Hi.
- Brought you a small advance.
- What's this?
- That is just a tiny advance on the money...
...this company knows you're gonna make.
- Shut the front door.
Sign here.
- Thanks. Nice to meet you, Bobbie.
- Nice to meet you, too.
- It isn't fair.
- This is business.
It isn't about being fair.
Are you in?
Yeah, I'm in.
[THUNDER BOOMS]
- Uh-oh. That's two.
- Yes, that's two.
Just one left.
JOSEPH:
Why are we walking? We can fly.
[BAND PLAYING
"WOULD YOU LOVE ME ANYWAY"]
BOBBIE [SINGING]:
Would you love me anyway?
Baby, I need to hear you say
That you know me
You really know me
And you love me anyway
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
HASKINS:
Why does it need to be a real cowboy?
Because a real cowboy walks, talks,
feels real.
Some model is not gonna be real.
That's ridiculous.
This whole world is an illusion.
Nothing I do is real.
She is.
She's absolutely the real deal.
BOBBIE:
Hey, what about this one?
Let's see.
- He's handsome enough.
- I like him.
- He looks like the real thing.
- Who is he?
Just some cowboy,
rides the rodeo circuit.
A rodeo cowboy.
Perfect.
WOMAN:
Dale, someone's on the phone for you.
- Is it the bank?
- Nope. Some production company.
- Production company?
- Mm-hm.
- What do they want?
- Why don't you talk to them and find out?
- Why don't you not sass me, booper?
- I have to. I'm your sister. It's my job.
- Sure it ain't the bank?
- I'm sure.
- You think it's the bank, Rog?
- Yes.
[LAUGHING]
- Go answer the phone.
- Okay.
I need me a good bull this weekend.
Hello?
Yeah, this is he.
A video?
Yeah. And what would I have to do?
Ride a horse, wear a hat and smile.
Hell, I can do that.
But how much does it pay?
One thousand dollars?
Two thousand dollars?
You gotta be kidding me.
Three thousand dollars?
Shut the front door.
You know who you're talking to?
This is Dale Jordan, the bull rider.
Okay.
Yes, sir.
You got yourself a deal.
You're a hell of a good
negotiator too, sir.
Yes.
See you Monday.
Five thousand dollars.
[SIGHS]
Excuse me, sir.
[HONKS HORN]
I'm Dale Jordan.
Think I'm supposed to be in this deal.
Oh, yeah, the cowboy.
They were just looking for you.
You're in dressing room number two.
Park right next to the dressing room.
Then I think they wanna see you
in the makeup trailer.
Makeup trailer?
Here we go.
What is that stuff you're stirring?
This, my darling, is a special elixir that is
going to have you sparkling like a diamond.
It is my very own personal discovery
of brilliant vitamins and minerals...
...that when applied
to your facial epidermis...
...will make your skin come alive and
dance like angels in front of the camera.
- You're gonna put that on my face?
- No, no, no.
I'm going to paint it, like Picasso.
Now close your eyes.
Come on. Close your eyes.
First, I'm going to take care...
...of this little mustache that's growing
that we're going to...
[CHUCKLING]
Mr. Jordan.
Hi. They're ready for you over in Makeup.
I'm just gonna let this set that
right there.
Wait, wait, wait.
Uh, um...
They sent me here for, uh, like, makeup
or something.
- Oh, oh. The cowboy. Yes, of course.
- Yeah.
All right. Come in, please. Sit down.
- I'll be right with you, all right?
- Okay.
Um, excuse me, one second.
- Hello, are you all right?
- No. I look like an alien pig.
And he saw me.
Oh, come on. Don't be so vain.
You have to come out so I can finish.
I'm not coming out there while he's here.
[CLEARS THROAT]
You know what?
I think we can do you right now.
Hey, I don't want you to put
that white stuff on my face.
Oh, oh. Heaven's no.
With you it's just a matter of a puff there
and a little puff over here.
All right?
I saw that smile.
You can smile, you know.
It's just different for me, okay?
Have a little brush-brush here
and a brush-brush there.
[CHUCKLING]
Okay, here we are, here we are.
Just let me take one look.
You're all done. Okay?
Thank you.
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
- Is he gone?
- Yes, Miss Vain, he's gone.
You can safely emerge
from your place of hiding.
[MAKEUP ARTIST CLEARS THROAT]
What's wrong with my face?
What's wrong with your face?
Nothing's wrong.
You have a beautiful face.
Then why'd you put all this gunk
on my face? You didn't put any on him.
Because, my dear, you are the star.
[SINGING]
We can't trust what we can't see
We're not strong enough to fight
When we feel weak
We can't resist another flame
We're not able to live above the blame
But love is
Love is
It's always been
It always will be
We may not be perfect
But love is
We may not be written
Anywhere close to the stars
But wherever we are
Love is
It's always been
It always will be
Love may not be perfect
Oh, we may not be perfect
But love is
Love is
Ooh
[DIRECTOR CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
BOBBIE:
Thank you for helping me with my video.
DALE:
Well, it was interesting.
I hope all this works out for you.
I really enjoyed your singing.
BOBBIE:
You said that last time.
What?
Do you remember me?
You know, maybe if you put some mud
on your face it might help.
- You do remember.
- Of course I do.
You made quite the first impression.
So did you.
You've sure come a long way
since falling off that wagon.
I have my first real concert this Saturday
at the Municipal Auditorium.
Wow, huh? Jeez. Big time, huh?
I've never played anywhere so big.
I'm a little nervous.
You'll do great.
If you'd like to come,
I could get you tickets.
Uh, I'd love to
but I got this rodeo in Beaumont.
But if the old bull throws me off
in the afternoon...
...and I don't make the finals...
...I might be able to make it
to your concert.
Great.
I'll leave you tickets and backstage passes
at will-call.
All right. Okay.
If I don't make it to your concert...
...good luck with it all.
- Thank you.
- You ain't gonna wish me luck?
- Nope.
I'm rooting for the bull.
Ha, ha.
See you.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
WOMAN:
Thank you. Enjoy the show.
- Any good news, Bubba?
- Not much.
- Spurs won.
- Yes.
Must have been the Lakers.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
WOMAN:
Hi.
BOBBIE: Oh my gosh. Hi.
- Hi.
Just stopped by,
wanted to wish you luck tonight.
Thank you. I'm gonna need it.
No, you won't. Just do what you do.
You'll be fine. You'll be great.
I can't believe you're standing here
in person, talking to me.
I am still standing.
- Anyway, good luck.
- Thank you.
All right, bye.
Come on, Bubba.
BUBBA:
Good luck following that act, boss.
[CROWD CHEERING]
- Knock them dead, kid.
- I'll try.
- Have you seen Dale?
- Who, the cowboy?
No. Is he supposed to be here?
Never count on a bull.
ANNOUNCER: Here she is,
country's newest star, Bobbie Thomas.
[SINGING]
Hey, hey
Black leather boots
Deep-sea green eyes
A miracle in blue jeans
Cut her out to size
What did I do?
How did I find?
How did such a good love thing
Walk into my life?
Oh, that's my man
He loves everything I am
That's my man
Honeysuckle kisses so delicious
Honey, that's my man
I can't get no sleep
But that's all right
The magic in his fingers
Filling up my nights
I get a little bit weak
When he holds me tight
Taking me to heaven
He's my magic carpet ride
Oh, that's my man
He loves everything I am
That's my man
Honeysuckle kisses so delicious
Honey, that's my man
Sweet as honey
That's my man
Oh, oh
[CROWD CHEERING]
HOST:
A little later in the show...
... we'll meet country music sensation,
Bobbie Thomas.
And we'll hear the touching story
behind her number one record...
... and we'll have a couple of surprises
for her as well.
So stay tuned, we'll be right back.
WOMAN [ON TV]:
Kymaro's New Body Shaper...
... is so light that you can
wear it year round.
It can be worn with the clingiest of fabrics
and is great for casual and formal wear.
Call right now and get
Kymaro's New Body Shaper...
... for the incredible low price
of only 39.95.
Yes, for a limited time,
it's yours for only 39.95.
And listen to this. If you call right now...
[GRUNTS]
Looks like one of them
touchy shows, huh?
What are you doing here?
I'm not really sure, to be honest.
I mean, I got this phone call...
...and they said that you'd be here.
And it seems wherever you are,
there's free food.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
- It's nice to see you again.
- It's good to see you too.
Miss Thomas, you're on after
the next commercial. You ready?
I guess so.
Knock them dead, kid.
- Wish me luck.
- No.
- I'm betting on the bull.
- Ha.
Right this way.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
Well, music critics all across the country
are calling my next guest...
...the country girl with the gift.
Please welcome
the new star of country music...
...Bobbie Thomas.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Wow, what a welcome.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
- Thank you, Bobbie, for being on the show.
- Thank you for having me.
Okay. So your first single goes to
number one on the Billboard music charts.
Your first video has just gone
to number one on the country video charts.
You're currently the opening act for
the undisputed king of country music...
...and the critics have dubbed you
the girl with the gift.
How do you feel about
all this sudden success?
Well, I'm very thankful.
Uh, it's fantastic. It's like a dream.
Oh, this is no dream, I can assure you.
So let me ask you about the lyrics
to your first number one hit...
..."Would You Love Me Anyway?"
I understand these lyrics
are very personal to you.
Yes. My mama died
while giving birth to me...
...so I was raised by my Aunt Ella.
And I never really knew
much about my daddy...
...other than the stories that Ella told me.
So the lyrics to this song are really
just the stories that she told me.
- So you've never seen your father at all?
- No.
When you were a little girl wondering
about your daddy late at night...
...did you even have a picture
in your mind...
...what he might look like?
Well, I remember...
I used to close my eyes
as hard as I could...
...and I could picture him
on a big, white horse...
...but I never could really see his face.
Did you ever picture him looking like
that handsome young cowboy...
...you used in your video?
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
I don't know.
We happen to have that handsome
young cowboy with us here with us today.
Dale Jordan, ladies and gentlemen.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Welcome to the show, Dale.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Oh, he's so polite.
So I understand that you, yourself...
...handpicked this handsome
young cowboy...
...to be in your video.
Well, yes.
[CROWD CHUCKLING]
- Dale, did you know that?
- No, ma'am.
- Kind of flattering, huh?
- Yes, ma'am.
The audience is eating this up.
Wait till you see the next surprise.
It's a doozy.
I'd have to say
that we have the greatest research team...
...in all of television on this show...
...because waiting for you backstage
is an incredible surprise.
Brace yourself, because you're about
to meet the rodeo cowboy...
...who is your daddy.
[CROWD GASPS]
Roy, come on out.
Go ahead, Roy.
Give her that long-awaited hug.
[CROWD CHEERING]
I'm Marilyn Montgomery
and we'll be right back.
Brilliant. Did you hear the audience?
They loved it.
- What's wrong with you?
- What are you talking about?
How could you do this to her?
I didn't do this. I had no idea
this was gonna happen.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Hey, look, kid, these shows do these things
all the time.
I had nothing to do with it. Honest.
Hey, he's lying.
He's lying?
You're a jerk.
I can't believe you fell down
and hit your face on a music stand.
You're such a klutz.
That's me, Mr. Klutz.
Excuse me, can I get another one?
So, Daddy, you've just been riding
the rodeo circuit all these years?
Psst. Roy.
- What?
- You've been riding the circuit...
...all these years?
- Oh, no. Not for a while.
- What have you been doing?
- Oh, you know, just living.
This is great. I have my daddy.
And thank you both
for coming to dinner with us.
It's the least I could do.
Hey, can I get another one?
Anybody want dessert?
No, I'm trying to stay in shape.
I gotta hit the head.
Excuse me.
You know, I'm gonna join him, actually.
Thanks, I got one.
You couldn't stay sober for long,
could you?
Long enough to do that show.
You know, you're, uh,
not what she expected.
Hell, I'm not what I expected.
So, what are you gonna do about it?
I don't know.
I didn't bargain for this.
They just offered me a bunch of money.
Hell, I couldn't say no to it.
You're gonna break her heart.
Seems like a nice kid.
I don't wanna hurt her.
Then do the right thing.
Clean yourself up.
Thank you for inviting me to dinner.
Yeah, I really enjoyed it.
So did I.
- Good luck with your father.
- Thank you.
- You sure did look beautiful tonight.
So much is happening to me right now.
It's so fast.
- I sure wish you could see the show again.
- Yeah.
- Another rodeo.
- I know.
Oh, hey.
Now, I got you something
just to keep you company on the road.
[LAUGHING]
- It's not quite as mean as the ones I ride.
- I'm sure.
Thank you.
It kind of reminds me of you.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
- See you.
- Right.
Smile.
Daddy, you all right?
Daddy?
I've been called about everything else,
but not daddy.
You'll get used to it.
No.
- This isn't any good.
- What do you mean?
This daddy, I'm not a daddy.
Don't say that.
Look, I'm not what you've been dreaming
about all these years.
I'm not a rodeo cowboy.
I'm a drunk.
You asked me what I've been doing.
I've been drinking.
I drink till I pass out,
I drink till I throw up on myself.
I'm no good for you.
Sooner or later, you're gonna get hurt.
I don't wanna hurt you.
The best thing I could do is
go on down the road...
...mind my own business.
You're not going down any road.
I've been waiting my whole life.
I'm not gonna let you just go.
Well, you have to.
I'm an alcoholic.
- I'm sick.
- We'll get you in one of those programs.
I've been through those.
They don't work for me.
But I'm here now.
I'll help you. Whatever it takes.
- We'll get through this together.
- Bobbie, I'm a bad drunk.
A time's gonna come you'll wish to hell
you'd never found me.
Never. I'll be there for you,
no matter what.
I'll be there.
I promise.
MAN 1: Mark, let's do another mic check.
MARK: All right. On my way.
MAN 1: Hey, double-check those levels.
MAN 2: Got it.
WOMAN:
Check for the house sound.
MAN 4: Are they gonna use this spot?
MAN 1: Yes.
[CREW CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
Hey, check this out.
Come on, come on, watch me, watch me.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
How are you?
Me and my best friend right here.
GUARD:
Come on, Roy, cool off.
[CATTLE MOOING]
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]:
Get the adrenaline pumping...
... and let's get ready for the bull riding
event of the evening.
MAN:
Hey, Dale. Good luck, man.
ANNOUNCER:
Make some noise for this cowboy...
... because that may be
the only paycheck he gets.
He's a cowboy that needs to make
a paycheck, folks.
He's finished number eight all around
and this year he's making a big comeback...
... after some injuries
he took at Cheyenne last month.
Cowboy Dale Jordan
was last year's winner...
... but he's gonna need to score big
to hold the lead.
MAN:
Get ready. Nice and easy.
ANNOUNCER:
This bull has been unridden this year.
He's setting in the chute,
waiting for the nod.
[BULL MOOING AND SNORTING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
ANNOUNCER:
Oh, no. That doesn't look good folks.
The bullfighters are out there
doing their work.
Oh, God.
- Any good news, Bubba?
- Not much.
- Spurs lost.
- Damn.
ROY:
All right.
- Bobbie, tell these rent-a-cops who I am.
- Miss, he keeps saying this is his show.
- Get the hell out of here. I run this show.
- Stop it. Everyone. Everyone.
- You shut up.
- Daddy, stop.
I'll handle this. Shut up!
- Your daddy?
- Yeah. Come on.
[GRUNTS]
- What are you doing?
- Get off me!
I don't take nothing off nobody,
especially some little snot-nosed kid.
- What is wrong with you?
- You watch your attitude, you little tramp.
You're just like your mother.
All your makeup and a little hussy.
Get out.
- Get out of here.
- Nobody tells me what to do.
- Get out. I never wanna see you again.
- I am not leaving. I like it.
- There's lots of action, free booze.
- No, you are not staying here.
- Party time.
- I hate you.
I wish I'd never found you.
[THUNDER CRASHES AND ALL GASP]
Oh, no. No, no, no.
- That's, um...
- Three.
...three. Yeah.
Hey, what's the problem?
You want some?
[GRUNTING]
Hey, Bubba, get his ass out of here.
Come on, Roy.
You all right?
I think so.
Good, because you got a show to do.
- You get yourself together.
- I know. I'll be ready.
Okay. Then let's do it.
Damn, I think I broke my hand,
that hardheaded SOB.
[SIGHS]
[PHONE RINGING]
[LINE RINGING]
We're ready for you, Miss Thomas.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[WHIMPERING]
- Poor little guy.
- It's empty.
It was a very big voice.
Perhaps too big for her.
We'll have to put it back on the shelf.
What was that?
[CROWD CHEERING]
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss Bobbie Thomas.
[BAND PLAYING COUNTRY SONG]
[CLEARING THROAT]
[MUSIC STOPS]
[CROWD MURMURING]
[BAND PLAYING COUNTRY SONG]
[MUSIC STOPS]
What the...?
[CROWD JEERING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Bobbie, how long have
you been singing?
My whole life. Why?
What's wrong with me?
Well, nothing. Ha.
That's what makes this so unusual.
We've run every test imaginable,
over and over...
...and they all say the same thing.
With your larynx, you should never
have been able to sing at all.
In simple terms, it's defective.
- Congenital?
- Since birth.
HASKINS: What are you saying, doc?
When will she be able to sing again?
She'll probably never be able
to sing again.
That's what the voice clinic said, Charlie.
They ran every test possible.
They don't know how she sung in the
first place. They said it was a miracle.
Well, maybe it was just a matter of time
before this happened.
Well, we can't be held responsible
for that.
The contracts?
Well, of course I have them.
Of course I read them.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
Come on, old buddy,
how long we been working together?
Yeah, well so long to you too.
Well, kid, I'm sorry.
If you can't sing,
you're not worth anything in Nashville.
- What do you mean?
- It's simple.
You signed the contracts. It's over.
- What's over?
- Everything's over.
Your singing career, your record deal...
...your rented houses, your money,
everything.
But I've had a number one hit.
We haven't even released a second single.
There's gotta be some money left.
Who do you think's paying for all this?
The cash advance, the studio time...
...the studio musicians,
the professional band...
...the producer, the music video...
...the transportation...
...Morita's Cadillac...
...the cell phone bills, everything?
This is part of your deal.
Right now, you owe the record company
a lot of money.
And if you're lucky, lucky...
...your album sales will offset
most of the costs and you won't get sued.
Singing's what made you special, kid.
If your voice is gone, so are you.
I been waiting for you, child.
I tried to call you a million times.
Why didn't you answer?
- Are you okay?
- Oh, I'm fine.
Didn't wanna talk on the phone.
You look sick.
You sound sick.
I lost my voice.
I know.
It takes a strong person to carry
a gift that big.
You have to be strong enough
to follow the rules.
I don't know what to do if I can't sing.
You can sing, child. Sing like a bird.
You just have to learn to do it differently.
You don't understand.
I've lost my voice. It's gone.
And the doctors say I'll never get it back.
Then you'll have to learn to sing
with your heart.
How do I do that?
You search your heart.
Search for what?
For a way to make amends.
For the wrongs that were done
and the people that were hurt.
Right now...
...your heart is empty, child. I can feel it.
When your heart once again is filled...
...with love and joy...
...you'll sing again.
It might not sound the same
but you will sing.
Sing like you never thought you could.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO]
Sure is nice to see you, again, Bobbie.
It's nice to see you, too, Wes.
I appreciate you driving me all this way.
Aw, what could be better than
a beautiful girl in my truck...
...driving down the road
on a beautiful afternoon?
It really is a nice truck.
- Sure you don't mind waiting?
- No, no.
Not when I got a CD player
like this baby's got. Ha, ha.
[SIS CHUCKLES]
SIS:
Just gentle, like this.
Hi, I'm Sis. This is Megan.
Hi, I'm Bobbie.
I was looking for Dale.
I know who you are.
Dale's my brother.
But he isn't here right now.
[PHONE RINGING]
Could you stay with Megan
while I go answer the phone?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
How you doing, Megan?
- Do you like horses?
- Yes.
They're soft.
They say the softest spot
in the whole world is a horse's nose.
- Do you wanna feel?
- Mm-hm.
- You like that?
[BOBBIE HUMMING]
Wow. That's amazing.
Most of the kids will relate to horses...
...even if they don't pay any attention
to people.
But we've had trouble with Megan.
She hasn't responded till now.
This is amazing.
Well, this is Dale's thing.
It's very special.
That's why he rides all those damn bulls.
It costs a lot of money
to keep a place like this going.
I'm not sure what we're gonna do with
him all busted up in the hospital like that.
Hospital?
Watch it.
Oh, sorry.
Howdy.
Is he okay?
Old bull smacked him
pretty good this time.
I keep telling him he should stop...
...but he thinks he gotta keep on riding
till that barn's paid off.
That's his whole deal in life, you know,
helping them kids.
To look at him, you wouldn't know
he was one of them.
- What?
- He was autistic like them kids...
...he's helping now.
- He was autistic?
- Yep.
We didn't know
what you called it back then.
We just thought he was slow.
Never spoke a word
till he was 11 years old.
I used to take him down to the barn
and let him sit on the horses.
He seemed to like it.
Hell, the first word he ever spoke
was "horsy," not "mama" or "dada."
Can you beat that?
One day a bee stung this old bay horse
right there on the butt...
...while Dale was sitting on him.
That old horse would have broke you
in two, but now Dale...
...he hung on.
That's the first time he ever smiled.
- How long do they think he'll be like this?
- Like what?
Unconscious.
Hell, he ain't unconscious,
he's just asleep.
Dale, Dale, wake up, son.
You got company.
What?
Hi.
You bet on the bull again, didn't you?
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Thank you.
I think right now we need to thank
a very special young lady.
The young lady
that put this whole thing together.
Bobbie Thomas, come on up here
to the stage and take a bow.
[CROWD CHEERING]
A very important person in my life
once told me...
...when I lost my voice,
that I could sing from my heart.
So if you will excuse the sound of my voice
and just listen to my heart...
...I'd like to sing a very special song
for these very special kids today.
[PIANO PLAYING SOFT MELODY]
[SINGING]
There comes a time in everybody's life
When your destiny is born
And there's no doubt
What you're all about
Is there without a warning
And when it comes
You gotta take it
And believe you're gonna make it through
There's not a challenge you can't face
There's not a rainbow you can't chase
Dream big
Reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith
A whole lot of luck
And some love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
Always know what the future holds
Is in the hands of fate
And don't forget
That when times gets tough
The gift is worth the wait
But when it finally comes together
Your star will shine forever more
And you'll give hope to all the rest
Show them how to be the best
Matthew, Joseph. Come here, quick.
- What's all the ruckus?
- Look.
[VOICE SINGING]
I've never seen this before.
What do you think it means?
It means...
[YELPS]
...the gift should be returned.
She has redeemed herself...
...found a way to sing without her voice.
[LOW RUMBLING FROM ABOVE]
Well, it seems you're right.
Well, go on.
[VOICE SQUEALING]
[SINGING LOUDER]
Dream big
Reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith
A whole lot of luck
And some love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
Come on, come on
ALL: Dream big
- Dream big
ALL: Reach high
- Reach high
ALL: Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
Dream big, reach high
Don't ever be afraid
And you just fly, fly, fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
ALL: Dream big
- Dream big
ALL: Reach high
- Reach high
ALL: Don't ever be afraid
Just spread your wings and fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
ALL: Dream big
- Dream big
ALL: Reach high
- Oh, reach high
ALL: Don't ever be afraid
- Oh, no, oh, no
ALL:
Just fly, fly, fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
ALL: Dream big
BOBBIE: Dream big
Reach high
ALL: Don't ever be afraid
- Oh, no, oh, no
And you just fly, fly, fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might come true
Dream big, reach high
Don't ever be afraid
Just fly, fly, fly
With a heart full of faith, a whole lot of luck
And love to see you through
Dream big
And it just might
Come true
[ALL CHEERING]
Good job.
---the end---