- It's been almost a year,
yet we still know
nothing about them.
Who they are,
where they come from,
why they went down...
all we know is, since they came,
two quiet hours a day
is all we have.
- What was that?
- I'm not sure.
- A gunshot?
- No, it can't be.
- No, I heard an engine.
- It could have been anything.
- What if there were
people out there?
And they found us?
- It's nothing, Ok?
- Would you shoot someone
if you had to?
- Go back to sleep.
- What's she saying?
- Uh... they've left the UK,
and stopped here.
And some
country's name I couldn't understand.
- Shh!
- Turn it off!
- Why?
- Because it creeps me out, Ok?
If you go out the back,
make sure to lock the door behind you, Ok?
Is anybody there?
- Hello, survivors.
Tom Connelly here,
playing just for you.
Dad?
Who are you?
God what is wrong with you? I
told you to shut the door.
- I'm sorry.
- That's the second time. Do
you want to get us killed?
He's been shot.
- Where?
- In the leg.
- Could that be what
we heard last night?
Sarah?
Are you gonna fix his leg?
Well, you shouldn't.
He stole our food.
- Hold the light closer.
- Is he gonna die?
- No.
At least no from me hitting him.
- What is this?
- A survival blanket.
From Manchester.
Twenty-Seven
- What do you see?
- One of their mines.
Looks incredibly deep.
- I heard they're taking minerals
from the core of the planet.
Can you see them?
- No.
- What are we gonna do with him?
- I don't know, I'm thinking.
- We'll have to see what dad
thinks when he gets home?
- Do you think he'll be back tonight?
Sarah?
Oh, for Christ's sake,
how could I possibly know?
- Good girl.
- Coffee?
- There ain't much milk.
- It's been a while since
she had babies.
- Will she stop producing it?
- Eventually.
I'm sorry, Ok?
- It must be Dad.
- Hello?
- You'll catch a fever washing
in that filthy water.
Why did you run away?
I meant you no harm.
I suppose you don't see
many people in these parts.
It's quite isolated, isn't it?
What's your name?
- Sarah.
- You live alone in that big house?
- No.
- Who else is there?
- My brother.
And my father.
- How old are you?
- I'm twenty-five.
- How old are you really?
Eighteen?
Nineteen?
- What do you want?
- He's there, isn't he?
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
- You're lying to me, Sarah.
Did you tie him up?
- Sarah...
- Shh...
- Sarah?
Fine.
- You've got ten minutes to get him out.
Ten minutes.
Or big, bad wolf will
be knocking on your door.
Over.
- How many are there?
- I'm not sure. At least two.
I think there night be
more hiding in the back.
- Let's just take him
out as she said.
He must be with them.
- Then you tell them
it's just the two of us.
And then we'll be screwed.
We might as well kiss our animals goodbye.
- He wouldn't know. He's
still knocked out, isn't he?
Come, let's take him out.
- So they can invite themselves over?
- We can take him out
through the window, I'll help.
- I imagine they want to kill him.
- So what? He's a thief.
- That would be murder.
Sarah, we can't keep him here.
What if he breaks free?
It could be dangerous.
- What do you suggest?
That we kill him?
Come with me.
It's stuck.
- Sarah?
- I didn't mean to frighten you.
- Your friend has already contacted us.
- My friend?
- The woman who contacted
me on my CV.
- I'm alone.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- They've been following me.
- Why?
- How did you get here
if you weren't in that van?
- I bundled myself inside
survival blankets.
Old ones that the army took out.
They're full of rodents
and asbestos fiber.
They work if the patrol
vessels fly high enough.
But it's like playing
Russian roulette.
I was lucky.
But believe me! These
are not good people.
Untie me and I'll protect the house.
- Keep quiet.
I don't trust you.
- Is it the uniform?
- Maybe.
- But I'm not a soldier.
I'm a journalist.
- They why are you dressed like one?
- I took the clothes from a dead one.
Look in my front pocket.
There's a picture in there.
Please take a look at it!
- What is it?
- That's my wife and daughter.
They're dead.
- So what?
Is that suppose to
make you a good man?
- Oh, come on! You
can see that I was shot.
- Could have been an accident.
A self-inflicted wound.
- Do you think you can
hold the four alone?
You don't know what
they're capable of.
They won't stop until
they've got your farm.
- Well, it seems to me
like it's you they want.
- No, don't delude yourself.
How many farms with
souls and piles
of livestock do you
think you can find
Please.
Untie me.
- So you can open the door to your friends?
- You can't beat him alone.
- Our father will be back soon.
- Where is he?
- He went to town to
get some supplies.
- And how soon will he be back?
- Soon enough.
- How many of them are there?
- Five.
Used to be six, but one of
them was killed by the blasters last night.
- That must be what we...
- Don't.
- I went inside an abandoned
house to look for some food,
and one of them
followed me without cover.
I escaped just before the blast.
- If what you're telling
me is true, then why are
they trying so hard
to capture you?
- You're a liar!
- Please.
Let me help you.
No, no!
- What are you doing?
- Shutting him up.
- Let him talk, Sarah!
- Be quiet!
- I'm gonna go upstairs, Ok?
- Knock knock.
Big bad wolf.
Keep quiet, bitch.
- You need to untie me.
Those guys will
kill your sister.
Then they will come down
here and kill me and you.
Do you want that to happen?
There's a knife
in the side pocket of my bag.
Get it for me and let me help.
I'm not going to
lie to you, I promise.
Come here.
Here.
Great. Yeah. Stay there.
No one can see you.
You'll be fine.
- No!
Thanks.
- Jeez!
Are the other locked?
- No.
- We'll be safe now.
- Tom?
- Sarah?
Are you Ok?
- Yeah.
- What did he do to you?
- Nothing.
- Your sister's fine.
- Did you hear them leave?
- I heard an engine.
They moved a van.
- They have broken
into the barn.
- They'll attack us again at sunset.
- That's how everyone
left is killed.
You've done a good
job cleaning up my leg.
You a nursing student?
- Something like that.
Tell me what you did to them.
Tell me the truth.
- I killed one of them.
My brother.
They killed my wife and daughter.
They broke into the basement
where they were hiding.
My wife tried to defend
what little food we had.
And they killed her.
I came back from a water run
and found them carrying
boxes to their van.
And I just hid.
I remember her wiping
blood on her pants.
Him
eating our food.
And their brother
bragging about what he'd just done.
Thought I'd never see him again.
Then, a couple of days ago,
I'm riding in a bunker on
the coast and I hear a voice.
Their brother's.
I killed him whilst he slept.
Then ran.
They've been chasing me ever since.
- And your daughter?
- They got her, too.
- How do you know he isn't making
up stories to make you feel sorry for him?
- Tom...
- Was he in the picture he showed you?
- No.
- Then you don't know for sure, do you?
- He saved my life.
- Maybe he plays the good
guy till he's done with the people outside.
- Look, we're all in this together.
- I'm just saying we
should watch our backs.
He killed a man before your eyes, how do
you know he's not gonna kill us, too?
- How can you judge him so harshly
you can't even see him?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
- That's another five.
Mediocre shot.
That's a nice radio.
Who taught you how to use it?
- My father.
- Your father sounds like
quite the survivalist.
- He didn't...
He doesn't like to
take things for granted.
He would always be
prepared if we went to ship.
- Did you get your electricity
from the solar power?
- Some. But we save
the batteries for the radio.
Wait a minute.
Your men will live
They keep doing alright
This usually means you're OK
- An unusually big swarm has been
spotted over Bradford heading south.
I repeat. An unusually big swarm has been
They're three quarters advanced
- They're heading our way.
They've been acting
strangely lately.
- What do you mean?
- Their patterns have changed.
They'd been drilling like crazy.
Like there's no tomorrow.
- It's Jimmy.
Don't come back
it's too risky at the moment.
- Tom, why don't you fetch
this bowl of mine?
After all, it's been a long
time since we've had a guest.
- Sure.
- I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to intrude.
When did Tom lose his sight?
- He was flash blinded
the day they came.
He was outside feeding
cattle with mum.
All he remembers is this
intense light
telling him to run away.
She died.
It was the last thing he saw.
- And your father?
I saw his grave.
They got him, didn't they?
I saw a blast a distance
a couple of days ago.
- Is that why you came here?
- I was hoping to find people.
Life.
- Yeah, and you've left them to us.
- I didn't know they were following me.
I'm sorry.
Tom needs to know.
The longer you wait,
the harder it's going to be.
- You know what? This is
none of your business.
- So you're gonna keep lying to him?
Give him false hope?
- Sorry. It's burnt.
We ran out of oil.
Hello?
- What's happened to my husband?
Did you kill him?
Well?
There's been enough
bloodshed as it is.
Release your prisoner
and we'll be square.
- He's gone.
-You're lying
- I'm not.
He cut his ties and escaped.
- When?
- A couple of hours ago.
He's probably dead by now.
If not, the survival blankets
won't protect him for long.
- What did you do with
my husband's body?
- He's still with us.
- Take him down at sunset
so we can have a Christian burial.
We'll leave the house
as soon as it's done.
You have our word.
Over.
- What do you think?
- I wouldn't believe them.
- She should be allowed
to bury her husband.
- That's not what they want him for.
- What do you mean?
- Well, they need to eat to survive.
- And what about you?
Have you been eating
dead people, too?
- Of course not.
- They gave us their word.
- It means nothing.
- It's worth taking a chance.
They might go away.
- If what I think
will happen happens,
they will be able to
stay out there for days
while we're stuck in here
with no food or water.
What do you think, Tom?
- I think you need to leave.
- Tom!
- If he left, they'd go!
- No, they wouldn't.
They'd come back for the farm.
- We need his help.
- We were fine before he turned up!
- He wouldn't make it
out there by himself.
-I don't care if he dies.
- Um...
I'm sor-he didn't mean that.
- Are they back?
- Yeah.
She'll call.
- Ok.
Will you come with me?
Back in a minute, Ok?
- Ok. Ok.
- We'll be alright.
- You alright?
- Dad should be back by now.
- They thought they
could contain him.
If we were without our
satellites we were dine for.
The heat.
Snow.
A stench of decaying flesh.
There are no words for it.
And soon we'll have no
newspapers to send them to.
So I got back in the car,
drove home faster than I could.
- Is there anyone left in cities?
- No.
The blasters didn't
leave them a chance.
The old fire blankets,
the solar panels,
that just drops in the ocean.
And those who you
love survive to become animals.
They hide in basements or bunkers.
They get sick or lose their minds.
- Have you heard of anyone
actually making contact with them?
- No. Never.
- Well, maybe there isn't anyone.
Maybe they just sent the machines.
- Or maybe they just
don't give a shit about us.
- Is that what you believe?
That they don't care?
- Why would they?
What makes us more special then the
ants or... field mice
or dolphins?
- Our art?
Our ability to build,
to think about our life in sequences?
- Hence build completely
sophisticated colonies.
Birds decorate their nests,
- Yeah, but they don't...
regret, they don't dream,
they don't hope.
- Maybe they do.
Maybe they don't.
- It's probably for the best.
It won't get hard that way.
- Tom...
Uh... why don't you
play something for us?
- I don't feel like it.
- Come on, do it for me.
- What should I play?
- What you were playing
over the radio.
- Hello?
- You Ok?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
You can come in.
- What did you study?
- Veterinary medicine.
First year.
It doesn't matter now,
though, does it?
- You could have studied
English lit, like me.
Believe me. You won't
want me sewing your leg up.
What happened to your father?
- I found him.
Yesterday morning.
A few yards from here.
He must've been...
...confused.
Maybe his watch stopped, or something.
When he left,
I vaguely remember waking up
remembering I'd forgotten to
turn off the alarm the night before,
telling myself every
way it hadn't rung.
I'd just go straight back to sleep.
And when my alarm did go off
a few minutes later,
I got out,
and I saw his bike
leaning against a tree.
- And you really think it was a mistake?
- What are you saying?
- Maybe...
he just wanted to
get it over with.
- No...
No, my father was a fighter.
He kept saying that
we had to keep going.
That we could never give up...
he wouldn't...
Never...
- In this world,
people change.
- It was a mistake, Ok?
My father wasn't a coward.
He would... never have
abandoned us like that.
He knew I couldn't protect him alone.
- Or maybe he knew you could.
Maybe he thought you
were stronger than him.
You are, Sarah.
You're stronger than you think.
- Where were you
when all this started?
- Just... grocery shopping with my wife.
We were bickering
because I was wasting
money on expensive food and
she was trying to save a few in the summer.
Sounds trivial, doesn't it?
- What was her name?
- Lisa.
Our daughter's name was Marty.
She was such a lively
little girl. She was.
Dancing around.
Lisa said she could
become a ballerina.
And I remember the last
night before I left them.
Marty woke up
She wanted to come with me.
She wouldn't let go
of my hands, as if
somehow she knew.
- Sarah?
Nooooo!
No...
No!
- Oh, shit.
Tom?!
Tom?
Tom!
No... he wouldn't have.
- No!
There were too many patrols around.
- He's all I have left!
Tom!
Tom!!
- Tom!
- What?
They burned the straw.
- They're still here.
Go! Go.
- What are you doing?
- There is no asbestos.
We'll be fine.
- Tom!
- Sarah! Hey!
Tom's alive.
Ok?
Wait. I heard laughing.
- They're in the cellar.
- You alright?
- We need to get him out.
- I'll take him by surprise.
What are you doing?
-He'll sniff them out.
- Tom?
Tom.
Tom, Tom
It's me.
- Come on.
- Stay here, Ok?
- She's not here.
I guess they've gone.
- Tom?
- Get up!
Come over here, boy.
- Why did you shoot him?
There was no need.
- He killed my brother.
- You killed his wife.
- No...
They were already dead.
His wife ran to a
death with their child.
She just couldn't take it anymore.
We found him scavenging
for tomatoes in the garden.
Took them back to her bunker.
I guess we didn't agree on
what we had to do to survive.
You were wrong.
And because you wouldn't
listen, you got my husband killed.
- He tried to rape me.
- I don't believe you.
It's time for this to end.
- You're going to be Ok.
- I just needed you to trust me.
- We need to go.
Come back when it's safe.
- I didn't mean what I said about Jude.
- I know.
- What now?
- Are you sure this is what you want?
- Stop!
Maybe we should wait.
- What happened?
- They're gone.
- They left the same way they came.
Without warning.
Dad used to say as long as
there's hope in our hearts,
we'd survive.
He was right.
The end.