Tie him up.
The hands are not the issue.
The fight is the issue.
The battle is the issue.
Who imposes the terms of the battle
will impose the terms of the peace.
You think he has a handicap? No.
The other guy has a handicap
if he cannot control himself.
You control yourself, you control him.
Take him to court.
A man distracted is a man defeated.
That's right.
You heard that before, huh?
Heard it again.
- Take him to court.
- Taking him to court.
Good. Cut him down. Fight's oνer.
That's it.
Fight's over. Finish it here. It's over.
Okay. Improve the position.
Improve the position.
Keep the weight on his head.
What next?
Watch the slam. Keep your head up.
Nice. Nice. You felt that, huh?
Good. Keep your back.
Keep your back. Let's do it.
Okay. Okay. Improve.
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
Good. Good, you felt that. Good.
Okay.
Improve the position.
Good.
Take him to Brazil. Good, good.
Arm bar. See that? Excellent.
Triangle. Hold. Insist. Insist on it.
Insist on the move.
Good. Now what?
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
Good. Good hit.
Okay, breathe. Breathe.
Breathe. You know the escape.
You know the escape.
Breathe. Breathe.
There's always an escape.
You know the escape.
You know the escape. Breathe.
- There's always an escape.
- I'm passing out.
All right.
Great class.
Great. Hey, stick around.
You don't fight your way clear?
I was passing out.
There is no situation
you cannot escape from.
You know the escape.
You know the escape. Show it to me.
Show it to me. Show me the escape.
Good!
Good. You know the escape.
You just got tired. What's the lesson?
- Don't get tired.
- Let the other guy get tired.
You wanna fight like a black belt, huh?
You wanna test for the black belt?
- Snowflake, give him his wish.
- All right. Raise your hands.
Well, your hands. Get them up, up.
Administer the fight.
Insist. Insist.
You told me this training
saved your life.
This is how you repay me?
Breathe through it. The moνes work.
Defend the neck.
Take the fight out of your face.
Well, that's it. Officer down.
That makes you mad, huh?
Control your emotions.
Control your emotions. Breathe.
Breathe.
All right, all right. Okay, okay, okay.
That's it.
That's it. That's it.
Good.
Hit the showers.
Come back in. Good.
You okay?
- Yeah. He's good. He's good.
- Good.
Hi, I'm lost. I can't find
the fucking pharmacy.
What?
I don't know.
Well, you said I had to find it
before 8.
All right, thank you. Okay.
Hey, hey. Wait, wait!
Stop!
That's the one.
Hi. Hi, yeah, I missed the guy.
I'm gonna need your help
with some of those things.
No, a regular doctor's not gonna fill
the prescription.
What?
Because he's closed.
The prescription's not gonna stand up
at a straight pharmacy.
All right, but I need a-
All right. Okay.
Hello? Hi, this is Sondra Terry
with Southside Jiu-jitsu.
Yeah, I have
your inνoice number 20903.
Yeah, you indicate you did not receive
our payment.
Okay, but on my record it shows that-
Look, I'm trying to run a business
just like you and-
Oh, wait.
As all the world knows,
tomorrow's Wednesday.
So be on Wednesday's schedule.
Nine a. m., Beginning Self Defense,
15, I'm washing the mats.
You're gonna have to train if you
want that black belt, Officer Joe.
Mike?
What, you want the officer
to walk you home?
It's rough out there.
After he gets his black belt
he can walk me.
- That would make me feel secure.
- How?
I know his fucking pants
aren't gonna fall down.
Hey, by the way,
weren't you gonna buy a new rig?
- I was thinking about it.
- Oh, you were thinking about it.
I tell you what. Why don't you take
some of that good off-duty money...
...and buy a new shoulder rig. Why?
A shoulder rig's
nothing but a handle.
Excuse me. Who's the-?
- It's all right. Come in.
- Hi.
- Mike?
- Yeah.
I belieνe I-
- Can you come here?
- Take it easy.
Yes, thank you. I was driving-
Take off your coat.
How can we help you?
Look, I hurt your car, okay?
Hey, Joe, take the lady's coat.
Come on.
I'll pay you cash so we can just-
No! Stay away from me!
- Miss.
- Don't touch me! Don't touch me!
I'm a police officer!
The wind blew something in
through the window.
- The wind blew something in?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Sure.
Y'all okay?
Yeah. We're fine.
You want me to start the cleanup?
Yeah, thanks, Snowflake.
What am I gonna say,
"She tried to kill a police officer"?
You sure?
I'm sure.
It's okay.
- I'm an attorney. I can't-
- The officer thinks it didn't happen.
I'm sorry, I don't...
He thinks it didn't happen.
You were going to the mountains.
No, that's funny.
Joe? Joe still inside?
- No. He just left.
- Left?
Yeah. Maybe he went to the club.
- What happened to the window?
- Isn't he on at the club?
That's funny.
Weren't you going to the mountains?
- Why would he go to the club?
- Isn't he working tonight?
The club? No, no, no. He hasn't
worked at the club in months.
Listen, I have to tell him something.
Okay? Tell him.
- Why?
- Why what?
Why hasn't he been working there?
Yeah, no. Listen, I gotta get home.
Officer Joe let the girl walk.
Yeah. I suppose he did.
That was generous of him.
Yeah, I think so.
Why did he do that?
He didn't wanna bring dishonor
on the academy.
- Yes, of course.
- I need a black belt for him.
He didn't want to bring dishonor
on the academy.
Yes. Thank you.
The car?
The girl drove into your car.
I didn't look at that.
They want cash to get the window
boarded up.
Do you have any cash?
And on your business...
...for which you have no cash,
we need to replace the window.
Your check bounced.
My check?
To the martial arts supply.
Mike, we're short.
You have no cash.
If we pay the window,
I can't make the rent.
Hello?
You need to ask Ricardo for a loan.
Mike. You go ask him for a loan.
Hey, Mike.
Hey, Billy.
Jimmy, you can't smoke in here.
- We got Mike Terry down here.
- Fucking world turning into a dungeon.
He's sorry. He's busy. Five minutes.
Ricardo said that?
Bruno. Ricardo's out.
Put the cigarette out.
- Fine. I'll take a beer.
- You ain't got no bouncer?
- Just weekends now.
- Officer Joe?
Billy. Billy, I'll roll you for this drink.
I hardly think so. Joey the cop?
- Yeah.
- Quit.
Come on. I'll roll you for this drink.
Here, you check out this die.
- So where you been, the cruise ships?
- He works the cruise ships.
- Why'd Joe quit?
- Yeah, hold on a second.
Check this out.
You ever seen that?
I'm fucking fantastic. Somebody buy
me this fucking drink.
- Officer Joe. Why'd he quit?
- What?
Why'd Joe quit?
Because Bruno wasn't paying him.
They never paid him.
They never paid him?
Coming from that Brazilian
jujitsu background...
...I spent time with Silva years ago
before he moved into MMA...
...and he'd showed me
his secret technique...
...his grandfather showed him.
we've been doing that...
...since I was 12
in high school wrestling...
We have a deal
or we don't have a deal?
He's gonna have his hands full
with Morisaki, but it's gonna be great.
I don't know why
everybody is not coming to this fight.
The main event for the IFA-
We got a deal. What good's a deal
if nobody's making any money?
Ricardo won't do it.
What, he's too pure? What, it's not
elegant? That elegant life he liνes?
How long's that gonna last?
Answer me that.
Morisaki's gonna do it?
This bullshit?
Morisaki's a whore. He's gonna do
whatever the fuck I tell his people.
If he did this, he'll do anything.
"The gold and ivory-studded belt is
worth one-quarter of a million dollars.
It was presented to Taketa Morisaki
by the Emperor of Japan. "
Is he on the level?
The belt's a fucking nationaI treasure.
It's worth a quarter of a mil.
He's going to give it to Ricardo
if he loses?
It's publicity. It's publicity.
It's something to tell the papers.
It's a story.
"I am a samurai,
should this gaijin defeat me...
...I will surrender my fucking belt. "
And wilI he?
Look, we're not selling tickets.
Sell the tickets, sell the show...
...and we'll figure that out
on the way to the bank.
The point is
you've got to sell the show.
Ricardo's the biggest in Brazil.
Read the street signs,
we're in America.
Morisaki's doing his part,
you've gotta do yours.
Ricardo's gotta do his.
Where the fuck is he?
Pay-per-view is pulling back
on the promotion.
We need a gimmick.
One more time.
Ricardo brings the old man
up from Brazil.
He fights for the honor of his mentor.
Morisaki brings the belt.
He fights for the emperor.
What do you got? A grudge match.
It's back to the '30s,
black against white, Irish against Jew.
A racial grudge match.
Get me some velocity. Velocity.
Or else it's just two monkeys
in the ring.
We'll speak English here
in front of my friend.
Marty,
this is my brother-in-law.
Mike Terry.
Could I have a word with you?
I'm trying to do business, Mike.
What do you want?
I gotta talk to you about money.
- Money?
- Yeah.
You want money? Tell you what.
Fight on the undercard.
I'll put you on the undercard.
Round robin,
winner takes home 50 grand.
You got a good chance to take home
the money. Fight on the undercard.
Joe Collins, the cop.
- Joe Collins, the cop?
- Yeah. Your bouncer.
- He worked here several months-
- All right. All right, all right, I got it.
Did you ever pay him?
- Did I pay him?
- Yeah.
- What the fuck do you care?
- Did you pay him?
No, I heard you.
What business is it of yours?
The guy's got a family.
What the fuck are you saying?
This guy's got a family and I owe him
some money and what?
- Is this business of yours?
- Did you pay him?
I told him, as I recall,
he would have to wait for his money.
He got hot-headed and quit.
Yeah. This is Bruno Silva.
Put him on.
Chet Frank just walked into the bar
without his wife.
Without his bodyguard. No. No.
Get a news crew outside and-
Who did they get the tip from?
Some cabby driving by,
the fuck do I care?
Chet Frank just walked into my bar.
Would you call the newspapers?
Thank you.
Thank you for stopping by.
How's my sister?
- I'Il have a caipirinha.
- I'Il have another one too.
- I'Il take care of the lady's drink.
- How you doing?
- Everything's a fucking struggle.
- Take the high ground, huh, Chet?
- Yeah, right.
- The lady thanks you.
Anything for beauty.
Nobody's tough
when it comes to beauty, huh?
Indeed. Indeed. My pleasure.
Excuse me. I'd like to buy that.
She's a friend of mine.
I admire your taste.
What? I'm sorry, what did you say?
I said, I admire your taste.
I heard what you said.
I don't know what it means.
- All right.
- What does it mean?
Whatever you want it to mean.
I'νe had a tough day.
And what the fuck is that to me?
Fucking tough guy in the movies.
- Look-
- Where's your protection, tough guy?
I didn't know you knew her.
You insulted me, then you insulted
the young woman.
And don't you have a wife? Didn't I
actually read that you have a wife?
I didn't come to fight.
I came for a drink.
Well, maybe you came
to the wrong place.
You know what? Just calm down.
I'm calm. You fucking calm down.
- I have some ideas.
- No, I don't think you do.
Oh, I don't?
I just wanna have a drink.
How do you like that, man?
Come on!
Take that.
All right! Make a lane.
Hey, baby, you can hear me.
You can hear me.
- I'm all right.
- Ambulance?
He's got a guy or something?
I'm sure they made the call.
Hey, pal. Why'd you come out
alone, huh?
You looking for trouble?
He's okay. He's all right.
They banished the professor
down here, huh?
Here you go.
- I thought Joey was on the door.
- Nope.
- Hey, Mike.
- Hey, Lenny.
What the fuck happened?
I don't know. Some kind of bar fight.
Show it to me.
What are we talking about here?
Couple of bad boys
jumped on a movie star.
How about that?
Loomis has them
out at the ambulance.
What happened to them?
Did they fall down?
Something like that, I think.
Our friend here is all by himself.
Jesus Christ.
You got the tape.
I never threw a punch.
I'm a stone-cold victim.
What happened to the other guys?
How would I know?
What about you?
Nobody knows who I am.
You didn't get the loan.
Ricardo wasn't there.
Did you ask Bruno for it?
You didn't ask for it.
Are you afraid of money?
You tell me how we can run
your academy without money.
You tell me that so I can do it
and not disturb you in your purity.
How am I gonna run my business?
All the time you need me...
...alI the time,
all of my money's going to yours.
There are some things
I don't understand.
My father made money.
My brothers make money.
And you are somehow too pure.
You're too pure to compete.
- It-
- It weakens the fighter.
- That's right.
- Because a competition is not a fight.
That's correct.
And what about
the fighter's family, Mike?
What do they eat
while he's being so pure?
I have to take money
from my business...
...which is making money.
You replace the window,
you can't pay your rent.
The insurance
will replace the window.
You want to turn your friend in?
Your precious friend?
- Yeah.
- Your prize student?
The policeman?
The girl tried to kill him,
and he let her go.
The girl, he'd turned her in...
...the cops would have said
it was attempted murder.
And wasn't it?
- It was an accidental discharge.
- Was it?
She's disturbed, all right?
The girl was disturbed.
And now what? You're her doctor?
She walks into your academy,
you take responsibility for her crime?
They would prosecuted her.
She would go to jail.
It would haνe ruined her life.
So, yes, he gave her a pass.
And you think it was noble.
The code of the warrior.
- You think it's noble.
- No. I think it's correct.
Well, that's fine. Except, as we report
the wind blew in the window...
...it was an act of God, and not
covered under our specific policy.
And so until we find the money...
...we have to live
with the window boarded up.
And you tell me how that brings
money into your business.
Hello.
Hi, Nikki. Yeah.
No, I can't order the new fabric now.
No, I can't.
I can't.
Of course I'm going to reorder.
Okay. Nikki, I'll see you
in 10 minutes. Okay?
Okay. Bye.
Now I have to fix the window.
Where I'm getting the cash...
...to buy the fabric for my business
without which we cannot eat?
One moment.
Where did you get that cut?
Thank you.
It's for you.
What is it?
It's an invitation.
- Who is it from?
- From Chet Frank.
- Chet Frank?
- Yeah.
We're invited to his house
for dinner tonight.
- To Chet Frank's house?
- That's right.
Really?
Where's Joe?
Mike, tell him,
what's the best weapon?
- Best weapon is a flashlight.
- Tell him why.
So you can look deep
in the other guy's eyes.
They had a dustup
at the Sao Paulo last night.
Is that right?
- Two ran into a Cuisinart.
- Can't believe everything.
Lenny and Loomis saw the tape.
Said it was better than Titanic.
We gonna ride,
or you still getting pretty?
- I'Il be right out.
- Wished I was there, Mike.
Yeah. I wish I was there too.
Hey, Mike.
You come down
because of that thing?
Thing? What thing?
I got something for you.
- No.
- Yeah.
- I don't deserve it.
- It's overdue.
Belt is just symbolic.
The belt, as Snowflake says,
is just to keep your pants up.
Thank you.
What thing?
- What?
- You said, am I here about the thing?
The thing with the girI
that never happened.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Open it later.
What is it?
Well, apparently, it's a wristwatch.
Yours? Whose is it?
It's yours. I set you up with a job
with my people...
...who apparently stiffed you.
Yeah. You went to the club.
Why didn't you tell me
they weren't paying?
You know, I...
Well, they paid you now.
That thing, take it and pawn it...
...and take your wife to the mountains.
What does the black belt mean?
That I represent the academy.
Then respect your teacher.
Hey. What's going on?
Who ordered this?
Who's paying for this?
Mr. Terry, I am heartily ashamed
of what I did. I'm so sorry.
I will, of course, make it well.
This is a check...
...for the damage to your car.
I would like to contact the officer
to thank him for what he did.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Mr. Terry, I'm an attorney.
I know what the officer did.
Out of courtesy,
he refrained from actions...
...that might have sent me to jail
or to an institution.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey, Richard.
Who do you like
in the Morisaki fight?
One of them's gonna win.
- Little word from a little bird?
- Yeah. I don't play that.
- If you did, who would you like?
- I can't help you.
You sure? You help me,
I'm gonna help you.
A word to the wise on this fight
is sufficient to put...
...money in your pocket.
Who does it hurt?
I can't help you, Richard.
You know as much as me.
I know as much as you.
Mr. Terry...
As you can see...
...I have a problem.
I have something of a problem.
Is there some way
that I can help you?
You work with the police.
I'νe trained the police.
And what do all the belts mean?
The white belt is someone
who walks in off the street.
Black belt is someone the teacher
recognizes as fit to instruct.
In between we have blue, purple
and brown.
What do you have to do
to get a red belt?
There's only one.
All right. I'm not going to touch you.
But if you were to hold me,
could I strike you?
If you put your arms around me
and held me? Could I strike you?
With your knees.
If you turned your body slightly
and grasped me...
...could I strike you? From there?
- No.
- What?
No.
Could I strike you now?
Where can I strike you?
Don't stand there.
An enrollment form.
Should you wish to continue
your instruction.
Yeah.
I'm looking at scene 87-C. I got it.
Well, enough is as good as a feast.
Let's take a walk. Come on.
Excuse me, but I have to ask you,
where did you get your dress?
- I made it.
- Oh, she made it.
Do you cook too?
- But where did you get the fabric?
- The fabric. I made that too.
You made that?
Yeah. Since I was a kid in Rio.
You made the fabric?
Yeah. I have a company in Brazil.
No. I don't believe it.
I just don't believe it.
Come and sit down. Lucy and I just
wrote a book about fabrics.
- Really?
- Yes.
We have a company. She has her
degree in it, in textiles.
I love this fabric.
I have some people,
my family's people, in Brazil...
...and they are the ones that-
- I love this fabric.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I would love, if you guys want...
...I can show you more.
I have tons of colors.
So, what is jujitsu?
You use one fighter's strength
against him?
Yes, in a way.
You let him use his strength
and you use your understanding.
So it's a form of wrestling.
Yeah.
Like we see in the mixed
martial arts competitions.
Yeah, that's right.
- You compete?
- No.
Because?
Competition is weakening.
Because it's fixed.
Two guys in a ring,
people betting money.
It may be fixed.
Any one fight may be fixed.
- But you train people to fight.
- No. I train people to prevail.
In the street, in the alley, in combat.
The bodyguard, the cop, the soldier.
There's one rule:
Put the other guy down.
You have to train in order to do that.
Any staged contest must have rules.
Everything has rules.
The problem is sticking to them.
Your wife. She's a beautifuI woman.
Yes, she is.
Booze. Women.
What in this life
doesn't get you in trouble?
Turn to the side.
Everything has a force.
Embrace it or deflect it.
Why oppose it?
How you doing? You healing up?
- I'm good.
- Well, you're young.
So there's the neckline,
the waistline...
- ... and the hemline. Right?
- Right.
So if you bring the hemline down
in this direction...
- ... it gives a better rhythm. Right?
- Yeah.
Yeah. And if your repeat
on the fabric is 1 foot, let's say.
Repeat of 1 foot? It's too costly.
That's what I'm saying.
Not from my people in Brazil.
You can get this fabric?
Absolutely. I make the fabric
and have it to you in a week.
- Zee.
- Yeah?
He's got to be on the set
in five hours.
Zena, let's let these nice people
go home.
Sure, honey.
- Thanks, pal.
- You're welcome.
Take care of that thing
for tomorrow morning.
You bet, Chet.
Movies. We get up early
in the morning like the military.
You in the military?
Yes, I was.
I'νe never seen Chet socialize
on a schooI night.
The guy saved his life.
- Zena?
- Oh, thank you.
Tomorrow.
I want to see you tomorrow.
Those are all my numbers
right there.
Mike.
- Mike, tell them the story.
- No. They want to go to bed.
Come on, baby. Tell them the story.
- The fighters before a fight.
- Three marbles.
Each fighter has a two-in-three odds
of choosing the white marble.
White marble's a pass.
What if he picks the black?
- Black marble is a handicap.
- What does that mean, "a handicap"?
- You lose the use of an arm, or-
- Because?
You never know
when you may be disabled.
Thank you for a beautiful evening.
Thank you for having us
to your lovely home.
A fighter gets a handicap.
Do they do that in competitions?
- No.
- Well, they should.
A lot of money in that.
It'd be like a reality show.
Chet wants you to come down
to the set.
Can you do that?
Yeah. Okay.
Mike. Over here.
Yeah, well, hold up.
Chet's a little bit late.
He's a little bit late.
What do we need
to make you comfortable?
- Abby?
- Yes, Jerry?
Get him a script.
Put him in a trailer if he wants.
Chet's running late.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Abby. Abby.
Yeah, they want all the scenes
up in costumes on set right now.
WilI you pay attention?
Come on, what are you gonna do,
stab me with your purse?
Come on!
No, no, no. This is bullshit!
You gotta stab me
with the fucking thing.
- I'm trying, George.
- Well, try harder! Let's go!
Come on. Come on, stick me.
Come on. Come on.
You gotta make it real.
You listening to me
or am I talking to a fucking wall?
Make it look real.
You've gotta make it look real.
Chet ain't gonna look reaI
if you don't make it look real.
Anybody can do this fucking move.
- You.
- Me?
Yeah, you. I'm gonna show him
how to do the fucking move.
Come. Take the knife.
Ain't gonna hurt you. It's rubber.
Mike, what the fuck
are you doing here?
I don't know. Jerry Weiss.
- You coming on the show?
- No. He just got all wannabe.
- He ask if you were in the military?
- Yeah.
- You tell him what you did?
- No. He didn't ask.
You take the fucking knife.
He's Chet. I'm you.
You take the fucking knife and-
Well, what we have here
is a wise guy.
How the fuck are you?
I'm good. I don't wanna take up
any of your time.
No, they're shooting something else.
They're always something else
to shoot. Step in my office.
What are we shooting today?
"Meet me, 0-dark 30, AOC."
I never served.
I know I didn't miss anything.
But what are you gonna say?
But how would I know?
Fucking guy who lucked out.
- Here you go, Chet.
- Thanks, dolI.
Yeah, I'm just a fucking guy
who lucked out.
I drink too much.
I fool around. You know how hard it is
for a man to step out?
A famous man?
And who can you trust?
What were you doing in the bar?
- I went in to get a drink.
- Why didn't you bring your protection?
I wanted to get into a fight.
- Why didn't you fight him, then?
- I wanted a beating.
- What, are you a psychiatrist?
- No, I'm a fighter.
If that ain't strong enough,
you tell me.
Thanks, babe.
What are we shooting today?
Gulf War flashback.
That's right. It's not my department...
...but what are these numbers
doing on my boot?
If the guy had been in combat,
they'd be worn off.
The sizes would be worn off, right?
- It's not the sizes.
- No?
Guys in the desert, they'd...
...ink their number in the platoon
on their boots.
That way, if their legs got blown off
or their bodies got blown apart...
...somebody in their platoon
would know who it was.
"0-dark 30. AOC."
- What does AOC mean?
- "Ass on curb. "
"Ass on curb. "
That's good. Is that something
a guy would say?
He might. It's old army. World War I I.
Maybe the guy learned it from the guy.
It's good.
Yeah? Are you free tonight?
You, me and Jerry.
I wanna meet over at Fiori's
after we wrap.
I wanna make you a co-producer
on this film.
Yeah, hey. This is Mike Terry.
Yeah, George Koriani asked me
to send him some materials.
Yeah. I found it.
Do you want me to fax it to you?
Okay. I'm gonna fax it.
I'm gonna have dinner
with Jerry and Chet tonight.
Yeah, okay. Okay.
They wanna put it in the movie.
Put what in the movie?
It's Desert Storm.
It's a bunch of combat.
George is doing this.
George is doing the stunts.
- George is doing the stunts?
- Yeah.
Then why do they want you for?
They want me to be a producer.
What does that mean?
To begin with,
they wanna use my training idea.
Gulf War.
They're training for hand-to-hand.
The captain in the film, he's training
the guys using my training method.
Sondra Terry.
Lucy, hi.
Yes. Yes. I'll be right out.
Yeah, yeah, I'm bringing the sample.
Okay, bye.
- Sorry, babe. You were saying?
- They want me to be a producer.
I'm gonna head out to the set, and
then I'm gonna go to dinner with-
What?
Who's gonna take
the beginners class?
Baby. Let the wheel come around.
Just let it come around.
Sometimes you can just let
the wheel come around.
I can't just cancel the class.
What message does that send?
Baby, you made Joe a black belt.
Right?
And so he's qualified to uphold
the honor of the academy.
Let him teach the class.
Okay? Okay?
Okay.
Let the wheel come around.
Good for you.
I gotta go.
See you later, okay?
They're gonna take me
in their company.
Yeah, this is Mike Terry.
Yeah, did you get the fax
I just sent you?
Okay, good. I'm gonna go through
the whole script here.
Yeah. It's all about authenticity.
Am I supposed to meditate?
No. Just sit for a moment.
All right.
I don't understand.
The first step is the hardest.
And what is the first step?
To leave the outside outside.
I think I've come to the wrong place.
I'm so sorry.
Conquer your fear,
and you'Il conquer your opponent.
Yes.
Mr. Terry...
...a man raped me.
He held a knife to my throat,
a man twice my size.
And then he raped me.
He held a knife to your throat?
Yes. Look, I appreciate
what you'νe done, it's just that...
...I don't think there's anything I could
learn here that would really-
There's no situation that you cannot
escape from.
There is no situation that you cannot
turn to your advantage.
A man was gonna cut my throat.
Like this?
Don't move. There's a knife there.
There's a knife there. Grab my arm.
Drag it toward me.
Toward me. Good.
Now, move to the right.
Move to the right and behind me.
Good. Now stab me with the knife.
Good. Stab me with the knife.
Stab me with the knife.
Let's hear it. Let it out.
Let it out. Let it out.
It's all right.
There's no one here but the fighters.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, this is Mike Terry.
Yeah, I'll put that stuff together
for you.
Yeah.
It is good. Yeah.
Yeah. No, I'm working
on the script now. Yeah.
Okay. No, thank you.
Hey, Joe. Thanks for coming in.
I want you take the evening class.
White belts.
Hip escape, escape the mount,
pass the guard, arm bar.
- What time you going on-shift?
- I've been suspended.
- The wristwatch was hot.
- The wristwatch?
The gold watch the guy gave you,
you gave me. I pawned it. It was hot.
It was hot?
- Two-dollar pistol.
- You pawned it?
I did. The pawnshop called it in.
The captain wants to know...
...what I'm doing
with a hot $20,000 watch.
- What'd you tell him?
- I told him...
I told him I gotta telI him tomorrow.
He suspended me.
Tell him where you got the watch?
I didn't wanna hurt the academy.
I couldn't tell him
you gave me a hot watch.
Well, no. Let me clean it up.
It's easy.
- It's easy.
- It's easy?
Yeah, these guys, these guys
I'm sure.
The guy gave me the watch.
He got stiffed.
It's easy. I'm sure he'd wanna know.
Take the class. Sweat it out.
Sweat it out.
It's okay, Joe. It's easy.
Sorry I'm late.
Chet might be shooting till dawn.
He wraps early, he'Il come down.
He sends his regrets.
Here's what he wanted to talk
to you about.
And you should get a lawyer...
...he wants to make
an arrangement with you.
He's got some big ideas,
some of them might even be mine.
Here's one of them.
This could be money.
Luccha, Luccha.
What would you like to drink? Pinot.
- No. I'm good.
- You don't drink?
- I used to.
- You don't anymore?
Jerry...
...there's a problem.
And I need you to help me work it out.
Of course.
It's difficult for me to say.
Best way I know? Spit it out.
Chet gave me a lavish gift.
- A lavish gift.
- All right.
There was a money issue
and I asked a friend to pawn it.
- Pawn it?
- Yeah. I'm sorry.
- Chet sent you a wristwatch.
- Yeah.
And you pawned it.
Hey, look, look, he gave it to you.
It yours to do with as you want.
- Jerry, how you doing?
- Hey, Billy.
- How you doing.?
- You got a minute?
- I'Il catch up with you.
- I got something Chet would like.
I'll come right over.
- I was going to call you about it.
- Okay.
Somebody pawned the watch
Chet gave you.
And he was told
the watch was stolen.
- Stolen?
- Yeah.
Son of a bitch.
Some motherfucker sold...
Someone sold Chet Frank
a hot watch. Goddamn it.
I can't use a celI phone in here.
I'm gonna to use the phone.
I'm gonna clean this up right now.
But she gave me this number.
She. Mrs. Frank gave me this number.
I called the other number
and it's out of service.
It's out of service.
Thanks.
Their numbers are all out of service.
How come it's out of serνice
if they gave me yesterday?
- Who?
- Zena Frank.
I had a meeting with Jerry.
They've changed the number.
I'νe ordered $30,000 worth of fabric.
I placed an order to Brazil
for $30,000 worth of fabric.
Lucy Weiss, please.
She's on vacation.
She won't take my call.
I had a meeting with Jerry.
- What did you do to screw this up?
- You placed an order to BraziI.
What did you do?
You placed an order for $30,000.
- Yes.
- Why?
Zena told me it was a done deal.
They were gonna use my fabric
in their shop.
- Where did you get the credit?
- What?
- Where did you get $30,000 credit?
- I paid cash.
- What?
- I paid cash. Are you deaf?
Do you know what's happening
to my life?
Where did you get the cash?
I took out a personal loan
for two weeks.
I was gonna get the fabric. We-
I was gonna be part of their company.
You took out a personal loan
for $30,000 for two weeks?
- From whom?
- It was a done deal.
Now it's not a done deal.
I wasn't even gonna need it
for two weeks.
They told me
they would write me-
Who gave you the loan?
Richard gave me the loan.
You borrowed $30,000
from a loan shark?
Are you crazy?
She spent it.
She spent the 30 grand I gave her.
That's right.
She said she wanted the money
for two weeks.
She spent the-
What the fuck am I gonna do?
What can you give me?
How soon could you get it to me?
Richie, if you could carry me.
The money ain't mine, Mike.
The money ain't mine.
I gave it out on my word.
I owe that money to my guys.
You understand? It ain't mine.
Now, what do you own
that you could turn to cash?
What do you got
that you could liquidate, huh?
Something for you?
It is an Asian samurai
training technique...
...going back to the 17th century.
Every fighter in the tournament, each
match, each fighter will pick a marble.
Should he pick a white marble'
he'll be given a pass.
Should he pick a black marble'
he'll be given a handicap.
For the fighters on the undercard,
each one could get a handicap?
That's right. The samurai say
that this approximates-
What do you got that's worth money?
- where one can never tell
if they might become disabled.
So there you have the undercard.
In the main event
we have bad blood evidently...
...between Morisaki
and your brother Ricardo.
Morisaki feels he's been insulted.
That is correct. It is unfortunate,
but this competition...
...has turned into a grudge match
between my brother and Morisaki.
Under the laws
of intellectual property, the copyright...
...that is the possession of the idea
and alI profits...
...deriνed from its exploitation...
...belongs to Mr. Terry.
The three marbles-
You can't copyright an idea.
You can't, but you can copyright
its expression...
...which he has done, through use...
...through exploitation of his system,
in order to earn his liνing.
- It's a historical form.
- Which idea-
- It's not.
- The Japanese-
- That's nonsense.
It was discovered in a training manual
in the 19th century.
You show it to me in one,
we'Il pack up and go home.
You show me where he
eνer transcribed-
He has a document
of his training regime...
...that he's used for many years
in his academy.
So he says. And I'll give you that.
Who's seen this form
outside of his academy?
We can assume the Silvas
and your client had access.
- The presumption of access.
- You can assume whatever.
The courts will concur the relationship
between the parties being so close-
Is that your case? Is that
what you wanna roll the dice on?
You sure you wanna play
in this league?
What do they want?
Let's financialize the problem.
No. Not. Please ask him to wait.
However...
...my client's prepared
to relinquish today.
To relinquish all rights to his creation.
In return for what?
In return for a payment of $200,000.
Payable today.
- That's a lot.
- It's a great idea.
- It's a good idea.
- It's great.
Or why would you be promoting it?
No, ask him to wait. He's gotta wait.
Your name could be here.
You wanna make some money?
Fight on the undercard, $50,000.
I saw you fight.
You've got a month to train.
You wanna make some money?
Give me a call.
I'll make you some money.
Thank you. That's very generous.
Today we need a cash payment
of $200,000.
You know, I don't think so.
- Mr. Brown, I tried to stop him.
- It's okay. It's your new partner.
It's Jerry Weiss, the producer.
I faxed him a copy
of the training sheet.
It's conspiracy. You gave the one guy
the information...
...who gave it to the other guy,
who denied it...
...as A, it's theft,
B, it's conspiracy to defraud.
You wanna get cute, you threaten
with criminal prosecution under RICO.
I'm glad I caught you.
I think you're about to become
a wealthy man.
Blew your case back there,
didn't you?
If I could just have one moment.
I will need some time
to formulate our new demands.
Of course.
But I wanna show you something.
Joseph Collins. Los Angeles Police.
On the night of June 12th, you stole
his weapon and fired on him.
Here's the ejected shell
from his pistoI.
It has your fingerprints on it.
Officer Collins did not file a report.
He is also prosecutable,
we'Il see to it that he is.
Prosecuted for?
Witness to the attempted murder
of an officer.
Oh, please.
- Which he suppressed.
- Why?
- In exchange for a bribe.
- A bribe?
This will end his career
with the police and send him...
...as well as the person who suborned
him to jail, with the assailant.
A bribe?
Your client gave him a wristwatch
worth $20,000...
...in exchange for his silence.
I'νe contacted the officer
and shared with him the alternatives.
You withdraw your claim
or we'll subpoena him...
...force him to incriminate you
and Mr. Terry...
...for which you will stand triaI.
How would you like to proceed?
I'd like to proceed directly to court.
From the academy, I'll need
notebooks and journals from day one.
Thank you for your time.
Speak to no one about this case
from now on in.
You motherfucking son of a bitch.
What have I got? What have I got?
Nothing. Nothing.
Do you know what the pension is
for an officer who kills himself?
What is the pension of a suicide?
Do you know? It's nothing.
- Tell him. Tell him.
- Ma'am.
Please don't touch that.
He didn't wanna bring disgrace
on you.
I have no husband.
I can't pay my bills.
I can't pay my rent.
And now I don't eνen have
his pension. And for what?
For what? For your stupid principles?
You are a sick fool.
How am I going to live?
Who's gonna pay these bills?
Are you? Are you? Are you?
Are you gonna take care of me, huh?
- What are you gonna do?
- I need you to step outside now.
How about that, huh?
All right.
Okay. Copies
of state regulations signed.
All right, we wanna get the main on,
if possible, by 11 p. m.
First elimination: Romero, Sanchez.
- Right here.
- Here.
Up second, Terry and Garcia.
Winner goes on to the second round.
All right, it's new,
but it's fairly straightforward.
As your match is called,
you wilI be walked to the ring.
We wilI now go to the ring, then I will
release you to the undercard room.
Now, no one is allowed
in the undercard room...
...but fighters and trainers.
Our part of the broadcast
starts at 8 p. m.
The broadcast starts at 8 p. m.
We wilI be calling the first fight
at 8: 15.
So you will take your corner.
The referee will calI you out...
...and an official
will perform the ceremony.
The officiant,
who will be wearing this mask...
...will show the bowl.
He will show the bowl
and the marbles.
He will then raise the bowl
and you will choose.
Black is the handicap.
The handicaps will be chosen
by the referee.
They are: left arm bound...
...right arm bound...
Okay, if you have no questions,
make your way back...
...to the undercard room. Thank you.
Yamato-damashii
is the undying spirit.
The spirit and honor of the samurai.
Yamato-damashii is a way of life.
Good. Good. Good.
- Sanchez, Romero. Sanchez, Romero.
- Come on. Good.
This fight is sanctioned by...
...and will be fought under the rules
of the California State Commission.
While the fighters are in the ring...
...they'll be under
supervision of the referee.
Any judgment made wilI be final
and subject only to disqualification...
...pending a drug test.
Trainers, I wanna see those cards
and I wanna see them signed.
Be strong. Grab the shoulders.
Grab the shoulders.
- is a legaI document signifying
your acceptance of the rules...
...under the statutes
of the State of California.
First fight. Sanchez and Romero.
And Dylan here is explaining what
the three possible handicaps could be.
What are they?
Break them down for us.
They'll basically draw from the bowl
a black or two white marbles.
If you get a white,
you're getting a pass.
If you draw the black...
...you're gonna haνe
one arm tied to your body...
...or both arms tied to your body
or a blindfold.
- Fighting with a blindfold?
- Yeah. How's that sound?
That sounds like fun. Well, it's gonna
be fun for the audience tonight.
Great to be here tonight.
Mike Goldberg with Josh Rafferty.
Josh, the explosion of mixed martial
arts is unbelievable.
Why do you think this sport
is so popular?
It was a good warm-up.
It was awesome.
Don't worry about them back there.
Do you have your mouthpiece?
All right.
Okay.
Yeah, okay. Just take it easy.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...Bobby Sanchez has drawn
the handicap...
...and he will fight one-armed.
Bobby Sanchez has drawn
the handicap...
...and he will fight one-armed.
Welcome to the IFA.
Okay, fighters, move forward.
I went over instructions
in the dressing room.
Do you have any questions?
Fight hard. Fight clean. Fight fair.
Okay, touch gloves.
To your corners.
Okay, here we go.
Judge. Judge. Judge.
Are you ready?
Are you ready? Fight!
Terry and Garcia on deck.
Terry and Garcia.
Terry and Garcia, next up.
Stop, stop, stop!
Stay down. Stay down. Stay down.
Winner.
By submission, at one minute-five
of the first round...
...Felix Romero.
Our next bout in 15 minutes
will feature...
...Mike Terry and "Toro" Garcia.
Okay.
This fight is sanctioned by
and will be conducted...
...under the rules
of the California State Commission.
While they're in the ring...
...they'll be under discretion
of the referee.
Any judgment rendered by the judge
is final...
...pending the outcome
of a drug test.
Let's see the gloves.
Your acknowledgement
of the physician's statement...
...is a legal document signifying
your acceptance of the rules...
Terry and Garcia.
Let's see the blue card. All right.
Let's go.
Let's go. We got some people
waiting out there.
Let's go. Come on.
From Los Angeles, California,
a well-known figure...
...in the martial-arts world,
a champion at close combat...
...making his first appearance
in competition...
...at 179 pounds...
...Mike Terry.
Excuse me. You can't smoke here.
Well, I don't know about you,
but I love it.
And I think boxing is as dead
as Woodrow Wilson.
What a fight.
Yeah, I've got eyes on the fighters.
They're walking.
Okay, handlers, keep a hand
on your boy, keep your eyes on me.
You know the drill. We've been
through this before. Let's go.
We'll be under here
for about 15 minutes...
...then the man will come through
to take you to the ring.
When you get to the ring,
listen to the ref.
Sorry.
I'm handing them off. I'm coming up
now under the bleachers.
The undercard. What did we just see
in the first eνent, Dylan?
Here's what we saw.
Here's what the IFA has done...
Eyes on the prize, Mike.
Eyes on the prize.
This is your road game.
There's Terry, an unknown.
Hey, you saw the fight.
What do you think
of this new competition?
One guy has a handicap. How would
that effect you as a fighter?
After the fight, after the fight.
Leave my guy alone.
They're coming down
the stairs, right?
Goddamn shame, Mike.
Goddamn shame about Joey.
He thought the world of you, Mike.
Ladies and gentlemen, we have a very
special guest with us tonight.
From Sao Paulo, Brazil...
...the Redbelt himself...
...the Professor,
Grandmaster Joao Moro.
You. You, the fighter.
Back up. Back up.
Back it up. Take it all the way.
Let's move it. Back up.
It's fixed? The fight is fixed?
Of course it's fixed.
What the fuck do you think?
Hey, how you doing?
What do you want?
You brought the old man up
from Brazil for this bullshit?
You run your business, I run mine.
Who I brought to where
is of no concern to you.
- His life. His teachings.
- What do you know of his teachings?
What the hell do you know
of his teachings?
This is my family business,
and it is a business, okay?
What the hell did you think it is?
There's television out there.
It's about to be big business,
and no one has forgotten you.
So cool down and sit down.
None of the fighters know
the fight's gaffed.
You weren't supposed to know.
- I don't get it.
- We pick who gets the white marble.
Here's what you're missing.
Here's what you inνented. The thing?
It's not a way to ensure
the fight is fair.
Any two guys fighting for money,
no way the fight is fair.
What you did is a way to fix the fight
without the fighter's knowledge.
You stole my idea.
How about that? So look, what?
Who gets the pass tonight? You.
Every fight tonight, the other guy
gets the handicap. You win.
You go home with the 50 grand.
You settle your various debts.
How about that?
Make a name for yourself.
I love a fighter. What the fuck?
All right, alI right,
Ricardo's gotta rest.
- Hold on.
- Are we done?
- And.
- Aren't we done?
And you come back in three months
for the rematch.
Ricardo fights Morisaki
to retake the crown.
You're throwing the fight tonight?
Everything in life,
the money's in the rematch.
You told him he wins tonight?
You'd throw the fight
in front of the Professor?
The Professor an old man.
He no longer has family to support.
Terry? Terry?
Fifteen minute warning on deck.
Fifteen minute warning.
The cop died.
Everybody dies.
You wanna help his widow?
What about the stolen watch?
My friend, he shot himself because
someone gave me a hot watch.
Fellow sold me a watch.
I got a deal on a watch.
How do I know where it came from?
I gave it to you.
Is he fighting or you wanna call it?
What kind of motherfucker pawns
a watch he got from Chet Frank?
How'd you know
how the window broke?
That ain't important.
- We were the only ones there.
- Leave it.
A guy killed himself
because a window broke.
How'd you know?
Your wife sold you out.
Well, who did you think
you married?
Brazilian princess
married the soldier.
Five years
and the soldier's pumping gas.
A smart girl's gonna move on.
Your fight or I'm calling the fight
and you're out.
Either way, Mike. Either way,
sometimes you gotta do business.
Pack it up. We're going home.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...on the undercard,
there's a substitution.
Our next fight, a substitution.
Juan "Toro" Garcia...
...and fighting
in place of Mike Terry...
...Steve "Moose" Malloran.
Steve "Moose" Malloran
will fight Juan "Toro" Garcia.
But jujitsu can,
if all else goes wrong...
...give you the ability
to turn the fight around.
And turn the fight around is exactly
what we saw here tonight.
Teacher breaks up boys
fighting in the schoolyard.
Asks one boy, "You like to
fight?" He says, "No. I like to win. "
Well, after all, Dylan,
isn't that what it's all about?
And that's why we're here
at the IFA tonight.
- We out?
- Thanks.
- Want me to take the mike, Dylan?
- I'Il see you at ringside in five minutes.
Mr. Flynn!
- Hey, hold on!
- Mr. Flynn!
Mr. Flynn!
Hey! Stop him! Stop him!
Mr. Flynn, I need to talk to you!
- Mr. Flynn!
- Mike, Mike.
- I need to talk to you!
- Stop him!
WilI somebody stop him?
Mr. Flynn,
I need to tell you something.
Somebody stop him.
What's wrong with you, huh?
You wanna fight?
Why don't you go to the ring?
Just a moment.
- Mike, you hear me?
- I'm going to rip it open.
Oh, you're gonna fucking rip it open?
All right, great.
You think you're going to the ring?
Yeah? You're going nowhere.
You're going nowhere. You see?
You're going nowhere.
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
That's right. That's right.
I'm ending this charade.
I'm going to the ring.
You're going to the ring to do what?
To do what? To ruin my business?
- That's right.
- I'd prefer you didn't do that.
I understand that.
You know? My sister's not wrong.
You are wrong.
You know what you are?
You're addicted to poverty.
I'm going to the ring.
I'm talking to you.
Okay.
You wanna play?
Okay. Let's do this thing.
Let's play the game.
a relatively new sport.
It's only been here in this country
for 14 years...
...a little longer than that in Brazil
and Japan, but still relatively-
After alI, that's what this is about.
The old meets the new.
I'm excited about the undercard
here tonight. For these competitors...
Tommy. Tommy, check this out.
You've gotta see this.
- That's Terry.
- That's Mike.