Better hurry.
Here you go, my friend.
Make sure you get us as close as you can!
I'll give you something extra,
if you make it a good trip.
Hey, I'm going to get you close, my friend.
But not too close, eh?
You don't want to be eaten.
You ready, amigo?
- Ready!
One, two, three!
Eric, heave!
You scared?
Uh-uh. This is great.
See anything yet?
No, not yet.
- What was that?
- I don't know.
- Hold on!
- What's happening?
Just hold on!
Make it stop!
What happened to them?
I don't know.
Oh, my God!
- We're gonna crash!
- All right, all right. No, we're not.
- I'm gonna cut us loose.
- We're gonna crash!
I'm gonna take this loose!
- Let go of the rope. Let go of the rope!
- We're gonna crash!
Move your hands!
Come on!
Here we go!
It's gonna be okay, bud.
Actually, Charlie, those are herbivores.
They really wouldn't be interested
in fighting with each other.
But these ones here are carnivores,
and they really like fighting with each other.
They use their teeth and their claws
to rip each other's throats out.
Alan, he's 3. Let's wait till he's 5.
Oh! Right. Sorry, Charlie.
- Ellie?
- Yeah?
It's Tom again. He says he has to
talk to you about the last chapter.
Just tell him I'm not gonna lose
the Jack Horner quote.
My editor thinks he's a paleontologist.
Hey, Mark!
Hey, babe, look who's here!
This is Alan.
Nice to meet you, Alan.
- I heard a lot about you.
- Daddy, daddy...
This is a herbivore
and that's the dinosaur man.
Dinosaur man?
Jack, say my name. Is my name Alan?
Is my name Alan?
He used to know me.
- It's sad, huh?
- Here you go.
Thanks. So, you know, Mark's been
working for the State Department now.
Yeah, what do you do, Mark?
It's international relations,
mostly treaty law, things like that.
Uh-oh!
- Call of the wild one.
- Oh, here. I'll go.
You guys... catch up.
Thanks, babe.
He's a great guy.
So, what are you working on now?
Raptors, mostly.
My favorite.
Do you remember the sounds they made?
I try not to.
Ellie, all our theories
about raptor intelligence,
what they were capable of,
we weren't even close.
Tell me.
Well, we did cranial scans of a fossil skull
and we found what looks like a very
sophisticated resonating chamber.
Wait a second. So, we were right.
I mean, they had the ability to vocalize.
I'm convinced it's the key
to their social intelligence.
Which explains why they could
work together as a team.
They'd coordinate attacks, so their prey
wouldn't know what was going on.
They could talk to each other.
To a degree we never imagined.
Ellie, they were smart.
They were smarter than dolphins or whales.
They were smarter than primates.
I just wanted to say,
if you ever need help with anything,
sometimes you forget to ask.
So, you can call me. Anything, anytime.
Sure.
You're still the best.
I mean that.
The last of my breed.
It is through the painstaking study
of the anterior chamber
in multiple specimens that we can
determine the exciting correlation
between the upper palate and the larynx.
This lets us theorize, theorize, mind you,
that the raptor was capable of
sophisticated vocalizations,
which would have been
a tremendous evolutionary advantage.
Raptors were fierce, intelligent
and socially sophisticated.
They were able to hunt in numbers
and coordinate their efforts.
Were it not for the cataclysmic
events, which overtook them,
it is entirely possible that raptors,
rather than humans,
would have become the dominant
species on this planet.
I hope this has been of interest.
It certainly excites us as paleontologists.
There is much, much more to discover.
That is why we continue to need,
and ask for your support.
Thank you.
Thank you very much, Dr. Grant.
Now, does anyone have a question?
Fine.
Does anyone have a question that
does not relate to Jurassic Park?
Or the incident in San Diego,
which I did not witness?
Yes, sir?
Your theory on raptors is good and all,
but isn't all this conjecture kind of moot?
I mean, once the U.N. and Costa Rica and every-
one decides how to handle that second island,
scientists will just go in
and look for themselves.
Dinosaurs lived 65 million years ago.
What is left of them is fossilized in the rocks.
And it is in the rock that
real scientists make real discoveries.
Now, what John Hammond
and InGen did at Jurassic Park
is create genetically engineered
theme-park monsters.
Nothing more and nothing less.
Are you saying that you wouldn't
want to get onto Isla Sorna
and study them, if you had the chance?
No force on Earth or Heaven
could get me on that island.
So, what've we got here, Nashy?
Einhorn 20-millimeter,
gas-operated semi-automatic.
10-shot, magazine fed, rotating bolt,
recoil-reducing muzzle brake.
High explosive incendiary...
Udesky.
Mr. Udesky, it's Paul Kirby. Just checking...
Ah, yes, sir! We're good to go here.
Matter of fact, I can lock things down
just as soon as you drop me that payment.
Well, that's right, two of the very
best men I could possibly find.
No, sir, I haven't worked
with them personally,
but believe me, sir, both of these men
come very highly recommended.
Are you all right?
Nothing to worry about, sir.
It's gonna be a walk in the park.
Billy, I don't think I'm doing this right.
Let's try the toothbrush.
You've got to go slowly.
Just take a little bit at a time.
I can never tell what's rock and what's bone.
Technically, it's all rock.
The calcium in the bones
is replaced during fossilization.
But you can feel the difference, see?
Rough.
Smooth.
Rough, smooth.
Dr. Grant.
Mr. Brennan.
So, how did it go?
Well, it's not too late
to change your major, Billy.
- That good, huh?
- Worse.
- We're gonna have to pack up in four weeks.
- Three.
I had to rent some equipment.
Come here. I got to show you something.
You like computers, right?
I like the abacus, Billy.
Meet the future of paleontology.
It's a rapid prototyper.
I enter in the scanned data
from the raptor skull.
The computer breaks it down
into thousands of slices.
And this thing sculpts it,
one layer at a time.
It's done.
I give you the resonating chamber
of a Velociraptor.
Listen to this.
Wow!
This is brilliant, Billy. Really, it is.
Sad to say, it's just a little bit late.
Dr. Grant? Paul Kirby, Kirby Enterprises.
My card. How're you doing, Billy?
What can I do for you, Mr. Kirby?
Well...
First thing, I'm a great admirer of yours.
And I have a proposition
I'd like to discuss with you.
Would you have dinner
with my wife and me this evening?
It'll be our treat.
That'd be great,
but I'm tired. I've been traveling.
Maybe some other time.
Believe me, this will be worth your while.
We'd love to.
Oh, terrific! That's the spirit. Good.
This evening then.
- Ah, Billy, thank you for coming.
- How are you?
- Dr. Grant, how are you?
- Mr. Kirby.
- Amanda, this is Billy and Dr. Grant.
- Mrs. Kirby, how are you?
So, what are you boys drinking?
- Ice Pick, Catfish.
- Two, please, Cat.
Well, we've admired your work for years.
Really. Truly inspiring.
Amanda and I just love the outdoors.
Heck, we've been on just about every
adventure tour they can come up with.
The Nile, Galapagos, K2.
We even have two seats reserved on
the first commercial flight to the moon.
And for our wedding anniversary this year,
we wanted to do something really special.
- Something...
- Once in a lifetime.
So, I've chartered an airplane
to fly us over Isla Sorna.
And we'd like you to be our guide.
There you go, guys.
That's a very kind offer, Mr. Kirby,
but I'm a very, very busy man.
I can recommend a couple of guys
who are really highly qualified...
No, no, no. You're the best.
You've seen these animals in the flesh.
There's no one who even comes close to you.
You wouldn't be able to fly low enough
to see anything of any real interest.
Well, see, that's the interesting part,
because we have permission to fly low.
How low?
Well, I'm no aviation expert, but a heck of
a lot lower than anybody else I can tell you.
From what I understand,
it's pretty much whatever we want.
That's hard to believe.
Well, you see, through my business dealings,
import-export, emerging markets,
I've made a lot of friends in high places.
In this case, the Costa Rican government.
Dr. Grant, you have no idea
how important it is to us
that you come along.
It would make all the difference.
Mrs. Kirby, I...
And, of course, we'd love to make
a contribution to your research here.
So...
I could write all kinds of numbers
on this check, Dr. Grant.
Tell me.
What's it gonna take?
Even with what I pay you,
couldn't you afford a better bag?
No way.
This one's lucky.
Couple of years ago,
some buddies and I went hang gliding
off these cliffs in New Zealand.
And this big updraft came and
swept me right against the side.
Wham!
Wow, that does sound lucky.
It was this strap alone that saved my life.
Got hooked on a rock as I was falling.
Reverse Darwinism.
Survival of the most idiotic.
Alan, I want to thank you
for bringing me along.
Yeah, well, the bones will still
be there when we get back.
That's the great thing about bones.
They never run away.
And truth is, you got me into this.
And I have no intention of being
on my own with these people.
Don't get too excited, Billy.
Chances are, we won't see a thing.
Your turn to be nice.
Wake me when we get there.
So, how do you know the Kirbys?
Through our church.
Alan!
Wake up. We're almost there.
Unidentified aircraft approaching Isla
Sorna, this is San Juan Approach.
You're flying in restricted airspace.
Immediately turn to coordinates 2...
My God, I'd forgotten.
We did it, honey. We're here.
Cooper, if you see anything, yell up!
No, I thought I'd keep it to myself.
I'm sorry. Look, everyone,
if you look out the left of the plane,
you can see a whole herd of Brachiosaurus.
In fact, you can see in the front of
the group the alpha male grazing there.
Udesky, Nash? How about up front?
You guys see anything?
Nothing yet, Mr. Kirby.
Mrs. Kirby, look, out here,
you'll see a group of Triceratops.
Mr. Kirby, we have a landing strip up ahead.
You want me to put her down?
No, no! I told you, I want to
circle first, see the whole island.
What do you mean set her down?
You can't land here!
- What are you talking about?
- Hold on, hold on. I can explain...
You cannot land on this island!
- It's gonna be fine, Dr. Grant.
- Don't worry, please, Dr. Grant.
- Are you crazy?
- Sit down!
Dr. Grant, will you please sit down?
Billy, tell me we didn't land.
Eric!
Ben!
I think they're looking for someone.
Eric!
Ben!
Dr. Grant, are you all right?
- I'm sorry we had to...
- Who hit me?
- I'm sorry we had to be so rough.
That would be Cooper.
What are they doing?
They're setting up a perimeter
to make the place safe.
- These guys are good.
- Mr. Kirby, trust me.
On this island, there's no such thing as safe!
We have to get back on that plane!
Will you tell your wife to stop
making that noise!
That is a very, very bad idea!
- Amanda!
- Ben!
Amanda, honey, Dr. Grant
said that's a bad idea.
What?
He says it's a bad idea!
What's a bad idea?
What was that?
That's a Tyrannosaurus.
I don't think so.
It sounds bigger.
We have to leave!
We have to leave now!
- Get on the plane now!
- What's going on?
- Get on the plane!
What about the other guy?
Cooper's a professional.
He can handle himself.
Get on the plane! Hurry!
It's all right.
- Paul, we can't...
- It's all right. It's all right.
We'll just circle the island.
Give me a hand here, Udesky!
- Stop!
- What are you doing?
That's Cooper!
Stop.
Come on, get out of the way!
You know I can't stop this plane.
Oh, my God!
- Fuel cut-off!
- We're going down!
You okay?
We're okay up here.
Everyone, just stay put.
San Juan Approach. Mayday, mayday!
Who has the satellite phone?
I do. I got it right here.
I'm not getting anything. The radio's gone.
We haven't landed yet.
- All circuits are busy.
- Damn it!
Oh, man!
What was that?
Keep still! Keep still!
Relax. What is it? What?
- What is it?
- Hold it! Hold it!
Hang on, everyone!
Help me!
Mrs. Kirby, come back!
No!
Amanda!
Follow me! This way!
In here!
I think we lost him.
It's okay, it's dead.
Nobody move a muscle.
No, no, no, no! Please, please, don't!
Stop, please.
It's time you did some explaining, Mr. Kirby.
We called everyone.
We did everything we could.
No one would help us.
The Costa Rican government
said this is a no-fly zone.
The U.S. Embassy,
that's our U.S. Embassy,
told us we should accept the inevitable.
Can you believe that?!
You let a 12-year-old go parasailing alone?
- No!
He wasn't alone. He was with a friend.
Ben Hildebrand.
Paul and I divorced over a year ago.
All right, so, why me?
He said we needed someone
who'd been on the island before.
Yes, but I did not tell you
to kidnap somebody.
I have never been on this island.
Sure you have. You wrote that book.
That was Isla Nublar.
This is Isla Sorna, Site B.
You mean there are two islands
with dinosaurs on them?
- All right, you stay out of this.
- You know what? Please!
So, how long have they been missing?
8 weeks.
Almost 8 weeks now.
Billy, we go back to the plane,
salvage what we can.
Then we make for the coast.
Dr. Grant, we're not leaving
this island without our son.
Then you can go and look for him.
Or you can stick with us,
as long as you don't hold us up.
Either way,
you probably won't get off this island alive.
So, what do we do?
We search for your son.
In the direction that they're going.
Excellent, excellent.
Oh, sorry, sorry.
That is nothing you haven't seen before, Paul.
How much weight did you say you lost?
About 25 pounds. I've been swimming.
Swimming? You hate to swim.
You don't even know how to swim.
I know. I learned.
You look good.
So do you.
How would you classify it, Billy?
Well...
It's a super-predator.
A Suchomimus.
- That snout.
- No, think bigger.
- Baryonyx?
- Not with that sail.
Spinosaurus aegypticus.
I don't remember that on InGen's list.
Because it wasn't on their list.
And that makes you wonder
what else they were up to.
So, Mr. Kirby, tell me.
When you climbed K2, did you base
camp at 25,000 or 30,000 feet?
30,000 feet. We were pretty close to the top.
You were about 1,000 feet above it, actually.
No, no, that's a common mistake.
Now, Mr. Kirby, there's no such thing
as Kirby Enterprises, is there?
It's Kirby Paint and Tile Plus.
The "Plus" stands for bathroom fixtures.
We're in the Westgate Shopping Center,
Enid, Oklahoma.
So, I don't suppose that check
you wrote us is any good.
Now, listen to me, I will pay you
the money I owe you.
- This is good.
- No matter what.
Here we are, in the worst place
in the world, and we're not being paid!
All right. Now, wait, fellas. Hold on!
I'll make this up to you.
If you ever do a bathroom or a kitchen...
You're not really a mercenary, are you?
I never said I was.
That's true. What are you?
Well, I'm like a booking agent.
One of the guys got sick and couldn't come.
Excuse me. Here.
- So, you run a hardware store?
- Paint and tile, yeah.
You never can tell about people, can you?
Ain't that the truth?
- Eric!
- Quiet.
Would you stop that?
Dr. Grant says this is
very dangerous territory.
Look, maybe we should
split up or something.
You know, we could cover twice
as much ground that way.
Dr. Grant says that's a bad idea.
Dr. Grant! Dr. Grant says...
Well, what's the good of hiring an expert,
if we're not gonna use his advice?
Yeah, except Dr. Grant isn't looking for Eric.
He's looking for the coast.
Okay, fine. Go ahead and scream.
And when that "Tricycloplots" attacks you,
don't come crying to me.
- Don't worry about that.
- What?
- Nothing.
- What did you say?
- Never mind.
God, Paul, just drop it!
If we split up, I'm going with you guys.
- Eric!
- Mrs. Kirby!
Mrs. Kirby, the chances are remote
they're still in the vicinity.
Young adult.
Hey, guys!
That's my camera.
The battery's dead.
I've got an idea.
Let me have the camera.
Where were you on that one, Ma?
Okay, dive, dive, dive.
Come on, Ma.
Eric!
Ma, you were supposed to catch it!
I shot this the morning they disappeared.
Hey, no, no, no, I want that.
Hey, let me take that. Let me take that.
Hey, come on, give me that.
Come on, baby.
- See anything yet?
- No, not yet!
What was that?
Unclip us. There's a clip! There's a big clip!
I can't see! I can't do it!
Look, I'm gonna unhook you, all right?
One, two, three!
Are you okay, buddy?
Okay, I'm gonna drop myself down now.
The camera's still on.
He's alive. I know he's alive.
We're gonna find him.
Can you fly one of those?
Maybe.
As long as the sail is not torn.
Well, let's take it.
If we spot a plane, it might be
a good way to get attention.
Pull it over this way.
- I got it, I got it, hold on!
- Get it off of me!
- Okay, okay.
- Oh, my God!
Mrs. Kirby, please. Mrs. Kirby!
Okay, okay, you're free, you're free.
Get her back, Mr. Kirby.
Amanda!
Wait!
Amanda, stop, stop, stop.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry about Ben.
It's not Ben, Paul.
It's Eric. He's out there all by himself.
I know, I know.
Our baby is out here all by himself.
Listen to me. We'll find him.
I promise.
Paul.
Dr. Grant!
You should come look at this!
Raptor.
We're gonna find him.
Are you listening to me?
Kid's got resources.
Remember what it was like
to try to ground him?
Where's Billy?
What are you doing?
I was photographing the nest.
Don't do that again.
I'm sorry.
If I lose you, it's just me
and the damn tourists.
I bet you Eric's in there.
Don't you think? I'd bet my bottom dollar!
What do you think it is?
As far as I'm concerned,
it's the Four Seasons.
Eric!
Paul! Don't!
What the hell.
Who's got some change?
It only takes quarters.
I've got a buck-10.
This is how you make dinosaurs?
No.
This is how you play God.
This way! This way!
It's locked!
- This way, this way, this way!
- Go, go, go!
Hey, over here!
Push, push!
My God!
He's calling for help!
Come on!
Into the herd!
Head for the trees!
Udesky.
Mr. Kirby!
Billy!
Is Alan with you?
Oh, my God!
Mr. Udesky!
He's dead.
Oh, my God! No, he's not!
No, no, no, wait, wait.
Something's not right.
We've got to help him.
Amanda!
Hold on!
They set a trap.
They actually set a trap.
What are you saying?
What are you looking for?
Wait!
Thanks.
Thanks a lot, Eric.
- You know who I am?
- Yeah.
Your parents are here.
They're looking for you.
Together?
Together.
That's not good.
They don't do so well together.
You'd be surprised what people
can do when they have to.
You're Alan Grant.
What are you doing here?
Your parents...
invited me along.
I read both of your books.
I liked the first one more.
Before you were on the island.
You liked dinosaurs back then.
Back then, they hadn't tried to eat me yet.
When InGen cleared out,
they left a lot of stuff behind.
Any weapons?
No, and I just used
the last of the gas grenades.
And I appreciate that.
Be careful with that. T-Rex.
It scares some of the smaller ones away,
but it attracts one really big one with a fin.
This is T-Rex pee?
How did you get it?
You don't wanna know.
- Dessert?
- Sure.
Eric, I have to tell you,
I'm astonished that you've lasted
8 weeks on this island.
Is that all it's been?
Well, you're alive,
and that's the important thing.
Thanks to you, that's one thing
that we have in common.
Did you read Malcolm's book?
Yeah.
So?
I don't know. I mean...
It was kind of preachy.
And too much chaos. Everything is chaos.
Seemed like the guy was
kind of high on himself.
That's two things that we have in common.
Listen.
Compys!
Alan!
No matter how this turns out,
it wasn't your fault.
Eric's always been a strong-willed kid.
Always.
Then you throw someone like
Ben Hildebrand into the mix...
Well...
Well, what?
All I'm saying is, it's not your fault.
No.
If he'd been with you,
he'd be completely safe.
You drive 5 miles under the speed limit, Paul.
And I've totaled three cars in three years.
Well, not three.
The Buick wasn't really totaled.
I just said it was,
'cause I wanted to get the S.U.V.
I am so sorry that you have to be here.
I'm not.
Yeah, there is a boat.
Right alongside the bank.
Looks in good shape.
Rescue boat?
No, no.
Just something left behind.
But it floats.
We stick to the plan.
Head for the coast.
You're not gonna look for Dr. Grant?
The coast was Alan's idea.
If he's alive, that's where he's headed.
I agree.
What about Eric?
Eric's a smart kid.
He probably knows he stands
his best chance by the coast.
He figures all the big dinosaurs
are in the center of the island.
Right?
Sure.
You know what this is?
That's a raptor claw. I used to have one.
A fossil.
Mine is new.
How much of the island did you explore?
I stayed pretty close to the compound.
I figured if anyone came looking for me,
that's where they'd start.
We need to get to the coast.
That was the plan.
Are you sure?
The closer you get to the water,
the bigger things get.
Well, if we can find our way
down into the canyon,
we can follow that river out to the coast.
After we find your parents.
And then what?
- One step at a time.
- Listen.
What?
That's my dad's satellite phone!
Wait a minute. How do you know?
"Kirby Paint and Tile Plus, in Westgate!"
Dad!
Mum!
Mum! Dad!
- Eric!
Eric, this way!
Eric! Eric!
Mum! Dad!
Eric!
Mum!
Mum, Dad!
I knew it. My God!
I knew it.
Oh, God! Oh, my God!
Boy, am I glad to see you.
Hey, you got my bag.
Yeah. Lucky strap.
Want me to carry it?
We need to find a gap here.
How did you know we were here?
The phone. That stupid jingle
from the store. I heard it.
- My phone?
- Yeah, your satellite phone.
- Where is it?
- I don't have it.
When did you use it last?
On the plane.
I got a call on the plane and...
- What? What?
- I loaned it to Nash.
He must have had it when he...
Run.
Alan, you want to give me the bag back?
It's okay, Billy, I got it.
Please, give me the bag.
It's not safe.
Raptor eggs.
Did you steal raptor eggs?
Now it all makes sense.
I swear, if I'd known that
you were gonna end up with them...
I took them on an impulse.
I thought they'd be worth a fortune.
Enough to fund the dig site
another 10 more years.
Look, you have to believe me.
This was a stupid decision,
but I did it with the best intentions.
"With the best intentions."
Some of the worst things imaginable
have been done with the best intentions.
You know what, Billy?
As far as I'm concerned,
you're no better than the people
that built this place.
What are you doing?
Those things are after us because of those.
Those things know we have the eggs.
If I drop them in the river,
they'll still be after us.
What if they catch us with them?
What if they catch us without them?
There's a boat at the bottom, just downriver.
We can try and make it to the coast at least.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Let's do this one at a time, shall we?
Okay, come on over!
One at a time!
All right, Eric.
I'm gonna leave you just for a minute, okay?
And then you're gonna be
right behind me, okay?
Mum!
I've been alone in a water truck for 8 weeks.
I think I can manage
the next two minutes without you.
Right, we're all together now.
Okay, Eric.
- Okay.
- Come on, honey!
Over you go.
Mum?
Oh, my God!
What is it?
It's a birdcage.
For what?
Dad!
Eric!
- Eric!
- Help me!
Eric!
I can't see him!
No!
This way!
Billy!
Billy, stop!
Billy, stop! Don't, Billy!
Billy!
Eric, hold on!
Eric!
Jump!
Billy!
Let go now!
- Eric!
- He's there.
Eric!
There he is! He's across the river!
Get him out of here!
- No!
- Go, go, Eric!
What about Billy?
Hang on, Billy!
Get away!
There's plenty of gasoline.
Now we've just got to
make our way to the coast.
Work out some sort of a signal.
Build a fire or something.
Something they can see from the air.
Dr. Grant?
Hey, Eric, how're you doing?
I'm sorry about Billy.
You know what the last thing
I said to him was?
I said...
"You're as bad as the people
that built this place."
Which wasn't true.
Billy was just young. That's all.
I have a theory that there are
two kinds of boys.
There are those who want to be astronomers
and those who want to be astronauts.
The astronomer or the paleontologist
gets to study these amazing things
from a place of complete safety.
But then you never get to go into space.
Exactly.
It's the difference between
imagining and seeing.
To be able to touch them.
And that's... all Billy wanted.
Dr. Grant.
You know something, Dr. Grant?
Billy was right.
Listen.
Find it before it stops ringing!
Eric, you stay on that boat.
It's here. Whoa, whoa, whoa! It's here.
God!
I got it.
Hello? Hello?
You, too, can own a timeshare
in beautiful Guadalajara.
Enjoy a meal in one of
our four-star restaurants.
Look out!
Turn off the power.
You've got juice for maybe one call.
Whatever you do,
don't call the U.S. Embassy.
They won't do a damn thing.
Hey, guys, come here! Look at this!
Bonitos.
Something must have spooked them.
Get the engine going, Mr. Kirby.
Open the throttle.
Pick up. Pick up.
Hello?
Ellie?
Charlie!
- Charlie!
- Hello?
Charlie, take the phone to Mummy now!
Take the phone to Mummy!
It's the dinosaur man!
Okay.
Listen to me, Charlie.
Charlie!
Are you taking the phone to Mum?
Hi, everybody!
It's great to be here!
Hi, there! Hi! How are you today?
This is gonna be great!
- Who's on the phone?
- The dinosaur man.
He is? Alan?
Look in the boxes! Look in the boxes!
Find a weapon!
Where's the phone?
- There! There!
- Get the phone!
Ellie, Ellie, listen to me!
Alan, are you on a cell phone?
I can't hear you.
The river! Site B! The river!
Hello?
Hey!
Dad!
Paul, you jerk!
You can't leave me like this!
I'm not going anywhere!
Remember when we went fishing
a couple of summers ago?
I was putting the boat in the water
and the trailer sank?
The tow truck tried to pull us out
and it got dragged in, too.
The truck driver wanted
to knock my lights out.
I miss fishing.
Mr. Kirby?
That lady you called. Who is she?
How do you know that she can help us?
She was the one person
I could always count on.
I owe her a lot.
I don't think I ever told her that.
You should.
You hear that?
The ocean.
They want the eggs.
Otherwise, we'd be dead already.
Everybody get down.
She's challenging us.
She thinks you stole the eggs.
Get behind me.
Give me the eggs.
Do it, Mum.
No. No, no, no. Call for help.
That's a helicopter.
Dr. Grant? Dr. Alan Grant?
- No!
- Stop!
- That's a very bad idea!
Second squad, move!
Wow!
You have to thank her now.
She sent the Navy and the Marines.
God bless you, Ellie.
- Dr. Grant?
- Yeah?
- Is this man with you?
- What?
Hey, you made it.
Yeah.
I rescued your hat.
Dr. Grant, we need to go now.
Oh, yeah.
Well, that's the important thing.
Dr. Grant!
Can I get you to sit here and buckle up, sir?
Sea Shadow to Dust Storm,
be advised, six souls on board.
Dust Storm to Sea Shadow, roger.
What the hell is that?
Dr. Grant, look!
Where do you think they're going?
I don't know. Maybe just looking
for new nesting grounds.
It's a whole new world for them.
I dare them to nest in Enid, Oklahoma.
Let's go home.