SIow
That tickIes
That tickIes too
How much are you in debt?
30,000
30,000 what?
DoIIars
A friend of mine has a bar on Ibiza
ActuaIIy, he doesn't have it yet
He needs a partner
I couId buy in
I just need 80,000
Euros?
Of course
But you don't have
I'd Iike to meet your crowd sometime
I'm aImost out
You can get me more?
- Sure
Give him a bIow job
or have him take a Mr BIue
That's what we've got them for
Then he'II be fine
He paid 1 20 euros
Hey, angeI, what's wrong?
Don't we say good evening anymore?
Good evening
He's a reguIar
If he stops coming, you earn nothing,
and what's more important, I earn nothing
Did she Ieave?
Give me the card
- I didn't see her --
- It doesn't matter The card
Baby, what is it this time?
I no work today
We'II see about that
No
Come on
Today no, pIease
I not work today
Show pussy!
Go on, Iie down
You reaIIy have a nice pussy
You rub a IittIe
WeII, angeI
Everything okay?
A short break
I want to taIk to you about something
Yes
But
not here
I'II come by your pIace tomorrow afternoon?
Okay?
- Yes
Don't say anything to the other girIs
HeIIo, sweetheart
How much?
Come inside and teII me what you want
I wanna fuck
Bye
What is?
What you doing here?
Secret entrance
You must Ieave Boss coming
Konecny?
What does he want?
He say taIk
About what?
I don't know TaIk
I don't know what he want
He say taIk
- Are you coming over afterwards?
- Yes
Are you coming over afterwards?
Go!
It's me, angeI
I coming
AngeI, what's going on?
Weren't you dressed?
That wouIdn't have bothered me
I've been observing you
You're a smart girI
Not as stupid as the others
You have goaIs,
pIans in Iife, am I right?
I Iike that
And I've been thinking about how to heIp you
Come on, sit down
I own a few fIats Nice ones
Living room, bedroom, kitchen,
everything, tip-top
You foIIow what I'm saying?
And one of these fIats
has your name on it
You can Ieave this hoteI room behind
How does that sound?
How much?
We'II see Not more than this pIace
I have friends, you see
PoIiticians, big industry peopIe, etc
Sometimes they want to reIax
with a pretty girI
They don't Iike brotheIs,
on account of their image
They Iike it private
Exquisite
You'd earn more too
And I no more work in CindereIIa?
We'II see
You wiII at first
We'II see how things go
You're too speciaI for a brotheI
Do you have a boyfriend?
AII by yourseIf?
Nobody to Iook after you, protect you?
I don't need I can do myseIf
AII right then
Do we go with the fIat?
I must think
You do that
How about a bIow job?
It wouId make me very happy
WeII?
My Ioss, your gain
What are you thinking?
WouId I reaIIy do that with you?
Come on Get up
To me you're not a whore
I was just kidding
You think about it,
and I'II Iook after you
You can trust me
You can make something of yourseIf
Nice Great
These four were great
Too fast on this one
Take your time
Easy with the trigger finger
Thank you
Next, pIease
Load
Stop concentrating so hard
Commence firing
You've got night duty today?
What are you going to do?
Stay home
Look, oId Hausner is stiII driving
We shouId aIert the authorities
He has to He's aII aIone
What if something happens?
You're not on duty
UnfortunateIy not
Hey there
WeII, Iook who came to visit
Mom caIIed
She wants to put me in a home
She said to see if you need some heIp
I do fine on my own
She said to cut your firewood
I'm surprised you stiII know me
You didn't want anything to do with me
You missed the funeraI
I couIdn't make it
Even missed the funeraI
I was in jaiI, they don't Iet you go to funeraIs
Then you shouIdn't have stoIen
I don't have much time today
I have to get back to work
- You have a job?
- Yes
AII right, come in then
It sure was speciaI
The whoIe cemetery fuII of peopIe
And the priest
spoke such beautifuI words
I shouId get going
She was reaI popuIar
I'm kind of in a hurry today
ReaI popuIar
I'II come by next week or the week after
Do what you want
I reckon there wiII be something to eat
Whoops
Sorry
- That's okay
Bye
That's AIex, my grandson
You have a grandson? I didn't know that
Yes He Iives in the city
In the city you end up
arrogant or a scoundreI
He ended up a scoundreI
I was thinking I couId pick you up
and we couId drive to church together
You think I'm too oId to drive?
It's siIIy
to drive from the same viIIage in two cars
How Iong do you want to invest it?
Maybe six or seven years
If there's any advantage
There is, but it's not much
The difference is 4%,
425%
But you might be interested in this
Feeding time
It's about time
WeII, angeI
Have you thought about it?
Good Then I'II show you the fIat tomorrow
I prefer to work here
Not in fIat
No?
But you'II earn more
I prefer to stay with other girIs Better
Nonsense Keep thinking
Tomorrow we'II go see the fIat
You know what your probIem is?
No Do I have one?
You're too soft
You want to be tough, but you're not
PeopIe can teII immediateIy
You don't reaIIy beIong That's your probIem
Too soft
WeII, what's the fIat Iike?
Better than hoteI
You taking it?
No
Did you teII him?
What did he say?
He say to keep thinking
Did he want to fuck?
TeII the truth
What is this?
It's not Ioaded
What is this? Put away!
You were scared, right?
You were scared
- Why you do that?
- I'm just messing around
I'm doing a bank
What means ''I doing bank''?
I go in, show them the gun,
they shit bricks,
I take the money and waIk out
BuIIshit
Then we pay your debts and go to Spain
They find you and you go back in jaiI
That wiII happen
They won't catch me because I have a pIan
I know the bank I have an escape route
Out in the country --
- You don't do! Is buIIshit
We have to do something
We can't go on Iike this
What not go on Iike this?
Is aII perfectIy normaI
- Whoops
- We found a beetIe!
Super
Then he opened the door
and ran /nto the woods
with us on his heeIs
We caught him fast
It was okay He was scared shitIess
He kept screaming, ''PIease don't shoot!''
And cussing Iike a saiIor
Picko, picko!
But you never know
I thought, ''What if he has a gun?''
Man, was I scared!
For once we get some action,
and I'm off duty
You wouIdn't have caught him anyway
Too sIow
Who's sIow?
Cheers!
Thanks for inviting us
When is it due?
Any day now
Hubert toId me you miscarried
In my third month
Must be horribIe
I was so scared that wouId happen to me
We're so stupid,
we aIready finished the nursery
Thanks
Maybe we shouId adopt after aII
Susi, no It'II work out
We just have to be patient
We've been patient so Iong
Maybe it worked this time
How do you know?
A woman feeIs that kind of thing
Look, adoption just causes probIems Iater
The kid isn't ours
It's from just anybody
There's no way of predicting his character
You just can't know
You're right
What you do/ng?
- Come on, get out of there!
- No.
PIease not!
- Why are you yeII/ng?
Stop yeII/ng and obey.
I said obey!
And you, fuck off!
Are we getting nervous?
- Are you crazy?
Are you crazy?
CaIm down, paI!
Stay cooI
You teII me to soften her up --
The man is new around here
He doesn't know how things work yet
You gotta excuse him
No ActuaIIy, I owe you an apoIogy
My Ioss, your gain
Good thing Harry's an oId friend
A gentIeman
I'm sure he's wiIIing to forget everything
We'II taIk about that Iater
Now, you apoIogize
- I hear that
- Sorry
Come on Do it properIy
Shake hands
Sorry, I didn't mean it
Now take our angeI to the hoteI
She can caII it a day
And no more mistakes from you
Shut up
Tamara, he paid him to break you
I was there
They taIked Iike best friends
He bawIed me out
Made me apoIogize
Why he do it?
Yeah, why?
Why do you think?
Come here
HeIIo I take waIk
How can someone go /n and out,
and no one not/ces a th/ng?
She had noth/ng on her.
Sa/d she was tak/ng a waIk.
Then why /s her room cIeared out?
I don't know. She went for a waIk.
You don't know?
What do I pay you idiots for
if you don't know anything?
I never Ieft the front desk
She was just taking a waIk
But now she's gone
AIong with her Iuggage, right?
Right?
Did you say anything to her?
- No
I'm not stupid
She stiII owes me this month's rent, 500
Who's going to pay that now?
Want me to teII you?
I'm deducting it from your wages,
haIf each
You got that?
Come on Let's go
Why you back so soon?
Pack your things! We gotta go
- Why?
- I'II expIain Iater
Where we going?
To a hoteI I have no idea
- Does he suspect?
- Yes That's the probIem
PIease hurry up
They're coming
Who's coming?
Who do you think?
Hurry up, pIease!
The taxi is waiting
What we do now?
Come on Let's grab some breakfast
I'm scared
Nothing can go wrong
I have bad feeIing
Better to not do it
OnIy idiots without a pIan get caught
I know a guy who --
Anything eIse?
Nothing can go wrong
Don't be scared
I don't want to wait here
It won't take Iong, just a few hours
I come with you
Tamara, that's siIIy You can't heIp me
I wait outside
Tamara, why?
It's siIIy
Nothing can go wrong
I go in, they give me the money,
and we spIit
But you must not shoot
I can't shoot It's not Ioaded
How many times do I have to say it?
- Promise!
It's not Ioaded
Not Ioaded
Now what?
We do it
Nothing can go wrong
I'II be right back
On fIoor!
AII
There too
Faster
Now, on fIoor
Morning This is a no standing zone
You'II have to Ieave
But if you go to the main square,
there's pIenty of parking there
My boyfriend be right back
Where is your boyfriend?
Had to make shopping
Do you have some ID, maybe a passport?
My boyfriend aIso has
Where are you from?
Ukraine
And your boyfriend?
I don't know
What, you don't know?
Are you crazy?
- On fIoor!
- I won't hurt you
PIease
He fired
CaII/ng aII un/ts.
Bank robbery at the VoIksbank.
One suspect, armed--
GföhI 20 here Come in, pIease
GföhI 20 Come in, pIease
He just opened fire
Shattered our rear window
Don't be scared They won't catch us
Tamara, what's wrong?
What is it?
Did he hit you?
Say something!
Isn't anyone here?
Ah, it's you
SIeeping in broad dayIight?
No, I feIt a IittIe dizzy, so I Iay down
Here to chop wood aIready?
Yeah
I wanted to,
but my motorcycIe broke down
What do you mean broke down?
The engine died
So I came through the woods on foot
- You want some schnapps?
- No
Can you Iend me your car?
My car?
I have to go to Vienna, straighten things out
I don't know
Take care of things
I won't be Iong, a few hours
I'II be back tonight
What's wrong with the engine?
What's wrong?
What?
What couId be wrong?
How shouId I know?
Nothing, everything's fine
Dinner's aImost ready
Come on, Robert TeII me
- What?
- Something's wrong I can teII
Come on Out with it
It's nothing speciaI Rough day, that's aII
Bank robbery
What, in our viIIage?
They got away with aImost 50,000 euros
My goodness!
I ran into them by chance and
tried to detain them, but
they jumped in the car and were gone
You ran into them?
By chance
Were they armed?
Oh, my gosh
It's not that bad
We'II catch them eventuaIIy
You ran into armed suspects,
and you didn't teII me untiI now?
Nothing happened
Were there a Iot of them?
A man and a woman
Okay, you ran into them,
and did they threaten you?
Let's drop it
I'm gIad to be off duty now
And Iike I said, nothing happened
I'II get it
KargI, heIIo?
Yes, he's here
Robert, it's for you
Yes?
Yes, I'II be right there In about 25 minutes
Yes, aII right
What happened?
I have to go to the state poIice office
Now? Why?
They found the getaway car
You have to go to the city for that?
I'II expIain it to you Iater
Yes, that was her
No doubt in your mind?
And who is she?
No ID on her
I doubt she was even registered
Maybe they argued about money,
and the bank robber shot her
From behind? Through the rear window?
With a GIock? No
I aimed at the tires
Yeah, shit happens
You have a visitor today?
Yes, AIex
He's chopping wood
- We met once
- ReaIIy?
Yes, briefIy at the farm, in the doorway
You must be gIad
- Yep
Hear about the robbery yesterday?
What robbery?
They robbed the bank
Our bank?
Robert ran into them Just imagine!
He tried to detain them
They were armed
I hate to think about it
- Robert?
Was he hurt?
- No, thank God
There was a casuaIty
I'II teII you tomorrow when I pick you up
I Iike these best
Is her husband a poIiceman?
We need butter too
- Are you coming with us tomorrow?
- Where?
It's Sunday
No, I'II keep working
It sure wouIdn't hurt you
I'm going for a waIk
- It'II be dark soon
- Doesn't matter
He thinks it's normaI
to go for a waIk in the dark
Now they are investigating
the use of firearms,
checking whether it was justified
Of course it was!
And they fiIed a compIaint
Against you?
Who did?
District poIice office
For what?
MansIaughter
The nerve of them!
You risk your Iife
and they fiIe a compIaint!
Your own peopIe
That's the system
A fine system!
Do they know who they were?
StiII no Ieads
Foreigners Russians or PoIes
Maybe iIIegaI aIiens
She might have been a prostitute
Good riddance!
He doesn't show it, but it's a huge strain
No wonder, she's dead
It's awfuI
He thinks about it constantIy
I'II be right back
Don't Iet him get to you
He has no idea
What?
Your dad doesn't see how hard this is
Yeah, you know how he is
I'm just cooIing some beer
We're aImost out of mineraI water too
Besides, it's not that bad
So she's dead
What was I supposed to do?
It was just bad Iuck
There's nothing you can do
You know him Just Iet him taIk
- I'II get dessert
- Fine
You know who I ran into?
SyIvia Staudacher
She has twins GirIs
They are so cute
Yes, they're adorabIe
What about you?
What couId be better
for the two of you right now?
- It wasn't meant to be
- House is done
You're over 30, the perfect age
Yes, Mama, we're trying,
but you can't force it
It wouId get Robert's mind off --
Yes, I know We want kids
It's highIy unIikeIy,
if you want to know the truth
Why? You were just pregnant
IncredibIe Iuck, apparentIy
A fIuke
I can't beIieve that
Did you get tested?
And what's the probIem?
It's not me
Then what, Robert?
Now that I reaIIy can't beIieve!
He's so athIetic
Hi
That's quite a piIe
You'II need a month for that I reckon
- A week
- ReaIIy, just a week?
I get tired just Iooking at that piIe
Where is Hausner?
Isn't he inside?
I didn't check
Bet he's gIad someone's heIping him
I feeI sorry for him aIone on the farm
Here he is
You're here aIready
Then Iet's go
He's not coming,
born and bred a heathen
Be gIad he's doing your work for you
I don't know if I can stiII pIay
No fair You have to pIay now
You promised
It's been so Iong
Some things you never forget
Hausner is going to pIay for us
He reaIIy pIayed up a storm
Hasn't been that happy for ages
He's Iike a new man
I think he enjoys
having someone on the farm
Are you staying a whiIe?
No, just Iong enough to finish the firewood
I guess I'II be going
Have fun Fun
Good Iuck
Your husband doesn't go to church?
He doesn't hoId much stock in it
He'd rather run his route
His route?
To the pond and back
Every day
Hi
I'm pIaying again
Do you miss her?
The work aIone!
It's depressing aII right
But I'II see her again
It won't be Iong now
You'II see her again?
She's waiting
Why didn't you caII?
CaII? Why shouId I?
It's past 1 :00 am
I didn't know where you were
WeII, nothing happened
I stiII get worried
I was with the other officers
We were taIking I Iost track of time
- About what?
- I'm sorry
TaIking about what?
What did you taIk about?
Nothing speciaI
About work and what happened
You taIk to the other men, why not to me?
You don't understand anyway
Maybe if you taIked to me I wouId
Besides, the men know it was an accident
Bad Iuck
And I don't know that?
Then why do you Iook at me that way?
What? How do I Iook at you?
You think I can't teII what you're thinking?
You think I can't teII?
What am I thinking?
That I shot her
I can teII you think it's my fauIt
What?
You want to taIk?
Want me to justify myseIf?
Even though you don't beIieve me
You weren't reaIIy serious in there, were you?
You're right Forget it
You don't reaIIy beIieve that's what I think
You're right
Are you coming to bed?
I'm just going to finish my beer
The appIes are just about ripe too
Here,
taste this
WeII? Like it?
Yeah, not bad
The best winter appIes far and wide
Who are you pIaying for?
When Hausner gets started,
there's no stopping him
She brought us a cake
Did you scare me!
Hausner wouIdn't Iet me go
It's great he's pIaying again
It's what he Ioves most
What do you want from us?
What do you mean? Nothing
Why do you come here?
What do you want?
I figure it makes him happy
I feeI sorry for him on the farm aII aIone
He's not aIone anymore
You act Iike we know each other
Do we know each other?
No
We don't know each other
And it's better that way
WeII, aren't you uncouth!
You're turning things upside down
I want you to Ieave us aIone
Cake, music, dance, tra-Ia-Ia, I don't want it
I don't want you coming back
Do you think that's possibIe?
Then come to my house
I'II be aIone tonight
If you want
Wait tiII it's dark,
come around the back so no one sees you
If you want
You didn't chicken out
Come in
I wouIdn't be surprised
if you were surprised at me
I'm surprised at myseIf
GIass of wine?
White or red? I've got both
Whatever
I prefer white Red makes you sIeepy
White perks you up
White's okay
Be right back New bottIe
It wasn't fuII, though
Not that you think --
Sit Make yourseIf comfortabIe
I'II be right back
WeII, I hope you Iike it
I think it's quite good
It's our house wine
WeII then, cheers!
Have a seat
Nice house
Thanks It turned out nice
Do cops earn this much?
No, I've got the store, doubIe income
We did a Iot ourseIves --
Robert and his friends, that is
And we got money from our parents
and the bank
It owns haIf the house, the upstairs fIoor
But that's okay
It's just for a few years
Everything neat CIean
Tip-top
Yeah, you know, you want it to be cozy
Have a seat
Nice house
Good husband
Everything perfect
ExactIy as it shouId be
You must be happy
- Yes, I guess
Sure, I can't compIain
So why do you want to fuck me?
I guess it was a stupid idea
I didn't reaIIy think that far, sorry
Wait
- For what?
- Can I take a shower?
- Upstairs on the right
Another gIass of wine?
Yeah
How cozy!
Why are you doing this?
Are you bored with your cop aIready?
No, he's my husband
I just wanted to
What does your God have to say?
He understands
A very understanding God
What is it?
Can't you just be friendIy?
WiII you Iose face
acting Iike a normaI person?
What happened to you?
Do you have kids?
No
But you have a nursery upstairs
But we don't have any
I'II be going
Why are you this way?
What did anyone do to you?
Be gIad you don't know everything
WiII you come again?
You sure can work
Got to give you credit for that
You shouId get married
A man needs a woman or he gets batty
You'II find one easiIy the way you work
You think chopping wood impresses women?
They notice a man who can work
Won't be any different nowadays
- HeIIo
- Hi
What's wrong?
Just dizzy
Does this happen often?
Yeah, sometimes
Can you hand me the bag baIm?
It works wonders for headaches
You have headaches too?
AII the time
You shouId go in for a checkup
Doctors don't know anything either
But it can't hurt
I don't need a doctor for a IittIe headache
You're a stubborn oId fooI
You're a stubborn fooI yourseIf
Who wiII Iook after the cows and the farm?
I'm not Ieaving
They can carry me out in the end
It won't be my probIem anymore
But untiI then, I'm not budging
TiII the end
AIone today?
How's Hausner?
He's okay
TeII him I said hi
I'II be aIone again tonight
Hey, Robert, come on!
Let's drink to my son
Give him a gIass, wouId you?
- CongratuIations
- Thanks!
205 inches, 68 pounds, bIack hair
- Here, have a drink
- I'm on duty
Stop taking everything so seriousIy
Pass me my gIass Thanks
He came at 3:00 yesterday Took forever
- You were there the whoIe time?
- Of course
You're aIways scaring me
Come in What if someone sees you?
I was sure you weren't coming
Good thing I didn't bet anything
Have you aIways been a Ione woIf,
coming and going?
Sorry, but that's my impression of you
No Not aIways
WiII you go back to Vienna
when you're done?
You have a girIfriend?
I know nothing about you
I had one untiI recentIy
It's over?
What happened?
She was murdered
What?
- Oh my goodness
- And the man who did it
Iives on
Just Iike aIways
He couIdn't care Iess
- That can't be true
- But it is
He goes on Iiving his Iife
And she is dead
And aII I ever think about
is that I have to change that
He can't simpIy go on Iiving
You wanted to know what's wrong
Now you know
You can't do that
You mustn't even think it
What?
KiIIing someone out of vengeance
I know you don't beIieve, but it's a sin
You mustn't do it
Now I understand you
That's why you're so coId
So brutaI
CoId?
You mustn't do it
Promise me
Now I understand you
Come on
You have to go Robert came home
Find your way out
Don't Iet him see you
Maybe he'd Iike to meet me
PIease don't PIease go
Don't ruin everything
PIease go
Why are you home aIready?
What's wrong?
Robert, what happened?
They gave me a Ieave of absence
Leave of absence?
I'm unfit for duty
The counseIor said it's perfectIy normaI
It's a normaI reaction to the events
Sure it is
And he said I might need psychoIogicaI heIp
I'm not sick It's normaI
It's how anyone wouId react
That's absoIuteIy right
- I aimed at the tires
- Everyone knows you did
I normaIIy hit my mark
I don't know how this couId happen
It was just bad Iuck
Bad Iuck
Why am I pIagued with bad Iuck?
Why can't I do anything right?
I think a psychoIogist is a good idea
And I can't stop Iooking at the damn photo
I don't understand It couIdn't have been me
What photo?
Of the woman
You have a photo of her?
Where did you get this?
I aimed at the tires
You shouIdn't have this
ShouIdn't be Iooking at it
I'm going to throw it away now Okay?
I'm throwing the photo away
What's wrong?
I'm okay now
You beIong in bed
Yeah, maybe
I'II be fine tomorrow
You need a checkup
At a hospitaI
Things wiII faII apart if I'm not here
Everything wiII go to ruin
Nothing wiII go to ruin
I'II stay here
I'II keep an eye on everything
You'II stay here?
I'm not going to any hospitaI
They never Iet you out again,
and then they put you in a home
I'm staying on the farm
They can carry me out
You're not dying yet
Rest a IittIe
We'II go in a bit
I'II feed the cows in the meantime
HeIIo
Hi
- You're Hausner's grandson, right?
- Yeah
And?
How do you Iike it here?
Not too exciting, is it?
Pretty dead compared to the city
No, it's fine
Nice spot here
Aren't you the cop who shot that woman?
How do you know that?
PeopIe taIk
And it was in the paper too
Yes
That's me
Must be a heavy experience
WouIdn't want to go through it again
You aimed at him, the bank robber,
I guess Am I right?
I aimed at the tires
Wanted to
Yeah, but I don't understand
They're much Iower
You must have aimed higher
for that to happen
It aII went so fast
I don't understand it myseIf
- Aren't you scared of him?
- Scared?
Why?
You kiIIed his girI
What if he tracked you down
and wanted to shoot you?
Out of vengeance
Let him
But there's one thing I'd ask him
What?
Why he took her aIong in the first pIace
She wasn't driving,
wasn't heIping him escape
He went into the bank aIone
It doesn't make sense
Why did he take her as if it were an outing?
The whoIe mess happened
because she was there for no reason
That's what I'd ask him
Bye
Dinner is ready
What's aII this?
Are we ceIebrating something?
Yes, maybe
I have to teII you something
It's stiII too earIy, and I'm not positive,
but I have the feeIing
I think it finaIIy worked
What?
Guess
What, you reaIIy think so?
That you're pregnant?
Yes
HeIIo?
Anyone here?
Ah, someone's here after aII
Where is Hausner? It's Sunday
HospitaI
- What's wrong with him?
- We don't know Tests
Poor man
You're staying tiII they know?
Someone has to
- I wanted to taIk to you
- Yeah?
Come in
Let's hear it
You ran into Robert at the pond
PIease never teII him what we did
- Why shouId I?
- Promise me
Swear it
I swear
We shouIdn't see each other anymore
It was great and eIectrifying,
but we shouIdn't do it anymore
I mean, if we meet by chance,
perfectIy normaI
But I think it's better this way
Who's that?
The girI I toId you about
Were you there when --
when she died?
That was you?
What?
You robbed the bank?
What wiII you do now?
Stay here if they don't catch me
As Iong as he's stiII around
I have to go now
PIease don't teII him what happened
Don't worry
I have to go now