Good morning.
It's a sunny 65 degrees.
I'm Neil Simmons.
Today is Monday, May 15th.
From L.A.'s KDHP,
this is the morning news.
The president meets at
the White House today
with the prime minister of Norway.
The United Nations Security Council
debates on an amended U.S. resolution
on sanctions against
non-cooperative nations.
Also in this hour,
George Finnerty asks the question,
"How organic are your
organic vegetables?"
Los Angeles traffic is next.
We have a considerable
heavy volume of traffic today.
We have a Sig Alert on the southbound 101
into downtown at Alvarado.
There's an apparently
broken-down delivery truck
inadvertently blocking
the number two and three lanes.
There's a parked tractor trailer
on Sepulveda Boulevard
blocking the northbound airport exit
from the 105 East.
The driver has locked
himself inside his cab.
The LAPD is rerouting local traffic
off Sepulveda at Century Boulevard,
and La Tijera Boulevard--
Baby, coffee.
Thank you, sir.
No.
A little make up for last night?
Oh, I gotta get up and get ready.
Here's your latte.
Thank you.
Right there?
I put the sugar in the thing.
Thanks, babe.
Do you want me to run the shower?
Hey, you got that--
whatever it's called tonight?
Yeah. Sorry.
Last one.
- Paper down.
- Hmm, they found us.
Yeah, took them two weeks.
Oh, man, I forgot to charge my phone.
I don't think I can go to work.
Well, don't go.
Quit it.
Come on.
I have to.
Where's my car charger?
Hey, baby, it's 8:19.
Earlier they said that
the 101 is all fucked up.
- So you might want to take side streets.
- Oh, thanks, babe.
You guys rehearsing today?
Uh, no, but I got some calls to make.
- The cable guy's coming, right?
- Yeah, he's supposed to.
Do you mind getting my dry cleaning?
Yes, dear.
I love you.
Thanks for cooking last night.
Pretty good, right?
Yeah.
Oh, I'll finish unpacking
the bedroom boxes tonight. I promise.
- So, yeah, like, that's--
- It was so so--
- That's it, yeah?
- Yeah.
- It was good.
- Yeah?
Yeah, that's it.
Drive safe!
"RIGHT AT YOUR DOOR"
We interrupt your regular programming
for a KDHP emergency news break.
This is Neil Simmons reporting
from KDHP's Pasadena studios.
Multiple explosive devices
were detonated simultaneously
across Los Angeles moments ago.
The crowded streets of downtown
Los Angeles and Beverly Hills--
Essentially L.A.'s heavy volume
of commuter traffic is the target.
Okay, I understand we have
KDHP's Kathy Reynolds,
who is in our downtown studio,
reporting from her cell phone
with an intense update.
Kathy, are you there?
Debris from a building
is falling right now.
People are running
through the streets.
Smoke is everywhere.
People are--
Figueroa Street--
Neil, can you still hear me?
This is of course is an incred--
Message DFl-6.
There! Another boom!
There was another boom.
Where is your vantage point?
I'm running up Figueroa
between 8th and 7th.
Another explosion just occurred.
There is a man covered in blood.
He just fell.
People are--
Kathy?
Kathy, can-- can you hear me?
Okay, uh--
I have just received word that--
apparently a second explosion
has been witnessed in Beverly Hills
near the Century City Plaza.
Shit.
Lexi!
Brett, it's Steve.
You got the news on?
I know, you hear all this shit?
Yeah, Jesus Christ, where's Lexi?
- Is she downtown?
- Yeah, I gotta go.
I have just received word
that there was just another explosion
at Los Angeles International Airport
- on the departures--
- All circuits are busy.
Fuck!
We've lost contact with Kathy,
and what is occurring downtown.
New eyewitness reports
from a vantage point on Chavez Ravine
say that incredible plumes of smoke
are rapidly rising from the downtown skyline.
Shit.
Los Angeles is on a red alert.
A red alert has been--
Fuck!
Come on, work.
Hi, this is Lexi.
Leave me a message.
Lexi, baby, it's me.
Listen, I've been trying to call you.
I'm gonna head downtown,
and I'm gonna come get you.
Just call me when you get this and tell me
what route you're taking back.
Just call me and tell
me that you're okay.
All right.
I love you. I'm leaving now.
Another explosion just occurred.
People are scattered all over the street.
I can see glass everywhere.
They are evacuating buildings.
There is smoke--
Do not attempt to enter
any of the disaster areas.
An official statement
from authorities now released.
Los Angeles streets
need to be left open
for rescue vehicles.
Okay, now I understand
we have Kathy Reynolds back on the line.
Kathy, can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
When I lost contact
with you, Neil,
I was trying to get
a better vantage point.
The police asked me
if it was a question of life and death,
and I said, "Come on,
I have to get close there."
A portion of the
library tower exploded.
People are screaming
and running up North Figueroa.
Everybody is just trying
to find a way out of here.
Police continue to try
and contain the masses.
Now, we have Juan Martinez
from the streets of Beverly Hills.
Juan, are you there?
Yes, Neil.
Someone came running
into the lobby
of the Beverly Grand just prior,
yelling about an explosion downtown.
It was at that moment
when this first explosion rattled ever--
Fuck!
- Damn it!
- Are you okay?
Are you okay?
My kids are at school.
Oh, shit.
... when the first explosion went off
on Santa Monica Boulevard.
Authorities are barricading access
into the three impact zones:
Hollywood to downtown and East L.A.,
Century City, Beverly Hills and adjacencies,
L.A.X. and the surrounding
beach communities.
They urge everyone to stay at home
and leave the rescue to authorities.
Okay, we go right back
Kathy Reynolds downtown.
Kathy, what is happening?
... in an immense crowd
off of Figueroa
onto 5th street, and back towards Hill.
Police have blocked the street.
What I could gather at this point is that all
of downtown Los Angeles is a crime scene.
And no one is allowed to leave, as--
That's what I heard.
How many explosions was it?
- Do you have those tire patches?
- There's no time.
The news is saying get home
and off the streets
as soon as possible,
especially right now.
Hello? Hello?
Everybody out!
Right now! Let's go!
Shit.
Oh, they're open.
God, tell me they're open.
Batteries and water.
...now suspect potentially toxic chemicals
have been released with the explosions
and potentially deadly toxins are traveling
in the smoke from the fires.
An official recommendation
to stay home,
close and seal your house
the best you can.
Please, one at a time.
How much is it?
Just take it outta here.
Another five minutes!
All main streets are being
barricaded from civilians.
Police are urging,
if you have to abandon your car,
to please pull it off
the side of the road.
Rescue vehicles need
the right of way.
Officials continue to caution
that the explosive devices
could be, quote,
"dirty bombs"
or chemical bombs.
No details are available
what is meant by this.
Turn around, buddy!
This road's closed!
As explosions continue
to be detonated,
rescue officials are taking
all necessary precautions.
The immediate goal is to extinguish the fires,
which continue to burn,
spreading alleged toxic smoke into the air.
Authorities urge everyone
to return home and to--
Okay now, now we go
back to Juan Martinez in Beverly Hills.
The instant gridlock may be actually
helping authorities
keep the event contained.
Stay in your car!
You're contaminated!
Freeze!
You will be quarantined!
It seemed as if every car
in the vicinity was abandoned.
Traffic came to an
immediate dead stop.
- It was instantly impassable.
- You!
Leave your window up!
- Were you near one of the blasts?
- No.
Turn around! Go home!
Sir, my wife is downtown.
Downtown, Beverly Hills, L.A.X.--
They're all getting shut down.
The smoke from the fires
is moving this way.
That ash is deadly.
Yeah, well, I'm not just
going to leave her out there.
I'm not giving you a choice!
Turn around! Go home!
There'll be more information
on the news telling you what to do.
Don't move!
Get back in your car!
Freeze!
Fuck!
I told you to stay in your fucking car!
Shit.
Unfortunately I can not see
a way out at the moment.
People continue to panic,
demanding information
from any authority figure
that they can find,
who are-- quite frankly,
are unsure what to do themselves.
For the moment, they are
trying to extinguish--
Authorities are issuing
a daylight curfew on the city.
The surge of people that have attempted
to enter the disaster areas
has hindered the rescue efforts.
Police are arresting anyone attempting
to enter those areas
impacted by these alleged chemical
explosions.
Son of a bitch.
They are detaining all those who are...
- Hey, kid. What's your name?
- Timmy.
Where do you live, Timmy?
You need to go home right now.
Something really bad
has happened, okay?
Come on.
Go, go, go.
Run!
...which is also elevating a panic--
Lex!
Lexi!
Come on, fuck.
Fuck!
Authorities are trying
to contain the crowds.
There are still sirens everywhere.
Many people have submitted to
the crowd control method of the authorities,
however, hundreds are still trying
to push past the barricades,
and riot police--
They keep pushing us in circles.
Are we on 8th?
Up and down 8th Street--
Ash continues to rain
from the sky.
There is black debris,
and as you say, Neil,
this ash is confirmed toxic,
They'll have a much
bigger problem on their hands,
and-- and so will we.
The smoke is just getting so heavy
and the smell has become unbearable, Neil.
The panic over the--
the severity of the toxic level
is definitely rising.
I have my shirt wrapped around my face
as I speak to you.
The one remaining--
Others cover their nose
and mouth with scarves,
newspapers, almost anything.
Please try your call again later.
Fuck!
Sir, I work next door.
I know, I've seen you before.
What the fuck are you
doing in my house?
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to be in your house.
Mr. Gallagher is not home.
The bus--
The bus is stopped-- I got no car.
- Please.
- You gotta go home.
I have nowhere to go.
Please.
I don't know what to do.
I won't make it.
Shit.
Come on!
Come on.
Sir, is it okay to--
Listen, my wife's out there.
Can l--
Fucking--
Fuck!
Sir... sir?
What are they saying?
I don't know what that means.
No, I can't believe it.
I can't believe it.
Marina del Rey,
Playa del Rey,
El Segundo,
Playa Vista, Baldwin Hills,
Westchester,
Inglewood--
What are you doing?
What were they saying?
What did you hear?
Sir, we need to close up the house.
Of course, Beverly Hills
and Century City.
All areas considered
Beverly Hills adjacent.
Sir...
- Listen to me, you got a wife?
- She's home.
Well, don't you want to be with her?
She wouldn't want me to kill myself
trying to get there.
Sir, please?
Please?
Sir.
Sir!
We have to close the house, please!
Listen, we're not doing
anything until my wife gets home.
Hollywood, Glendale,
Atwater Village--
Come on, the fucking line--
...if you are living in
one of these areas,
considered part of
an immediate threat zone...
Fuck!
...will soon be instructed what steps to take
in order to insure the safety
of you and your family.
...continue testing the sites
for chemical readings,
- they have confirmed.
- Sir?
- I repeat, confirmed...
- What?
... the use of dirty bombs...
How long are you going to wait?
... recommending that anyone
within a three-mile radius,
any of the three impact areas,
should seal and close themselves off
from external air.
All necessary precautions should be taken.
These three to eight-mile areas,
the authorities are considering the red zones,
and consider these areas
contaminated by the toxic ash,
which travels in the smoke from the fire.
Chemical bombs have been
detonated across Los Angeles,
this is an official word
from city authorities.
All adjacent areas
to the three main red zones
are considered to be
in imminent danger.
A quarantine is in effect.
I have never seen anything like this.
There is ash from the fires
falling all over the neighborhood.
Cars are being coated
with a soot from the fire.
The entire area for blocks
is getting contained
like an oversized crime scene.
Beverly Hills is engulfed
in smoke and flames.
I stand here with hundreds of people,
and I swear we can feel
the heat from four or five blocks away.
Lucky enough to have saved
a dust mask which was handed to me
by a helpful security guard from the hotel--
We had the wherewithal to grab a first aid kit
before we were evacuated.
I've been given numerous
answers to the question,
"How toxic is the gas?"
"Is there--
It seems all structures
have been evacuated,
but there is nowhere to go.
No information on who is responsible
for these coordinated attacks
on the innocent people of Los Angeles
is available from authorities.
Officials do not yet fully understand
the lethal properties of the toxin,
but continue to caution
that it is acutely fatal.
I am in the middle
of a full-on riot down here.
Toxic ash rains from the sky.
People are fighting
to exit the quarantine area.
Police struggle to contain the crowd.
Police on horses are kicking their way
into the massive crowds, injuring dozens.
A police car was overturned
just a few moments ago.
The fires have spread.
People are getting
knocked to the ground.
Many have been trampled.
Authorities continuing
seeing crowds tonight
have been given numerous
answers to medical questions--
How toxic is the ash?
Is there medicine?
Mostly semi-positive answers...
From what I can see,
I can confirm that the city is under siege,
and this area is being quarantined
as an enormous crime scene,
as well as the potentially
toxic crowd of individuals
that are a threat
to the rest of the city.
The levels of tension
in the crowd is immense.
Everyone is concerned about
the toxic levels of the ash.
An immense crowd has been corralled
here on Beverly Drive.
... organizing a way
to move this crowd
safely away from
the immediate dangers.
The fires still burn.
Ash still rises into the sky.
Hundreds of people who tried to run
from their gridlocked vehicles,
now seek to re-enter their car,
only to find someone else inside.
Juan, I'm sorry to interrupt you.
I understand we have
Heather Malone, a city official,
now speaking from
a Burbank Sheriff's office in the valley.
Please stay safe, Juan.
We'll check back with you
as soon as we can.
She's safe.
She'll be okay.
We're all going to be okay.
Everything-- We're safe.
Seal it.
Fire Departments are busily trying
to extinguish the fires.
We have determined that
the explosive devices used
have let off immense amounts
of deadly molecular toxins
that are now traveling
in the smoke from the fires.
Due to gridlocked streets,
the fires had a larger head start...
... full understanding of what kind of toxins--
their life span,
the full effects are still being determined.
We have a team of specialists
gathering samples...
... and a team of scientists
arriving on the scene to run tests.
Mobile labs are being
set up across the city.
Antibiotics will be distributed to those
now quarantined in the red zones.
So please, do not attempt
to join someone
who has been quarantined.
If by chance, someone who
was near one of the blasts
approaches your home,
refrain from contact.
All air traffic in southwestern United States
has been grounded.
California, Nevada,
Arizona, Utah,
and New Mexico have no flights.
... taking shelter under awnings,
inside cars,
but it seems
to be covering everything.
It is harder and harder to breathe, Neil.
Everyone here has their faces
wrapped with shirts, towels, jackets,
whatever they can get their hands on, Neil.
There is a gentleman
lying on the ground here.
Civilians are actually tending to him.
He's bleeding profusely from his head.
I asked if he was hit by debris,
and a bystander said,
"No, he was run over
by all the people fleeing."
- Hello?
- Brad! Jesus!
We've been trying
to reach you all day.
Mrs. Fontana.
Is everything okay?
- Yeah.
- You're okay, right?
- Yeah, we're fine.
- Oh! They're okay!
- Yeah, um--
- They're okay!
- Lexi took the freeway.
She took the freeway!
I guess the phone
lines are jammed, huh?
All day.
Can I speak with Lexi, please.
Can I speak with her?
What?
You're okay, right?
You know, we sealed the house.
That's good.
They say that's good.
Oh, God.
We saw the whole thing on the news.
They say the chance
of survival for anybody
near the explosions
is most likely zero.
Brad, I need to speak with my daughter.
Brad?
All circuits are busy.
Please try your call again later.
A total of three explosions in downtown,
three more blasts near
the Century City Plaza in Beverly Hills.
Yes, okay,
we would like to correct an earlier report.
It is now confirmed
that the blast at L.A.X.
was on the arrivals level,
not the departures,
between terminal 6--
I should have fucking went.
It's suicide.
No one really knows
what's going on yet.
Anyone approaching your home,
who has been exposed to the deadly ash,
must remain quarantined
until further instruction.
Please do not tend to the medical needs
of anyone contaminated.
Refrain from contact.
They are highly toxic,
considered lethal,
and need professional attention.
Authorities have reported that some
who were within blocks of the blasts
have fled to other parts of the city.
Isolate the people who
were near the impact areas.
The civilians, police,
and other rescue authorities
that were unfortunately
near one of the blasts,
are being held at a high-security quarantine
in downtown Los Angeles.
Brad!
- Lex!
- Thank God you're home.
Oh, God.
You're home.
Honey, open up!
Open the door, honey.
Honey.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
The bombs were half
a block from my car.
The cop threw me up against
a wall with his club.
It hurts to breathe.
Someone picked me up off the ground,
and the sirens were so loud.
The entire block was on fire.
Open the door, sweetie.
Open the fucking door.
Open the door.
What are you doing?
Listen, baby,
we're gonna get you checked out.
We're gonna get you
to a hospital as soon as we can.
- Open the door.
- Baby...
they were dirty bombs.
It's chemical shit.
Open the door.
- You're contaminated.
- I can't.
The news said that you
have to be isolated.
What are you talking about?
The shit's airborne.
- Nobody knows what's going on.
- Wait--
Everybody on the radio said
guys were wearing toxic suits.
What are you doing, Brad?
What are you doing?
I didn't know what to do.
They said tape up the house.
It's some kind of poison.
I saw these cops.
And you're just going to leave me out in it?
Look, it's not going
to be for long, okay?
Brad! Go around back.
Get away from the front of the house.
- I didn't know if you were okay.
- Well, here I am!
- You gotta get to the back of the house.
- Oh, my God.
Go around back and we'll figure this out.
Brad, open the door.
I can't.
Baby...
Baby, listen to me.
What the fuck is this?
The news said that people
need to be isolated.
People?
It's me!
What, did you plan this?
They said to seal
the house
and you weren't here in time, so--
Who the fuck is "they"?
Fox fucking news!
What the fuck do they know!
You're pretty quick to lock
me out of my own home!
Baby, the, uh--
the--
the neighbor's handyman is inside.
What?
What!
Well, he didn't have any--
And not me!
Fuck-- You idiot!
Look, I know it's fucked up.
I couldn't just--
He had no where to go.
- I just couldn't--
- Yeah, well, join the fucking club!
We saw the ash
and the dust cloud
roll across the sky
and we didn't have a choice.
I was there, Brad!
Half of somebody's fucking arm
flew in my goddamn car!
You know, everybody's a little--
Once we get some information,
it'll be better in a while.
You know, they'll have answers.
It's just hysteria right now.
l-- I love you.
We just--
We gotta calm down for a second.
Okay, just calm down for a second.
I'm sorry.
Take this.
Have not released an official report
regarding the name of the toxin as of yet.
They believe it to be
a hybrid of several durable,
toxic chemicals with
an unrecognizable viral strain
with lethal properties.
Local authorities indicated
that they had full federal support--
How long?
They, uh--
[sighs]
They don't really know anything.
I'm gonna be here with you, okay?
I'll stay right here with you, all right?
We'll get some help.
However, it's the long-term effects
that everyone has been
and will be concerned with.
9-1-1 emergency is experiencing
a high volume of calls.
Please try your call again la--
The smoke and ash still hangs in the air.
The enormous rescue lights
pretty much have obliterated--
I thought duct tape was stupid.
It is stupid.
It just-- It was--
- He said it was the only way to--
- What?
Honey, I left the door,
the front door open.
I left it open as long as we could.
l-- I just thought--
I was hoping that you were safe somewhere.
Are they sugar coating it?
No.
They don't fucking know
enough to sugar coat anything.
They-- I mean--
We're going to be
fucking smart about this.
When we figure it out,
we're going to get help.
They got to be sending fucking help.
There's still fire all around...
Thanks for the travel tip.
What were you going
to do today, anyway?
So how's the phone work?
It's, uh--
It's in and out.
There's no Internet either.
Why? Do you want me
to try to call somebody?
No.
When you listen to your voicemail--
- Yeah?
- Ignore my messages.
Sorry to interrupt, Kathy,
but we have just received word
of another city press conference in progress
at the Burbank Sheriff's Department.
We estimate that
those who have fled,
and are affected by
any of the immediate blasts
and toxic ash should remain
quarantined for several days.
We do not have
a specific number of days.
Three, five, ten--
We just don't have any idea.
Fuck! Lexi!
What the fuck!
Get out!
You sleep out here!
I'm gonna die!
I don't want to die!
Lexi, fucking stop it!
- Stop it!
- Why?
- You want to fucking kill me?
- Why do you want to kill me?
Stop, stop.
The radio just said
the medical team
will be in this neighborhood by morning.
They're running tests.
We'll know everything's okay in the morning.
They'll be in this area.
- Let me do this.
- You got it?
- Yeah. Go on. Yeah.
- Fuck!
...near the impact zones.
You will be turned away.
There is an emergency hotline.
Please call that number.
Describe your situation
and your location,
and help will be dispatched accordingly.
The investigation into who is responsible
for this horrific action is well underway.
- Lex.
- What are you doing?
You want to li--
Live without me?
Lexi, come here.
It's not you.
I'm not locking you out, okay?
- You understand that?
- Yeah.
I love you.
You know that, right?
- You know that.
- Yeah.
I'm glad you're safe.
I'm going to get some help here.
We're going to fix this.
Okay?
Okay.
9-1-1 Emergency is experiencing
a high volume of calls.
Please call
the 24-hour hotline:
888-777-4432.
The Los Angeles Emergency
Hotline is experiencing
a high volume of calls.
- Please try your call again later.
- Fuck.
Here.
Juan, how is morale there?
Well, as I mentioned earlier,
everyone is a bit suspicious of how long--
when, what-- seem to remain
calm, despite the anxiety.
Answer the phone, Mary.
Please.
Answer the phone.
There was a word of caution
earlier to use bottled water
until tests have been completed.
The president made it clear
in his statement this morning
that an investigation into the "evil-doers"--
It's your mom.
- She called earlier today.
- She did?
... went on to say that our
nation will not be intimidated.
What did you say?
I told her that we were okay.
Then I hung up on her.
Thanks.
...and our resolve will
hold firm, and our values--
It started out on a typical, beautiful day--
The Los Angeles Emergency Hotline
is experiencing a high volume of calls.
Please try--
... the longest day for all of us here.
I did hear some gunshots
a couple of blocks away.
It's hard to imagine what is going on
elsewhere in the city.
Authorities urge everyone to stay at home.
Help is on the way.
The, uh, city's red zones
will remain under quarantine
for an undetermined amount of time.
Fuck.
Lex!
Lexi!
Yeah. I got it.
I got it.
Copy.
Meet you back at the complex.
Brad. Brad!
Brad!
Brad. Look, I just saw
some guy with the cops.
They just handcuffed
some guy and hauled him off.
Stay back here.
Don't let them see you.
They're not fuckin' around.
I saw a cop shoot a guy.
- What?
- Yeah, when I went to get you.
You went to get me?
Of course I went to get you.
Where are the doctors?
That guy said they'd be here by the morning.
- He lied.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
I think it was his way
to calm us down.
Tell him to come out here
and die alongside me.
How about that for an idea?
Fuck!
Look, nobody's gonna die, okay?
Not now, not later.
Look at me. Nobody. Okay?
Fuck him.
Can I have my phone?
Yeah. Sure.
Just don't--
Don't go anywhere anymore.
Give me a minute.
Okay, Lex.
Lex! You can open the door.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Oh!
I talked to the Hotline.
What'd they say?
That they're doing everything
they possibly can at this time.
What'd they really say?
Did they say I'm dead?
Can't we just talk?
Six years, you've never
said, "Can we just talk?"
What'd they say?
Am I dead?
Just say it!
- Lexi.
- Brad!
Nobody is sure, 100%, of anything right now.
Can't anyone help me?
They said that the toxins
have to be like 1.5 microns--
- What?
- Diameter, or something like that.
- They're distributing antibiotics.
When?
They're using the help
of the U.S. postal service.
'Cause all the hospitals and
rescue centers are overwhelmed.
They're turning people away,
so we're going to have to, um--
- No!
- Whatever they have, it could help.
Brad!
No...
Help and medicine will be
dispatched accordingly.
Do not attempt to go
to rescue centers or hospitals.
Help will come to you.
The president has activated
10,000 reservists--
to help in the rescue efforts.
They're being flown into
Edwards Air Force Base,
briefed, and driven by school bus
into the red zone.
It's my mom.
- Mom.
- Lexi! Finally!
Hey.
Brad told you we got
disconnected yesterday, right?
- Yeah.
- Oh, I'm so happy to hear your voice!
You're doing okay.
You're safe.
- A little confused.
- Well, me too.
It's terrible.
Everybody thinks it's gonna
happen here next.
But you're doing okay.
You and Brad have enough supplies?
Lex? You're--
You're okay, right?
- No.
- What?
- Brad said--
- Doesn't matter what Brad said, Mom.
- I was there.
- Oh, God. What are you saying?
I just don't know what to do.
Jesus, why did Brad lie?
Oh, God!
Okay. Okay, Lex.
I need you to listen to me.
There are places that
you can go for help--
There's nowhere to go.
They're arresting people
for crossing the street.
Okay? Your news is not
what's really happening.
- Calm down.
- Stop telling me to calm down, Mom.
It's so easy to say.
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm sorry.
What can I do to help you, huh?
How can I help you, sweetie?
- You can't.
All right, Lex.
Hang up with me, and call for help.
Call for help!
- Mommy?
- Call the hospital.
Mommy, the entire city is a crime scene.
- Everything is overloaded.
- Get to the hospital, Lexi!
Get to the hospital.
They're setting up health stations.
No, Mom, they said to stay put, okay?
I see it here.
It's right here in the news--
They said they'd bring us antibiotics
to calm us down.
- Lexi, you cannot just sit there!
- God, Mom.
Look! You're stressing me out, okay?
I don't want this either!
You always think you know
how to make everything right,
but this is fucking real, and you can't
just make it magically disappear.
I'm sorry.
I love you.
Let's take it-- Are you all right?
Listen to you!
Oh, God.
Listen to you, Lex.
- Lexi, you need to get help!
- Hey!
- Honey--
- What's happening?
- Hey!
Lex, talk to me.
Lex!
- Are you okay?
- I love you. I got to go.
- Don't hang up, honey.
- No, I love you, and--
Tell me you're gonna be okay.
Tell Dad and Jason
I love 'em too, okay?
- Stay on the phone. Honey--
- Gotta go.
I want to help you--
Hey, come here.
Come here, come here.
Where are you going?
What's going on?
- Where are your parents?
- They're at work.
- What's your name?
- Timmy.
My mom-- My mom--
My mom and dad's at work.
They're at work?
Want some water?
Come and have some water.
I have crackers, too.
New York City subways,
Chicago's L-Train service,
Boston's M.T.A.,
and Washington D.C.'s Metro,
are all resuming normal schedules.
- Sir?
- What?
Don't you care?
That's your choice.
I know where my wife is, okay?
I left my deadbeat family a long time ago.
So whoever the fuck that is,
I don't really feel like
picking up and telling 'em,
"Hey, man, everything's fucking fine,"
'cause it's not fine!
Listen, if you got any problem at all,
you can stop sucking my oxygen
and get the fuck out of my house.
Look, I didn't mean anything by it.
Then what did you mean?
I don't know.
Rescue efforts in the red zone--
You're saying that
I don't love my wife?
No. No.
That's not it.
We both made the same decision.
So what, you got nothing to say, now?
We didn't decide anything.
It was instinct.
It was just instinct, man.
When you call about your
location, your condition,
the situation you and your family are in,
uh, authorities are surveying each household
and then deciding what to do.
I want to clean him up.
I saw that kid in the street yesterday.
I made him go home.
I watched him run.
Yeah, well, now he's here.
We're okay. Right?
Why can't we go in there?
Well--
Uh, we're just--
We're trying to keep that dust out.
Yeah. That's a good way to look at it.
Timmy, how come
you didn't run home?
Remember when I told you
to run home?
- What happened?
- I was scared.
You were scared to go home?
- Why?
- Because. The bomb.
You know about the bomb?
- What did you see?
- Half of the Earth blew up.
Well, we're going
to get you cleaned up now.
Yeah, we just want
to get you clean.
Okay?
Take a shower?
I'm gonna give you--
I'll give you guys the bathroom.
Yeah.
We'll get this dust off us, okay?
The men and women have learned
they have to withdraw
from distributing the antibiotics.
Look, uh...
I'm gonna leave.
Look, I didn't mean what I said, okay?
That's not it.
I need to be with my wife.
Nobody answered the phone?
I reached my cousin.
He hasn't heard from her.
Well, uh, try somebody else.
I'm sorry I put you through all the trouble.
It's no trouble.
Why don't you try a neighbor?
She could be safe, you know,
next door or something.
Okay.
You take care of Lexi.
Make sure that she knows
she's not alone.
God help us.
Hey.
You don't have to leave.
Don't do this, man.
I'm going through the office.
You seal the door to the hallway.
I should have never came.
I would have never gotten
the house sealed up in time.
Rescue teams, of course, remain ready,
in protective suits and red alert.
So I urge everyone to call
the 24-hour emergency hotline.
State your location, and the condition of you
and all your family members,
and they are prioritizing houses,
and will bring the proper medicine to you.
Do not attempt to go to a hospital
or a rescue center,
especially near the quarantined areas,
near the impact zones.
You will be turned away.
You will not receive medicine.
Authorities are trying to contain
the already overwhelming crowds.
National Guard reservists
continue to be briefed
at Edwards Air Force Base,
and then bused into the city
where they are to help with the--
No new news has surfaced
in the last several hours.
It's a goddamn sauna
in here.
Do you have water?
I think.
Alvaro left.
Just walked out.
You think the shower's safe?
You know what, honey?
I think it'll be just fine.
Yeah.
The very special and important
people in charge of this disaster
said that it was okay.
In fact, they phoned today,
and they said,
"Sorry to interrupt
"your busy fucking day,
but in case you were wondering
"if your wife can take a nice, hot shower,
"she can, 'cause the water is safe.
There's not toxins in it."
Brad? Timmy.
And they also speculate
that boys like Timmy--
in general--
'course, you have to leave
it up to interpretation
what "general" means,
that boys like Timmy
are immune, too,
because they have
built-in antibiotics.
Can you believe that?
I mean--
They forgot to mention that.
Oh, shit.
Because I haven't seen
my family in ten years,
and I fit the classic profile
of the out-of-work musician
living off the bread-winning
coat tails of my wife,
that I'm immune too.
Since all the hospitals
are overloaded,
and we're told to
stay put at the time--
I think everybody's immune
to this mystery poison.
I think it's just
one big goddamn
public service announcement.
All right, I'm done.
You okay?
Yeah.
Oh, God.
I hope the mailman's
carrying some good drugs.
Were your parents supposed
to pick you up?
Yeah, they s'posed
to pick me up at school.
Don't worry.
We'll find 'em. Okay?
Brad?
Yeah?
Did you hear that?
No. What is it?
Sounded like someone
at the back gate.
Shit. I'll get a flashlight.
Brad, what do you see?
Hang on a second.
Do you see anything?
Are you sure
you heard something?
Lex! Get out of the bedroom!
Get away from the back of the house!
There's someone in the back yard!
Run!
Lock the doors!
You see anyone in back?
I can't see!
He went around the side.
- Let me see.
- Stay in the bathroom.
- Lexi, what do you see?
- I can't see--
Lex! Get back in the bathroom!
Get away from the door, Lexi!
He's on that side
of the house!
Brad? I can't see him!
Help!
Timmy, what is it?
Oh, God.
Timmy?
What, what, what?
What is it?
I saw something in the window.
Lexi!
What is that?
Someone's out there!
Lock the door and stay in the bathroom.
- Brad, what is it? Brad!
- I can't see!
I'm gonna check around back.
- Who is it?
- Come on, it's me Rick!
Rick?
Lexi!
Oh, my God.
It's Rick!
- What?
- Oh, my God! Thank God.
Are you okay?
- Are you okay?
- No, I was downtown.
What the fuck is he doing here?
- I was downtown.
- Oh, fuck.
Oh, my God.
Thank God it's you.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm in trouble.
- Where's Brad?
- He's safe. He sealed himself in.
- Good. That's good.
- Yesterday, he didn't know where I was.
No, he's doing the right thing.
Oh, that's terrific.
Lexi!
I've been trying to get a hold of you.
Gail said she couldn't
get in touch with you, either.
Hey, Lexi, I need to talk to you.
- We gotta get help.
- Yeah, but--
They're setting up an airlock
at the children's hospital.
I'm going.
You can come with me.
No, we're supposed to stay put
if we want antibiotics.
- The news said stay--
- No! Fuck that! Fuck that!
- There's a Navy ship docking off of--
- Lex!
Oh, my God, Rick.
Don't go near that man.
There's a Navy medical ship
docking off of San Pedro.
Really?
We gotta get help.
Lexi!
Rick, here.
Here, here!
Lexi!
- What?
- I need to talk to you.
What?
Brad, there's a Navy ship
at San Pedro--
Don't get near that guy.
He's got real information.
He could be fucking worse off than you.
- What?
- He sounds awful.
So what, Brad?
I sound awful.
You never really liked him, anyway.
The guy's a scumbag.
You told me that!
Are you fucking kidding me?
He's dying. I'm dying.
Stop playing God.
What is that supposed to mean?
Fuck.
All we have to do is get on the right side
of the barricades at the hospital.
Okay? Let's go.
Come on, we gotta do something, all right?
Okay, we'll go.
- Okay?
- Fuck.
Symptoms continue to worsen.
The first round of medicine--
You're right. I'm sorry. I just--
It's just that I feel like, I guess,
that I should be taking you to the hospital.
I think it's a good idea,
it's just--
All over the news they're just saying--
Fuck the news.
Baby, fuck the news.
We're dying.
I gotta go.
I gotta take Timmy, too.
Listen, are you--
Are you sure that you want to go out there?
It's my only chance.
I have to go.
I'm gonna be back, okay?
I have no choice.
I promise.
...clearly in over their heads.
- They are understaffed...
- Fuck.
...and you know, quite frankly,
they seem ill-equipped.
As soon as they receive any
new information from the labs,
they disseminate it through
the crowd on slips of paper.
Information about the toxin
is still being analyzed
in remote labs.
No official understanding
of its dangers is available.
It's understood to be a viral hybrid
which attacks the respiratory system first.
Symptoms have rapidly increased
as precious time continues to slide by.
Sir, I'm Corporal Marshall from
the Special Emergency
Medical Epidemiology Nexus.
Jesus Christ.
I need you to remain inside your house
and answer the following questions.
Were you anywhere
near the accident?
No.
My wife was.
Are you the one that called the hotline?
Yeah.
My wife's been locked
outside for two days
because that's what
you said to-- said to do.
Do you have any children?
- What?
- Do you have any children?
- No.
- Do you have any pets?
- Do you have a gun?
No. Wha--
What? What is this?
How well is your house sealed?
It's very sealed.
Keep your house sealed
and remain inside.
Is your wife around back?
No.
She, uh...
She walked to--
She walked to the hospital.
Sir, we need everyone to stay home
until we do a pre-screening process.
Have you or your wife started coughing?
Yeah, I mean--
- You?
- Not me.
I need you to stay
inside your house if you want to live.
And if your wife returns,
you instruct her to stay put.
Do you guys have any medicine?
We're surveying each household
and gathering data
and trying to decide what to do.
We cannot leave medicine behind.
We cannot waste any medicine on a maybe.
My wife's not a "maybe."
We don't know the full limits
or lethality of the toxic ash yet.
Has she been inside?
Well, I mean...
I mean...
You know, not really.
She has?
She hasn't been inside,
but she broke a window.
- Did you touch her?
- No, I didn't touch her.
She-- She just--
Used her cell phone
and broke a window, and--
Did the toxin get inside?
I don't think so.
I mean, there might have--
been a little something on it.
I threw a rug over it.
- Did you reseal the window?
- Yeah.
Right away.
How long ago did she break it?
Um, like, uh--
Like, a day, day and a half.
You have an air-conditioning system?
No, it's 100 fucking degrees in here.
I'll need you to gather a sample for me.
There's ash all over the street.
We've gathered that already.
I need a sample of the ash
that your wife was in contact with.
I'm not opening the door.
Which window did she break?
She, uh--
She broke a window in the back.
It's right here, sir.
Put some in a bag, and put it
through the broken window pane.
And I want you to put
some plastic on the inside
and seal it up,
make it air-tight.
I'm not touching that stuff.
Put some in a bag.
What about my wife?
I can't answer that question
at this time, sir.
It won't kill you,
and after we're downtown,
we'll have it analyzed.
All right.
Fuck.
Here, I'll put this
through the center for--
We'll check in later.
Keep inside your house
and keep it sealed.
It's your only chance of survival.
Yeah, what kind of chance?
Stay put.
And instruct your wife to do the same.
If she returns, refrain from contact.
Why can't you guys just
tell me what's going on?
I mean, what's the big fucking secret?
We're not trying to cause
any more panic than there already is.
Yeah.
1621 Russell Avenue.
Red tag.
What the fuck does that mean, red tag?
What does that mean?
Where are you guys fucking going?
Son of a bitch.
Hey!
What the fuck are you guys doing?
I answered all your fucking questions.
If you're not gonna fucking do anything,
get out of my house!
Listen, if you don't have
any fucking medicine,
then get the fuck out of my house, okay?
What he fuck are you guys doing?
Get out of my house.
What are you looking for?
If you're not gonna help me,
get the fuck out of my house!
...is researching its properties.
Increased dosages do not
seem to help, either.
The extensive search
for those who fled downtown
in Beverly Hills
and in L.A.X. has heightened.
The president has activated another
5,000 more reserves in Southern California.
Please stay inside your homes.
The 24-hour curfew for
Los Angeles County
remains in effect.
Please stay inside...
Brad?
Brad!
Jesus-fucking Christ.
Lex, did you get help?
- No, I couldn't get in.
- What?
They took Timmy.
They ran through the crowd,
and they took all the children.
- They were giving them medicine.
- Well, that's good.
The cops got Rick.
They shoved five guys in a van--
Took off.
- I just started running.
- You gotta get away from the street.
Those medical people came by today.
They're not doctors.
They're fucking soldiers.
Lex!
Lexi, please go around back!
Lex, get around to the back of the house!
- What is this?
- Who cares what it is!
- What does it mean?
- Who cares what it fucking means!
- You gotta go around back!
- It's gotta be bad.
Lexi, please!
- Would you please go around back?
- Okay.
Do not leave your homes.
What the fuck is this?
Fuck!
Lexi!
There's fucking thousands of people
at the hospital.
They're pushing
and they're screaming,
and and they're climbing over each other.
There's people jumping
from a parking garage
across an alley way into a window.
And cop cars are blocking the doors.
I mean, what is that?
Fuck!
Motherfuckers!
Oh, Brad.
I mean, what is that?
That's not help.
No one's coming here with medicine.
Maybe you should
go rest in the bedroom.
I'm good here.
The air feels good.
What is it?
I don't know.
Baby, get in the back.
Go in the bedroom.
Lex, where are you?
It's dead birds.
There's dead birds everywhere.
Are you okay?
I'm okay!
I'm okay, it's just me.
It's just me.
Lexi, it's me.
Listen, I'm gonna head downtown,
and I'm gonna come and get you.
Just call me and tell me that you're okay.
I love you.
I'm leaving now.
Lexi, it's Mom.
I hope you're getting help.
Dad needs to speak with--
You know how he is.
Jason is up at the house, too.
We're worried sick.
Please call us, sweetie.
We love you, okay?
We love you.
Lexi, it's me, Rich.
No one was at the office,
and Gail said she couldn't reach you.
I'm headed your way.
Lex, it's Gail.
I love you.
That's all.
I...
I pray that you're safe.
Lexi, it's Mom.
We love you.
I know that you know that.
We're praying for you, baby.
Please call us.
Lex, it's Jason.
I talked to Mom, and--
if you get this--
I don't know.
I love you.
If there's anything I can do,
if I can-- just call me.
I'll do anything.
Mom 's driving me fucking crazy.
I don't know what to say.
All I know is I miss you.
Call us.
Bye.
Lex! Are you okay?
What the hell is going on?
- It's bad.
- I know. Mom said--
- Where are you?
- It's really bad, Jas.
Fucking Christ, Lexi!
Listen, there's nothing
anyone can do, okay?
I just...
I just want to talk to you.
What? Lexi, did you get help?
Did you go to the hospital?
They said on the news that there--
Jason, I tried.
There's nothing I can do!
Lexi--
Please just talk to me, okay?
I just want to hear your voice.
Just talk, okay?
Please?
Jason?
What do you want to talk about?
I don't know.
Anything.
How are you?
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
It's okay if you can't.
I, um...
I drove by the house
with Dad yesterday.
- You did?
- Yeah.
How is he?
He's... the same.
The house is brown now.
- No! Really?
- Yeah. Really ugly.
- Weird.
- Yeah.
Lexi, are you okay?
Lexi?
Listen...
I gonna go, okay?
What? Don't.
- I'm tired.
- Don't.
- Jason--
- Lexi, is there anything I can do?
I'm gonna go be with Brad.
I love you, Jason.
No, don't hang up!
Don't--
The president is set to hold
a press conference tonight
where he will ask for assistance
from other allied nations
for professional and scientific relief.
In the meantime, National Guard reservists
continue to be briefed at
Edwards Air Force Base
and then bused into the neighborhoods.
You know...
you did an amazing thing.
What?
You saved Timmy.
Brad...
I'm sorry for...
anything...
Ugly.
No, I'm--
I don't know.
The fights seem--
Stupid fights seem stupider now.
They seemed stupid the other night.
Yeah. It's just...
I was...
working so much and keeping so busy
and thinking about the future.
We were...
When we were getting married,
I had doubts about you and me.
Why are you telling me this?
I don't know.
I never had any.
What else should we talk about?
Why don't we talk about
the children that we never had.
We would have screwed them up anyway.
You know what's gonna happen, right?
We're gonna...
end up on one
of those daytime talk shows.
Like a... a real sappy one,
you know?
I mean, we'll take their calls, and...
I'll ramble on about how we managed...
to survive and, you know,
all about how much
I love you, and how much...
You mean to me.
You're the reason
I get out of bed every morning, and...
how you make...
my life complete.
We'll just-- We'll rip their hearts out.
We'll jam 'em right through
the phone lines.
You'll tell 'em how we met?
Your version or my version?
The only version.
I love you.
How much?
To Catalina and back.
Oh, fuck.
I'm sorry.
No.
It's not our fault.
You stay with me, okay?
I need you to stay.
Listen, baby,
you'll be okay.
It's okay.
I'm okay.
Brad!
Let me in! Brad!
Don't you touch her!
Don't fuckin' touch her!
Let go of her!
- Get the fuck off of her!
- Brad!
Open my fucking door!
Don't you fucking touch her!
We're here to help you!
Get your hands off of her!
Let go of her!
Don't you fucking touch her!
You motherfuckers!
Get the man!
Stay put!
Don't fucking move!
Your wife is safe.
The best thing you could have done
was to keep her sealed right outside here.
What?
The toxic level in your house
has reached an irreversible level.
Your airtight house has incubated
the ash into an airborne hybrid.
You've created a breeding ground
for the poison.
What are you saying?
The air in your house
is a deadly supply,
and you're a lethal carrier.
I'm sorry, sir, but there's
nothing we can do.
Please don't struggle.
Wait a minute!
What'd you do with my wife?
Hey!
Jesus Christ.
Oh, fuck!
Hey!
Hey, stop!
Fuck!
Stop!
I'm still in here!
Stop it! I'm still alive!
I can't breathe!
Please fucking stop!
Lexi!
I'm still alive!
Brad! Brad, get out!
- Help me!
- Let go!
Somebody help him!
No!
I'm still alive, you fucking assholes!
Come on, come on, come on!
Somebody help him!
I'm still alive!
No! Brad!
Help him!
Pump the gas for another 20 minutes.
It'll suffocate the disease.
There's nothing we could have
done for your husband.
The virus has grown to an
uncontrollable proportion inside the house.
It's lethal.
The condition is irreversible.
Say a prayer.
You might just make it.
Condemned structures will be razed,
barreled, and shipped
to an undisclosed location
for final analysis.
Plans to honor the specialized rescue teams
are underway in Washington.
Subtitled By J.R. Media Services, Inc.
Burbank, CA