Space exploration began with dreaming.
Thousands of years of humans staring
into the heavens and wondering, "How
did this begin? What else is out there?"
The earliest answers
were given in myth and poetry.
Now, they are sought
by space-age technology.
And while each mission increases
our knowledge,
it also leads our imagination
further and further.
How did life begin? Did it happen
more than once in the universe?
The answer may lie on Mars.
ROVING MARS
Mars today is desolate, dry, and barren.
And at first glance, has little in
common with our own planet.
And yet from orbit, we see what looked
like dried-up lakebeds and canyons.
Clues that three or four billion years ago,
Mars may once have been wetter and
more Earth-like.
And since life blossomed here on Earth,
the question is:
Did it ever take place on Mars?
To answer this question, NASA's jet
propulsion laboratory brought together a team
of scientists and engineers whose mission
was to discover if Mars ever had
what was needed to support life.
A geologist and astronomer at
Cornell University,
Steve Squyres, was chosen to lead
the science team.
As principal investigator, he would direct
the team's search for
life's most essential resource: water.
I've been working on the question of water
on Mars for twenty-eight years.
You can't learn what you need from
a telescope. You must be a geologist.
A geologist is sort of like a detective
at the scene of a crime.
Um, somethin' happened here a long time ago.
What happened?
Was it warm? Was it wet?
Could life have existed here?
The key is in the clues and the
clues are in the rocks.
On Earth, a geologist can find
an interesting rock,
crack it open with a hammer,
and just look at what's inside.
But we're not ready to send
human geologist to Mars yet.
So we had to build a robot geologist.
And the only place this could be done
was NASA's jet propulsion laboratory
where some of the most innovative
engineers in the country work.
We're talking about a robot.
A rover that can go to Mars,
land on the surface, take a look around,
and then cut the cord and go
carrying everything it needs with it:
cameras, instruments, communications
equipment. Everything.
Something that can look inside rocks
and that can tell us
what clues those rocks hold.
This place, to me, is almost sacred.
This is the place where our rovers
are assembled for the last time
before they leave this planet.
Everything that we do in this room must
be perfect.
Over four thousand people have worked
on this mission.
For every single piece of this spacecraft
down to the tiniest one,
there was a person somewhere who conceived
it. Who nurtured it.
Who took it from a concept to
something real.
It's taken this team three years to design
and build and test these rovers
and we still have work to do.
We can only launch when the two planets are
properly aligned
and that's just a month away.
But we still have tests to run.
We're working in shifts.
We're working almost around the clock
and we don't know if we're gonna make it.
There's no one person who can really get
their arms around the whole thing and say
"I understand everything about this vehicle."
It's now burst the bounds
of our brains.
Well this rover is-is more than just
a roving geologist.
This rover also has to be a-a spacecraft.
It actually has to fly itself from
Earth to Mars.
In addition, it has to do the very subtle
and quick timing control
of all the things that happen as it enters
and lands the vehicle.
We had to stuff all that intelligence
and capability into
that little six-wheel vehicle back there, so
that it could get there safely on its own.
I call our spacecraft "The Origami Spacecraft,"
which means it's really
a complicated series of folds.
We've had to punch holes in the lander
pedals for the wheels to snake through.
We've had to fold everything into these
complicated shapes to get this system
to fit inside this tetrahedron.
It's beautiful, but at a price.
And that price in this case is complexity.
There have been missions to Mars
since the sixties.
There've been dozens of them.
But two-thirds of those missions failed.
Mars is a spacecraft graveyard.
A spacecraft has to travel about three
hundred million miles to get to Mars
at about sixty thousand miles an hour.
But it still takes seven months
to get there.
Trying to hit our landing sites from that
distance is like shooting a basketball
from Los Angeles to New York and having it
go through the hoop without touching the rim.
The smallest mistake on our part
could put the whole mission in jeopardy.
Two of the last three missions
to Mars were failures.
One spacecraft burned up in
the Martian atmosphere,
the other one crashed on the surface.
This time, NASA decided to send
two identical spacecraft
to double our chances of success.
The two rovers are named Spirit
and Opportunity.
The rovers have very different
personalities.
They did even when they were babies,
back when we were first building 'em.
Spirit was our troublesome first-born.
Every test we ran, it seemed
that we ran on Spirit first
and the first time you try
something it usually doesn't work.
So we'd run these tests on Spirit and
they'd fail and we'd try to fix things
and we'd run another test
and that would fail too.
By the time we got to Opportunity,
we'd learn stuff and things
went much more smoothly.
The biggest problem was that we
underestimated the size and weight
of the rovers. Once we realized how
big they really had to be,
we also realized that the
landing system we planned to use
couldn't get them to the ground
in one piece.
As the rover got heavier,
the lander got heavier.
As the lander got heavier,
the arrow shell got heavier.
The whole thing got heavier
and heavier and heavier.
From the very beginning on this mission,
it seemed like nothing was going right.
The air bags are like the air bags in
your car but way more expensive.
They inflate explosively around the
vehicle and they cushion the landing.
The first time we tested them,
they tore open and deflated.
The setbacks we knew
they are going to happen.
I always tell people when
you start these projects.
Uh, the same thing probably what happened
to Lewis and Clark and, uh,
Captain Cook in their exploration.
Uh, what is guaranteed is that
there will be setbacks.
Three...two...one.
These rovers have to land
using a supersonic parachute.
The parachute design we
thought would work ripped to shreds.
The lander had gotten so heavy that
the chute just couldn't handle it.
We were practically out of time and
all we had was a chute design
would destroy
the spacecraft when we tried to land.
We had to build a whole 'nother set of new designs.
No less than three or four
designs that we had to test
We were running out of money,
we were running out of time.
Uh, well, I mean, the drop was successful.
Yeah.
See, uh, the fact that, uh, the parachute
exploded...not a good thing.
Well, yeah, I'd rather have it
happen here than any place else.
Mars.
Yeah.
That's right. Unfortunately, strictly
speaking, that chute that just exploded
was the chute that we
were planning on taking to Mars.
Mars is a tough place to send a spacecraft.
The average temperature is sixty degrees
below zero.
It goes down to a hundred below zero
at night.
There can be dust storms
that darken the skies for months at a time.
But if the rovers make it, they'll give us
the experience of
what it would be like to be on Mars.
We'll be able to look off into the distance
and say, "Yeah. I'd like to go there,"
and then actually go and see what we find.
The rover's arm has the same dimensions
as a human arm with a shoulder,
an elbow, and a wrist. The arm tucks up
tight under the front of the vehicle
for when we drive around. But when
we get to a rock that we want to examine,
the arm unstows and reaches out
using all of its joints
to place the instruments on a rock
and to begin to study them.
The hand has four fingers. One is a
microscope, two are spectrometers
to tell us, in detail, what the rocks are made of.
And the fourth one is called the RAT.
The Rock Abrasion Tool.
MARS
To examine the rocks, we've got to
get to them and Mars is very bumpy.
So to deal with the bumps, our engineers
came up with something called a
rocker-bogie suspension system. It's a very
clever design that allows each of
the six wheels to go up and over
a rock independently
while the rover itself hardly tilts at all.
'Kay. Come on in, guys.
Now stay clear, watch it. Watch it.
Stay clear of this thing 'cause
it's gonna move in a second.
Watch! Watch the wheels. Watch the wheels.
Watch the wheels. Now watch.
It goes way beyond this single mission.
See that?
The eventual goal is to send humans to Mars.
But the first person to walk on
Mars is not an astronaut today.
It's someone in high school.
Or in elementary school.
So it's turnin' in place, then when it gets
lined up just right,
we're gonna drive it backwards.
We've invested so much work...
so many years...
so much of our hopes and our
dreams into these rovers.
And then when you think about
where they're going,
the ride they're gonna get on
that rocket, the transit through space,
what it's gonna be like when
that parachute goes out
at mach two goin' through
the Martian atmosphere....
You're standing next to this little robot
and you realize it's gonna spend eternity on
the surface of another world.
It's goin' to another planet for real.
And once they're gone, that's it.
After the rovers launch,
we're never gonna see
them again with our own eyes.
We've done everything we can to prepare them
for the dangers they'll have to face.
But it's gonna be very hard to say goodbye.
NASA
Spirit will be launched first, then
Opportunity, three weeks later.
Mars and Earth are both orbiting the sun so
they're always moving
relative to each other.
Every twenty-six months,
there's a brief interval when the
planets are lined up just right.
At that time, and only at that time,
we have enough rocket fuel to make it.
So this is our one shot.
We don't fire a rocket motor
all the way to Mars.
We don't need to. We just place the
spacecraft on a trajectory
to Mars and let it
coast for seven months and three hundred
million miles until it reaches the planet.
Once it's been pushed on it's way
to Mars by the launch vehicle
it has to, uh, maintain its orientation
toward the sun and it needs to be able
to correct its orientation and
direction so that it would hit Mars
and-and get to this very, very tiny,
uh, spot on Mars that we're aiming for.
So all that has to take place over the
course of the seven month journey.
7 MONTHS AFTER LAUNCH
SPIRIT LANDING DAY
Planning is when the real challenge begins.
Mars is so far away it takes about ten
minutes for a radio signal to travel
one way between Mars and Earth.
But it's only six minutes from when
you first hit the top of the Martian
atmosphere to when
we're bouncing on the surface.
So there's nothing we can do
to help when it's time to land.
The rovers are on their own, and we're just
passive, passionately interested observers
waiting for a radio signal that shows
whether or not they've survived.
Not going to be an issue. The current
reported temperature is about zero degrees
Celsius which, um, is close to the
limit-- the flight allowable limit.
However...
Landing a spacecraft on Mars is so complicated.
There are so many things that can go wrong.
The flight computer has to know precisely
the right time to deploy the parachute.
If it deploys it too high, when the
parachute opens the wind forces
will just rip it to shreds.
If we deploy the parachute too low of an
altitude, it won't open in time
and it
will just crash right into the ground.
The trick is, every time there's
some critical event:
the parachute deploys, the heat
shield falls away, we change the frequency
of the radio signal.
And so Polly's sitting at her console and
she's looking for these changing frequencies
and when the number changes,
she knows that this event has happened.
That event has happened.
Flight director, Jason Willis, reporting
that all systems are go for entry
descent and landing.
We are roughly eleven minutes,
forty-eight seconds from landing at the
Gusev Crater
in the southern hemisphere of Mars.
Atmospheric entry in three...two...one.
We have just passed one minute
to atmospheric entry.
Current altitude: one hundred
and twenty-one miles.
Current velocity: twelve thousand
eighty-four miles per hour.
We are now at an altitude
of seventy-three miles,
moving at a speed of twelve thousand
one hundred ninety-two miles per hour.
Expected parachute deploy in five seconds.
Four...three...two...one...mark.
We're awaiting confirmation the
parachute has deployed.
Parachute's been detected.
Heat shield deployed event.
Uh, spacecraft reporting that heat
shield has indeed jettisoned...
Spacecraft reporting lander has separated.
Moving at a speed of
one hundred seventy-three miles per hour.
We are near our terminal velocity.
Expected retro rocket ignition on my mark.
Mark.
At this point in time,
we should be on the ground.
Any signal that we receive from now
indicates the vehicle would be alive,
on the ground, and bouncing.
The spacecraft has to survive all the
bounces for the landing to be a success.
No signal at the moment.
Standby.
Signal strength is currently intermittent.
We don't see a signal at the moment.
Right. We saw an intermittent signal
that indicated we were bouncing
however...however, we currently
do not have signal from the spacecraft.
Okay.
Please stand by.
This time, we're approximately ten minutes
after landing.
The vehicle should have
rolled to a stop by now.
The deep space network stations at Goldstone
and Canberra are still searching for the signal.
They see it.
What do we see?
We've got the signal!
The first thing we have to do after
we land is open our solar panels
to the sun so we'll have some power.
This charges up the batteries.
After that, we can deploy the camera
mast so the rover can see
and deploy the antenna so
the rover can talk to us.
Our first pictures from Mars!
Look at that!
That's looking down on our vehicle.
We could not have imaged returns
as early as this, as clear as this,
as successful as this, and in the
volume that it has been.
Uh, ladies and gentlemen, Mars.
We sent Spirit to Gusev Crater, a crater
in the southern highlands of Mars.
It's a hundred miles in diameter.
What makes it special is that emptying
into it is a giant watercarved channel.
So Gusev is a hole in the ground
with a dry river flowing into it.
There has to have been a lake
in this crater once upon a time.
We sent Spirit there to seek out sediments.
To look for sedimentary rocks that
were laid down long ago in that lake.
Once we landed, I think the scariest
part of the whole mission
was the initial unfolding of the rover.
There are so many gears and springs
and motors and hinges and latches
that have to work just right or you're done.
Once everything's deployed,
we're ready to start lookin' around.
We can look off into the distance with our
cameras and with our infrared spectrometer,
and we can learn a lot from a distance of
fifty yards, a hundred yards about what the
look like and what they're made of.
Then, if we see a rock that has a texture or
a composition that looks interesting to us,
we can drive over to it
and check it out in detail.
For driving, the rover has these kinda
googly-eyed cameras that it uses
to take images of the terrain in front
of it. They've got wide-angle lenses
and they provide sort of a fish-eye view.
Spirit uses these pictures to
make it's own decisions about how to drive.
It'll drive forward and then take
a look at a rock and say,
"That's too big, I have to go around that."
Or, maybe it'll see smooth sailing
and just move on.
But we can actually program different
levels of courage or cowardice
into the rover, telling it how aggressive it
should be depending on how dangerous
we think the terrain is.
These rovers are so complicated, that it
takes hours to get a set of commands right.
So when we operate 'em, we'll normally
send commands to them just once a day.
The first rock that we looked at was this
one. We named it Adirondack.
When a rock sits on the surface of a planet,
it can undergo what's called 'weathering.'
When it's exposed to sunlight or humidity
or wind, the surface of the rock
can be modified and the evidence of
how it formed can be destroyed.
So to get to the clues you need,
you have to get inside the rock
below the weathered surface.
The key to understanding Adirondack
was the rock abrasion tool.
The RAT gives us the ability to grind into a
rock, exposing the unaltered
evidence inside.
So we put a RAT hole into Adirondack
and then we hit it with everything we had.
We looked at it with our cameras,
we looked at it with our spectrometers,
we looked at it with our microscope.
Adirondack is a piece of lava.
It's not a sedimentary rock.
And every other rock around it
is a piece of lava too. This was a huge
disappointment.
We came to Gusev Crater looking
for sediments that were laid down
long ago in a lake, but what we
found was lava. Volcanic rock.
The sedimentary rock must be there but it's
been buried under the lava
and we couldn't get to it.
When we realized that we hadn't
landed on the stuff we came for,
we decided we had to go some place else.
A mile and a half away,
there's this spectacular range
of hills called the Columbia Hills.
You gotta remember that Spirit was designed
to go only six hundred yards
over its lifetime.
So we set out for those hills not
knowin' if we'd ever make it.
Meanwhile, on the other side of Mars,
Opportunity was about to land.
When Opportunity landed at Eagle Crater,
it was a three-hundred million mile
interplanetary hole-in-one.
We rolled to a stop right in
front of layered bedrock.
Bedrock is geologic truth. Opportunity
landed in front of a Martian history book.
When we drove off the lander
and looked at the soil in front of us,
we saw that it was littered with what looked
like little round beads.
An uncountable number
of little round things.
We took out our microscope,
we reached out,
and looked at the soil in detail and
the picture that came down was astounding.
They were perfect spheres.
I will remember for the rest of my life
how I felt when I saw that first picture.
When we got to the outcrop
and looked at it up close, we realized
that the spheres are embedded in the
rock, like blueberries in a muffin.
The rock erodes away and
the blueberries fall out.
And roll down into the soil.
The blueberries, it turns out,
are made of hematite,
a mineral that on Earth is
often formed in liquid water.
Next, we found jarosite, which is a
mineral that couldn't have formed
unless there had been water in the rocks.
So there was water underground here.
Our most extraordinary discovery
came when we found ripples in the rocks.
Ancient ripples that formed when water
flowed over sand on Mars
billions of years ago.
So there wasn't just water underground
here... there was water at the surface.
Opportunity discovered that
at this place billions of years ago,
Mars was most
likely a habitable world.
It was a place that, for some interval of
time, was suitable for some forms of life.
Decades of work paid off with this discovery.
Billions of years ago there were shallow,
occasional pools of water.
Don't think an ocean, think of salt flats.
And the water may not have
been a pretty blue.
In fact, it may have been so acid
it dissolved iron out of the rocks
and made wine-red pools under a
pink Martian sky.
All the discoveries that Opportunity
made about water
happened in the first six weeks of the mission.
Everything went right for that rover.
I call Opportunity
"Little Miss Perfect".
Opportunity lands in this place
where the evidence is right there.
The driving is
like a parking lot. Everything is perfect.
Spirit, our kinda tough hard-working
blue collar rover lands
in this awful, rocky, rugged place
on a lava plane a mile and a half from
the nearest interesting rocks and has to
struggle for five months
just to begin her mission.
Spirit had to work for everything,
literally had to climb a mountain on Mars.
We use the power that comes from the
sun to operate the vehicle
and to charge the batteries.
So the solar arrays are essential.
On the way to the Columbia Hills, Spirit's
solar rays were getting coated with dust.
We were getting to the point where
Spirit was simply gonna die.
Then, one wonderful day we, climbed
up onto the crest of a ridge where
we were hit by not one but several gusts of
wind that just cleaned the solar arrays off.
It was like having a brand new rover.
Spirit got high up in the Columbia Hills
and started to find stuff that was different
from anything we'd seen.
There were salt deposits in
the hills and there were rocks
that clearly had been altered by water.
It took months of work and struggle
but Spirit finally showed us there had
been water on both sides of the planet.
She gave us exactly what we needed.
These rovers were designed
to last only ninety Mars days
and they've already done many times that.
They've developed personalities.
They're work horses. They say,
"Push us. Ask us to do more.
We can go further, we can go faster."
So we asked so much more
than they were ever intended to.
And to our amazement, they'd do it.
We don't know what will kill these rovers;
they do get old, motors break,
lubrication goes away in the motors,
the wheels may stop turning.
We have no idea what will happen.
But they're not gonna last forever.
And as the dust keeps falling,
the solar arrays keep getting dirty.
What could happen, with time,
is some day we won't be able
to charge the batteries enough
to keep the rover warm at night.
And if that happens,
the rover's going to get too cold.
And one morning, it just won't wake up.
Spirit and Opportunity have shown us that
once, three to four billion years ago,
Mars had the essential ingredients for life.
So the next step is to seek out evidence
of life itself. Right now,
we have one example of life. Us.
We may be all there is.
We simply don't know.
But if you can show that life
developed twice in one solar system
and then you considere the
multitude of solar systems out there,
it takes no great leap of imagination to
believe that
life might be a common phenomenon
throughout the universe.
Our rovers have gone farther, harder,
and longer than even we, their creators,
believed possible. They've done heroic work.
But some day we won't need robots.
Some day, there'll be humans on the surface
of Mars and boot prints in our wheel tracks.
This mission has put us on
a great trajectory to learn
more about Mars and about ourselves.
But right now, Spirit and Opportunity
are still roving Mars.
It's not just
that they've exceeded our wildest dreams.
In many ways, they are our wildest dreams.