Help!
- Eddie!
- What?
Eddie! Wake up!
- Don't move. Okay, Listen to me.
- Where are we?
- Whatever you do, don't lean forward.
- What's this? What's...
- What's going on?
- No!
Hello. I want to play a game.
The devices on your heads are symbolic of
the shackles that you place upon others.
You recklessly loan people money,
knowing their financial limitations,
counting on repossessing more
than they could ever pay back.
You are predators, but
today, you become the prey.
And it is your own pound
of flesh that I demand.
This is your fault!
The scale before you is
your only path to freedom.
However, only one of you may pass,
and the toll is the ultimate sacrifice,
the sacrifice of flesh.
Before you are the instruments
to exact this flesh.
Move with haste, though,
for when the 60-second timer hits zero,
the one who has given the most
flesh will release their bindings,
while the gears on your opponent's
head will engage, piercing their skull.
Who will offer the most flesh
order to save their life?
The choice is yours.
No!
I'm not dying for you, bitch!
I ask you, Special Agent Strahm,
have you learned enough to trust me?
For if you do not, this room
will forever be your tomb.
You will never be heard from again,
your body will never be found,
and my legacy will become yours.
Make your choice.
There was a pre-existing condition,
which you did not inform
your insurance company of.
Thank you.
Hey, babe. Good. Listen, I am so,
so sorry, but I can't make dinner.
I've got to work late again.
well, I've got to meet with legal,
and that's going to jam me up for,
certainly, the rest of the afternoon.
I know it's your birthday. I'm going
to make it up to you, I promise.
Love you.
- What were we talking about?
- We're talking about your deposition.
Don't worry about me, Debbie.
Some small-time lawyer
trying to squeeze us
is not gonna get me to say
anything I don't want to say.
I have no doubt about that,
but as lead counsel for this company,
if you screw up, it comes down on my ass.
So what do you say we
prep your deposition?
Christ.
Do you remember dealing
with a Mr. Harold Abbott?
William, I have a Casey
Patterson on line 1.
Take another message, Addy.
I'll get back to her this week.
Some time. Keep going.
When opposing counsel asks you about
Mr. Abbott, how will you respond?
I am going to respond by saying,
as Senior Vice President
of Membership and Claims,
it is my job to review
every terminated policy.
As a matter of fact, Mr. Abbott
was sitting right where you are now
when we discussed his appeal.
I just... I don't get it.
I've been with this insurance
company for over 10 years.
I know, Harold. But, unfortunately,
when we reviewed your claim,
we discovered that you failed
to mention a previous condition.
What condition? There was no condition.
It says here you had oral surgery
to remove a cyst from yourjaw.
This is absurd! I have heart disease.
It has nothing to do with some
oral surgery I had 30 years ago.
Any type of oral surgery is
going to leave scar tissue.
Scar tissue can lead to gum disease.
And, as you well know, gum
disease can cause heart disease.
You know what? You're...
You're a criminal.
You are a goddamn criminal.
I paid my monthly premium for 10
years without so much as a cold.
And now that I'm actually sick,
you're going to deny my coverage?
- I have a family!
- Those are the rules, Harold.
I'm sorry, but your own
actions have caused this.
You've just given me a death sentence.
I mean, who's going to cover me now?
You just killed me.
I have family, too, so I can
empathize with his argument.
But, basically, the guy
lied on his application.
- Hey. Watch it, Will.
- What?
Do you think he did that on purpose?
All right.
It wasn't my job to assess
what his intentions were.
It was my job to check
the accuracy of his claim.
Look, everybody thinks
we're the bad guys.
Nobody mentions the millions of
people help every year without incident
or the millions of dollars we
donate to charity every year
or all the free clinics we support.
- Short answers, Will. Short answers.
- Today in probate court,
the assets for one of history's most
notorious serial killers, John Kramer,
were distributed.
They were mainly in real estate
holdings. But in my time researching...
One more question. Who found
the error on his application?
The dog pit. They work as a team.
If there's a discrepancy to be found in an
application, the six of them will find it.
Sir, they're waiting for
you in the conference room.
Very good.
- How's it going today, people?
- Great, Mr. E.
Found two application errors
for a chronically ill client.
This guy practically lives
at his doctor's office.
I mean, this could probably save
us nearly 200K over his lifetime.
Terminator strikes again.
I'll be back in a few hours.
Looking good, Hank.
Who will offer the most flesh
in order to save their life?
The choice is yours.
I'm not dying for you, bitch!
Yeah.
I'm on my way.
What's going on?
Feds who took over the crime
scene are requesting you ASAP.
Erickson.
I didn't know you ever made
it out from behind the desk.
I make exceptions when fingerprints
are found at a Jigsaw murder scene.
Have a look.
We also got a right index off the scale.
- Been ID'd yet?
- Yeah. They're Agent Strahm's.
When I learned that he and Perez
were being targeted by Jigsaw,
I should have been more aware.
But I didn't see this coming.
Not from Peter Strahm.
- It was a shock to all of us.
- Yeah.
But we have something
he doesn't know about.
You want to follow me?
Lindsey.
- Detective Hoffman.
- Perez.
It was my call, Detective.
I knew that Jigsaw wasn't working alone,
but until I knew for
certain who was helping him,
I couldn't guarantee her well-being.
- So you let me think she was dead?
- well, I didn't know who I could trust.
What else have you been keeping from me?
We know that Agent Strahm knew the
five people in the real estate scam,
the victims from the
traps that Erickson found.
- How'd he know them?
- Strahm and I investigated them
after the house fire.
It was arson and all five
people were accountable.
But after our lone witness went
missing, no charges were ever filed.
Strahm couldn't let them get
away, so he put them in a trap
in which slaughtering each
other was the only way out.
So, what are you telling
me, he's a vigilante?
Call him whatever you like,
but he has to be found.
We'd like to work together on this.
You led me to believe that she was
dead, and you want to work with me?
Look, we're offering full
disclosure, Detective.
From now on, everything we
know, you know. Is that fair?
Detective Hoffman,
how about a quick word?
Pamela Jenkins, the resident
Jigsaw sensationalist.
Just reporting the facts, Detective.
Is that what you're doing? "John
Kramer, conundrum of carnage. "
If you'd like to make a
statement on the record,
I'd be more than happy to take it.
You know, twisting the facts to
make a better story is irresponsible.
Excuse me. Nice catching up.
I know more about John
Kramer than you might think.
Somehow I doubt that.
Kramer left his wife a box in
his will. Did you know that?
Maybe I did, maybe I
didn't. How do you know it?
Probate court. It's public record
for those who know where to look.
All right. What do you really want?
Jill Tuck. Help me get to her and
I'll dial down on the sensationalism.
Really? I'll see what I can do.
Do you remember how you
were transported there?
I don't know how I got there.
Just opened my eyes
and... He did this to me.
Who did this?
Jigsaw.
- You didn't cut your own arm off?
- I did. I did.
But he made me do it.
And why is that?
Because what Eddie and
I were doing was wrong.
We were... We were
ruining people's lives.
And he wanted us to learn.
And did you?
Look at me.
Look at my goddamn arm!
What the fuck am I supposed
to learn from this, huh?
Look at my arm! What... What am
I supposed to learn from this?
- Just breathe.
- Look at me!
Hello, Gideon.
- It's a good name, hon.
- wow.wow.
Could have been Scarlet.
But, no, has to be a boy.
Let me see if I can get
all three of us in there.
Snuggle around here.
Lean inside. There we go.
- There We are.
- Hey, Gideon.
Here's a little happy family.
- We love you, Son. We're waiting for you.
- We love you.
Gideon, Gideon, Gideon.
If you're watching this, Jill,
I'm long gone from this world.
I'm leaving you a box today, and
its contents are of grave importance.
Hello. I'm not in right now,
but please leave a message.
Miss Tuck, this is Pamela
Jenkins calling, yet again.
I was hoping you can clear some
things up for me about your husband.
Let me buy you lunch or a cup of coffee.
I've found something interesting
about John Kramer's death.
Are you there, Detective?
By hearing this tape, you will
likely assume this is over.
You feel you now have
control, don't you?
You think you will walk away untested.
Look here.
These are the Jigsaw pieces
cut from previous victims.
This is the piece taken
from the latest victim.
- It looks like all the rest.
- Yeah, that's what we said, too.
The skin abrasions, they're indicative
of a knife with a partially serrated edge.
- So?
- So, all of the other cuts were made
with a near-perfect
blade of surgical quality.
Obviously, Strahm used a
different knife than John Kramer.
Right. But it got us curious, so
we pulled the files to compare.
That same knife was used
on only one other victim.
And that victim was Seth Baxter,
the man who killed your sister.
You're telling me that you can tell a
different knife was used from a photo?
No, but I can. I was the
one who examined that body.
I've examined every victim
of the Jigsaw Killer.
Good work.
The tape from the latest victim was missing,
so we're looking into the Seth Baxter tape.
- Why's that?
- well, if a different person cut the piece,
then maybe a different
person made the tape, too.
- Strahm?
- Yeah, maybe.
Strahm's voice on that tape
would be our smoking gun.
If we had that, we'd go
public with his involvement.
Hey, Jill.
- But that's not what the prescription...
- I'm sick!
- Look at me! Look at me!
- Hey. It's okay. Sorry.
I didn't expect to see you here so soon.
Change of plans.
- The game begins tonight.
- Why?
Because somebody knows
about the box that shouldn't.
- Who?
- That's not your concern.
All you need to know is that from now
on, I control all aspects of the game.
That's not what John wanted.
Give me the envelopes.
And that's not a request.
Here.
From now on, I work alone.
I know. I'm only carrying
out John's final request.
well, John's dead. And
his work is almost done.
- Who's this?
- Unfinished business.
When I'm done, we no longer speak.
- ... forty-five minutes.
- Yes, I understand that.
- Please! Please.
- But we have to wait for the doctor.
Let my hand go.
Methadone is a masking agent. It
doesn't heal, it simply numbs the senses.
I've found a better way.
These people, they will continue
to hurt you and let you down.
They're addicts, John.
Recovery is a process.
Maybe addiction's just
part of human nature.
But what about these people, Jill,
who come here every day and use you?
They bide their time. They're
avoiding prison sentences.
They're getting hooked on masking
agents. Do you call that recovery?
It's not that simple.
Addiction is not simple, Jill! Wake up!
These people have no respect for
the lives that they're destroying.
Once you see death up close,
then you know what the value of life is.
And that's my way.
And I brought proof that it works.
- Amanda?
- Hello, Jill.
Jill,
you once told me that
she was a lost soul.
But here she stands.
She's clean and whole.
And she has a new
appreciation for her life.
It works. It's real. He helped me.
...as this is not just the
macabre conjectures of a psychic,
but a foregone conclusion just
waiting to rear its ugly head.
Even though police would have you
believe John Kramer, aka Jigsaw, is dead,
just this past week a new so-called
game was discovered with grisly results.
Victims have included anyone associated
with the life of John
Kramer, however remote.
The Jigsaw Killer may be
dead, but the murders continue.
Shit!
Hank, you still here?
Don't fucking move.
Shit! Oh, fuck! Okay.
Okay, I'm gonna take care of you. Just...
Where'd you get hit? You wearing a vest?
Hello, William.
Oh, Jesus.
You've probably been wondering
when we would see each other again.
- Today is that day.
- No!
For years, your probability formula
has decided the fate of others.
The healthy have benefited
while the potentially sick
have been unjustly rejected.
However, this formula does not take
into account the human will to live.
When faced with death,
who should live versus who will live
are two entirely separate things.
Today, your policy
will be put to the test.
There are four straps around your limbs,
and you have four tests you must complete,
for if you don't, the straps on
your arms and legs will detonate.
Look closely.
Oh, shit!
You have 60 minutes to complete your
tests and avoid this fate, starting now.
You are not alone in this game.
Just as you have taken loved
ones away from their families,
if you don't reach the end
before the timer hits zero,
you will never see your family again.
Mom? Mom! Mom. Mom, wake up! Mom.
Mom.
- Where are we?
- I don't know.
- What is this?
- I don't know! Look.
Oh, my God.
Here is your first test.
Your health and hereditary background put
you in the highest category of success.
However, the same cannot
be said for your adversary.
While only 52 years of age,
this man has continued to smoke
even though he has a history of high
blood pressure and heart disease.
This demonstrates very little appreciation
for the blessings of his own life.
Your game will focus on
the simple element of air.
Once this game begins,
every time you take a breath,
the clamps around your chest
will close in and crush your body.
The only escape is in
the other's failure.
So I ask you, when faced
with death, who will survive?
Live or die, William. Make your choice.
- Fuck you!
- Who the hell is that?
Hold your breath!
What the fuck? Oh, Jesus!
Come on! Come on!
Shit!
Please help us!
Help us! Someone,
please! Please! Help us!
Somebody, please! Please!
Please, somebody help!
Anybody?
"Live. Die. " What the fuck?
It's connected to that.
- "H-F." What does that stand
for? - Hydrofluoric acid.
This stuff will eat through
human flesh within seconds.
- What should we do?
- Pull the lever. You want to live, don't you?
What about the timer?
That has to mean something.
I don't know. I don't
even know why we're here.
We're here because of your father.
Miss Jenkins.
Please, this will only take a
second. We can help each other.
What makes you think you can
just come to my door like this?
Because I found something
you'll want to see.
Go on.
- Where'd you get this?
- It was at the location where John died.
- Does it mean anything to you?
- No.
Goodbye, Miss Jenkins.
If you think of anything.
I want to thank you for
sponsoring this party, William.
And I know how much the
clinic appreciates it.
- John Kramer.
- William Easton.
- Kramer? You're Jill's husband, right?
- I am.
- Nice to meet you.
Sounds like we'rw in a
similar business, John.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
well, you try to predict
people's behavior. So do I.
When people come to us for coverage,
we have to analyze each person
for the probability of success.
- How do you do that?
- well, it's a formula.
It's pretty complicated, actually,
but, in essence, it breaks
down to monthly payments
multiplied by lifespan minus
the probability of illness.
And if the sum is positive,
we consider coverage.
- Who devised that formula?
- Me.
So, in a sense, you
choose who lives or dies.
No. I... No, I'd say I decide
which people have the potential
But you're not taking into consideration
the most important human element of all.
- Which is what?
- The will to live.
Until a person is faced with death,
it's impossible to tell whether
they have what it takes to survive.
Fuck that.
Shit.
Hello, William.
Standing on the platforms behind
me are two of your colleagues.
One, your file clerk, a young,
healthy male with no living relatives.
The other, a middle-aged woman
with a family history of diabetes.
According to your policy, your
secretary is older and weaker
and therefore less worthy to survive.
But you know the loss that
she will be to her family,
while young Allen will disappear
without a blip on the world's radar.
Only one can exit this room, and
the choice of whom falls upon you.
You must let go of one to
save the life of the other.
As you can see, the
choice is not so clear
when you are face to face with the
people whose blood will stain your hands.
Let the game begin.
Wait! No! No, wait! I won't
do this! I won't do this!
William!
It's a business! My decisions
aren't made this way!
No, I'm not gonna do
it! I'm not gonna do it!
I'm not gonna do it!
- Stop!
- Please! Help me!
- I'm sorry.
- No! No!
I'm sorry.
Thank you. Thank you!
You try to find a way out of here,
Addy. I have to keep going. Be careful.
What if we put acid on the metal bars?
It'll eat through the metal, won't it?
Yeah, but how are we going to get
it on the bars? With our hands?
What are you looking at?
I wonder... The mirror.
- What?
- Who's behind the glass?
What do you want?
Why are you doing this?
Help me, please! Please, help me!
Hello, Pamela. You've
sensationalized my life,
twisting the truth and exploiting
my message for your own benefit.
- Hoffman.
- It's Erickson.
- We found the Seth Baxter tape.
- Yeah?
But there was something else that
we wanted to discuss with you.
- What's that?
- Better to talk about it in person.
It's time-sensitive.
I'll be right there.
Excuse me.
- Just down there.
- Thank you.
The device Timothy is strapped to is my
personal favorite. I call it The Rack.
Last-minute tweaks? Told
you he'd fuck with it.
If you switch the gear ratio,
you have to change the gear grease
to match the increased friction.
Maybe you should stick
to the heavy lifting.
You need five-weight.
It's in the gun.
Check with me next time.
How many next times are there gonna be?
However many there needs to be.
That's a human being.
Do you like how brutality feels, Mark?
Let's be honest. You want him
to suffer just as much as I do.
- So when's your test, Detective?
- I don't need one.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Because I didn't take
my life for granted.
You're still dragging your
knuckles on the ground.
What do you know about life?
Get used to me, 'cause
I'm not going anywhere.
You sure about that?
Time is short.
You okay?
Now it's time to go get Dr.
Denlon from the hospital.
Okay. I'll take you back.
Go. Be quick.
- Why'd you come?
- John, please stop.
- Don't do this.
- I promise you,
when all this is done,
I will provide a way out for you.
I wish that time was now.
Then I have something for you.
What's this for?
When the time's right, you'll
know what to do with it.
Shit!
I came to talk to you, Will, because
I've found a treatment for my cancer
that I think holds a lot of promise.
But my requests for coverage
- have all been turned down.
- Yeah.
So I was hoping that if I
came and explained it to you,
that you might be able to
get that overturned for me.
- well, the buck stops here, John. Fire away.
- Okay.
This is a doctor in Norway.
He's got a 30 to 40% success
rate with gene therapy.
He injects what he calls suicide
genes into cancerous tumor cells.
Then an inactive form of a
toxic drug is administered...
Yes. I'm familiar with the
therapy you're talking about.
Right. And a new trial's starting.
He's looking for new patients,
and he seems to think that
I'm the perfect candidate.
John, if your primary physician, Dr. Gordon,
thought you were a suitable candidate,
- he would have pursued it.
- No.
Dr. Gordon is a specialist. You know,
he's making money on his specialty.
He's not a thinker.
I mean, the man has his hand on the
doorknob half the time that I'm there.
I'm gonna be straight with you. At your
age and with the development of your cancer,
it's simply not feasible
for Umbrella Health...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What's not feasible?
By whose mathematical
equation is this not feasible?
It's policy, John. It's policy.
And if you go outside the system
and seek out this treatment,
which has been deemed ineffective,
you will be in breach of policy
I'm sorry.
Did you know that in the Far East,
people pay their doctors
when they're healthy?
When they're sick, they
don't have to pay them.
So, basically, they end up
paying for what they want,
not what they don't want.
We got it all ass-backwards here.
These politicians, they say the same
thing over and over and over again.
"Healthcare decisions should be
made by doctors and their patients,
"not by the government. "
well, now I know they're not
made by doctors and their patients
or by the government.
They're made by the
fucking insurance companies.
Piranha.
John, please. If you do
this, you'll be on your own,
and the subsequent cost
to you will be staggering.
Don't talk to me about
money. I have money.
This is about principle.
You see, Will, this is my
life we're talking about.
- You remember?
- What about Jill's life?
How's she going to be taken
care of when you're gone?
Let me worry about Jill.
The type of cancer you have
is malignant and inoperable.
That rolled off your tongue real smooth.
Even if the treatment works, the
cancer will return eventually.
- It's an unwinnable battle.
- That was even smoother.
As a matter of fact,
that was downright slick.
You think it's the living who will
have ultimate judgment over you,
because the dead will have
no claim over your soul,
but you may be mistaken.
Oh, shit!
Hello, William. You have
seen the flaws in your policy.
But what you have not seen is
the extent some people will go to
when faced with death.
The lawyer from your firm has...
- Debbie!
- ... 90 seconds to cross this room
or the device attached to her chest
will discharge and pierce her brain.
It's gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay.
She will find that the journey across
this room is filled with danger.
In order for her to make it, you
will need to be there for her,
and it is you who ultimately
holds the key to her survival.
When faced with death, will
she have the skills to live?
Let the game begin.
Okay. Okay, Listen!
- Jesus Christ! What the fuck is this?
- Debbie! Debbie! Listen to me!
- Debbie! Okay, Debbie, Listen to me! Debbie!
- What is this?
- Get me the fuck out of herw!
- Get through the maze
as fast as you can. Listen to me!
- Get me out of herw!
- Debbie!
Okay. You've got to get through this maze
as fast as you can! Go! Move now! Go now!
Come on! You can make it! You can
make it! You got to keep moving! Go!
- Will, this is insane! I can't!
- Go! You can make it!
Come on! You can make it!
You've got to keep moving!
Wait a minute! I think
I can help you up here!
Maybe this will stop it!
Yes! Yes!
Do it again! It worked! It worked!
- Do it again! It worked, it worked, it worked!
- Okay! Ready?
- Yes!
- Go!
Keep moving! Don't stop! Keep
going! Keep going! Keep going!
Don't stop!
You gotta keep going!
Keep going! Go! Go!
Keep moving! Go! Go! Go!
Fuck, I can't! It's a fucking
trap! There's no way out!
It's a fucking trap! I can't!
No! No, there's a ladder at the
end! So just go under! I'll help you!
Ready?
Go!
God! Come on, Debbie, go! Climb! Climb!
Come on! Come on, you're almost
there! You're almost there!
Go! Go! Go!
Okay, look for a key. There's
got to be a key! Look for a key!
What?
What are you waiting for?
- It's in you.
- What?
- It's fucking inside you!
- Oh, fuck!
Okay. Okay, I can do this. Wait!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- I need that fucking key!
I can get it! I can
get it! I can get it!
God! No! God! No!
Hello, Pamela.
Well, today you will experience
the meaning of sacrifice.
And you will see the consequence
for those who unjustly hurt others.
Fuck!
Someone's there. They're watching us.
Why? Why would someone do this?
To see how we respond.
They want to know what
decision we'll make.
- Let's pull it.
- No! We don't know what it does yet.
It's too risky.
Fuck!
Hey.
- Thanks for coming in.
- What'd you find?
- An abnormality in Strahm's fingerprint.
- What?
Take a look.
So the human fingerprint
leaves an oily residue,
and depending on how long it's
been exposed to the elements,
- it's highly susceptible to contamination.
- So what's the problem?
well, we found trace
amounts of halo methane R-12.
She means Frwon.
Production of R-12 ceased in 1994.
So the question is, was the
contaminant we found at the site already
or did Strahm bring it in with him?
Yeah. We're looking into
the building's function
before it was abandoned.
Excuse me.
Did anything come from
the Seth Baxter tape?
Yeah, actually, we
might be on to something.
The tape was in pretty
rough shape when we found it,
but we were able to authenticate it.
The voice was intentionally distorted,
but it didn't match John Kramer's.
- It's currently being analyzed.
- For what?
well, we're trying to descramble
the tape to find the original voice.
He's on with the tech right now.
Are you timing something? Your watch.
I was before I got your call, yeah.
We got it. This is our smoking gun.
The lab's off-site. Come on.
- You're coming, right?
- Of course.
You shut up! All you do is try
to take over every situation.
You don't know what the
fuck you're talking about!
Shut the fuck up!
- Fuck off!
- Would you two just shut up already!
We can figure this out.
- Hey! Who's in there?
- Mr. Easton? Is that you?
- Yeah. Shelby? Who's in there with you?
- Mr. Easton!
We're all in here, sir. All six
of us. What the hell is going on?
Everybody! We need your help.
What can you see?
We can't see anything. It's pitch dark.
- What's that sound?
- I don't know, something we're chained to.
- It's spinning. Oh, God.
- Get us out of herw!
- You have to help us!
- Please!
Come on, get us out of here, Mr. E!
Mr. Easton!
Mr. Easton! You got
to get us out of here!
Oh, my God!
Pull it together, Mr. Easton. Come on!
- You can do it!
Mr. Easton! Mr. Easton!
Please! Please get us
out of here! Please!
Mr. Easton, what is this?
It's a game.
- Game?
- Mr. Easton?
Hello, William. Before you are six
of your most valuable associates,
the ones who find errors in policies.
Their findings result
in over two-thirds
of all applications denied
or prematurely terminated.
Now you must apply your analysis to them.
And will you be able to find their errors?
Six ride the carousel.
But only two can get off.
The decision of which two
survive falls upon you.
But remember, the mounted
gun will continue to fire
until all six rounds are spent.
And if no decision is made on
your part, all six will perish.
What? What?
To offer the two reprieves,
you must press both buttons
at once in the box before you.
However, in doing so you'll
give a sacrifice of your own.
Two can live, four will die.
Your decision's symbolized
by the blood on your hands.
Mr. Easton, wake up! You
gotta get us out of here!
- Pick me!
- Mr. Easton, come on!
Listen to me. Mr. Easton, I
am the one who should live.
- Do something!
- Fuck.
Jesus Christ!
Please, Mr. Easton! Mr. Easton! Please!
Follow the policy, Mr. Easton. Do it!
Please! Mr. Easton, follow
the policy! Follow the policy!
- Holy shit!
- Oh, my God!
- No!
What the fuck!
- What the fuck!
- No!
Mr. E! They say we're only
as strong as the weakest link!
I'm the strongest! You can't let me die!
Fuck him! I'm healthy,
sir. I'm healthy! Please!
Mr. Easton, come on!
No, I have two kids. You
know them well. Please!
Please, they can't grow up
without me! They need me!
Oh, shit!
Thank you! Thank you!
- Fucking hell!
- Thank you.
Fuck her! You don't even
know her, Mr. Easton.
Listen to me, okay? My
parents are sick, okay?
- They need me. I'm all they have, please!
- You fucking liar!
- Your parents hate you! They cut you off!
- What?
- Shut up! That's not true!
- Fuck you, it is true. I sit next to you!
- I... I'm pregnant. I'm pregnant!
- No, she's not! She's lying!
- She's fucking lying!
- Fuck you!
- Mr. Easton, she is lying!
- I'm pregnant!
- She's lying.
- No! No, fuck!
- I'm pregnant!
- She's fucking lying!
He's lying, Mr. Easton, it's
not true! Please! Please!
Fuck! Push the thing! Push the thing!
- She's lying.
- No!
- Mr. Easton, push it! Push the thing!
- Oh, God! No!
Push it!
Oh, God! What the...
What the fuck!
You have to trust me!
I won't lie to you!
- Oh, please! He's a kiss-ass! -
Mr. Easton! My parents are loaded!
- Oh, God!
- They'll give you whatever you want!
- Just say a number!
- He's a thief!
He's been stealing from
the company for years!
It's true! It's true!
- Thief!
- Fuck you!
- It's true! He has been...
- Don't Listen to them!
- Don't Listen to them, Mr. E!
- It's true!
Christ! Mr. Easton,
come on! Mr. Easton...
Okay, Mr. Easton, Listen to me carefully.
I'm on your side, and I can help you.
- But you cannot trust this bitch!
- What? Fuck you!
- She's a fucking liar!
- What?
You cannot believe her. She
has already tried to lie!
And she's just going to
continue to do it! You know it!
It's me, Josh!
No, I haven't! What about you? He
wants to be you! Okay, you know that!
But he'll slit your throat
at the first opportunity!
Please don't let me
die! Please! No, please!
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, fuck!
Oh, God!
Thank you!
Oh, well, that's it,
isn't it? It's over!
- You motherfucker!
- Stop it!
You spineless,
pussy-whipped motherfucker!
That's all it takes, eh? A bitch
says one thing and it's all over!
You know what, William?
Your policy, it's bullshit!
Fucking bullshit!
well, you Listen to
me, you son of a bitch!
I did everything for you.
Look at me! When you're
killing me, you look at me!
Thank you.
Oh, my God!
- Thank you.
- Emily.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
- How's it going?
- Good.
This is it.
Whoever made this tape had access
to some very impressive
audio-filtration equipment.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
Fortunately, we have some
tricks of our own here.
We can turn his algorithm upside down and
let us hear what he really sounds like.
Let's hear what you got.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
You okay?
You seem a little preoccupied.
I'm just anxious about the tape.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
- Right now, you're feeling helpless.
- You know, there are still a couple of things
- I can't quite wrap my head around.
- Right now, you're feeling helpless.
Like, I don't understand
Strahm's motivation.
He was my partner for five years.
I mean, we all knew he
was a bit of a hothead.
But I never saw any indication
of psychotic behavior.
You never can really tell what
someone's thinking on the inside.
...helpless.
- Hear that?
- Right now, you're feeling helpless.
We're getting there.
Come on, I thought you
had something to show us.
Yeah, it's just I never really
thought of him as being vengeful.
- Right now, you're feeling helpless.
- You know? I mean, all the facts are there.
- But something doesn't sit right.
- Listen. It's getting closer.
- Right now, you're feeling...
- You know, there is an alternative.
Let's say that Strahm killed Seth Baxter
specifically to set you up
as an accomplice to Jigsaw.
Okay.
well, there's a problem
with that, though.
On further analysis of
Strahm's fingerprints,
it was found that the uric acid
levels in the eccrine gland residue
were inconsistent for an individual
with an active epidermal metabolism.
In other words?
In other words, when he left his
fingerprints on the latest victim,
Strahm was already dead.
- Right now, you're feeling helpless.
- There it is.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
Who else knows about me?
Who else fucking knows about me?
- Everyone.
- You lie. You're fucking lying.
I found something you'll want to see.
It was at the location where John died.
Does it mean anything to you?
What are you doing?
Get as far away from the
sprinkler head as possible.
We don't know what it does!
I'm not gonna just sit
here and do nothing.
We need to make a decision!
Don't you understand?
Okay. You can pull it. I love you.
I love you, too. Get back.
No. You don't know what it does!
- On three, I'll pull it.
- Okay.
No. No.
One,
two,
three!
What the fuck?
It doesn't even work! It
doesn't even fucking work!
What the fuck?
It doesn't make any fucking sense.
I think I know what it does.
Get used to me, 'cause
I'm not going anywhere.
You sure about that?
Amanda will fail you.
We'll see.
"Amanda, you were with Cecil
the night Jill lost Gideon. "
Go.
- What the fuck are you doing? Go. Go.
- I don't know about this.
- What do you mean, you don't know?
- She's been good to us.
I've been good to you.
- I know...
- Please, please, go.
You drive me crazy.
Go on, you fucking pussy! Go! Go! Go!
- Cecil! No!
- Listen to me!
"You killed their child.
"You know it and I know
it, so do exactly as I say.
"Kill Lynn Denlon or I will
tell John what you did. "
She doesn't deserve to go free!
Amanda, Lynn is more
important than you know.
Lynn!
I made it. I made it. I made it!
If you fail, you will
never see your family again.
- What are you doing here?
- Will!
- Pamela!
- Yeah.
I know it's your birthday. I'm going
to make it up to you, I promise.
Are you really standing up your
sister for work? I'm your only family.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Let her go! I mean it! I won!
I followed your fucking
rules! Now you let her go!
You son of a bitch!
You've just given me a death sentence.
I mean, who's going to cover me now?
You just killed me.
Come on, Let's go.
You're the man that killed my dad.
Hello, Tara. My apologies for exposing
you and your son to this kind of treatment.
But I can assure you,
it is not without reason.
The man before you just made the
sacrifices to save the life of a loved one.
However, when given the opportunity
to save your husband's life,
he chose not to.
Now you will be given
the power to save a life.
Will you grant this man the
opportunity to continue living?
Or will you dispense
the same death sentence
he issued your husband?
Live or die.
The choice is yours.
It's not my game.
I'm leaving you a box today, and
its contents are of grave importance.
Miss Tuck, what's in the box?
Please. Please forgive me.
Have mercy, please!
Did he show mercy when
my husband was suffering?
John left you five envelopes.
The sixth one was for me.
This is John's will.
...to watch this horror!
- He had no choice!
- He always had a choice!
The reason I am doing this
isn't because I can't forgive you
for what you did to me.
The reason I'm doing this
is because I couldn't forgive myself
for what you might do to someone else.
Please, no. Please.
- You will never kill again.
- Please.
Please.
Please. Please.
I can't. I can't kill him.
But I can.
- No, Brent!
- You killed my father, you motherfucker!
Now you burn in hell.
Game over.
- John Kramer.
- William Easton.
Nice to meet you.
- Those are the rules, Harold.
- You've just given me a death sentence.
So, in a sense, you
choose who lives or dies.
No!
It's policy, John. It's policy.
You think it's the living who will
have ultimate judgment over you,
because the dead will have
no claim over your soul,
but you may be mistaken.
So when's your test, Detective?
- I don't need one.
- Oh, yeah?
You know why you're here, don't you?
I want to know if you have
what it takes to survive.
You feel you now have
control, don't you?
You think you will walk away untested.
Do you like how brutality feels, Mark?
I'm only carrying out
John's final request.
You want a chance?
I'll give you a chance.
Remember...
Remember, don't trust
the one who saves you.
Don't trust the one who saves you.