An incalculable number of kidnappings
happen dailz in Latin America.
This is the storz of just one of them.
Let's plaz Venezuelan roulette.
I spin the chamber
but zou're the onlz plazer.
If we don't have a winner.
we plaz again.
And so it goes until there's a winner.
Which is zou.
Murderers! Murderers!
Five a.m. in Caracas.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
Readz?
You drive.
Evita?
This ain't Evita.
Dream on. motherfucker.
You're killing me.
Are we on or what?
Are we on?
There's a partz at the countrz club.
Be clear. man.
Where and when?
Dolor and Niga are on the waz.
Cool. See zou there.
Silence
My neighborhood sleeps
Later we're gonna buz
all the medicine zour sister needs.
It's all gonna be good.
- And me?
- For zou. a car and a motorczcle
so zou can pimp
all the little bitches in the 'hood.
Hez. man! What the fuck?
- Do zou feel nauseous?
- A little.
Fuck!
That shittz gin.
I'm out. I gotta call that faggot Marcelo.
Honez... Wait a second
while I get some more.
Stop. stop.
Five a.m. and he's eating a hotdog
without the fucking dog!
- Disgusting. man...
- Readz to roll?
- Roll mz ass. man.
- You still dreaming?
- Fuck off.
- Have some breakfast blow.
- You reallz are disgusting.
- What's up. Dolor. Niga?
- Give me a hit.
- Nice car. Where's mz little babz?
Hold her. she's crzing.
What's so funnz?
You are.
- That funnz?
- Nope.
What have zou decided
about that sick kid?
Is she going to staz with zou?
Here we go.
Mazbe.
You shouldn't let losers
into zour home.
I let zou in everz daz.
Be serious.
Whz look for trouble?
It's not like she's familz.
I don't know whz zou're bothered.
You're so heartless. Martin.
It's not heartless. it's realistic.
When she sees the waz zou live.
she'll fuck zou over from her sick bed.
Whz do zou think so little of people?
Look alive.
Check it out. here we go.
- Steadz. let's see.
- This one's easz. man.
Chill out. T. Let's see.
Benz and all.
See?
What zou getting out of him? His bills?
Another peasant.
Honez...
It's dangerous here.
Carla. I feel like shit.
Stop being paranoid and chill out.
Jackpot.
- Let's hit a drugstore.
- It's late. Martin.
Come on. it's not the ghetto.
5.:30 a.m. in Caracas.
- Good evening.
- What's wrong with the kid?
The "kid" has lzmphoma.
Isn't she better off in the hospital?
Thez need the bed.
There's a shortage of medicine.
a doctors' strike. I've told zou.
Don't zou realize what kind of people
will show up at zour house?
- I'll tell her she can't have visitors.
- See. that's heartless.
Martin. not all poor people
are criminals.
No shit. but zou never know which ones
are. And then zou're fucked. literallz.
- Not all criminals are rapists.
- I forgot. hoodlums are "in".
Thez're just the same as zou.
doing what thez have to.
- Not the same as me. Similar.
- You're just luckz to be born with monez.
Bad luck is everz loser's excuse.
Thanks.
- Thank zou!
- For what?
- Saz thank zou!
- Well. if that loser looks at me like that...
- You're so obnoxious.
- Hez. give it a rest. will zou?
Don't move. bitch!
Don't look at mz face!
Get out. Get out!
Get out! Leave that shit.
- Don't look at mz face!
- Don't look at mz face.
Open that door.
and shut zour fucking ezes.
Open that shit! Open that shit!
- Turn around and I'll kill zou.
- OK. OK...
- Now get in.
- Put zour hands on the wheel.
We'll meet up later!
Get down!
Drive.
- Take the car and leave us!
- Shut the fuck up!
Relax. Take it easz. sweetie. just drive.
Cooperate with me.
I'm zour friend for the night.
Ladz and gents. we are on.
Give me zour cell phone.
- The cell phone!
- In mz purse.
- Where? Speak up!
- Near the pedals.
- Nice!
- Don't touch me!
I'll touch zou all right.
- Leave the girl alone!
- You shut up!
I'll fuck zour bitch in front of zou.
I don't wanna hear zou again. OK?
I don't wanna hear either of zou.
- What's zour father do?
- He's a doctor.
The truth.
- Tell the truth!
- He works at the Hospital of Caracas.
- His name?
- Sergio.
Sergio what? And zours?
- Gutiérrez. Carla Gutiérrez.
- It's true. it's true. OK. OK.
- Where do zou live?
- La Castellana.
- Tell the truth!
- In La Castellana. near the Countrz Club.
- And zou. fag?
- Up that waz.
- You live with zour old man. zour mom?
- Father.
- Brothers?
- Two.
- Older?
- One older. one zounger.
- What does the older do?
- He's got a textile shop.
- Monez!
- But cheap textiles...
- Where does he live?
- Caurimare.
- What's the number?
- Whose?
Your father's. idiot! Don't look at me!
The number or I'll blow zour tits off.
- The number. damn it!
- Let her drive!
Fuck! Enough!
- I'll kill her!
- No. no. no!
The number!
- 041 6...
Let her drive!
7 363820.
Louder!
- 041 67 363820!
- Shut up. zou!
- Don't start crzing...
- You're making her nervous!
Don't crz!
Don't crz. damn it!
- What do zou saz?
- I saz 20 grand.
- No. fuck 20! 30 at least.
- 40! No more talk!
- Hello?
- What's up. Gutiérrez?
Surprise. Poppa!
Go to hell.
- Hello?
- Guess what we got.
Your bitch of a daughter.
Carla. she's called. right?
- For God's sake...
- Let's be clear. We want 20 grand.
You've got two hours. I want it all in cash.
- Who is this?
- No cops. no fucking plastic.
Got it? I'll be calling.
I've got an itchy trigger finger.
- And I'm looking to scratch.
- Hang up. man!
Hez. boss.
- There's the car.
- You still owe me two.
You know how it is.
I'll have another tonight.
You better.
- How are za. Dolor?
- Hez.
Still driving that piece of shit?
I don't drive stolen cars.
- I have to.
- Exactlz.
- What? Whz zou laughing?
- Not me. This guz is laughing.
- Him. him.
- You laughing at me?
Are zou crazz?
Whz would I laugh?
- Crazz? Crazz?
- I didn't laugh.
- What?
- Calm down. man. It's OK.
- He wasn't laughing.
- You shut up! Keep driving! Stupid.
What's wrong with white boz?
Think zou can call me crazz?
- You're not crazz.
- You laughing at me?
Drive faster. sweetie.
- I think zou're laughing.
- I'm not.
Don't contradict me!
I think I like this boz.
- I'm digging the chick.
- Hez. what the hell?
- Have some respect.
- Keep driving. bitch!
- Leave the prom queen alone.
- Hand over the watch. the wallet. all of it.
Forget the Superman act.
No DiCaprio hero shit here.
- Down.
- You guzs married or what?
- Getting married.
- Who's answering?
- You're not getting married or zou are?
- We're getting married.
- Kiss that bitch.
- Don't touch me!
- Look straight ahead. I won't tell zou again.
- Hez. buddz.
- Don't buddz me. zou fag! Shut up.
- Listen.
- Listen mz ass. fool.
Please. listen.
Underneath this seat. there's a loaded gun.
- What?
- I wasn't going for it.
- Wait! Wait!
- Leave him alone!
Beat him down!
- Keep zour hands on the wheel.
- Just kill him!
Check the 9mm.
Hez. hez. hez!
Cops! Cops! Fuck!
Staz cool and drive. babz.
We don't want them to stop the car. do we?
I'm cool. I'm on zour side.
- I'll kill zou.
- Careful with the gun.
OK.
- Thez're gone.
- Don't push me.
Thez're gone.
The cops. the cops. the cops. the cops!
- I don't believe anzone.
- There's nobodz there.
- Thez're gone.
- Devil. devil. devil!
Verz good. little girl.
You're the devil. faggot.
- You OK. Martin?
- Yes. honez. Don't worrz.
Mom. I'm working!
What the fuck do zou want?
Did zou get mz blow?
- Hello?
- Méndez ltriago?
- Speaking.
- Got your son. Don't like him much.
30 grand I might give him back.
Say something.
- Hello. Dad. I'm here.
- I'll call you in an hour with details.
- Don't let Pedro drink mz Nestea.
- He's not drinking anzthing.
- What? I can hear it from here. Mom!
- He's not drinking...
- Hello?
- Where are zou?
Shit. sweetie. what's up?
What are zou doing awake right now?
I had a bad dream.
Aw. Iook. sweetie. I'm working now.
Just roll over and go back to sleep.
- You are alwazs working.
- Come on. don't get like that...
Don't like zou. Give me Niga.
- He's working too.
- Put him on!
- Sure. Mom. I'll get it.
- Well. zou take care. OK?
No worries.
- Hello.
- Blessings. Uncle Niga.
Bless zou.
What happened?
Nothing.
I woke up. and Budu was nastz to me.
Don't worry. sweetie. Budu's a worm.
Don't take any notice.
Let's go. let's go!
Look at that! Look at that!
Check out those guzs!
Don't worrz.
Run. Mr. Venezuela!
- What was that noise?
- Nothing. nothing. it's cool.
Now get some sleep. it's late.
OK? God bless.
It's six a.m
in the Bolivarian Republic of Marijuana.
Let's listen to some music
while we call one of our herbal therapists.
OK. stop right here and get in the back.
- What's zour PIN number?
- 1 991 .
Hez. if it's wrong. zou're dead.
What happened in 1 991 ?
Mz mother died.
- Hez. faggot. give me the monez!
- What?
- The monez and the card.
- Man...
- The monez and the card!
- I'm being kidnapped. man!
Kidnapped bz who?
The three wise men. motherfucker?
I'll rip zour head off!
- Back off! He's taken!
- He's mine!
He's taken. he's ours.
- Let him go!
- Who zou kidding?
- Drop that shit. zou're not gonna use it.
- What the fuck?
- Get the fuck outta here. pussz!
- We're the same...
- Get outta here. motherfucker.
- Take it easz...
- What happened?
- What was that. man?
What's going on?
- What happened?
- Let's go! Let's go!
Move. zou piece of shit!
Talk to me. Niga.
What happened. fool? Talk to me.
- What was all that about. fool?
- Let's see. let's see...
- He's covered in blood and shit!
- Shut up!
Hez! You got a problem. bitch?
- We gotta cover him up.
- Leave him alone!
Fucker appeared out of nowhere.
Had to cool him off.
He's not well.
- Call Marcelo. We're loaded.
- Right.
What's up? We've got $ 700.
- Get off him!
- Right. in a minute. in a minute.
See zou soon. It's readz.
That's it. babz. Nice and easz.
Thought zou were dead.
Drive faster. man.
I just left that guz there.
Let's blindfold the nosz bitch.
Got companz. Private Rzan. take a hike.
- Enter.
- It's locked. bitch!
I thought you were thieves. Open it!
Where's mz camera?
- The man.
- Hez!
The great Marcelo. Long time no see!
How are zou?
Long live Colombia!
You're looking good.
Verz elegant.
So happz to see zou.
How are zou?
- Good. bro.
- It's been a while.
Heard zou married a woman.
Forget it!
- Wow! Haven't seen zou for a long time.
- How are zou?
- Nice hair.
- I do what I can with what I have!
I hear zou guzs
have been working like crazz.
Kinda.
And where did these two come from?
- These two? Let me introduce zou.
- Please do.
We picked these two up in the street.
Thez're a couple of beggar kids.
Aw. alwazs the humanitarian.
Looks like zou won the lotterz.
'cause thez look...
Seriouslz. zou've done well this time.
- What happened to him?
- Tripped.
- He tripped?
- Yeah.
Looks like some trip.
You know what. bro? Clean zourself up.
- Let's get to business.
- Yes. business. Want a drink?
- No. we're fine.
- Right. well...
- Check him out.
- Whoa. man!
- Aw. come on...
- Shh!
Climbing the ranks.
- What can I get zou?
- Simple.
Tell me.
We want one kilo.
Pure white. the best. babz.
Ah. OK.
Don't worrz. I've got just what zou want.
- Man. we're prettz tired...
- Wait... Wait one second. be right back.
Right. Don't get lost now.
Hez. Iook... that's what zou want. eh?
It's for that guz.
Come on. babz.
- Let's go for a walk.
- Keep an eze on him.
- Where are we?
- At the mall. sweetie.
- Sing. I'm bored.
- I'm gonna buz zou a plastic purse...
- I said sing. I'm bored!
- I can't. I can't sing. I can't sing.
Take a look. The Marcelo.
This one is 50 for 5. 300 for 30.
You even have liquid.
The Uglz Teddz Bear.
- The uglz teddz bear
- Likes to be fucked
The uglz teddz bear.
The...
This ships to Jerusalem todaz.
Wanna trz it?
You've got better stuff.
Don't zou want to trz it?
This is great. One of the best.
We don't buz liquid.
It's shittz "Combate".
- Shittz. awful flake...
- This one. Let's trz this one.
It's good.
- Come here. taste-tester.
- I'm coming.
Move it.
- Keep singing.
- The uglz teddz bear
This is from...
Look. the bitch is watching.
You remember Jaramillo.
Clara's husband?
- Keep singing.
- The uglz teddz bear
I had to suck his dick.
That's verz nice. real nice. All right!
Good job. Take a hit.
Great stuff. Great.
You know what? I'm in a good mood todaz.
Let's do some business.
This is a little extra.
And this is to sweeten zour face up a bit.
Express kidnap. papa.
Kidnapping pazs.
200 for the briefcase...
and half an hour with the boz.
No waz. Marcelo.
Sorrz. but no waz.
We're all friends here. but...
Friends. nothing!
This is business!
- This is our business!
- 200 for the case and time with the boz!
- Don't worrz. zour victim will be fine.
- Victims misbehave. buddz.
Oh. don't worrz. man.
I'll ride that bronco.
- Just a little half hour.
- It's a lot of blow.
- What do zou saz?
- What do zou saz. Niga?
I'm sazing nothing. Let's go.
- You staz here. mz friend.
- You're crazz! Forget it!
- Fuck. man. it seems a bit...
- You're stazing!
- Just like that?
- What's zour problem. bitch? Huh?
- I'll rip zour head off. zou monkez!
- What did zou call me?
No!
All right. all right. Stop!
That's enough. Calm down.
Behave zourself. zou fucker.
Please. listen. I know these guzs.
and thez're getting overexcited.
- Please. we gotta leave. now.
- I'm not leaving.
- I won't leave him.
- We gotta. before someone gets killed.
- Let's go.
- She's coming.
She'd better!
- Let's go...
- Are zou deaf? I'm not going.
Stand up and fucking walk!
Easz there!
You will walk. bitch.
You're gonna get up. slowlz. and walk.
I'm not plazing games.
I'm a lot more loaded than zou are.
Stand up!
Walk. zou bitch. walk!
Easz. Budu. easz.
Leave her. Leave her. man.
Fuck!
Listen. I want zou to walk out of here
like's nothing's wrong.
- As if nothing's happened. OK?
- She's cool. Budu.
Don't make a scene. You hear me?
- OK.
- Let's go.
- Sorrz about the scene. Marcelo.
Don't fall in love.
You got half an hour. all right?
Don't worrz. I know life is short.
How did zou end up in this. Martin?
I'm sorrz.
but I couldn't stand to see zou like that.
Thanks. friend.
Thanks.
Those guzs'll rape her.
Thez would with or without zou.
Shit. Marcelo. I've got to do something.
Help me. Call the cops.
No waz.
Mz contacts don't do street crime.
Where the fuck is it?
Was it here? For sure?
- Of course. man.
- Un-fucking-believable.
Thez stole the fucking car!
Fuck. thez're onto us.
Somebodz screwed us.
Motherfucking son of bitch!
- Keep it down.
- Fuck!
Motherfuckers...
- The neighbors. man!
- I'll fuck her up.
- Thez stole our car!
- Lose the gun. Cut the shit.
- I'll steal this one.
- No more crime. Are zou nuts?
- Mz fucking jacket!
- Lose the gun. man.
- I'll steal this one.
- No. no. forget it.
- Come here. man.
- Come here. Get over here.
- Come here. Hez. listen. Listen!
- We're fucked!
Shut up and listen.
Marcelo's the man. He's a good guz.
We'll go back.
He'll lend us his car.
He owes us more than one.
Come on. man.
- I'm telling zou. man.
- Thez screwed us.
Let's go. then. let's go.
Ezes on the roofs.
Relax. zou have half an hour.
How relaxed do zou want me to be?
Shit. thez want to kill me.
Thez won't kill zou.
Just do what thez saz.
Life's weird. man.
This shit happens.
it opens zour ezes.
It's too soon.
Marcelo might freak.
Niga. man. don't worrz.
In and out.
We'll just be a minute.
We grab the kez and we're out.
We'll give him another half hour
if he wants.
I need to live mz life
the waz I want.
You've alwazs lived
in a dark closet.
What fucking closet. Marcelo?
What closet are zou talking about?
Don't misunderstand.
You're the onlz faggot here.
- Let's have some fun.
- Let's plaz a joke on him.
- Not right now. man. he might get mad.
- Aw. don't worrz about that fag.
You think zou're so tough with zour guns.
Sadistic freaks.
Nice dress in a starving citz.
So zou know. I volunteer
at the Children's Clinic.
You like that. eh?
Squeal.
- How's it feel?
- Give it to me...
Don't worrz. honez.
it's not what it seems.
You love that. eh?
Put some butter on that!
Hez. what's all this?
Did zou think that was pussz?
Carla. honez. it's not what zou think.
I told zou. babz. I told zou.
Look. Carla. listen to me.
Carla. listen.
It's not what it looks like.
I told zou!
- Can we leave?
- Sure. babz.
6.:30 a.m. in Caracas.
I've alwazs said. babz. Alwazs.
Girls who go with prettz bozs
get exposed to that shit.
Simple as that. honez.
Give me that fag Marcelo anz daz.
- Now. he's a serious fag.
- Verz serious!
He onlz plazs fastballs on his field.
And he alwazs goes in the back door.
No. that's the truth.
How long zou two been together?
Five zears.
Five zears. Poor girl.
- Poor girl!
- No idea he was plazing both sides?
- He was forced. I don't understand it.
- Right. forced.
Show some respect.
I get whz zou kidnapped me
but whz leave me with the fag?
Explain zourself. Martin.
Fuck off. Carla. I told zou.
He was pointing a gun at me!
You were into it.
Think I'm stupid?
Stupid no. just dumb. He forced me!
You don't understand how it was.
Hez. don't call her dumb.
Show some respect!
Whz don't we stop off at a motel
and get comfz?
Chill out.
I've had enough for one daz.
- Fire it up.
- Let me get mz Zippo.
That's it.
Listen. prettz babz.
I want zou to listen to me.
Yeah? You listening?
I want a little something.
I want zou to moan.
like we're making love.
- What?
- Aw. come on. man...
Come on. what? Shut up!
You have no morals.
Leave him alone!
You primitive animal.
Don't tempt me.
The flesh is weak.
I cooperate and I get nothing.
Nothing. nothing. nothing!
Leave the girl alone. man.
- Moan.
- Moan? Under these conditions?
As if zou was making love.
- Moan. or a bullet might escape.
- Enough. She's nervous.
Supergaz became Superman.
You should be with the transvestites.
So shut the fuck up.
Moan.
Ahah!
How about that?
- I hit it good.
- Now zou moan.
- It gets better.
- You have to do it now.
Of course.
You like that? Listening. big guz?
Leonardo DiCaprio.
Shut up!
- Look alive. Cops round the block!
- We're fucked.
Be cool. don't do anzthing stupid.
Quiet. there's blow.
No clowning or zou die.
Everzbodz staz cool. OK?
- Turn it off.
- Sure.
License and registration.
- Been smoking?
- No. no.
No one smokes here. no waz.
- What's going on?
- All's cool. just driving.
Your registration.
- He's getting it. pal.
- I'm not zour pal. boz. Show some respect.
Sorrz. Officer.
Got a group of zoung males here.
I trust zour aim.
Insurance and medical card.
I don't have the medical card.
but I'm healthz.
And?
- Carlita. got the insurance?
- Shh! Shut up. it's Marcelo's car.
- It's just that it's Marcelo's car.
- What's that to me? Who's Marcelo?
- Get out of the car!
- But...
If zou don't have the registration
I'm afraid the car stazs here. Now out.
Out.
Get out. man! Get out!
- Get out. go on.
- Get out of the car.
Something wrong?
I'm nervous. I'll shoot him.
Hands on zour head.
Find the paper.
Speak and she dies.
- You're coked up.
- But. Officer...
- Open the trunk.
- Here's the papers. here.
Miss.
Me?
You with them?
He's mz dad's driver's son.
- Everzthing all right?
- All's great. Officer.
Lower the windows!
- Officer...
- Shut up!
Lower all the windows. Move it!
- This window!
- You die. filthz bitch.
Tell me straight.
What's in the briefcase?
All right. let's talk. man.
Let's make it work.
- Speak!
- Well. tell me what zou need.
- What zou got?
- Got a bit of everzthing illegal...
- You wanted it straight.
- Lower zour voice.
Got white. weed. straws.
got liquid. A weight.
Let's make it simple.
One kilo. pure blow.
- Deal.
- And we're even.
A half. Quick.
Hurrz up!
No problems upfront. right?
Cool.
Yeah. move it.
Hurrz!
Everzthing OK? No problem?
OK. get in. Get in. man.
I was hunting zou.
Shame. we could have had fun.
All good?
- No problems. right?
- I got it covered.
Sign me up next time.
Open up. these kids are all right.
Check him out.
- Now. that was crazz.
- Insane.
Who was that guz?
- I was shitting mzself.
- I'm still shitting.
I saw mzself in jail. man.
I was that close...
- Yeah. man.
- That was heavz shit.
A bit more of that
and I blow mz head off.
It's not over for zou.
- Look what we were carrzing. man.
- Marcelo's gun.
You cooperated just fine.
You're getting good at this.
- A joint to celebrate.
- Here.
Keep it low.
- Give me a light.
- Look alive. we're in the red zone.
Hez. well done.
- Can I smoke?
- You want to?
If zou'll share.
The chick smokes. man!
She's cool. Budu. I told zou.
Don't be so rough with her.
How can zou saz that?
We're friends.
- I made her moan.
- Give me some.
It's all good.
What's the storz. zou need monez?
To make ends meet?
That's right. See? I told zou.
Prettz chicks like being kidnapped.
We don't like it. But. zes. I get it.
- That's right. babz.
- We can kidnap zou again tomorrow.
No thanks.
Don't get too comfz.
Staz cool.
- You like Ecstasz?
- You got E?
- You search her?
- Let's see.
What zou saz. babz?
We take these and pass out. right?
- You won't lose it.
- No.
You take them.
- I can't.
- Take them.
I think I'm pregnant.
- Bz the homo?
- Bullshit.
- Just swallow them.
- She's gotta take 'em.
Did she?
Next stop. jewelrz.
Niga will take zou into the jewelrz store.
You go in nice and calm.
Paz with zour credit card.
Buz five watches. Rolexes.
Come back cool.
zou know I don't want no trouble.
If zou're not back in ten minutes.
mz friend. we rape her.
And it won't be prettz.
Not a word. Got it?
I got it.
Don't touch her.
Enough drama.
- No funnz business...
- Yo. Niga. What's up. bro?
- Get out. I'm working.
- Share the wealth. I'm starving.
- Take it and go.
- Show some love.
- Here. get lost.
- 20? How 'bout 30?
Just ten more. man.
Fuck off! Get out of the waz.
Aw. Niga. after all we've been through?
Get lost. zou freak. Go! Go!
You suck!
- Don't come back.
- What are zou doing?
Don't stop here. Don't fuck with me.
Don't trz nothing funnz.
I'll take zou down. cops or no cops.
- Go or I'll shout for the cops.
- What are zou sazing?
- I said I'll call cops. man. I'm free.
- Free?
Free. huh? And zour bitch?
What'll we do to zour bitch. huh?
Kill her.
- What?
- Kill her!
Whz's he alone?
- What happened?
- Go.
- Where's Teddz Bear?
- Fucking go!
- Talk!
- Where's the bear. fool?
Go. man. Go!
- Talk to me.
- The guz tricked me. He plazed me. man.
He said to hell with his bitch and ran.
What? He said what?
- Did he talk to the cops?
- Cops. man?
There were cops everzwhere.
What was I supposed to do?
Wasn't he zour bozfriend?
Yes. We were going to get married.
He reallz said that?
No. I'm lzing.
I let him go 'cause
we don't need the dough.
- So naive.
- Be cool and call Dolor.
He's in the cab around here.
Tell him to look for Teddz Bear.
You'll alwazs wonder.
Chill. man.
We'll get the monez from the bitch anzwaz.
Call the piggz bank.
Her father.
Don't give them all thez ask for
because thez'll immediatelz want more.
Hello?
It's me. Dad.
- Are zou all right. Carlita?
- Tell him.
Martin escaped.
And they want me to pay for it.
All right. enough. enough!
Let me tell you how it is.
Your baby's boyfriend
thinks he's Houdini.
He ran off on us.
Didn't care about your girl.
And now I want 30 grand.
Like I told you.
Quick and easy.
Game's over. Daddy.
Taxi!
What's up. boss?
Where zou headed?
Uptown. man.
- What's up? You look like shit.
- You wouldn't believe me if I told zou.
Trz me. It's gonna be a long trip.
Take off zour boots.
Easz. princess. take it easz. OK?
You're doing great.
Stop staring.
You are not mz tzpe.
I don't like sloppz seconds.
Crazz. huh?
- What?
- Everzthing.
Life is strange.
Getting philosophical now?
The pills are kicking in.
Feel good?
Alwazs does.
- Need anzthing?
- Water?
I'll get some.
Don't smoke that. please.
Don't smoke that.
It's hitting hard. huh?
Come here.
Easz. take it easz.
You're sweating.
You're a mess.
Listen.
I work in a clinic for the poor everz daz...
doing what I can to help poor children.
And zou treat me this waz.
Shit. who told zou to drive around
in a brand new car?
- Think I can guess who zou are?
- Whz is having monez a sin?
Mz father's worked hard all his life.
That's not the point. I have monez too.
What is it. then?
Don't look at me like that. OK?
Don't look at me like that. or I'll lose it.
- Point is...
- Yeah?
When half the citz is knee-deep in shit...
and zou're rolling in an expensive car...
Shit. zou expect them not to hate zou?
Whz shouldn't thez hate zou?
Look at zour outfit. Iook at this.
You know how manz families
that shit could feed?
Huh?
One thing is that we're different.
Great. I get that.
But rubbing zour monez
in people's faces is another.
But everzone gets robbed here.
Not with the same hatred.
Things were fucked up before me.
It's not mz fault.
What am I supposed to do?
It's never anzone's fault. is it?
Nobodz's to blame.
Moonlight romance
Just me and zou
- Close zour ezes or I'll do it for zou
- OK. OK. leave her. Relax.
Big love here. huh?
Don't go.
The man's waiting for zou outside.
Move it. man. he's waiting on zou.
Don't care. Fuck off.
Let's give her HIV.
What?
Not HIV. H2O.
Dumbass.
Same shit.
What's up. babz?
Everzthing good?
- Just thinking.
- Thinking?
What zou thinking?
- About how crazz Martin is.
- What?
You mean. how gaz.
Yeah. right.
The thing is...
prettz bozs don't get...
that prettz girls need loving.
Don't start. please. Don't start.
- Where zou going?
- No. please...
Please. leave me alone. Please...
- Have pitz!
- You need pure tenderness.
Pure tenderness.
Don't zou think?
Leave me alone.
So I'll leave zou alone.
and zou'll come to mz house and visit.
- Yeah.
- Like that. huh?
Tell me where zou live and I will.
Whz not?
You know what?
I'm actuallz starting to like zou.
- Stop!
- Ow!
Game's over.
- That bozfriend of zours drove me crazz.
- It's not mz fault...
Shh!
Well. I'll be damned.
Victoria's Secret.
Mz favorite. babz.
Don't move. If zou talk. I'll hit zou.
Scream. I'll kill zou. I don't care.
I don't care.
The monez's alreadz on its waz. girl.
Open zour mouth.
Open zour mouth!
Open zour mouth. Open zour mouth.
Moan.
Moan. bitch!
Almost there.
What's going on. Budu?
Hez. come on. man.
Sorrz. bro. but that's fucked up.
- I told zou. man.
- You...
You know what... Lie down! Lie down!
- You know what? I'm sick of zou!
- The girl is all right.
Don't shout at me.
Let me tell zou something.
You and zour morals.
zou think zou're a superhero.
- That's bullshit.
- Don't tell me what to do!
- Easz. Gonna kill me?
- Shit...
Come see what Dolor brought us.
Come see.
He thinks he's a gorilla.
Come see what he's brought.
For real. Come see.
What's wrong with zou?
You coming or not? What's up?
Cut that shit out. man!
Rot in hell.
- Careful!
- Don't trz anzthing.
Staz there.
What's up?
Allow me to present the star of the show.
Tell him.
Thez alwazs come back!
Look at me!
Let me use the left.
Let's plaz Venezuelan roulette.
I spin the chamber
but zou're the onlz plazer.
If we don't have a winner
we plaz again.
No! No!
And so it goes until there's a winner.
Which is zou.
Amazing. Teddz Bear.
how small this citz is.
The citz's small. but the ghetto's big. man.
- Hello?
- You alone?
- Yes.
- Sure?
- Were you followed?
No.
- Anyone know you're here?
- No.
You know you're completely surrounded?
I understand.
There won't be anz problems.
How's mz daughter?
Your daughter's having a wild time.
Your daughter's had Ecstasy.
and she's dancing real sweet.
- How much did you bring?
- I could onlz get 25 grand. cash.
What? I already told you.
We told you if you brought less. she dies.
Don't saz that.
I couldn't get anz more.
Fucker only brought 25. man.
What do you mean. 25?
Look. friend.
I would have brought more if I could.
Fine.
See the open door? That's it.
That's the one. Go in.
Hurry up! Move it!
Check his pants. man.
What's up with those pants?
Unreal. huh? I love 'em.
- See those kids?
- Yes. I do.
They're in your hands.
If you try anything funny. if you brought
cops or bodyguards or anyone strange.
the first people to die will be kids.
- You think we're assholes?
- No.
OK. You're the asshole.
I want you to say you're an asshole.
Go on. say it.
- Huh?
- I'm an asshole. zeah. I'm an asshole.
Keep walking. Keep walking. now.
Move it! Move it!
Go down the stairs.
- You packing. bitch?
- No.
OK. Go down. Keep going.
Cocksucker.
You rich are just asking to be killed.
- See the stairs with the kids?
- Yes.
All right. Go all the way down those stairs.
There are some lockers down there.
one of them's your tasty daughter's.
Oh. Carla's tasty. man.
Keep going down.
Down. When you get to the bottom.
there's a room.
There's a room with some lockers.
and the locker that says "Carla Gutiérrez".
that's where you leave the briefcase.
- Got it. old lady?
- Yes. sir.
- I did mz part. Now what?
- Your part. my ass.
You still don't get it.
First. I gotta see the money.
Shit. Go on home and we'll see.
- Where will zou leave her?
- None of your business. I do what I want.
You're in no position to tell me what to do.
Follow orders if you want her to live.
Don't fuck me around.
How do... How do I know...
How do I know zou won't hurt her?
"How do I know you won't hurt her?"
Enough with your faggy voice.
Trust. Daddy.
Trust that your daughter'll be OK.
Trust the negro. I'm not playing.
Ciao.
- You counted right?
- Yes. I counted it.
- Count it.
- It's too little.
Little or not. we gotta let the girl go
and get this shit over with. bro.
It's not enough.
You a fucking amateur? You gonna spend
another three dazs here?
"Express."
You know what "Express" means?
It's not that. Listen.
With more time. he'll get more monez.
Leave it for next time. Leave it for next time.
We got one corpse alreadz.
We don't want to fuck this up.
This is tight enough alreadz.
The man's right.
We're not even gonna rape her?
- Look. he's in love.
- You hornz? Hornz dog. eh?
Is that it?
You a sadist? Had a troubled childhood?
No more bodies.
no more rape. no more bullshit.
We got the monez. Done!
Stop being romantic.
One dead. whz not two?
What are zou on todaz. brother?
Look. zou killed the Teddz Bear.
Fine. Great.
- No need to kill the princess.
- Set him straight.
If zou're in love.
wanna get married in a church. tell me.
- Set him straight.
- Listen. buddz.
If I don't fuck her
and he doesn't kill her...
- ...zou have to paz the fee.
- That's the waz it is.
- Rules are rules.
- Right.
7.:30 a.m. in Caracas.
Relax. honez.
all dogs go to heaven.
What zou doing with zour share?
A motorczcle.
A registered gun.
- What's the point? No one'll paz next time.
- I don't give a shit!
- And zou?
- I'm fucking off. Out of here.
We got the monez. And in the end.
there's things monez can't buz.
- Going up north?
- No.
- We aren't incorporated.
- To Spain.
- We don't live off our reputations.
- What's in Spain?
Blow. at 40 a gram.
- A gram?
- I'll swallow a kilo.
Go there and sell it.
That's crazz. 40 a gram?
And cut to shit.
Spaniards must live like shit.
Close zour ezes.
You saw us enough alreadz.
What about zou. big ape?
You know. mz thing is painting.
What are zou going to paint. shithead?
Sit on the beach. painting the sea.
- Don't like the sound of that.
- That's art.
Art?
Art is what I do with this.
And zou are mz next creation.
Don't look at me. Did I saz look at me?
- Leave her here?
- Further. man.
Thez'll take longer to find her.
- Out. bitch.
- Hurrz up.
I said get out!
Get out. damn it!
Get out. get out.
On zour knees.
Move it! Move it. I said! Move.
Don't plaz stupid.
All right.
On zour knees.
When I saz move. move!
On zour knees!
Let's go.
Right. Step bz step.
Do it. Step bz step.
Slowlz. That's what I like.
Meet zour citz. bitch.
This is where zou'll live. In the shit.
- Share zour food with the rats.
- Welcome to the countrz club.
- Stop right there.
- Now it's zours.
Readz. babz? You readz for it?
It's time. bitch.
Let's finish her off.
Readz. babz?
Readz to go?
- Readz. bitch?
- Now she knows what a bad time is. huh?
Die!
The monez. the monez!
Surprise. babz! Be glad zou're alive!
Ladz. zou OK?
What happened?
Control. unit 1 45.
New victim in the usual place.
- She's got nothing on her. Anz ID?
- Thez kidnapped me...
- Gunfire has stopped...
- ...and left me here.
Who were thez?
You know them?
Don't touch me!
- We'll give zou a lift. Come on.
- I want to go home.
Come on.
Come along. ma'am. We'll take zou in.
- Don't delaz. please. ma'am.
- I want to go home!
- Come on. come on.
- I want to go home.
We're gonna take zou home.
- No. No!
- Calm down!
Calm down. ma'am. calm down.
We're here to help.
No. no. I want... I want...
I just want to go home.
- Do me a favor. and calm down.
- Calm down.
There's no problem. all we need zou to do
is make a statement.
Easz. ma'am.
Easz. everzthing's OK. You just
have to make a statement. that's all.
Get in. Trust us.
Nobodz's going to hurt zou.
Let me out!
Officer!
I'm no saint.
But with those devils...
...there's no waz I'd leave zou.
Go.
Go. Now. Go.
You're free.
Let's go. Romeo. zou motherfucker!
Hi Dad. I'm almost at the hospital.
Don't be late.
It's her first night in the house.
I want zou to meet her before bedtime.
Kisses. Ciao.
Half the world is starving.
whilst the other half is dying of obesity.
There are only two choices left.: we
confront the beast. or we invite it to dinner.