WOMAN: For as long
as I could remember,
the four of us shared everything.
Stories...
...secrets...
...laughter...
...broken hearts.
So when we found a
pair of pants that,
by some miracle, fit
each of us perfectly...
...we took it on faith they'd come
into our lives for a reason.
That summer and the
two that followed...
...the pants had the magic
of keeping us together.
No matter where they found us.
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
BRIDGET: Bring it in.
CARMEN:
They saw us through
times of love...
...times of loss...
MAN: Congratulations.
- ... and times of change.
And those moments where you
feel your life just lift up...
...and take off.
Let go.
That fall when we left
for college, I watched...
each of my friends
settle into a new life.
Cut.
- Tibby was at NYU.
Bridget made the
soccer team at Brown.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]...
[CROWD CHEERING]
And Lena? She was
on scholarship...
at Rhode Island School of Design.
They made it look so easy,
fitting right in and
making new friends...
...while I was at Yale just waiting...
for something to feel
real or familiar.
I was lost without
them, especially when...
it felt like my mom
was moving on too.
I believed that the Sisterhood
could survive anything.
But maybe the pants had done...
just about all a pair
of pants could do...
...and the rest
we had to learn on our own.
How to become ourselves
without losing each other.
[MAN SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
LENA: Kostos?
I'm so sorry, Lena.
I know how much
Bapi meant to you.
It's good to see you.
These past few months have just...
- Lena.
I've missed you.
I only broke up with you because...
[SPEAKING IN GREEK]
Lena...
...this is Melia.
My wife.
WOMAN:
And treachery in me, your queen.
Wait, Kostos got married?
Yep. Apparently
there's a B-A-B-Y on the way.
Oh, my God.
I didn't get the whole story.
You have to Heimlich
it out of Lena.
Well, she must be devastated.
Wait, why didn't she call me?
I hardly hear from
her, or any of you.
She was probably planning on
telling you when school's out.
Listen, I gotta go.
I think I just found bliss.
Love you.
- Okay, l... Love you too.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS
O VER SPEAKERS]
CARMEN: Here you go.
Hold this.
- How was it?
It was great. One of your best.
Excuse me. Out of the way.
My God, there is nothing more
invigorating than a full house.
Here, take it down.
I just want to get this dress off.
I can barely breathe.
Perfect. Thank you.
You're welcome.
These came for you
during intermission.
Oh. Great.
She's consistent. My mother sends
two dozen yellow roses...
...every time she doesn't show up.
Let's see.
'Sorry I couldn't be there, darling.
See you in Vermont.' Of course.
Have you ever been to Vermont?
Vermont?
- Yeah.
I'm doing an acting
internship at the
Village Theater Arts
Festival this summer.
My mom will have to go to that.
A lot of her friends will be in it.
Professional actors.
We actually get to work with them.
Hey, Carmen, they're always
looking for people backstage.
I could pull a few strings
if you're interested.
Oh, wow. That's
really nice of you...
...but I made plans to go home,
because my mom's pregnant...
...and we're moving,
and my friends...
would kill me if I wasn't home.
But thank you.
- Yeah, I understand.
Dad, I'm home.
Dad?
FATHER: Bridget.
Hey, honey. I didn't expect you
home so soon.
I know, me either.
You hungry? Want a slice?
Favorite recipe.
No, it's okay, I ate on the road.
So how's school?
Good. Yeah.
How's everything with you?
Good. You know, same.
Yeah.
Okay. Great.
Um, I guess I'll go unpack.
Get some rest.
Mom.
CHRISTINA: What is it?
CARMEN: Where's my stuff?
We just wanted to get a jump-start...
on all the packing.
It's gonna be fine.
Here are your towels.
- Thanks.
CHRISTINA:
David, is this the box you wanted?
DAVID: Let me see it, honey.
Welcome home.
I'm sorry I'm late, I'm sorry.
I didn't pack the boom box.
But I'm here.
And it's so good to see you.
It's been too long.
Your piercing closed up.
I know, right? Cool in Bethesda,
passé in the Village.
Here, hold this.
Why are these open?
CARMEN: I got hungry.
Hi, Bee.
- Carma.
Wow, you came prepared.
- Well, it's all that theater work.
Theater work? Acting?
I always said you
were a drama queen.
Thank you, but no.
It's behind-the-scenes.
Does this mean you're
gonna be able to help...
me with my screenplay
for summer school?
Summer school?
Well, yeah, I got an incomplete.
I was supposed to write a romantic...
comedy, but my
characters broke up.
You're gonna be in
New York the summer?
Yeah, it sucks.
Brian will come visit
you every weekend.
Because the guy worships
the ground you walk on.
Don't you just hate that in a guy?
BRIDGET: Take these.
- Bee, be careful.
If you fall, I'll laugh.
LENA: It always
makes me nervous...
when she does this.
Oh, my God.
- Oh.
Piece of cake.
CARMEN:
We'll be like 85 climbing
up these stairs.
You not gonna be able
to do that again.
Okay, Tib, please come out
of downward dog.
TIBBY: Okay.
- Pants.
Check. Junk food.
LENA: Oh, wow.
CARMEN: Check.
Have some chips.
Cheesy '80s music, check.
[C YNDI LAUPER'S 'GIRLS JUST
WANNA HAVE FUN'
PLAYS ON STEREO]...
I forgot. What do we do first?
Carmen goes next
and she does the:
'Blah, blah, blah, rules one, two,
and three of the pants.
Blah, blah, blah.'
Prayer, and we hold hands.
And then we all sit
around and pray.
That's very sentimental, Tibby.
I'm just saying. We've
been doing this...
for a couple summers now.
We don't need the ritual
every single time.
Why not? It's not
any less important.
Okay, you guys, let's just keep
the same rotation. Okay?
So, what, now you guys
don't care about it either?
We care.
Carmen, we've done
this a million times.
It's not that big of a deal anymore.
So if we just keep going
as usual, you have...
them for a week and
you pass them on.
TIBBY: Bee's next.
LENA: Don't take
them on your digs...
...with those corroded bones
and corpses.
I'm sorry I'm not painting
in a studio all summer.
Wait, what are you
guys talking about?
Bones and studios, what is that?
I got accepted into this
archaeological camp in Turkey...
...so I'm gonna go
there for the summer.
Didn't you get my e-mail?
- No.
I'm taking a figure drawing class.
Cool.
What are your plans
for the summer?
Um...
I'm going to Vermont.
Really?
Yep.
Vermont.
Can't you take me
with you to RISD?
I'll die of boredom here, I swear.
Come on, I'm your sister.
I thought you were
going back to Greece.
Not until August.
Oh, God. Okay, that reminds me.
What should I do about Kostos?
What do you mean?
You know, if I see
him, what do I say?
Or do I not say anything?
God, what if I see him with her and...
she's, like, all out to
here and everything?
I don't know.
We agreed to see other people,
so I knew there was
a possibility he'd...
That he'd date someone,
not get her...
pregnant and have to marry her.
God, whatever. Just talk to him,
don't talk to him, I don't care.
WOMAN:
Effie Kaligaris, we have to go.
Yeah, coming.
Hey, Mom, can we pick up Ashley
on the way?
Why didn't you tell me
she'd been writing all these years?
Where did you get these?
Where you hid them.
Your mother and I weren't on
speaking terms with Greta.
It was in your best interest...
- My best interest?
What, to make me think...
my own grandmother
didn't love me?
You had no right to do that to me.
I had a right, Bridget.
I'm your father.
It's my job to protect you.
Protect me? From what?
I can take care of myself, Dad.
In case you hadn't noticed,
I've been doing it for years.
Over there is the Ford Theater.
- Oh, cool.
I'm so glad you
changed your mind.
CARMEN: Me too.
JULIA:
Thank God for summer
theater, huh?
Julia, Julia, Julia, darling.
How nice to have you
back with us this season.
JULIA: Thanks.
- How's your mother? Working?
Of course. But she sends her love.
Tell her love should not be sent.
Carmen, this is Bill Kerr,
our brilliant director.
KERR: Uh-uh-uh-uh.
My actors are brilliant,
I merely facilitate.
JULIA:
Carmen is one of my
friends from Yale.
Yale. Well, I shall try not
to hold that against you.
Welcome to the theater.
- Thanks.
KERR: Charming.
JULIA:
He's like family. God,
I love this place.
As you may have heard,
this season on the main stage...
...we will be mounting
The Winter's Tale.
And, as is tradition...
...acting interns will be
assigned roles in the ensemble...
...with the exception...
...of one sacrificial lamb...
Is he drunk?
[JULIA LAUGHS]
Ladies.
Sorry.
Who will be cast in a leading role...
...and have the great good fortune
of working very closely with me.
Margaret.
Auditions begin tomorrow at...
...9 a. M?
By my troth, an hour
I know not well.
[LAUGHING]
I would like everyone to prepare...
...a monologue or
a scene from the play.
Oh, God, I could
vomit, I'm so nervous.
Are you kidding?
You're gonna be fine.
I'll run lines with you.
Thanks.
Hello and welcome.
I am Professor Nasrin Mehani,
director of the university program.
Let me show you
where you will be working.
Shall we?
I'm guessing you're a virgin.
Pardon me?
To figure drawing, I mean.
You look a little nervous.
Nervous? No.
Oh, God, no.
I've never officially
taken a class before...
...but I've been sketching people
my whole life. It's a model, right?
It's not like I know the woman.
Talk that much
when you're not nervous?
Actually, I don't normally
talk this much, like, ever.
Good morning, everyone.
Please grab an easel
and let's get started.
Leo. We're ready
whenever you are.
Have fun.
Relax your strokes, Lena.
Find the areas of tension
within the pose, and then...
...feel the contours
as you move through them.
Okay.
ANNIKA: Okay, that's it for today.
Thanks, Leo.
He's a nude model,
Lena, not a porn star.
Hey, Tibby? The return
box is so jammed,
nothing'll fit through
the slot, do you mind?
Yes, I absolutely mind.
It's inconsiderate
of the customers...
...and interferes...
with the timely
collection of late fees.
I'm gonna call you back.
But, Tibby...
- Just send the sketch.
Hey.
- Hey.
Should I have called?
- No, I love surprises.
Good, because...
MAN: Tibby.
I'm with a customer.
Hi.
Happy anniversary.
It's 10 months today.
And I thought...
...we should celebrate.
You have a good memory.
I'm a romantic guy.
And I have a calendar
on my cell phone.
[PLASTIC CLATTERING]
MAN: Tibby.
- Oh, God.
[HIP-HOP MUSIC
PLAYS ON STEREO]
You convinced your boss
to give you the weekend off?
I told them the creators
of 'Dragon's Lair'...
...were giving me a lifetime
achievement award.
No, seriously.
- I told them the truth.
That I had to see
my favorite person in the world.
Oh, and you too.
Well, your favorite person in the...
whole wide world is
clearly incompetent.
Help.
You have to... Well...
[LAUGHS]
Okay, that was way too simple.
How's everything
so simple for you?
Everything's simple.
I mean, you don't play games...
...you don't take three days
to call a girl back.
Would you like me to give you
a simple answer?
Go on.
Because... I love you.
That simple, huh?
- Yep.
It's that simple.
- It's that simple.
So you just use the L word
and I'm supposed to...
...swoon?
Get a little emotional?
That'd be nice.
Okay.
I'm not gonna fight you here.
I know you really want
me to, but I can't.
You sure?
- I think so. Okay.
TIBBY: So now that we have
a new anniversary to celebrate...
...I just want you to know
that even though I am a feminist...
...I still do enjoy a nice box
of chocolates.
And I don't hate all poetry.
You okay in there?
What's wrong?
Uh... I think, um...
I think we had a malfunction.
It's not a computer.
What do you mean?
It broke.
I don't understand.
Those things last
forever in landfills.
When did it break?
- I don't know.
Look, I mean,
I was a little
preoccupied, you know.
Are you sure that
it was a real one?
Of course it was real.
My uncle gave it to
me for graduation,
you know. I was saving it.
For two years?
Brian...
God.
What was I, just like the first girl
to say yes?
Of course not.
I wasn't the first girl?
No, I mean, of course you are.
Bathroom.
[DOOR OPENS]
Tibby...
...Iook, I understand
that you're worried.
I'm not worried.
I just have to work on my script,
you know, because it's due soon.
It's okay.
You sure? Okay.
MAN: It's gotta come down at least
six inches. It's gotta clear it.
Can we hold the work, please?
And the rest is silence.
Lan, it's your time.
What you do still
betters what is done.
When you speak, sweet,
I would have you do it ever.
[CLICKS]
And for the ordering your affairs,
to sing them too...
KERR: Lan?
CARMEN: Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
Are you okay? I don't know what
happened. Are you okay?
As long as it wasn't
a comment on my acting.
No, I wasn't even watching you.
Now, that hurts.
- No, that's not what I meant.
KERR:
Where the hell is the
technical director?
Okay, you're fine.
- I'm fine.
Okay.
KERR: Go around.
Go around. Please.
Okay. Sorry.
KERR: Lan?
- I'm okay, Bill.
MAN: I think it's a jaw.
BRIDGET: Oh, awesome.
See? Should've brushed more.
Hey, guys. Cheese.
[MUSIC PLAYING]...
[LAUGHING]
Have a seat. Good day in the dirt?
Great, I almost have Hector
all the way out.
Hector. Very heroic name.
What makes you think it's a he?
The size of the skull.
We found a female skull last week.
And what did you name her?
Cleo.
I've been searching for
the last few bits of...
her because her skeleton's
almost complete.
It really doesn't
get to you, does it?
No, why would it? I mean,
these people are way long gone.
And what is 'way long'?
How do you calculate the moment...
when a person's death
becomes scientific...
...rather than emotional?
I don't know. I guess
when the last person...
they knew died.
Then you, my friend, have a thing
or two to learn from the Greeks.
Well...
Come on. Bridget, come on.
Go, go.
- No, only if you come.
No, I'm tired.
- Come on. No, you're not tired.
BRIAN [ON RECORDING]:
Tib, it's me, again.
Look, I really just...
I just want to talk...
to you. Can you call me, please?
CARMEN [ON
RECORDING]: Hey, it's
Carmen. What rock
are you hiding under?
Haven't heard from you in a while.
Call me back.
BRIAN: Tib.
It's Brian.
Oh.
Okay.
BRIDGET: Lenny, I enclosed
with the pants...
a little bit of ancient dirt...
...and a picture of me
with my new boyfriend, Hector.
Not exactly the lively type,
but he's got the
wisdom of the ages.
LEO: Aren't you a little early?
Oh.
Pretty sure class doesn't start
for like 12 hours or so.
Yeah. I just thought I'd come by
and get in some extra studio time.
What are you doing
here? Is this yours?
In exchange for the modeling,
they let me use the studio at night.
It's okay if you don't like it.
- No, I like it. I like it.
I really wish I were brave enough
to try something like that.
I'm sure you have your own style.
I'm Leo, by the way.
We didn't formally meet.
I mean, I was at the, I saw...
The class.
- Yeah. I'm Lena.
Lena. Interesting jeans, Lena.
Oh, yeah.
It's a long story.
I like long stories.
Who knows? Maybe you could
tell me one over dinner sometime.
I like dinner.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Great.
IAN: Are you stalking me?
Oh, God, it's you.
Shouldn't that be my line?
Oh, no, mine would be,
'Oh, bollocks, it's her.'
I'm British, you know.
Really? And here I was thinking,
'He does a really good accent.'
Gets them every time.
May I?
Sure.
So did I screw up your audition?
Yes. I didn't get the part.
Really?
- No, not really.
Ha-ha.
It was more of a formality.
I played Mercutio in Bill's
Romeo and Juliet last year.
That's very impressive.
Did you make a good death?
Excellent.
There aren't street fights
in A Winter's Tale.
Just your basic poisoning,
child abandonment,
obsessive jealousy.
Yeah, a more sensitive side
of Shakespeare.
Have you thought
about auditioning?
No.
No. I'm pretty sure
I'm right where I belong.
Belong? According to?
Right. Um, okay, bye.
Sorry, I don't even
know your name.
Carmen.
That's definitely
not a backstage name.
MAN: Goal.
I'll get it.
[YELLS]...
[COUGHING]
Bee. Bee. Are you okay?
Jesus, Bee,
what the hell were you thinking?
WOMAN 1: I hope she's okay.
WOMAN 2: She looks okay.
We have rules for a
reason, young lady.
Okay, okay, sorry.
Won't happen again.
So any idea
what the room was used for?
I'm guessing it was
the gynaikönitis.
Gynaikönitis means
'women's quarter' in Greek.
It is where the women
spent most of their time:
Weaving, entertaining visitors...
...seeing to the care
and education of the children.
It is likely where your friend
Cleo raised hers.
Cleo had children?
You can tell that?
You can tell a lot from a skeleton.
Look. Here.
We know that she stood
at just over 5 feet...
...and that she died
around the age of 35.
The shape of the pelvic bones
rules out childbirth as the cause...
...so it was most likely due
to an illness of some kind.
Wow. Uh...
I just never imagined
her that young.
My mother died at the same age,
four years ago.
I'm sorry.
I can imagine how difficult
that must have been.
So are we done here?
All set. Stay out of trouble.
Yeah.
Will't please you, sir, be gone?
I told you what would come of this.
This dream of mine.
Being now awake...
...I shall queen it no inch farther...
...but milk my ewes and weep.
Excellent, Julia.
Thank you.
KERR: Excellent.
JULIA: Thanks.
Trippingly on the tongue.
All right, thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Carmen.
What do you want?
Bill?
- No, no, no.
IAN:
Do you have time for one more?
Are you crazy?
IAN: You won't be disappointed.
KERR: Yes, fine.
Shock me, thrill me.
Come on. What have
you got to lose?
This is Carmen.
Hi. Wow, those lights are bright.
Yes.
You're Julia's friend.
CARMEN: Yes.
I'm Carmen Lowell.
You don't have to write that down.
I'm not here to act,
I'm just doing some
backstage work.
I'm not an actor.
Not that I don't love the play.
I love the play.
KERR: What do you love about it?
Well, I guess mostly
the character of Perdita...
...and how she doesn't really have
a true identity...
...but she knows what
she believes in...
and she sticks to that.
I guess.
I don't know.
KERR:
Why don't you give it a shot?
Perdita.
Page 62.
Lan, would you be a love
and read Florizel with her?
Begin with 'No shepherdess.'
Ready?
I hate you.
No shepherdess, but Flora...
...this your sheep-shearing,
is as a meeting of the petty gods...
...and you the queen on't.
Sir, my gracious lord...
...your high self, the gracious mark
o' the land, you have obscured...
...with a swain's wearing, and me...
...poor lowly maid,
most goddess-like prank'd up...
...but our feasts in
every mess have folly...
and feeders digest
it with a custom...
...I should blush to
see you so attired...
...swoon, I think,
to show myself a glass.
Thank you, Carmen.
Okay. Sorry.
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
BO Y: I want a DS now. Give me it.
WOMAN: No. No. No.
I said no. No, no, no, period.
Give me it.
WOMAN: I said no.
[BABY CRYING]...
[HOT HOT HEAT'S '5
TIMES OUT OF 100'
PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
Hi, Phil.
Morning, sunshine.
A guy named Brian
called for you twice.
Thank you.
Could you check the
return date on these...
for me? I think I
might be a little late.
What'd you just say?
I said I think I'm late.
Is that supposed to be funny?
Hey, honey. Sorry I'm late.
Okay, I'm just going to waive
the late fee for these.
Cool.
TIBBY: Don't worry about it.
Thank you.
LENA: So how can I help?
Can you throw a couple
onions in there?
Yeah.
What do your folks
think about art school?
I think they probably
wish I was still going...
just on Saturdays
after school, but...
They just want what's best for me.
What's that, two-car garage,
house in the suburbs?
Yeah, I mean, they've
worked so hard...
for what they have...
...and it makes me feel guilty
for not wanting the same thing.
It doesn't make you ungrateful.
Just for wanting to
find out for yourself.
Wow, everything
looks so beautiful.
You cook with so many colors.
Only another artist
would even notice that.
Can I taste something?
Yeah. Okay, let's try this.
Ooh.
You like mushrooms?
- Yeah. Looks good.
Mm. Wow.
It's good?
- That's so good.
You have to give me the recipe.
- Recipe? No, no recipe.
You don't use recipes.
- No recipes.
It's like painting inside the lines,
you know?
The downside is you never know
how it'll turn out...
...but it's kind of the upside.
Okay, so how can I help?
Yeah, try the saffron.
Just try not to knock...
anything over tonight. All right?
LENA: Yeah, yeah.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Beckwith, Beckwith, Beckwith.
Dorcas.
Well, at least I have a line, right?
That's good.
Hey, congratulations.
- Oh, thank you.
I was actually talking to Carmen.
What?
Carmen.
Perdita.
No. No, no, no.
No, no, that's not right.
No, this has to be a mistake.
Did you audition?
No.
Actually, yes.
I did, but it wasn't for real.
I was just standing there.
I was watching you and...
Congratulations.
Thanks.
It's gotta be a mistake.
It's okay. I'll be happy to help you
in any way that I can.
Thanks.
Congratulations. This is a big deal.
Come on, let's go celebrate.
Okay.
- This is great. I promise.
Hi.
You okay?
I'm fine.
Because you haven't
answered your phone...
or returned my phone calls.
I know. I've just been
busy with the script,
you know.
I'm worried too, Tib.
I am. But until we know
if this is real...
Real?
I don't mean that.
I could get a job, right?
- Yeah?
Yes, I could get a job, I could come
to New York. We have options.
What about my options? Huh?
What if I wanted to
take it all back...
...the whole night, everything?
Where's my option?
What are you saying?
I think I'm just a little weird and...
...busy, and I think
it's a bad combination.
What does that mean, like, what,
do you need space?
Oh, God.
I hate when people say that.
Yeah, because they usually mean
something else.
Like, I don't know,
you want to break up with me?
I can't finish that sentence.
Well, then why don't you call me
when you can?
CHRISTINA:
The movers are coming tomorrow.
CARMEN [O VER PHONE]:
I thought we weren't
moving till August.
Oh, I know, but David felt
that we should move sooner.
Mom, guess what. I
got cast in a play.
Nena, that's wonderful.
It was an accident, but still...
- Did you tell your friends?
Well, Julia knows.
- No, I mean your other friends.
Yeah. No. Well,
they're kind of busy.
I have to go. I'm gonna be late
for rehearsal. Can I call you back?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
- I love you.
Love you too.
Dear Carmabelle, these
might have had...
a miracle left in them after all.
I'll e-mail you. Love, Lena.
Hey. You ready? The read-through
starts in 10 minutes.
CARMEN: Yep, all ready.
Wow.
What are these?
- Oh, nothing.
They're just an old pair of pants.
- Oh.
CARMEN: Let's go.
Hey, Margaret. Where
would you like us?
We changed the call
to principals only.
We just need Carmen.
The rest of you can
have the day off.
Oh.
Wow, well, good luck.
Thanks.
MARGARET:
Carmen, your seat's next to lan.
WOMAN: Hello, dear.
Hi.
You're welcome.
Oh, I'm sorry,
did I forget to say thank you?
Thank you.
How do you feel?
Like a fake.
Please. You had them at, 'Um, hi.'
Morning, Nigel. Nigel, this is
Carmen Lowell. She's
playing Perdita.
Hi. It's nice to meet you.
I'm a big fan. Huge, actually.
Yes, our young apprentice
on the main stage.
Was that a compliment?
With Nigel, you'll never know.
KERR: Margaret.
The Winter's Tale by
William Shakespeare.
Act one, scene one.
Hey. How is it going
in the new room?
Well, apparently these women
never vacuumed.
[BOTH LAUGH]
I was wondering,
how's it going in the mortuary?
Have they found any more
graves near Cleo's?
Not yet.
Um...
I was thinking, maybe
I should transfer...
there, just in case
they need more help.
Bridget...
...archaeology is more than just
finding bones.
These people, they
painted their pots,
made their sanctuaries...
...told their stories
on every surface they had.
It is what I love most about them...
...that they left so
much of themselves...
for us to find.
Yeah, but...
Like you, I have lost family...
...and my home.
To a bloody war.
I'm just fascinated by what is left.
What endures.
'Tib, here are the pants.
Nothing happened. Carmen.'
Great.
Give me a miracle.
And feel the miracle.
Pants, please give me a miracle.
Ohm.
And stretch the miracle back.
[GRUNTS]
I just want a miracle, please.
[MUTE MATH'S 'YOU ARE MINE'
PLAYS ON STEREO]...
[PHONE BUZZING]...
Hello.
- Tibby.
What's going on? You
haven't answered...
any of my e-mails. Are you okay?
No.
- Well...
...I'm getting in the car right now.
Hang on. Can I
bring you anything?
Pregnancy test?
Lift up your countenance,
as it were the day of celebration...
...of that nuptial which we two
have sworn shall come.
Oh, Lady Fortune,
stand you auspicious.
God, why don't people
talk like this anymore?
We've gotten so lazy.
We don't say, 'Oh, Lady Fortune,
stand you auspicious.'
We say, 'Dear God, help me.'
Or instead of, 'Enjoy
the honey-heavy dew...
of slumber,' 'Yo, get some Z's.'
It's not the same.
It's just, it sounds so good
and it feels so good to say.
It's rich and luscious and...
See how she lays her cheek
upon her hand?
Oh, that I were a glove upon that...
hand, that I might
touch that cheek.
See what I mean?
Yep.
Give me those flowers
there, Dorcas.
Here's flowers for you.
Hot lavender, mint, savory.
Now...
...my fairest friend...
...I would I had some
flowers of the spring...
that might become
your time of day...
...but these I lack to
make you garlands...
of, and, my sweet friend...
...to strew you o'er and o'er.
What, like a corpse?
No. Like a bank for love,
to lie and play on...
...not like a corpse, or
if, not to be buried,
but quick, and in mine arms.
Uh...
Um, sorry, Bill.
I forgot my line.
Take a break.
We'll pick it up where we left off.
Do not go to drama school.
It'll ruin you.
Well, thank you, Nigel.
I'm enjoying your work too. Ah.
Carmen?
JULIA: Let me help you.
Did anybody see that?
No, you're fine.
- Okay.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Guess what got here
just before you did?
TIBBY:
So I thought it'd
be easier that way.
Wait. You told him
you weren't pregnant in an e-mail?
If I had called him
or told him in person...
...he might've thought
things could just...
go back the way they
were, but they can't.
Well, why not? I mean, if you're not...
pregnant, then
what's the problem?
I suck at relationships.
Should've been a guy.
No, a guy wouldn't worry about
sucking at relationships.
[TIBBY LAUGHS]
You know what the problem is?
Every time I try to
get close to somebody...
...it's like there's something
out there that just says, 'Oh.
Tibby's about to be happy.
Better get her.'
I'm not really sure what to say,
you know?
Well, maybe you're just scared.
Yeah, maybe.
Hey, I should really get back.
And leave me in the
middle of my life?
God.
I'll have another
breakdown if you stay.
Tempting. But I have
an early class.
Right-o.
- Come on.
I'll walk you back.
[WOMAN SPEAKS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]...
[NASRIN SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Look at you.
Hello.
Hi, hon.
[SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
WOMAN: Dear Honey Bee,
how is my sweetie doing?
The summer breeze
blows the sweet...
perfume from our garden
into my kitchen...
...and I think of you.
How you love flowers.
I'm sorry I can't visit you now.
But you should know
I always love you.
Dear Honey Bee:
Sometimes I want to
help your mom...
...but she thinks it is best
if I leave her alone.
I hope that she will get well
and let us visit again real soon.
Love always, Grandma.
BRIDGET: Dear Nasrin,
you deserve more than a letter...
...but as you probably guessed,
I suck at goodbyes.
You said archaeology
is more than finding bones.
And you were right.
People do have a power over us,
even after they're gone.
When my mother took her own life,
I tried to forget the past.
I ran away from the pain because...
Well, I guess I was afraid.
But the past is always with us,
and it's time I stop running.
Thank you for the lesson. Bridget.
Alas, Florizel, I know not
'tween the turkey club sandwich...
...or the Hamlet
and cheese omelet.
What say you?
Well, I come not to bury Caesar,
but to have a caesar salad.
Ooh.
- Now tell me about you.
Only child? Brothers and sisters?
Only child.
Oh, no. Well, not for long.
My mom is gonna have a baby.
It's kind of a long story.
Or not that long of a story.
Hey. Am I interrupting?
- No, not at all.
Great. Can we take
this chair? Thanks.
Sure.
Sit down.
Do you know Julia? Lan.
Yeah, we've met once or twice.
Lan's family are in the theater,
just like mine.
You went to RADA with
20 of my friends.
RADA?
Royal Academy of Dramatic Art,
it's in London.
Oh.
Did you hear about
Patrick O'Houlihan?
Lucky bastard.
I'm hoping to catch the show
when I go to New York.
We should get a whole group of
people together and surprise him.
Sounds fun.
Jam, on your lip.
- Oh.
You know, we really should order.
We've got a rehearsal
to get back to.
Caesar salad, please.
[JAMES OTTO'S 'SUNSET MAN'
PLAYING ON STEREO]
BRIDGET: Hello?
Excuse me, sir?
Hi. Greta?
Um, I'm really sorry.
I should have called first, but I'm...
I think I know my
own granddaughter.
You're not running
away from home,
are you?
No, actually, I'm coming home,
from Turkey.
That's an interesting
sense of direction.
So you fix your own car?
Cars are easy.
It's people you need a manual for.
Come on in. You
must be exhausted.
BRIDGET:
Yep. You don't even know.
GRETA: Why don't you go right up
and get some rest?
Hello.
- Hey.
Hey. Wow, you look great.
You think? Thanks.
So, what's the occasion?
Um, lan asked me to dinner.
I mean, I can be so
dense sometimes.
I didn't even know
that he liked me that way.
Did you?
- No.
But, then again,
I can be pretty dense too so...
I just thought he...
might have said
something to you...
...because you guys have become
such good friends. You know men.
So you're going, then?
You're going on a date?
Yeah. I mean, he's gorgeous,
and he's really nice, and...
...he's really real.
For an actor, anyway.
I just thought, why
not give it a chance?
We have so much
in common anyway,
and it might really work.
I know you need sleep
before rehearsal tomorrow.
I'll be really quiet
when I come home,
but don't wait up.
I won't.
- Okay. Well, have a good night.
Thanks, Greta.
Grandma.
I'm sorry, I don't know which...
I haven't heard from you in...
...10 or 12 years.
I know.
Look, my dad,
he hid your letters from me.
I just found them this summer.
I see.
So I guess we can skip...
...junior high and high school.
How's college?
It's good. I haven't declared
a major yet, but...
Got a fella?
No, not at the moment.
Listen, you ought to kick up
some trouble now...
...because in 40 years,
they'll all tell you you're old.
You made that the
summer you visited.
You must have been about
6 or 7 years old.
I've been here before?
Well, that was a long time ago.
TIBBY: 'Return to sender.'
Super.
O, the fates. How
would he look to see...
his work, so noble,
vilely bound up?
KERR: Stop.
Again.
O, the fates. How would he look to
see his work, so noble...
KERR: Stop. Again.
O, the fates.
How would he look to see his...
Stop right there.
Carmen, is there a problem?
No. I don't know.
Did I say the wrong line?
No.
You're supposed to sound like
a woman in love.
You sound like a woman
who's about to have a root canal.
Again.
O, the fates. How
would he look to s...
I hear the drill.
Again.
Carmen, wait.
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be
screwing everything up like this.
You've got great instincts.
You just need to trust them.
Why don't we work on it together,
tonight?
No. It's okay.
I should just work
on it alone. Thanks.
Oh, my God, that was torture.
- Hey.
All I could think
about was drawing you.
Sorry to interfere with
your concentration.
That's okay. I don't mind.
Okay.
Well, I guess you have to get back
to class, huh?
Yes.
I guess.
I'll see you later.
I'll see you.
KOSTOS: Lena.
There was no choice
but to be married.
My grandfather, I
think he could see
I did not love her.
And then that day at the funeral,
she saw it too.
That my heart would
always belong...
to someone else.
And that is when she told me...
...there never was a baby.
We had the marriage annulled.
I wanted to tell you right away.
But I was afraid. I didn't think
I had the right to
ask your forgiveness.
Maybe it's too much
to hope you could...
Forgive you?
I forgive you.
Lena, I thought...
That I'd be waiting
for you to come here?
No. I didn't expect anything.
I just wanted you
to know the truth.
Well...
...thank you.
The truth is we loved each other
a long time ago.
And my life is so different now.
Lena, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
No, it's okay. It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
I have to get to class.
[REGINA SPEKTOR'S 'BETTER'
PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
New York is so cool.
Mom and I, we came up
to see Hairspray...
and do a little shopping.
WAITRESS: Can I get
you guys anything?
Just give us a minute.
WAITRESS: Okay.
So you and Brian broke up, huh?
I guess.
Do you think you're over it yet?
Over him, I mean?
Like you wouldn't be
upset or anything if...
you found out he was
dating someone else?
Effie, what's this about?
I guess it's about
wanting to know if...
If you'd be okay with
me dating Brian?
Of course I said I didn't mind.
I just think it's a
little weird, you know?
She's not even his type.
And she's really
young, which is gross.
I can't believe he would
actually ask her...
out. Do you think he
would ask her out?
Whatever. It doesn't matter.
I don't really care.
I'm just curious, you know.
It kind of sounds
like you care, Tibby.
Otherwise you wouldn't
be here freaking out.
Like you're the poster girl
for even tempers?
I'm just saying
you can't have it both ways.
If you didn't want Brian
dating other girls,
then you shouldn't have
broken up with him.
Pretty simple.
You don't have a clue
why Brian and I broke up.
Well, do you?
Carmen, I was just kind of hoping
for some support.
Not a lecture and
some psychobabble.
I didn't drive all the way
up here in rush hour...
traffic just so you
could read your book.
I'm studying my lines,
Tibby. What do you...
want me to do, just stop my life?
It's not like I was
exactly expecting you.
I haven't heard from
you in what, a month?
Where the hell is
this coming from?
The fact that you even
have to ask that...
question pretty much
says everything.
Carmen. Hey, I brought
you a scone. Hi.
Thank you. Julia, this is Tibby.
Tibby, this is Julia.
You're the video-store girl.
The video-store girl.
I have to go. I have
to work on my script.
Wow. So you're a writer too?
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]...
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
LENA: Nice restaurant.
You know, it's not
too crowded either,
which is nice.
LENA: It's great.
How are you?
- Good.
LENA:
I can't believe you did all this.
Well, nothing's too
good for my muse.
What? Is that what I am?
Well, I've been feeling
really inspired lately, so...
Why do I get the feeling like
something's not right? You okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
I'm sorry, I'm just thinking.
About what exactly?
What's going on?
Nothing.
This idea of a muse,
it's romantic, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah, it's a little
romantic, I guess.
I've heard worse.
Have you ever been in love?
I love being in love.
Yeah, but...
...do you think that
there's one person...
that we're each meant to be with?
One person? No, not really.
I know that's not the answer
you wanted to hear.
No, it's the way you feel.
I like that you're honest.
But...
...you may not be into it?
No, I am.
I wanna be.
That's two different things, right?
But, I mean, Lena,
you don't need to...
apologize for what you want.
But I don't even know what I want.
I'm sorry.
And I'm sorry I keep saying
I'm sorry so much.
Then stop saying you're sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
Unless you don't like the food.
Then you should
definitely apologize.
Food's great.
TIBBY:
Uh-huh. Yeah, I'm
gonna wear black.
Excuse me?
TIBBY: Hold on, Mom.
Yes, I will be at the
anniversary party.
Call you later.
Do you know if this
movie's any good?
Well, that depends.
I mean, yes, if you
like nauseatingly...
smarmy love stories...
...that have absolutely
no basis in reality.
Oh. Well, what if
you're in the mood for,
you know, something romantic?
I would go with
Texas Chainsaw
Massacre, the remake.
It works for me.
- Thank you. Tibby, thank you.
[PHIL CHUCKLING]
I apologize.
Is there something
I can help you find?
Just forget about it, man.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Okay.
Freaking the customers
out, not one of...
the sales techniques
we discussed.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you take
the rest of the month off?
What? No, but...
Yeah, things around here
have been slow anyway.
Though with you gone,
they might just pick up again.
Yeah.
Oh, please. Please,
take anything you want.
Take it all.
Really?
- I'm lightening my load.
Thank you.
I didn't know she went to prom.
What?
Oh, yeah.
She sure did. She was so excited.
She bought five dresses.
Took them all back,
she bought five more.
But after that, she went into...
a downward spiral,
got so depressed.
Slept right through her graduation.
Yep, well, that was Marly.
Two speeds, high or very low.
[THUNDER CRASHES]...
[BRIDGET SOBBING]
Mom.
Honey.
Bee. What, honey?
What is it? What is it?
I remember it now.
There was a storm,
just like this one,
and she left me.
Even then she didn't
care about me.
No, that's not true.
Why didn't you stop
her from leaving me?
Why didn't you try harder?
It was complicated.
I tried to help her,
she wouldn't let me.
But I was always trying.
Listen to me, she loved you.
Then why didn't she
stay alive for me?
Because she was sick...
...and there was nothing that you
could've done to make her better.
You hear me?
That summer,
your father brought you to me.
Things had gotten
bad with your mom...
...and he wanted you to be here...
while he tried to get
her into a hospital.
She wouldn't let us
in her life unless...
we pretended that she wasn't sick.
Your father had to pretend.
I couldn't.
She wasn't strong like you are.
You're different.
The only reason she
hung on as long...
as she did is because
she loved you.
She loved you. You hear me?
Brian's on his way
to pick me up and
I can't find my hoops.
Can I steal yours?
Wait, Effie, you're going
to Tibby's parents'...
anniversary party with Brian?
Yeah, she said she was over him.
Effie. That's not the point.
You don't date your friend's exes.
Well, they're your
friends, not mine.
You've shut me out of
your little group...
my whole life...
...so that rule doesn't
really apply to me.
[CRAIG DAVID'S 'FRIDAY NIGHT'
PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
GIRL: Brian.
BO Y: Effie.
Brian.
- Hey. How are you?
So, what'd you think?
I thought it was great.
Everyone was good.
WOMAN 1: Hey, Effie.
WOMAN 2:
Happy anniversary, Mrs. Rollins.
Hey.
- Hello.
You know, I didn't know
if you'd be here, so...
How's the script?
Good.
It's a romantic comedy.
Which is an oxymoron.
Right.
What's...?
- Uh...
I should pr... Huh?
- L...
No, go ahead.
- What? No, l...
Jinx.
Back at you.
Effie's waiting for you.
What?
Effie.
I'm gonna get more quiche.
CARMEN [O VER PHONE]: Hello?
- Carmen?
Are you okay? What's wrong?
I'm at the hospital, honey,
the baby's coming early.
Now? Well, where's David?
He's flying back from
a business trip.
Okay, okay, I'm coming.
Mom, I'm about to start
a dress rehearsal.
I'll figure something out.
I'll be there. I'm coming.
You do what you have
to do. I'll be okay.
I just wanted to let you know.
Okay, I love you. Oh, God.
[PHONE CHIMING]...
[PHONE CHIMING]
What? Yes.
Tibby, it's me. I'm
sorry to call you like...
this, but I don't know
who else to call.
What is it, Carmen?
What's going on?
It's my mom. She just
went into labor early,
and I can't be at the hospital.
I'll be there in five minutes.
- Okay, thank you.
I'm coming.
[SCREAMING]
Again? Oh, boy, you're having
another one of those, huh?
How's it going in here?
Those ice chips are
not doing squat.
Look at her. You have to
give her one of those, the needle.
She elected to do...
...natural childbirth.
Are you crazy?
Lady, dear Queen,
who ended when I but began...
'Give me that hand of yours.'
Give me that hand of yours...
- 'To kiss.'
...to kiss.
KERR: Stop.
Okay, Christina,
I'm told you are ready to push.
No, no, no. I have to wait for David.
She's gonna wait for David.
She should wait for David.
Do you have something
to help her wait?
DOCTOR: You need to
stop fighting...
and let go. Push.
CHRISTINA: I can't.
Christina, listen to me, you can.
You can do this.
I'm here, okay? I'm here for you.
Okay? Just start pushing.
I'm not gonna leave you.
We're gonna do this together.
Okay, you and me,
we're gonna do this.
Okay. Okay. You ready?
All right, you're gonna push.
Beseech you of your
own state take care.
This dream of mine,
being now awake...
Um...
I'll queen it no inch further, but...
[BABY CRYING]
DOCTOR: There he is.
My beautiful baby boy.
TIBBY: He's really tiny.
And purple... Perfect.
Oh, my God, he looks like marble.
Carmen would be so proud of you.
She would've been
proud of both of us.
I couldn't have done it without you,
Tibby.
Thank you.
Thank you so much
for being there, Tib.
She was so lucky to have you.
No, no, no, don't wake her up.
Just give her a kiss.
And give the baby a kiss too.
Okay. I'll see you soon.
IAN: Good news?
Yeah, I have a baby brother.
Congratulations.
Thank you. I'm sorry,
I don't know why I'm crying.
God. I just...
I can't believe I wasn't there.
You know, my whole
life it's been me...
and my mom...
...Iooking after each other.
And I don't know, I just...
I recently feel so
far away from her...
...and my friends.
Not unlike Perdita.
Who lost her mother for 16 years?
I guess.
I don't even know
why I'm telling you all of this.
It's bad enough I single-handedly
am ruining our show.
Everyone knows you're upset.
But dress rehearsals
are supposed to suck.
Let me take you out to dinner
and we can talk about it.
I'm okay. Besides, you probably
have plans with Julia.
Julia?
I barely know the
girl. We had dinner...
once because she
fairly begged me.
What, she asked you?
Carmen, if there's anyone I've been
wanting to go out with, it's you.
I understand this
isn't the right time.
I'll see you tomorrow.
JULIA: Wow, that was just awful.
KERR: I am simply flummoxed.
My instincts about actors
are never wrong.
Bill, you can't beat yourself up.
I probably should have...
said something from
the beginning.
I love Carmen, but
she's very insecure.
At the end of the day,
maybe she just...
doesn't have what it takes.
Dad?
Oh, I must have dozed off.
How was your trip?
Good.
- Good.
Both of them, actually.
I went to visit Greta.
Bridget, I was only trying to...
- Dad, it's okay.
She helped me so much...
...to understand these
things that you...
and I were never able to talk about.
And what are these things
you think you understand now?
That you loved Mom
more than I ever knew.
And you couldn't have saved her.
No one could have.
It's just who she was.
If we're gonna get
through this, Dad...
...we have to start
taking care of each other, okay?
Don't you think that...
that's what she
would have wanted?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think that's what
she would've wanted.
I love you, Daddy.
I love you.
I'm really sorry.
That night...
...I think I felt a little more
than I bargained for.
Maybe I thought I
was being punished...
...for feeling too much.
Why didn't you just
talk to me, Tib?
Because I can't lie to you
as well as I can lie to myself.
You need to have a little faith, Tib.
Not everyone you love
is going to leave you.
I know that now.
So wanna get some breakfast?
Yeah. Breakfast sounds great.
CHRISTINA: This is
your baby brother,
Nena. Ryan Christopher Sands.
I tried to get him to
wait a little longer,
but this one's got
a mind of his own.
Just like somebody else I know.
He reminds me so
much of you, Nena.
When they put you in my arms
for the first time...
...I never saw anything so beautiful
in my whole life.
And I knew that from then on,
my heart would be full.
So you go out on that stage now...
...and you show them
how beautiful you are.
We'll be waiting for you...
...at home.
I love you.
Say goodbye. Bye, Carmen.
Hi. So I just want to say...
...break a leg, and...
...you deserve your
day in the sun, so...
Your night in the sun.
You deserve your night in the sun.
Bye.
Jesus, Carmen, where the hell...
have you been? You're
on in 30 seconds.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God,
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
These your unusual weeds...
...to each part of you do give a life.
This your sheep-shearing
is as a meeting...
of the petty gods, and
you the queen on't.
Sir, my gracious lord...
...your high self,
the gracious mark o' the land...
...you have obscured
with a swain's wearing...
...and me, poor lowly maid,
most goddess-like prank'd up.
O, the Fates.
How should he look,
to see his work,
so noble, vilely bound up?
What would he say?
See, your guests approach.
Address yourself to entertain them...
sprightly, and let's
be red with mirth.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]...
Great job.
- You too.
Carmen, that was incredible.
Sometimes words fail.
[EFFIE SOBBING]
Effie?
Effie, what's wrong?
What happened?
EFFIE:
Brian's going back to Tibby.
Can't he see that
she doesn't love him?
Well, you don't know that, Effie.
You don't treat someone
like that if you love them.
Well, it's not that simple.
You're actually taking
her side on this, aren't you?
No, I'm not taking sides.
Even though I'm your sister,
you've always chosen
them over me.
Effie, that's not...
I wish I was on my way to Greece...
...so I could be out of this house
and away from you.
You know, you've barely said
two words to me all week.
You get a couple good
reviews and suddenly
I'm not good enough
to be your friend?
Actually, I didn't read the reviews.
Were they any good?
That's not the point, Carmen.
In case you forgot,
I brought you here.
So you wouldn't have any of this
if it weren't for me.
But you didn't really
give me anything.
I am who I've always
been, and, sure,
maybe for a minute, I
was a little insecure.
I know you did what you could
to keep me that way.
Right?
Look, Julia, I'm very sorry
if my tiny bit of success...
...feels like I've taken something
from you.
But if there's one thing
I've learned this summer...
...it's that no one can diminish you
but yourself.
And you taught me that.
So thank you.
EFFIE: Lena.
Lena, I am so sorry.
- What's wrong?
I did something really terrible.
What did you do?
Well, I was mad at you
and at Tibby and everyone...
...and I took them.
Took what?
The pants.
You took them? You have the pa...
You have them over
there in Greece?
That's the terrible part.
You see, I wore them on the ferry
and they got wet...
...so when I got to Yia Yia's,
I hung them on the clothesline.
I never thought that...
- That what?
Well, I don't know if the wind...
blew them away or
what, but they're gone.
Look, they're not
lost. She'll find them.
How big is Santorini?
They're lost.
Are you sure she
even really looked?
This is Effie we're
talking about. No offense.
I hate to say this,
but this never
would've happened...
...if the rotation wasn't screwed up.
You were supposed
to send them to me.
I didn't get the press release
you were in Ala-fricking-bama.
Yeah, me neither.
- It must have been lost...
...along with
'Tibby has a pregnancy scare.'
Excuse me?
What pregnancy scare?
I didn't want to worry you.
You didn't have a
problem telling Lena.
I was here.
I tried to tell you, when I came up
to your place, you know.
I wanted to tell you,
we got in that fight...
I e-mailed everybody.
It's not my fault I
have a lame server.
Oh, well, thank God for e-mail.
You can have an entire
relationship...
and not even look at somebody.
E-mails, guys, really? That's lame.
Can we just focus on the pants?
No, maybe this is
a sign, you know.
That we should just forget about it.
What are you talking about, Tibby?
The pants, okay?
'The pants'. They're supposed to...
bring us together,
and look, look at us.
Look at us.
All the more reason
to try and find them.
My sister lost them.
I'll go to Greece and find them.
[SPEAKING IN GREEK]
My beautiful granddaughter.
Is Effie inside?
Effie? That girl.
She left for Athens this morning.
She was too afraid to face you.
Not very Greek of her, of course.
Naturally.
Come, your room is
ready. Come here.
Thank you.
CHRISTINA: It's Effie.
- Effie?
Here, take him.
Come on.
Yes.
Effie, what's up? Did
she find the pants?
I don't know, I'm in Athens.
Listen, I would've
never taken the pants...
...if I knew what she was going...
through, but she
never said a word.
So Kostos isn't married.
- Nope.
And he went all the way to RISD
to tell Lena that?
Two weeks ago. Effie ran into him...
in Greece, and he
told her the story.
He came out here and Lena...
won't even give him
a second chance?
Gee, imagine that.
- Shut up.
I just wish Lena
had said something to us.
I know.
Well, she shouldn't have to.
Yia Yia. How do you
say 'lost pants'...
in Greek?
[SPEAKS IN GREEK]
Greek girls do not lose their pants.
[CHATTERING]
TIBBY: Sure this guy knows
where we're going?
CARMEN: Yep, he says
we just stay on this main path...
...then we take a left
at the third bend.
TIBBY: Oh, so you
speak Greek now?
BRIDGET:
Come on, we've got
bigger problems.
One of your donkeys
just did something way nasty.
Shit.
Oh, that's gonna leave a mark.
Opa. Lena.
- Bridget.
What are you guys doing here?
You think we'd let
you do this alone?
Oh, my God. Hi.
It turns out my stepdad had
a million frequent flier miles...
...and they were about to expire,
so he gave them to us.
LENA: Hi, Tibby.
I just fell off a donkey.
Are you okay?
Are we having fun yet?
Okay, about 500 more.
There.
Excuse me. Do you
know somebody...
named Kostos or Kostas?
Tibs, everybody here
is named Kostos.
Bridget, please.
Kostos Dunas.
Kostos? Yes. Nice boy.
You miss him by 10 minutes.
Naturally.
He go to sell his
fish, to restaurant.
BRIDGET: Carmen.
We got a lead.
This guy over here just told us...
...He Who Must Not Be Named's
at the restaurant.
Excuse me. There is a tourist.
What?
With the pants,
that I found that has the pants...
...and he's at the restaurant.
So if we go to the restaurant, we'll...
find this particular
tourist with the jeans...
...who might be there,
will probably be
there. He'll be there.
Are you guys okay?
What?
- What?
We're fine.
- Let's go to the restaurant.
Hey, you guys, look, green hat.
Is that him?
CARMEN: Oh, my God.
I've only seen pictures,
but it totally looks like him.
He's hot.
- Everyone, be calm, okay?
I'll do the talking.
No.
- What?
We'll go and do the talking.
- Where are we going?
We're going to you
to warn you that
Kostos is standing
right over there.
Oh.
Well, that's okay.
We'll just calmly and quietly...
turn around and just
go right back...
No. He's already seen you. Go.
BRIDGET: Good luck.
Effie told me you were coming.
I kept hoping I see you before
I have to leave tomorrow.
I almost called to
ask you to meet me...
at my boat.
But I wasn't sure you remember
which one it was.
I remember.
So you said you were
leaving tomorrow.
Yes.
I got into the graduate program...
at the London School
of Economics.
Oh, really?
That's great.
Anyway, I should go.
It's good to see you, Lena.
I really hope you'll be happy.
You too.
Lena?
There's a full moon tonight.
It's called a 'sailor's moon.'
Maybe it will bring
you good luck, eh?
Help you find
what you are really looking for.
Hey.
- Hey.
Um... Well, that's that.
Let's just go.
That's that? That's that?
[SPEAKS IN GREEK]
Okay, Lena, will
you say something,
please? What happened?
Nothing happened.
Nothing happened? Do
you have any idea...
how long we've been
looking for this guy...?
Slick.
Wait. That's why you guys
were acting so weird?
You've been planning this
this whole time?
No.
- Yes.
Yes?
We didn't come to Greece
just for the pants.
Wait, I don't believe this.
Why would you guys lie to me?
Because, Lena, we knew you
couldn't do it on your own.
And why didn't you tell us that
Kostos wasn't married, Lena?
Because it doesn't matter.
- Yes, it does matter.
No, it doesn't matter.
He's... It's over.
Well, it didn't look over to me.
- Me neither.
Nope.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
No way you could understand.
What's to understand?
Why can't you just stop
thinking about it...
...and follow your heart?
- Because he broke my heart. He...
It hurts. I don't ever want to feel
this way again.
I don't think I could
go through this again.
Lena, this just happens once
in a lifetime, you know.
I think that you owe it to yourself
to at least try.
Lena Kaligaris.
We are terrible at
not loving each other.
I tried to stop, but I couldn't.
I tried too.
So, what do we do?
We figure it out.
[LAUGHING]
Well, now that Kostos
is taken care of...
Oh, shut up.
- Kostos.
Stop.
What are we gonna
do about the pants?
I don't know. We've been here for...
five days. What if
we don't find them?
BRIDGET:
I hate the idea of
leaving without them.
TIBBY:
God, I hate the idea
of leaving at all.
CARMEN: Oh, my...
What an idiot.
Bridget?
- Bridge, don't.
Bridget.
CARMEN: Hey.
Are you crazy?
TIBBY: Don't. No, Bridget.
LENA: Don't do this. It's not funny.
TIBBY: Stop.
I'm not the only
one that's going in.
What are you doing?
Come on, we're all gonna go.
- Jump.
No, I'm not doing this.
I'll dip my toes...
in the water or something.
TIBBY: Oh, my God, be careful.
One, two, three.
[BOTH SCREAM]
CARMEN:
Oh, my God, I can't do that.
Come on, Carmen, jump. Hurry.
CARMEN: Sometimes I
like to think that...
the pants got lost on purpose...
...that this was their
final gift to us...
...bringing us back together...
...back to a place
of forgiveness and love...
...and an understanding
that what we shared...
was all the magic
we could ever need.
And as we spent those
last few moments of summer...
...looking out at the blending
of sea and sky...
...I realized it was a color
I knew very well:
The softly faded essential blue...
...of a well-worn pair of pants.
The pants had brought
us together again.
The rest...
...was in our hands.