CAROLINE:
"I lost no time, of course,
"in telling my mother
all that I knew
"and we saw ourselves at once in
a difficult and dangerous position.
"Something must speedily be
resolved upon, and it occurred to us
"at last to go forth together and
seek help in the neighboring hamlet.
"No sooner said than done.
Bare-headed as we were,
"we ran out at once in the
gathering evening and the frosty fog.
"The hamlet lay
not many hundred yards away
"though out of view, on the
other side of the next cove
"and what greatly
encouraged me
"it was
in an opposite direction
"from that whence the blind
man had made his appearance.
"And I shall never forget
how much I was cheered
"to see the yellow shine
in doors and windows,
"but that, as it proved
"was the best of the help we were
likely to get in that quarter.
"For you would have thought
"men would have been
ashamed of themselves,
"no soul would consent
to return with us to the... "
Audrey? Sorry.
Mr. Talcott's gone.
Okay.
Front desk,
in case anyone shows.
I think you'll be waiting
a while, hon.
No. Didn't we call?
He said he had family.
Yeah. But they don't wanna
have anything to do with him.
You can dump it out back.
(SIGHS)
(BAND PLAYING)
Okay, take a look.
I interview tomorrow.
What about your job?
I had enough of that place.
Why, what happened?
Here's your beer.
Thanks.
Sure.
I lost a patient today.
Mr. Talcott.
I'm sorry.
You should have seen it.
The second he died,
it was like
they couldn't wait
to get him out of there.
It's just a business
to them.
It is a business,
but at least he had you.
No. It's supposed to be
a business about caring.
They couldn't care less.
Wait. This is Terrebonne
Parish. It's the freaking swamps.
I get the hours I need to start
nursing school, and I get paid.
And I get to help somebody,
my way.
They got gators in the
swamps, and guys missing teeth.
Are we dancing here,
or what?
Cary, look.
This work you're doing, are
you sure it's not changing you?
I'm 25 years old. What's wrong
with a little change?
(BAND CONTINUES PLAYING)
(DEATH LETTER PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Oh, my God.
(ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING)
Hello?
(KNOCKING)
(GASPS)
Hello?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
LUKE: Now that right there
is what love is all about.
Old-fashioned devotion,
like what you read about.
You must be Caroline.
I'm sorry, the door was open,
so I just walked in.
Oh, no. It's a big house.
I didn't hear you.
LUKE: It's okay.
(BOTH LAUGH)
So much for getting
their affairs in order.
I'm sorry. I'm Luke Marshall.
Estate lawyer.
We talked on the phone.
Oh, right.
The docs figure a month maybe.
He's pretty far gone.
CAROLINE: I understand.
His wife's having kind of
a rough time with it.
Most people do.
(GRUNTS)
LUKE:
Violet, you have a visitor.
May I present
Miss Caroline Ellis?
She works down at the hospice
in New Orleans.
Caroline,
this is Violet Devereaux.
You have a lovely home.
I'm sorry. It's just hard. The
idea of a stranger living here...
I understand, really.
She's Old South, you know.
She thinks women still curtsey.
So, he can't talk at all?
No. Stroke pretty much
paralyzed him.
Which side was affected?
Both.
It happened about a month
ago, up in the attic.
That's where
she found him.
Ben?
You have a visitor.
Meet Miss Caroline Ellis.
Hello, Ben.
I'm Caroline.
VIOLET:
She's not from around here.
She's not gonna
understand my house.
She's from New Orleans.
She wasn't raised in New
Orleans. You hear how she talks?
Who knows where she comes
from? Hoboken, New Jersey.
What, do you want
a Southern accent?
The last one left,
Violet.
All right.
But she's not gonna
understand the house.
The last girl left, huh?
LUKE: Wait. Let me talk to her,
we can straighten things out.
I can't help anybody
who doesn't want my help.
She does want help.
She's just scared.
Of what? Politeness?
No. He's the love of her life
and he's dying.
They've been together
forever.
She's losing
her soul mate here.
I don't know about you, but that'd
put some sandpaper up my ass.
Aren't you a romantic?
Look.
The last girl quit.
You're the fifth interview
since.
She shoots down everyone.
It's not personal.
But you being here
means he's really dying.
He's dying
whether I'm here or not.
What'd she mean
about the house?
What?
She said I wouldn't understand
the house. Why'd she said that?
All I know is
her checks clear.
Look, forget it.
If it makes you feel any better, I'm
still looking for my dream job, too.
All right.
So if you talked to her,
what would you say?
I'd say she could look
all she wants
but I doubt she'd find
any better than you.
So she'd do well
to treat you like it.
JILL: Okay, here are
my rules. No knitting.
No joining a bridge club.
And no playing bingo.
Okay, good. Good rules.
I'm serious, they'll try and
suck you into their elderly ways.
It's less than an hour away.
I'll be back all the time.
Yeah, well, you better.
Whenever you want to talk to someone
who wasn't around for World War ll.
Jeez, what is it with you
and old people?
Come here.
He'd be proud of you.
You know he would.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRD CAWING)
(PHONOGRAPH PLAYING)
Hello?
I need to pay for some gas.
(BEE BUZZING)
Hello?
(BABY CRYING)
(PHONOGRAPH SWITCHING OFF)
Is somebody back there?
(GASPS)
I'm sorry.
Excuse me. I just need
to pay for some gas.
(BABY CRYING)
(WOMAN SPEAKING CREOLE)
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
Jesus.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING CREOLE)
$17 for the gas.
Keep the change.
CAROLINE:
Mrs. Devereaux?
I'm unpacked.
(COME ON IN MY KITCHEN
PLAYING ON PHONOGRAPH)
Hi, Ben. Remember me?
I'm Caroline.
I'll be taking care of you
for a while.
There's not a lot of light
in here for you, is there?
So you're a fan of the
blues, huh? Well, so was...
You have to let go.
Ben, you're hurting me.
Ouch.
VIOLET:
There you are.
Time for his remedies.
Scoot over, child.
VIOLET: 9:00 in the
morning and 7:00 at night.
He takes his pills in powder
form. I'll show you how.
Be sure he drinks it all down.
CAROLINE: What's he taking?
Oh, Coumadin and such.
He gets the tremors sometimes.
Don't let that frighten you.
And a kiss
to make it taste better.
You're scrawnier than I'd
hoped. Prettier, though.
I bet you're all marked up,
aren't you?
Marked up?
Written on.
I know you young people
are always
jabbing yourselves
with ink and needles.
You're written on,
aren't you?
Not where you can see.
Well.
He's to be bathed daily,
his linens changed.
Don't bother with the housework.
I'm the only one that knows how.
How long
have you two lived here?
Let's see.
We came over
from Savannah in '62.
We bought this house
from a brother and a sister.
They'd inherited it a long
time ago, from their parents.
Lived here
since they were children.
There they are.
Martin and Grace.
Charming people.
But they fell on hard times,
had to sell.
You keep their picture?
Yes. I like to pay my respects
to the memories of this house.
VIOLET:
All right. Come along now.
This is the dining room.
We only use
about half of the rooms.
The others are
for Ben's antique business.
What he couldn't sell,
we stored here.
Except for the attic.
That has crystal and china.
And I keep a very close account
on that, just so as you know.
There are more than
30 rooms in all.
In the old days, they made
a separate key for each room.
For the owner,
they made a skeleton key.
This will open every door.
This one is yours.
I have mine.
Now, the pantry's
right out here.
You know, we may have to ask
you to go into town now and then.
Was there a mirror here once?
I noticed in the bathrooms
also there are no mirrors.
Child, when you get as
worn-out and wrinkled as we are,
you don't need
any reminding.
If you want a small one
for your own purposes
that's fine with me.
What'd you do with them?
Put them away.
The boy tells me
you don't smoke.
I do smoke. I smoke a lot
and I enjoy it very much.
I trust that won't
be an issue.
It won't be.
Good. Then for the most part
just realize that
I'll live here as if
you're not in residence.
After all, we're not kin.
Are your parents still alive?
My mom left when I was little.
My dad raised me
and he died last year.
Oh, my. So you cared
for him as well?
I would have.
I just thought
I had more time.
You think too much about
the time you have left,
you don't spend it living.
Be good to my husband.
Be good to his house.
Remedies at 9:00.
CAROLINE:
One, two, three.
(GRUNTS)
You don't see gardens like this
back in New Jersey, I expect.
Actually,
it's the Garden State.
(CHUCKLING)
I doubt that very much.
Nothing more glorious
than a garden.
Gone every winter,
back every spring.
You religious at all?
I try to keep an open mind.
That's good. That's very good.
Where are my trilliums?
Oh, fiddlesticks.
Do me a blessing, child.
Will you run up
to the attic for me?
I have some seed packets in a
box right next to the stairs.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
(RATTLING)
(GASPS)
What took you?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
I thought
the key opens everything.
The key? What key?
The key you gave me
for the house.
There's a door in the attic
it doesn't work for.
Oh, no, the attic,
it's never opened that.
I got my Dixie-Johns.
Why not?
What's in there?
I have no idea.
It's been shut ever since
we moved in.
I have to get these in the ground,
because there's rain coming.
Mrs. Devereaux,
Ben was in the attic, wasn't
he, when he had his stroke?
What was he doing in there?
You'll have
to ask him, child.
Be a dear and go see
to him, won't you?
I wonder if he wouldn't like
some iced tea.
(WATER RUNNING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(MOANING)
(THUDDING)
(SIGHS)
(METALLIC RATTLING)
(RATTLING)
(RATTLING CONTINUES)
His door was locked.
Ben!
(GASPING)
Stop right there, Ben!
Don't move!
Stop!
Ben!
Mrs. Devereaux!
(GRUNTING)
Ben!
(GRUNTING) Ben, what
are you doing? It's me!
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
Mother of mercy,
what's he done?
He got out of the window. I
thought you said he was bedridden.
He's having spasms.
Didn't you give him his remedies? Yes.
Did you make sure he drank
them all down? I thought so.
Ben, what'd they make you do?
His door was locked.
Just go get the wheelchair.
We've gotta get him out of this.
What about a doctor?
In the morning,
just get that wheelchair now.
VIOLET: Caroline!
What in damnation
took you so long?
I came as fast
as I could.
We're just gonna have to double his
remedies. That's all I can think of.
Caroline, help me here.
Help me get him.
Come on. That's it.
(BIRD CAWING)
Where did you think
you were going?
LUKE: You're here two days and
he already tried to kill himself.
Must have some kind of
bedside manner, huh?
One of my many charms.
So, what exactly happened?
I came to update her will,
she's up with the doc,
says he fell?
He did fall.
Like what,
from his wheelchair?
(SIGHS)
You cannot be serious. From up
there? He fell from up there?
How? He can't even walk.
Don't tell me you're quitting.
I have to start over again.
Will you shut the door? I
want to show you something.
You know what
my mama used to say?
If a lady invites you into her room,
she probably isn't much of a lady.
Homespun Southern wisdom grows
on trees around here, doesn't it?
I found this
in Ben's room
last night.
Found what? His laundry?
No, it had a...
There was...
Had a what?
There was a... It had a...
Forget it.
I thought it...
I don't know what I thought.
I admire you.
You know, what you do.
Hell, I wouldn't be able to
take care of my own parents.
You'd regret it.
I quit college to help out
with some friends' bands.
Out all night,
always on the road.
My father thought
I was throwing my life away.
So we didn't talk,
didn't visit.
Stubborn and proud,
and that's how we left it.
You mean...
Yeah.
He was gone before
I even knew he was sick.
I guess he wanted to spare me
from all this.
Is that so wrong?
No one should have
to die alone.
So tell me
what you were gonna tell me.
About Ben.
Do you ever feel like
he's asking you
for help?
Asking me?
With a look or
a touch.
VIOLET: Mr. Marshall?
Where in damnation
is that boy? Caroline,
have you seen Mr...
Well,
I see the children
are getting acquainted.
Now, Violet,
you know you're the
only woman in my life.
I know no such things,
and remove your perspirations.
The doctor has departed,
so I'm ready
to discuss estate matters,
if you have finished
soliciting your new business.
All right.
Whenever you get the time.
VIOLET: Caroline?
I'm making some sweet tea.
Are you interested?
Caroline?
"Sacrifice. "
Are you in the house?
(DOOR CREAKING)
(GASPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Caroline?
You're forgetful, child.
(GASPS)
PAPA JUSTIFY:
It is time, Lord.
From the dry dust,
out of these chains
from the devil's house.
It is time, Lord,
to take me
from the dry dust,
break me from these chains.
Bring me
from the devil's house.
Take me out of darkness.
Walk me out of blindness.
Lift me out of sadness.
Save me from my damned-ness.
Please, Lord.
It is time, Lord.
Take me from the dry dust.
Break me
out of these chains. Bring
me from the devil's house.
Take me out of...
Just a local band.
How about you
buy me a drink?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Whatever it is,
it's not your average attic.
She says it's been locked up
ever since they first moved in.
You found yourself
a hoodoo room.
A what? Hoodoo. You know what hoodoo is?
It's like voodoo, right?
JILL:
Wrong. Voodoo's a religion.
Slaves brought it to Haiti
from Africa.
You worship God,
heaven and hell.
How's hoodoo different?
It's magic.
American folk magic. God
doesn't have much to do with it.
Magic?
Yeah.
It's part African, part
European, part Native American.
And New Orleans is its home.
It started here.
My Aunt Nola's into it. She
shops at a place in Algiers.
Look, you said the house
had a history, right?
Hoodoo is pretty harmless.
Harmless how?
It's psychological,
like a lot of that stuff.
It can't hurt you
if you don't believe.
So this place
your aunt shops at...
Ever seen it?
It's either this street
or the next one
or the next one.
There.
There? That's a Laundromat.
Look, that's all I know.
That's where she goes.
So you coming in
or what?
I'm not.
I thought you don't
believe in this stuff.
I don't.
But I'm not just going
to mess around with it.
So, you wanna go in, go ahead.
You're scared.
Jill the Thrill is scared.
Kiss my ass.
You're never gonna live this down.
We come all the way out here...
I'm not scared.
(SIGHS)
(CREAKING)
VIOLET:
Good night, Caroline.
Good night.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
I told you about the mirrors.
I don't understand.
This is not your house.
I found them. I needed a
mirror for my bathroom...
I told you, and you heard me.
No mirrors.
No mirrors!
I've seen the room.
What room? The room you
say you've never seen.
It's not locked anymore.
No, child, you don't know
what you've seen.
You're gonna tell me
right now.
Or I'm leaving.
You're not from the South.
You won't understand.
That room up there,
you just don't go in and
throw things out of a room like that.
You leave them just
where you found them.
The house is theirs
just as much as ours.
The house is whose? Whose
things are in that room?
All right.
About 90 years ago
there was a banker here,
his name was Thorpe.
He made his fortune
cheating the poor.
He was a mean man.
He was a cruel man.
It was him, and his family,
and couple of servants
name of Mama Cecile
and Papa Justify.
Sit down.
The way I heard it, old
man Thorpe, he didn't know
that Papa Justify was
a "two-headed doctor. "
He was a conjure man.
So was Cecile.
They believed in...
Hoodoo.
Yeah.
That was their room.
They were famous
all through the bayous.
They healed the sick
and they hurt the mean.
"Hit a straight lick with a
crooked stick," as the coloreds say.
But old Thorpe,
he just saw them as help.
And he worked them
to the bone.
He abused them.
Until one night,
as the story goes
there was a party.
It was the bank's anniversary,
all the big mucketymucks were here.
Politicians, sugar barons,
riverboat tycoons.
There was a lot of drinking
and dancing
and a couple of trysts,
I'm sure.
And then, finally, when
it was time to say farewell
some of the guests wanted to
wish goodbye to the children.
But nobody could find them.
They hadn't seen them in hours.
So, being all full of brandy,
they made it a game.
"Let's Find the Children. "
Room after room after room.
Finally,
someone heard music...
Martin? Grace?
...and voices
and shouting
up in the attic.
PAPA JUSTIFY:
From the devil's house.
It is time, Lord.
VIOLET: The servants were
up there with the children.
They were trying to teach
them how to conjure hoodoo.
MAN:
And take his head.
Thorpe went about insane, and
so did the rest of the guests.
I mean, how long had this
blasphemy been going on?
The children said it was their
fault, that they'd wanted to learn.
But they weren't
having any of that.
(SCREAMING)
(WOMAN WAILING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
All that power and rage
and insanity.
The party was over.
It was a terrible thing.
Terrible.
Rumors got out,
but no arrests, no trial.
Money had its way.
What happened
to the family?
The bank went under.
Thorpe shot his wife to death,
and then turned the gun on himself.
People in the bayou say it was
Justify and Cecile's revenge.
The children stayed here
till '62.
But they never, ever, told us
why that room was locked.
Or why there were no mirrors
in the whole house.
Now we know.
You know what?
You see them
in the mirrors.
Who?
The servants.
I've gone and read some
hoodoo books, and they say
putting brick dust down
will keep harm away.
So I made a big circle
of it around the whole house.
You can't expect me to believe
you see ghosts in your mirrors.
The ghosts are here now.
But whatever
they did to him
I am not going
to let them do it to me.
Now you'll leave
like all the rest of them.
(BIRD CALLING)
That's some superstitious wife
you got there, Ben.
She thinks you have ghosts
in the attic.
Spooky, huh?
Ouch.
Hold on.
I'll be right back.
She says you see them
in the mirrors.
Ghosts in the mirrors.
(GRUNTING)
I'm sorry, Ben.
(GASPING)
Ben, stop it. Shh.
Relax. I'm so...
I'm so sorry.
(PANTING)
CAROLINE:
I'm so sorry.
You see them, too.
I'm going to town.
Shopping.
VIOLET:
What for, Caroline?
Caroline, what for?
We'll just have to see.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
MAMA CYNTHIA:
He won't beat you again.
WOMAN: Mama Cynthia,
he beat me last night.
You use the potion that
I'm gonna fix for you
and it won't happen again.
I will promise you that.
I'm scared.
Don't be afraid.
Are you sure
that I can do it?
I know it will.
It will work.
Just do as I say.
Don't be afraid.
It will work, and it won't
happen again, ever.
Don't worry about it.
He won't hit you again.
Just use this
potion I mixed up.
I have a lot
of things in here.
And you use it
as I told you.
Okay, I trust you, Mama. You'll do fine.
That brick dust at the door,
how does it work?
You lay a line down.
Nobody that means you harm
can cross it.
It's how you tell
who your enemies are.
It's like hypnotism, right?
Suggestion?
And when this stuff works, it's
because someone believes it works?
And if you thought,
you know,
magic made you sick
you might believe
in a magic cure, right?
Even though
it's all in your head.
Somebody been working
roots on you.
Say I knew someone
who believed he'd been...
Crossed.
Would he believe
he could be uncrossed?
What's the nature
of his condition?
He can't speak. Barely
moves. He had a stroke
but he seems to think someone
else made him that way.
And you want to know
what happened to him?
Yes.
(HUMMING)
JILL: You went in there.
You actually went in.
Are you out of your mind?
Come on. Haven't you ever heard
of psychosomatic treatment?
Yeah. But this
is not that.
How much of a patient's recovery
depends on his believing he can?
What recovery?
This is hospice.
You're just supposed
to help this guy die.
He believes in this stuff.
So what? Who is he to you?
Forget it.
No, you forget it.
He's not your dad.
Not this one, the last
one, or the one before.
Why are the two of you
so attached?
I'm sorry, Cary.
Just so you know,
if I'm not attached to him
I'm abandoning him.
Attached is better.
I know. Cary,
I'm sorry. Okay?
But would you
look at yourself?
You want to be a nurse and you
just walked out of a witch doctor's.
It's not for me.
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
WOMAN ON TV: Forecasters are
calling for up to a foot of rain
in the coastal areas
as this storm makes its way across
the delta, starting overnight.
Radar already shows
increasing precipitation
across the coastal areas and
moving rather quickly to the north.
The main forecast concerns
centers around potential...
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
Hi, Ben.
I'm gonna show you something.
It's going to be
our secret. You and me.
Violet says you
didn't have a stroke
in the attic.
She said some ghosts
made you this way
with a spell.
Is that what you think?
Because I know
a spell, too, Ben.
One that makes you better.
All you have to do
is believe it.
Backwards.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Cleanse this man.
Cleanse this room.
Cleanse this house.
His words have gotten lost,
lost and wandering in his mind.
Let the water run down
and wash away
this condition.
His tongue has gotten tied,
tied and tangled in his throat.
Let the water run down
and wash away
this affliction.
Send his voice to go free.
Let the water run down
and wash away...
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GURGLES)
Caroline.
(GASPING)
(STAMMERING)
Caroline.
It's all in your head.
Help. Help.
Ben, talk to me.
Keep talking.
Help me.
Help you?
Help you how, Ben?
Get me out of here.
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
VIOLET: Caroline?
Caroline?
(SCREAMING)
Get me out of here!
CAROLINE: Shit!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Caroline!
Just a second.
VIOLET: Caroline,
open this door!
What are you
doing to him?
Ben, why?
Get out of here, why?
VIOLET: Caroline!
One second!
VIOLET: Caroline,
open this door!
I'll help you, I promise.
Just talk to me.
What happened to you in that
attic? Tell me who you're afraid of.
(DOOR OPENING)
What have you done?
What is this?
He was...
He was struggling
in his sleep...
VIOLET:
Get away from him.
He was struggling.
VIOLET:
It's all right.
I brought water.
You were talking to him?
I was just telling him a story
to settle him down.
VIOLET: About what?
Just a story.
No ghosts.
That'll be all tonight,
Caroline. Thank you.
I'll come back
to check on him...
No, that won't be necessary.
That's all for tonight. Good night.
(CLICKING)
(CAROLINE GASPING)
PAPA JUSTIFY:
It is time, Lord.
(ECHOING)
(GROANS)
It is time, Lord.
Grace.
WOMAN: Caroline?
Caroline.
(GASPING)
(GASPS)
Mrs. Devereaux?
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
(SQUAWKING)
Her and her ghost shit.
CAROLINE: That attic is
filled with this stuff.
Recipes. Spells. Books
of them. Records of them.
I understand
your cause of concern
but my family is superstitious,
too. We're called Baptists.
This is different.
It's charming.
Local color.
You said yourself you
were worried about him.
Well, now I'm worried
about you. You know?
Are you a nurse
or a detective?
When did you first meet the Devereauxs?
Just before
he had his stroke.
They were looking for a lawyer
to update their wills.
Did you ever think that
maybe she knew something
was gonna happen to him?
How? Like tarot cards in the
attic? A séance in her sleep?
I want to know
why the last girl quit.
Hallie.
Some folks to see you.
HALLIE: You a superstitious
person, Caroline?
CAROLINE:
Not per se.
HALLIE: I told my mama
where I was working.
She said that house has been
nothing but blood and tears.
That the last owners were
some rich brother and sister.
Crazy people, supposedly.
They died of strokes right
after they sold the place.
Maybe they found something
they shouldn't.
Maybe now Ben did, too.
It may be their mess
in that room
but ain't no ghosts put
a spell on that old man.
She did.
Do you believe that?
Don't you?
But I heard
it can't hurt you.
I mean, it can't hurt you
if you don't believe.
Then I suggest you leave
that house before you do.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
LUKE: For God's sake, this is
insane. The man had a stroke.
CAROLINE: So why isn't
that what he thinks?
And you're gonna take him away
from her? From his own wife?
How can you believe...
I don't believe. I don't.
The point is, he does.
Stop the car.
What?
Why?
I've been here before. I'll
show you. It's not just them.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
See the line across the
doorway? It's brick dust.
Hoodoo. Keeps your enemies
from coming across.
See the bones hanging?
This stuff's got a hold
on people out here.
Yeah, but it's not real.
It doesn't matter if it's
not real. It's real to them.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
What's wrong?
CAROLINE:
This music. I know this music.
You sure this is
a good idea?
Hello?
Mama raised a gentleman.
CAROLINE: Hello?
(ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING)
Excuse me. Ma'am?
CAROLINE: We heard the music,
your record. I was wondering...
There's no record
for anyone here.
How about records
by a man named Justify?
How do you know that name?
Who sent you?
Who else is in here?
Someone else in here?
It's just me, ma'am.
Stop now.
Don't you go touching...
Do you know a record called
the Conjure of Sacrifice?
Because I have it, if you do.
You had that,
you wouldn't say so.
You do know it.
The strongest conjuration of all.
They say Justify discovered it
but he got killed
before he learned to work it.
Him and his poor wife both.
It's never been found.
What does it do?
It keeps you from dying.
Not forever, but for a while.
How?
You have
to sacrifice somebody
and take the years
that they have left.
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
Hurry up! He's all
alone with her!
Hang on, Caroline!
Wait! Shit!
Now you got me spooked.
If I get proof that she's out to
hurt him, will you stick by me...
By "hurt him," you mean kill
him. Will you or won't you?
Just listen to yourself.
Fine. Goodbye.
What are you gonna do here,
you gonna kidnap him?
You know something's wrong
between them. You know it.
Let me make some calls.
See about grounds for
a restraining order,
protective custody.
You're not gonna get a search
warrant till tomorrow anyhow.
Then that'll
give me tonight.
I'm all he's got, Luke. Me.
Get the proof. Okay?
CAROLINE:
Mrs. Devereaux, I'm back.
No. Where's the record?
It was right here.
Mrs. Devereaux, could you
come here for a second?
Caroline, I was beginning
to worry about you,
you were gone
such a long while.
Yeah, it's really
raining out there.
It's supposed
to pour all night.
Keeps up like this,
that swamp's going to rise
and ruin my flowerbeds.
Did you want to see me?
Yeah, I was wondering if
you could take a look at this?
There's a leak up here.
They're all over the house.
They're just rainwater.
Yes, but if you
look up close...
Come on in.
I could show it to you better.
Well, it...
Actually, I have supper
on the stove.
I shouldn't leave it.
It'll just take a second.
I can see perfectly from here.
You want this for the sill?
All right.
Could you come into the room
please, just for a second?
So I can show you
what I'm seeing.
You're a funny one, Caroline.
I'll make us some tea.
VIOLET: And, Caroline?
After you've given
Mr. Devereaux his remedies
would you be so kind as to
join an old lady for supper?
Well, I...
Wonderful!
We should have
done it days ago.
I've made something real nice.
(IKO IKO PLAYING)
We're leaving tonight.
VIOLET: Caroline!
Supper.
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
How's your gumbo?
I haven't started.
Would you like sugar for your
tea? I put it out for you.
No, I don't think
I'll have any sugar tonight.
But I thought
you liked it.
You always have sugar
in your tea.
You think I'm senile,
don't you?
Ghosts in the attic.
Spells on my husband.
I just don't understand.
These ghosts, why would they
put a spell on him and not me?
I've been in that room, too.
Maybe because
you don't believe in them.
Maybe all houses
have spirits
but we just don't see them
until we believe we can.
I'm really not that hungry.
Don't move.
I'll fetch the candles.
Eat your gumbo.
Oh, fiddlesticks.
Dinner by candlelight.
There.
So, was that the storm
or the ghosts?
Well, say what you will
about spirits.
I've always wondered
if there wasn't something
we could learn from them.
Like a spell?
I have great respect
for your husband.
And whatever he thinks happened
to him, he's fighting it.
What did happen
to him, Violet?
You haven't
touched your gumbo.
What have you done to him?
I made that special for you,
and you haven't even touched it.
What have you done?
He is my husband,
and I am his wife,
and I will do to him
whatever I wish to do!
He's not safe in this house.
What?
What is this?
You've done something.
He's not safe in this house.
Not with you.
This is my house.
I'm taking him, Violet.
No!
(GASPING)
Too late. Not again.
You little whore. He's mine.
Keep him in this house.
Keep him in this...
He's mine!
CAROLINE: "Protection. "
Where's the record?
Oh, God.
Got it.
You bitch.
Time to go.
(BEN GRUNTS)
CAROLINE: Come on, Ben.
I'm going to get you
out of here. Just hold on.
(GROANS)
Damn it!
Keep him in this house.
Hold on.
(CAROLINE SCREAMS)
Caroline?
CAROLINE: Oh, shit!
Caroline.
(GRUNTING)
Come on, Ben!
We've got
to hide you, Ben.
(GROANS)
(BEN GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
I'm gonna get help.
I won't leave you.
Okay?
Caroline?
(GUN FIRING)
You think you can take him
out of this house?
You think you're
stronger than me?
You've no idea
how strong I am, Caroline.
(GASPS)
VIOLET: Caroline!
You're just making it
harder on yourself!
Where are you?
VIOLET:
You can't get away, Caroline.
You understand me?
You'll never
get out of here, child.
Caroline?
Caroline.
VIOLET: Stop right there!
(GUN FIRING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Thank you.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Luke!
Jesus Christ.
She tried to kill me.
She had a gun.
She knows I know.
Ben's in trouble.
He's still at the house. Call
the police, Luke. I left him.
We got to get back out there.
The hell we do.
I left him there.
You didn't leave anyone.
Okay? Slow down.
Tell me what happened.
She tried to kill you?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Sorry.
Mrs. Devereaux.
To what do I owe the...
Heard from Caroline?
Why would she have...
What's going on?
Okay.
What happened tonight?
Hang on a second.
We need to record this.
(IKO IKO PLAYING)
Hurting him?
Hurting him how?
What do you mean?
What are you talking about?
I am listening to you.
(GASPING)
Good night, child.
(BLUES MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
(GASPS)
LUKE: A hell of a thing,
isn't it?
See, everywhere you look,
it's a whole new world
all around you.
It's like being born.
Or dying.
Of course, I wouldn't know.
(SOBBING)
(MUFFLED SHOUTS)
Hush, darling.
I know it's hard.
We're home!
He's missing.
She's hidden him somewhere.
Where is he, Caroline?
It's not him, it's me.
You want to sacrifice me.
Where is he, Caroline?
Why are you helping her?
Is everything ready?
VIOLET: No.
I can't start anything
till I know where he is.
What's our tale
if he gets away?
Caroline,
you will tell me exactly
where my husband is.
There's nothing anybody can do
for him, so there's no need to try.
Where is he?
Where is he, Caroline?
He's in the garden shed.
Don't scratch her up any more
than she already is.
She's teaching you.
You help her kill me,
and she'll teach you how.
Ben knew, too, didn't he?
That's enough, Caroline.
You want to shoot me,
shoot me.
Stop right there, Caroline!
I want my father's picture.
I want it with me.
Please.
Jesus. All right.
You want your picture,
I'll get your goddamn picture.
(GRUNTS)
(GUN CLICKING)
Fuck!
Violet, she's going outside!
Violet!
She's here!
VIOLET:
Quick! Go get her! Help me!
Come on.
She's fixed the door!
Violet, I can't get up
the stairs!
(GASPS)
You try to use
my tricks on me?
(SCREAMING)
On me, huh?
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
No!
(PHONE ENGAGED TONE)
(DIAL TONE)
(PHONE RINGING)
WOMAN: 911 emergency.
(STAMMERING)
My name is Caroline Ellis.
I'm at 1750,
Bayou Chapelet
in Terrebonne Parish.
I need police and paramedics.
There are people hurt here.
We're trapped.
Please hurry.
(PHONE RINGING)
JILL: What time is it?
Jill.
Cary?
Jill, I'm in trouble.
Caroline?
CAROLINE: It's real.
It's all real.
You're where? What?
I'm in the Devereaux house.
Caroline.
What's real? What...
(PHONE GOES DEAD)
Jill?
(SOBBING)
(GASPS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
VIOLET: Caroline!
You can't get
away, Caroline.
Oh, God, no.
VIOLET: Caroline.
CAROLINE:
"Chalk, sulfur, blood, hair. "
Sulfur.
Candle.
Chalk.
Hurry!
Circle.
Eyes.
Four eyes. North, south.
Hurry! Oh, God, please.
What's next?
Hair.
My child
I believe you broke my legs.
You can't touch me.
You can't get near me. See this?
This is your spell of protection.
Is that what that is now?
And who exactly
gave you that spell?
All that circle protects
is you,
from leaving it.
(CHUCKLES)
You stay back!
I'll kill you!
You stay away!
We've been waiting for you,
Caroline.
Waiting for you to believe.
It doesn't work
if you don't believe.
PAPA JUSTIFY:
It is time, Lord.
From the dry dust
out of these chains.
CAROLINE: I don't believe.
I don't.
I think you do.
The weakness is the flesh.
The flesh, the flesh.
I don't believe.
I don't believe in it.
(VIOLET LAUGHING)
The flesh. The coil.
I don't believe.
The frail. The weak.
CAROLINE:
I don't believe.
(RUMBLING)
I don't...
No.
Oh, my God.
(SCREAMING)
I don't believe!
(GLASS CRUNCHING)
Thank you, child.
Cecile?
You all right?
I'm fine now, Justify.
A fair bit harder than
the lawyer, wasn't she?
It's harder every time.
They just don't believe
like they used to.
Got to get them riled up.
Mmm.
I told you I wanted
a black one this time.
You know the black ones never stay.
Beggars can't be choosers.
I think it fits you
beautifully.
It's better than Violet,
or Grace, even.
We'll get used to it.
We always do.
(VIOLET GROANS)
The thing folks don't
understand about sacrifice...
(GASPING)
Get me out of here.
...sometimes it's more
of a trade.
Get me out of here.
No!
There, there, Caroline.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
CAROLINE: We thought it was just a fall
but now she can't move
or even speak.
Like a stroke
or something.
JILL: Cary?
Dearie me.
You called me.
I called you?
(GASPING)
For help.
Don't you remember?
Cary's not herself right now.
I'm Luke Marshall.
Devereauxs' lawyer.
Hi. Jill Dupay, her roommate.
Jill, yes,
I did call you.
Fiddlesticks. I don't know
what possessed me.
It's all right. I'm here.
They need real care now.
They can't stay here.
This is all my fault.
No, Cary. No, it's not.
It's not.
(VIOLET GROANING)
Someone should ride to the
hospital with them. Maybe...
Jill, would you mind?
And we'll meet you.
Of course. Whatever you need.
She meant so much to them,
her being here.
I know it wasn't
for long, but
they really loved her.
Why do you say that?
It's in their wills.
They left her the house.
(DEATH LETTER PLAYING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(IF I CAN DREAM PLAYING)