There are some things
in this world so frightening,
that we pretend
they don't exist.
Stuff of nightmares.
We tell ourselves,
''There's no such thing.''
But the truth is,
they're out there...
...even closer than we fear.
Silver bullets.
Nice touch.
So, caretaker.
Looks like you're out of a job.
You and your people
have been defending
these pathetic creatures
for a long time.
But it'll all be over soon enough.
We'll attack each of these camps
and destroy them.
And this disgrace to our true nature
will be over forever.
So, what was on the tape?
You'll never find the boy
in time.
No.
lt can't be.
lt's already begun.
The legend is true.
Where's the boy?
Tell me!
Not in this lifetime.
Hurry. Gather your men.
We have four days till full moon.
Take this to Varek. He goes north.
Tell him there's no time to lose.
You find this boy
or it's the end of us.
You can see for yourself.
The boy is safe.
But with the red moon,
we should be ready for anything.
Just to make sure.
And you be careful.
The red moon's powers
will be very strong.
And you'll have to lock down
till this is over.
l gotta go.
Good luck. Stay sharp.
He's gonna make it.
We all are.
This isn't a dream anymore.
Four more days.
Well, that's the good news.
Bad news is now you all
gotta spend the night downstairs.
lt's probably just a fuse.
l'll be right back.
Ralph?
Oh, my God.
Tell me when, Varek,
and they're all dead.
So it's true?
The boy's alive.
Where is he?
Don't hurt him!
That's not what l want.
lf you cooperate with us,
then you will be spared,
along with your husband.
lf you choose otherwise,
then you will be forced
to watch him suffer in agony,
allowing you one last
look at the life
that you elected to end.
Do you understand?
Good.
Now...
where's the child?
We don't know.
We never have.
She's lyin'.
They gotta know, Varek.
You think we hadn't thought
of something like this?
Of someone like you?
You think you're a martyr.
You might as well
be holding the blade.
No! No! No!
That's it?
You believe her?
lt doesn't make any sense.
lt's not possible, Varek.
lt makes perfect sense.
They can't tell us
what they don't know,
no matter what we do to them.
lt's foolproof.
They're dying for some kid
they've never even seen?
They have faith.
lt's all they need.
Think of something.
This kid is out there.
l'd rather die than
go back to that.
We'll find the child.
There is no alternative.
We'll find him, Sonja.
You can't even see the kid's face.
So that's how they did it.
Boosted morale
without risking a thing.
We're wasting our time, Varek.
We only have four more nights
to find this kid.
Zo.
Wait.
You see that?
- What?
- Right there.
Look at the mirror.
Huguenot.
Come on, baby, breathe.
Please, just breathe.
Will, he can't breathe.
l gave him his shot this morning.
l don't understand.
His inhaler doesn't help!
He just keeps getting
worse and worse.
Rachel.
lt's gonna be okay.
Tim, l want you to breathe deep...
...and don't move.
Come on, sweetie.
Thank you.
Man, this stuff smells like crap.
Yeah.
Hey, baby.
You okay?
You want to see something freaky?
lsn't that awesome?
Did you have another bad dream?
No, l'm fine.
Oh, come here, you.
Let's snuggle.
l love you, Mom.
l love you, too, baby.
Everything all right?
l was worried when
you weren't there this morning.
Tim had another attack.
A bad one.
He's all right now.
He's sleeping.
So is Rachel. She was up
most of the night.
The, um...
The moon...is
getting very powerful.
This may get worse.
Well, thank God for you, Will.
You've always been there for us.
l don't know what we'd
do without you.
lt's all in a day's work.
Hey.
Tim looks well.
Yeah.
He gets sick
and he gets better.
lt's his whole life.
He comforts me.
Jonas.
What's wrong, Rachel?
There's something
l have to tell you.
lt's time for me and Tim to leave.
We have to.
l have to learn to be a mother.
A good mother.
Figure out what l want to do
with the rest of my life.
You guys have raised Tim.
l haven't.
l'm so goddamned dependent
on everyone here.
l have to learn to stand
on my own two feet.
He's been dead
over 13 years now, Jonas.
What progress have l made?
His ghost is all around me,
every time l look
at you, Nana, Katherine.
l still see him.
Come on, Rachel.
Don't fool yourself.
My brother's ghost is gonna be
with you wherever you go.
So you need to be strong
despite that.
He'd want you to.
l'm sorry, Jonas.
l've already made my decision.
Hey, Doak!
Okay.
What up, dog?
You know.
Gotta give 'em what they want.
What's that, D?
l don't know. Let me see
what l got in here.
- Uh, oh. New DVD.
- Yes!
- Morning.
- Good morning, Rachel.
- Hi, Mom.
What's everyone doing here?
Did l miss something?
- Mail.
- Muffins.
Oh, you're forgetting your nametag.
- Oh, shoot.
- Here.
Thanks, Nana.
Come on, Kat. Let's go hang.
Totally.
Be cool, fool.
Ooh! Aw, shoot.
This piece of track keeps catching.
Uh, when did we start
wielding blades?
Oh, a few days ago.
What?
Mom gave it to me.
- All right.
- She was saving it for my birthday.
l caught her trying
to hide it in her jewelry box.
- So l got it early.
- Nice.
Let me see that.
Oh, sure.
lt looks so, uh, used.
lt was my dad's.
Hey, look what
the cat dragged in.
- Hey, Adam.
- Baby.
Hey, babe.
How you feelin', big guy?
l'm hungry.
All right. He said it.
Let's go get some breakfast.
- Easy.
- Why does he have to do that?
Hey. Heard you had
a bit of a scare last night.
How do you feel?
Huge. Check that out.
Check this out.
Thanks, Uncle Jonas.
Early birthday present.
Wow, Dad. ls that a smile?
Adam taking care of you?
Come on.
How about that moon last night?
lt was pretty wild, huh?
Shoot. l'm late.
So, you'll drop Timmy at the store?
We'll be there.
Wave to Courtney.
Hey, Adam! Rachel!
How's Tim?
All better?
He's fine. Thanks.
Good news.
Tim had an attack last night.
Last night.
We can't even sneeze in this town
without anyone knowing our business.
lsn't that weird?
l mean, it's not normal. lt's not.
We're not here right now.
Leave a message and we'll
get right back to you.
Thanks.
Hey, guys, it's me.
Where are you?
l thought you'd be here by now.
lt's getting late. Um...
Where are you?
Nana?
Do you think the moon
will be red again tonight?
Yeah, maybe.
Really?
What makes it red?
lt's getting late.
Let's just get you to the store.
Nana?
Come on.
All we want is the boy.
Did you hear guns?
Nana, stay down!
l'll explain later. Right now,
learn how to load a gun.
Adam, what are you doing?
We need to move now.
Timothy!
Quick! Get down!
Dad!
Head straight for the saddle shop.
Stay there until l come for you.
l'm not leaving you, Nana.
Do as l say.
Go!
Go! Get the boy!
Mom!
Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
Don't move until l tell you.
Now we need...
...to get to my garage.
Trust me.
Adam.
They're on us.
Where's Jonas?
Go. Let's move!
Come on! Come on!
Come on.
Give me your hand.
Give me your hand, Rachel.
Come on!
Adam, get her in the truck!
Give me your hand!
Mom!
Get out of here!
l can't believe...
Anyone else hit?
Get the bandages.
Okay.
Wait, let me see this.
Put some pressure.
Put pressure.
Nana! lt's Nana!
How did they find us,
Jonas? How?
What the hell is happening?
They want Timothy.
What are you talking about?
They want to kill him, Rachel.
And they're not gonna
stop until he's dead.
Why would anyone want
to kill Tim? He's just a boy.
ln three days,
on a full moon,
something's gonna
happen to Timothy.
Something they can't allow.
l'll find them.
You know that.
You're not making any sense.
We're cursed.
We kept you in the dark
all these years
because it was the best way
to prevent them
from finding Timothy...ever.
And we kept him safe, Rachel.
For 13 years, we kept him safe.
Don't.
We call ourselves Skinwalkers.
l don't understand.
You would call us werewolves.
Who were they?
Skinwalkers.
But not like us.
lt's really quite simple.
We want the curse to end.
They don't.
Why do they want me?
'Cause you're the only one
who has the power to end
the curse forever.
You're special, Timothy.
You have your mother's blood
and ours.
Nana was one of us.
So was your father.
No.
That's impossible. Not my husband.
Pull this thing over.
We're getting out.
- Rachel, please!
- Don't you get it?
l don't believe you.
You're no better--
Mom!
lt's gonna be okay.
l promise.
Don't worry. She's safe.
They're locked down.
She needs to see it to believe it.
You're not like them.
l'm just a friend.
l knew your father
when he was your age,
and Jonas and l go way back.
My people have been taking
care of these people
for a long time.
There's a legend,
a belief,
that if a child who's--
A half breed?
Something like that.
And if he lives to be 13 years old,
there's gonna be a red moon,
which is a signal to all Skinwalkers
that the prophecy will
be fulfilled at midnight
on the day of your 13th birthday.
When they turn, the craving
for human blood is so intense,
that if they break free and feed,
they will become the beast forever.
The ones trying to kill me,
they don't want the curse to end?
To them, it's not a curse.
The lust and desire
to consume human blood
is so overwhelming for them,
it's like drugs to an addict.
The first Skinwalkers
were Native American.
They believed that the power
of the wolf was a gift,
but it mutated and...
many couldn't control
the lust for power,
couldn't fight the beast
inside them.
What makes you think l can?
lf l live through this,
what is it that l'm supposed
to be able to do exactly?
l don't know.
Jonas.
Here you go, little girl.
- Thanks, LJ.
- Anytime.
l'll take your money.
How much was it, anyway?
Come to Daddy, baby.
Keep dreaming.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
So, are we gonna play some pool?
Let's play, baby.
Oh, yeah.
We're gonna play, all right.
Hey! Get your hands off me!
How about two against one?
- No!
- Party now. Yeah!
Get off me! Get off of me!
Hey, sweetheart.
You want some of this?
What the--
Please forgive us.
We're refueled.
l'm gonna head for the stronghold.
All right.
Hey, hey. Hey, hey.
You know, you might even
like it if you try it.
Not in this lifetime.
Where the hell
are we gonna go?
Follow the leader.
Zo.
Yeah?
Let's get it done.
l'm the same man, Rachel.
No.
You're not.
Not to me.
You've been living like
this your whole life?
Every month?
What about them?
The ones coming after us.
When they change, do they--
They hunt and they kill.
They're addicted to blood.
Once you feed, you can't go back.
Those beasts killed my husband
and now they're after my son?
How is a 13-year-old boy
gonna end all of this?
He's special.
The nightmares, the asthma...
Timothy...
Timothy's body is at war with itself.
And he needs you.
We need you.
So, what now?
How do we keep my son safe?
Now we keep together,
and we stay out of sight.
Now there's just two more days.
We're so close, Rachel.
- Hey.
What is it, baby?
Mom, l...
l don't feel so good.
lt's okay, baby. l'm here.
lt's gonna be okay, Tim.
What happened?
You passed out.
You'll be back
in the game in no time.
You'll be good.
So when you get the nurse...
... l want you to do a walk around.
l don't know this place.
l don't want any surprises.
All right, l'll do it.
What is going on upstairs?
Damn it.
Breathe.
Tim's gonna make it.
He always does.
He's stronger than
all of us put together.
Yeah.
l know that.
And l believe that.
l just...
l'm sick of looking over my shoulder
and not knowing who to trust.
How do you feel, young man?
Better.
- Now that you're here.
- Tim.
lt's fine. lt's cute.
Cute, huh?
You had all the lab technicians
scratching their heads.
Let me guess.
l'm a werewolf.
Not quite.
But he does have
a very rare blood type.
Not only that,
but his white blood count
was off the charts.
Uh, he gets that from me.
l'm AB negative.
That's not it.
What about his father?
That's a tough one.
Well, we're not sure.
Okay.
You have some pretty strong blood
running through you.
Adam.
We are so close.
Before we know it,
our lives are gonna be our own.
We can be
whatever we want to be.
Okay?
We're so close.
l want to be your better half.
Well, it's long hours.
Yeah.
What's the pay?
lt's more about the benefits.
How long before
we can be on our way?
Let me go talk to the doctor.
Don't be a stranger.
Thank you.
What? l'm almost 13, you know.
How is he?
He's doing okay. We'll be
out of here in no time.
Adam, get to the roof.
You might see something we can't.
Kat, you take the back entrance.
l'm gonna stay here.
Mom?
l want to get out of here.
We need to leave.
l know. Doak's gone
to find someone.
lt'll be a minute.
Car accident. Head trauma.
Let's take a look.
Jonas.
Bring the RV around now.
Excuse me.
Can you get a doctor, please?
We'd like to leave.
Hey, what are you doing?
Mom!
No! No!
lt's time to die.
No!
Tim, get up!
Go, Timmy, go! Go!
Get off!
You okay? Come on, get up!
Get up, Mom!
Come on!
Let's go. Come on!
Hey!
No!
Get ready, Doak!
Now! Go! Go! Go!
Move, move, move!
Move! Move! Move!
Rachel!
No!
- lt's okay.
-No! No!
Come here.
Come on! ln the truck!
- Take him.
- Come on! Come on!
Jonas.
Let's stop all of this...
...brother.
Cover me, Will.
Let her go, Caleb.
Caleb?
Don't make me do something
l don't want to do.
Join me.
We're one and the same.
l'm nothing like you.
l am what l was meant to be.
You live a lie.
You were wrong.
l know what you're feeling. Trust me.
Trust you?
You're killing
fellow human beings.
l am not human.
And l will not risk spending
the rest of my days as one.
Diseased and flawed.
We're better than that.
Let her go, Caleb.
Let her go.
l'll make you a deal.
Katherine for the boy.
My daughter for your son.
What?
What the hell's
he talkin' about, Varek?
No.
Screw this!
You told me he was dead,
Uncle Jonas.
You all told me that.
You all lied to me.
You said he was dead!
No! Mom!
They've got her.
Oh, my God, Jonas!
They've got Kat!
How you holdin' up, kiddo?
l thought he was dead.
Well, you were wrong.
Now he's trying to kill my son.
His son.
We have to keep on.
She was your wife?
lt was another life.
And that was your son?
l didn't know.
lt changes nothing.
lt changes everything.
That kid has to die.
You know,
Sonja's right, Varek.
This is screwed up.
That boy has to die!
l know.
l don't care whose kid it is.
You can't hesitate.
You shut your mouth.
You question my resolve?
That boy has no father.
And l have no son.
Jonas.
This is our best chance, Adam.
Will and l know this place.
lt's safe.
We'll be able to wait it out here.
We can protect him here.
Tell me she isn't worth it.
Tell me she isn't worth
going back for.
Why are you doing this?
He knows he's got
my only weakness.
That's why she's still alive, Adam.
And that's why we can't go back,
because that's
what he's counting on.
They're gonna torture
her mercilessly...
Please don't.
Well, this should be interesting.
...and you know she won't break.
Can you live with that?
Neither can l.
lt's just one more day, Adam,
and all this will be over.
Everything we believe in
lives in Timothy.
Everything l believe in is out there.
She's gone, Adam.
Now, if you go back,
it'll be the end of us.
Jonas.
We're as safe
as we're gonna get.
Time to lock down.
All right.
Adam, you first. Let's go.
The red moon is gonna be
even stronger tonight.
Adam.
Adam, l want you to find
some higher ground
and keep your eyes peeled.
Adam.
Get Timothy. We're leaving now.
We're no longer safe here.
How did he become one of them?
The night of the attack,
we thought he was dead.
But we were wrong.
Now, he must have survived
and he must have hunted,
'cause now he's one of them.
Jonas, it's Caleb.
My husband. Your brother!
The Caleb that you loved
died that night.
He is not dead.
How could you lie to me
all these years?
l did it to protect you.
Now, he's taken Katherine.
You don't think
that l feel any of that?
Do you?
l'm not like you, Jonas.
Any of you. Remember?
l don't have a beast inside of me.
Well, you better find it,
or your son will die.
Jonas!
He found her.
l told you not to go.
Now You've led them to us.
l didn't see anyone.
Everybody in the truck.
We gotta go now.
Tim?
You okay, baby?
l couldn't believe
that it was him, Daddy.
He looked so different.
He...He wanted to know
where we were headed.
The others
wanted me dead, but...
...he wouldn't allow it.
l guess he saved my life.
They're gonna be on our tail now.
Hopefully we can make up
some time tonight.
l'm sorry, Jonas.
l couldn't leave her.
Yeah, l know.
l love you.
lt's all right.
lt's okay.
lt's okay, sweetheart.
We'll talk about it in the morning.
l'll finish with Kat.
You two get yourselves locked up.
She's gonna need some time.
l'm sorry.
l just don't remember.
lt's all right.
l wish l had more for you.
lt's okay.
Jonas. We gotta get locked down.
You're gonna be okay, Katherine.
Try and relax.
We're gonna take this
one step at a time.
My head.
Daddy, something's
wrong with me.
Kat, what is it?
Get you hands off me,
you son of a--
Will, lock her down. Do it now.
Don't! Just leave me alone.
l don't know what's happening.
l can't control it.
lt's impossible.
They left her for dead.
No!
Will, damn it! He made her feed!
Do it now! Lock her down!
He gave me life.
Will?
Will, what happened?
Adam.
She'll kill us, and she'll kill Timothy.
lt's what Varek wanted.
Baby...
you have no idea
what you're missing.
God, it's so amazing.
We can feel it together.
She's gone, Adam. She's turned.
- Let me kiss you.
- That's not Katherine anymore.
Don't make me do this.
- Jonas, please.
- She's gone, Adam.
You gotta do it!
You gotta do something!
Jonas.
You shot me, you little prick!
l'm sorry. lt'll be okay.
All right? l...You'll...
Baby?
Help me.
Please.
l don't know.
She's gone, Adam.
You gotta do something.
She's gone.
Adam. She's gone.
No.
Don't. Don't do it.
Don't, Katherine.
Kat, l love you.
l lo--
You love me, too.
All right, that's enough, baby.
That's enough.
Katherine.
Please, Katherine.
Give me that.
Please.
You were wrong, Daddy.
Timothy.
Open the door, kiddo.
Timothy, don't!
- Timothy, stay down.
- No, Timothy. Don't!
- Keep the door closed!
- Quiet!
Timothy.
- Come on, kiddo.
- No!
- Sit...down.
- Timothy, come out!
Keep the door closed, Tim.
lt doesn't have to be this way.
Don't you want to feel
what l'm feeling?
Katherine.
Think about what you're doing.
You helped raise that boy.
This is not you.
lt's not you.
You have to fight it.
Kat, you have to fight it.
Give me your hand.
- Give me your hand.
- Timothy.
Open the door.
No! Keep the door closed!
Uncle Jonas is trying to hurt me.
Keep driving!
Timothy, don't.
- Timothy!
- Close the door! He's gonna die!
- Kat?
- Close the door!
Rachel, keep driving!
Don't stop! Keep driving!
Close the door, now!
Please. Please, stop it.
l'll miss you, Daddy.
No, don't do it.
Oh, my God.
There it is.
We only have to make it
till midnight.
Three bodies, but there's no kid.
There's nothin' back there.
They're all gone.
They're close.
Just one more hour.
We'll be safe in here.
lt has a steel door.
Lock's on the inside.
- What are you thinking?
- Well, l'm out there,
and you're in here with Tim.
You want to go out there alone?
l got a few tricks up my sleeve.
Let me help you, Jonas.
Now, you listen to me.
After l turn, l'm gonna be
fighting the need to feed.
We're here. We can help you.
On anything...and anyone.
Now, l don't know
what's gonna happen.
But if l feed,
l'll probably lose control.
And you're not gonna
have a choice.
Kill me.
You gotta kill me.
You swear it.
Swear to it, Rachel.
You'll have no choice.
lt's not for another hour,
but happy birthday, Timothy.
We just have to last until midnight.
You're gonna be okay, Tim.
Don't open the door.
Here.
Uncle Jo--
Get down.
Mom!
We've gotta move now.
Please.
Don't hurt him.
No!
Mom!
Mom, wake up! Please!
Mom, get up!
Mom, wake up!
Mom!
Uncle Jonas is in trouble.
Uncle Jonas! No!
Don't!
Uncle Jonas.
Let's get the hell out of here.
No.
Are you okay?
Dad?
Can l help you?
We'd like a room.
l need your names
and a credit card.
lt'll be cash.
Cash works.
Sorry. My wife's a little jumpy.
Yeah, sorry.
lt's just one of those nights.
So many people sacrificed
their lives for me.
And now we make sure
they didn't die in vain.
Uncle Jonas was right after all.
l do have the power
to end the curse.
lt's just not going to be
as easy as they all hoped.
The power is in my blood.
l've heard...
l'm here to be cured.
For some, l am salvation.
For the others...
their destruction.