Move and look anything
Tell you exactly how fast that /
That fascinating
You got fuck out off the way,
sucker!
Morning mayor
Mayor Donell...
He did necessary mean the strongest
Or the most intelligence
He organized that environment
Now, we're human
We think we more fit
More involved because
Was smarter / When you're five
That was 30 million years
And that rock l was found in 30
million years
So were you found that which the
most successful species
Round four, you have stay around
Rossian, cambodia is where to find
Hey Grant
Later!
He's teacher
l know that
Can l lend it?
That's it
See you guys later / That's it
Good bye!
That's wrong man never get
Ain't no mystery... start shiny
the loser
She's one to be lady
He's been nine degree
Gold digger, huh? / Oh hell!
Strongest mother, you 1 7 years old
big cadillac
And constitution what hell you do?
Wow / You're an American too /
What's that?
Country
You know the chinese people come
from
What you talk about? / Your mother
wait on home, what are you doing
here?
Surprise! Cut the bag
Oh yeah
Oh...
Oh baby
What's that really matter you?
Come on baby, it's been long time
l know l'm just...
Baby come on l don'tjust to switch
Sure you do!
Disrespectful
Come on l can play with you!
Come on baby!
Why don't you just work out for
yourself
Oh honey l'm didn't in the mood
can you tell?
What the hell are you?
Where are you going?
Out for walk!
Grant, baby!
He gonna use this
You kidding me / No!
Brenda!
l just think he big coward
She seen hurt me
Come on!
You could be more relevant / That
was game
l can hear that / Alright!
Come on! / Where we going?
Get over here!
When l tell you
l have to cross your need
Oh yeah
You just to be with him!
Like a shit! / Shut up!
We song got to sing last name
first!
You know my too girl!
wait! come on, l can't!
Sterla
She's wrong worry about me
That too late
outside
l gotta to go
Shit!
God!
Sterla!
Al, l got the roach!
Come on!
Come on / Wait!
Oh my God!
Grant!
Are you okay?
You okay
The favourite song show
l was hoping to be...
this path
l'm sorry about last night
l don't know to pursue Ray
May give you ejected
l do not wake up wait
You crying
Trust me of love.
What are you so sorry about?
That been?
Great l have that's been a while.
You slut!
You marriage woman
Strand, oh no it's like.
Guess like discover my body, you
know like.
Like little boiler or something.
l'm telling you it's that's real
changing grant
Me / Pardon Mr. grant
Oh hey there too / Welcome here!
Give me copy of that / How many
you need?
Eight
No, no, you know what?
How... Give me 14.
Have a party?
Yeah some like that.
Little surprised for a wife.
Grant!
What's lock on the door?
Benny arrange to the bank it's all
bust off
Sure you thought, you think you
ask somebody question
His birthday not 2 month
That close
And not really
l have my opinion
Mr. Howard they leave in 40 minute
Oh Stephanie
Where are you going?
That's l got. l got to work, l got
something more
What?
Grant that will start in hour /
Gotta go, got a work!
l'll meet you back!
l would never understand
Gormate like thousand dollar
List the morgan! / lt's not the
home
lt's not suppose l want to tell
you.
Fuck you bad ass!
We're still talk here! / Alright
l will be there!
l can beat your fucking ass hole!
Grant!
Damn girl!
You are chocolate for the ice!
That maybe you're start the other
man
l am!
Done a lucky
You have make that, alright / As
long as weekend l'm alone
Five person.
l don't know.
Hey / Hey!
Hey, Bill...
What are you doing? / Oh nothing
just...
trying to get buzz off but l can't
to much losmen
Oh really
Congratulations, by the way /
thank you!
See you / Yeah
lt's all read done it / No
So why you open it?
l don't know use this meaning
Surely hot in here / Yeah it's
burning
lt's hard to tell, can't tell the
most / Right
Yeah gesture make picture
What do you think?
Thank you!
l like to introduce Mary Jack with
me
Thank you!
He's crackers / Ladies and
gentleman
Right after the God, this world
about!
He came here
save the land!
And face the signal
and the end
And all over every living that
move it
The Palmiere!
When God say that!
He was take the dear season!!!
Are you ready? / Yeah!!!
Nine!
Eight!
Seven!
Six!
Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
Grant!
Let's the rock begin!!!
Dr. Grant please stop!!!
Grant!
Wayne you know about this view?
Grant why you change your phone?
Grant!!!
Baby what happen to Vice?
ltjust the beast thing
l'll be alright
Thatjust a reaction
l get you to the hospital / No, no
l will call the doctor and give
the prescription. see that!
She create so mad
lf this happen!
He has to come, this Dr. Grant
Stella how are you?
l'm fine, thank you, l was calling
about...
about Grant condition, l think he
maybe get worse
Which condition up here?
The one you just saw him about
l can see your husband...
Come Dr. Grant!
Okay you're do a good job!
l'm sorry, l don't wanna die!
No, here l'm glad you here
Treat yourself!
Hey Stella / Hey!
Phil, hi / Hi!
He drive by the chance? / Oh no
he's on market
Dr. Grant! / He's not home yet!
What's going on?
Do you know Brenda?
She call the house... / No
Girl disappeared Friday night
Sign of struggling in the house
Here in town
Yeah the thing is...
people saw Grant Collin to the
house
And not lasting see the girl
You must see someone looks like
Grant
Yeah, maybe
Yeah maybe you need call, Susie
need you
Alright / Thanks
Good night / Good night!
Ben, it's Sterla, you need to get
back here right now!
Please!
Baby l don't wanna hurt you!
Oh no!!! / Believe me!
l can't catch you wrong!
Sterla!
Tell me you in here!
Are you alright?
What the fuck was that?
Like one dollar Oh what, that like
it
Bill we need to talk
Shit!
Morning Jack we need to find this
girl, l mean yesterday
and stuck up on my ass
lt's not my business / Hey don't
you fuck up with me, you're chief
police in the town
And when l see her looks like the
damn squirt
She would maybe
She heard say squirt damn
mysterious
Shelby you gonna create histeria?
/ Not today Bill!
What's this?
At least police got case / You
know take a door to door if
anybody get recognize
No social respect! / What now!
And you! You don't know what is
that, you don't know what you saw!
That was almost bendy man, where
obvious about to got
Land diseased! / What? / Land
diseased!
lt cut from they faces!
lt is the same width when l
washing your hand
You got to land diseased!
and make sure look like a squirt
Fuck you all!!! / Chief!
Another attack! Over Castaban
What? / Grant has steal animal in
farm
Okay folks Get over your gun!
Fucking hot!
l don't think granny got another
pet killer on the desk
This task is real hard at all
Hey! / What?
Not this insight clear over here /
Put down that numb nuts!
He got the cattle here.
How can a man do that?
Slay all down by himself
You gotta to be in force
Open major belong inside / The
English is got prophecy
And in there
lt's hundred thousand acre, we
find a needle in the food stock
There's some folks together
We can do that strict
Dr. Grant Reynold camp food from
here
Right those ranch!
Two month ago that was stolen
from this property own by Fich
l know that guy / more problem
came out from the wall
And would be here on the place
And if he's use that pattern it
would be end up here!
Own back family
l know you all tired, better seen
your family
We gonna have to go tonight, l know
And wait
Let's get solve this thing!
Alright, boss!
Without this grenade come stake /
We should be together
Alright!
l don't know there was Rusky in
there
You seen this guy, they were
Just give me one second
Ben, l heard you going get Grant.
yeah / l think l should go with you
l'll go with honey
Billy you need me
But l should / l will coming this
is not my fault / he try to kill
you!
That another... l was try to help
.../ But l can't!
How you gonna find her?
How at least you bring Grant Alive!
Do this!
You have your own chance to do
something
He's got the point
Come on!
You alright honey? / No
Hey come on now!
What did you do your finger?
She's Japanese / yeah
At this morning boogeyman do the
ring
Force the crisis if you need
sometime
Here is Jack!
l want all of you stay inside
tonight, you hear!
Hey Otis!!!
You look like a bunch of idiot
Say good night
Yeah, l know that
You definite thing
Go along you two
He's brought box of lunch
Oh shit!
l stole it
You may not damn working
You knock my window
So start over here twelve
l was out 14
He said what's you doing up there
She's gonna run away to Hollywood
and be a big star
She's need a bodyguard, that what
we talking about
lf the theory anywork can take
yourself
l've been think it's you
l'm here for the corner.
l'm found your gift.
Not the best happen.
lt's right here and call my dad.
Hey l'm the cop!
Not from that party.
Yeah
Yeah this is my idea
Sex squirt / lt get worse
You looks like something l found
my dick turning in the war
Grant
No way!
Shit!
What will you do now?
Don't saw me on the filano!
Grant!
lt's okay Grant
You just think it all, you just
sick!
We just here!
to get you a help
Right now!
And l will save you
Just like l swore l would!
lt's not over.
Roger fucker morris!
Grant!
Burry and secret bond
Come on baby
lt's gonna be alright, Grant
Just come with us
Right there you son of bitch!
l don't care that!
Leave that girl!
And you can make this peaceful
Or you can make it hard!
Come on you cock sucker!!!
Some pussy, you afraid!!!
Pyschology!
Over there!
And you go!
lt never found you!
Sterla get the hell out of here!
What's that smell? / Something bad!
Come from there / He's inside
Oh!
Something wrong with me
l don't know
Yeah
Oh Jesus!!! God!
Brenda.
Why no one want see me like this?
l thought her, is she alright?
l don't know.
Sure.
What's going on here exactly?
l'm so fucking hungry.
l'm so hungry, l don't even know
anyone could be so hungry.
Maybe meal. That possible over
there.
l think we best get you to the
hospital
What they gonna do with her in
hospital?
Jesus Christ!!!
Relax!
l can't stop do that shit!
Get my mouth!
What kind a thing?
Kelly honey don't too long in
there / Alright mama.
l'm turn to the perse l'm know
turns into what
ls what you think about that?
Time to turning ladies
lt's couple my pages, Mom?
No!
Besides you know what day tomorrow
/ Family fun day / That is correct!
So good night!
Sleep tight.
Don't let the bug bites.
Good night, Mom!
Mom!!!
Shall we come here?
Lemming 41 , inside right away.
Sure you there!
Shelter we got emergency!
Oh God!
Shelby.
Shelby!
Shelby l need you to come down /
Oh Jesus!
Jesus!
That fucking push it!
Should about that and shitting
gift!
You know the scene anything like
that?
You heard anything like that?
Huh?
Melina
l want you all play fucking time!
More section out of here / That's
a long way
Without that out there / Yeah well
let's change page human, dear.
Alright you three get this folks
out of the bar, you take this.
l will get my car
Be careful / Yeah.
Not this is.
You know this is.
lt's god damn biological weapons
That's where it is.
Don't like that. You know what?
Get out and take no shot if nobody
stays here
they want it / Get cocky the
creedy!
And kiss my ass!
This shit contagious and turn us
into fucking mouse!
l'm gonna shoot bastard, l swear it
And you shoot the wrong side l'm
care if you do that!
Alright itjust shake mine, Just
like you said
What? / l'm sorry! for the...
To understand do you know.
Those my head!
But didn't mean to do none of that
thing, so
Not!
Kill them pets!
Not my Brenda.
Worm.
But it was my neck.
lt's rainy.
l can drain someone from acting...
According to the sound of nature!
l want to tell you what is going
on, but...
l was a freak you will love me.
l never knew those...
Wally, you alright?
You better step back down!
Hey!
And you need get some rest
You sick!
Let her go!
You just take step back, alright!
There you go!
Why... to the story
Why don't you get out from Dr.
Grant!
l'm your husband!
So put that god damn gun down!
Stay away from her!
Get away from her, or l will shoot
you l swear to the God! / Don't
shoot me Starla
l told you
You always need me, thank you!
You fight damn sure l got the
balls!
Son of bitch! / Hey!
What's going on?
How you doing?
Hey easy!
What happen to your eyes?
Was love here back maybe
Where is she?
Do not my parent
The worm is in her brain!
Alright look!
You'll stay in the spot l will
call the paramedic come to help
you!
And you can come with me.
What's that?
Get in the car!!!
Go!!!
So...
How's that?
Yeah.
Shelby u
Shelby you there?
Did you found that...
There mosquito driving me the
bunker
Shelby you seen this out.
l don't know what to call like big
slut in your fat
No slug!
But your mama call she said
the toilet back up again and she
want you coming to finish it there.
Alright, sweet heart listen to me
just for a second, okay!
She did it what you found out on
the back up.
Alright listen l will make you do.
l need you to get CDC for me, okay.
Shelby on your noting.
Oh yeah sorry, l will get you
right back.
She lost the baker.
Where is the Mr. Kyle?
l told you secretary to pack it's
only.
Yeah, blow like a water baloon?
And l still fucking god damn Mr.
Pimp / Jesus Christ Jimmy let me
get straight it
l'll be come it.
Hello!
Mrs. Grant toasting.
there is always a field
lt's god damn emotion.
Emotion is remark, Jack
lt's general term meaning outer
space
Look it up! / Enough!
Kylie!
This real face look like meal
there is always be another
He got his heart blast.
We'll find it
Shelby get pregnant
And itjust take his form.
And that's mean she's gone!
Now his fear!
l'm seeing is worm? / He's bring
single connected.
Like doll to you
lt's conscious deseased
Don't worry about that shit my
friend.
Go back and everything should be
okay.
Shelby get this CDC formula.
Welcome back.
Little lot like you.
Change play around the carter.
Hey!!!
Worse to be in here.
lt's alright, this is a grenade.
l have to used that, destroy the
whole system
Maybe / Maybe!
Okay!
Your idea.
You stay here, l'll be back!
This is your party.
l can't!
Hey mother fucker!
We got to go!
They all see.
Take this, here!
What we gonna do now?
l can turning to that, it's pretty
much for the day
You can save my ass back there.
Of course by tell our story.
What do you mean? / Like l said to
you.
Yeah we can win!
You like that!
Come on!
Who's there?
Do you like that?
You like to see that?
Hold on!!!
There's one way!
Let's bring the body
New breeders he's inside
l get it that's great
That's for the Johny together
l know this is so fuck up here!
Okay, come here!
l ain't stay here by my side.
Alright, come on!
You can't run from the party!
l can go everywhere!
Get off right here.
You know way feel like to be see.
l know you were try to kill me.
And kick side me.
Not to go there
After all of this
You did a good job decorate, baby
lt would be the memories
l know you don't want to hurt me,
babes
lt will not be coorporated
This is wrong
You were so wrong imagine that bad.
We don't have to be wrong
anymore.
We could be together.
l never had much trust any life.
Because you know that.
l'm gonna feed that now!
You kill me.
Please!
lt hold on car!!!
Take that with me!
Shoot!
Shoot him!!!
Bill
Bill...
Bill!
That really hurt.
Are you alright?
We need both them to thank for get
over me
Awesome!
That you're not good enough.
l was still enough. We're always
be there.
At least your film is few mil
downtown
You carry, won't you?
Tell me the great story
Oh yeah, Bill save me from my dear!
Oh yeah!