GENTLE MUSIC
TELEVISION PLAYS SOFTLY
BRAKES SQUEAK
GENERAL CONVERSATION,
COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYS
(Fires gun repeatedly)
What are you doing here?
Thought I'd surprise you.
It's a school night.
Yeah, I know.
Where's Adam?
He's in the car.
Great. You know
he'll come and have a drink.
Sorry.
Alright, who's for another one?
Who's this, then?
Heidi.
You nevertold me you had a sister,
Nicole.
Very funny, Brian.
Go wait in the car. I'll get my bag.
DOOR CLOSES
MUSIC PLAYS SOFTLY ON RADIO
DOOR OPENS
ENGINE STARTS
Did you let Misty out?
No.
Did you feed him last night?
Yeah, but he didn't eat breakfast.
He'll be alright.
God, I'm so late.
You'll have to get the bus, darling.
Mmm! Your hair smells good.
DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES
CAR ENGINE STARTS
GENTLE POP MUSIC PLAYS SOFTLY
Hey.
I made you a coffee.
Oh, ta.
It's perfect.
How come you aren't working today?
Raining.
Oh, yeah.
Did that hurt?
Yeah, hurt pretty bad.
Ones across bone hurt the worst,
but.
You know, metal against bone -
da-da-da digging away at you.
Can I feel it?
Oh, you weirdo. It feels like skin.
Can I?
INDISTINCT VOICES ON TV
VOICES ON TV CONTINUE
DISTANT BEEPING
VOICES CONTINUE
(Shocked whisper) What?!
(Gasps) Fuck, Heidi! Get off.
(Sobs quietly)
Mum!
Get away from me!
What were you doing?
Mum...
(Shouts) Get away from me!
We were doing fucking nothing.
You fucking bastard!
We weren't doing anything.
Listen to me.
I fucking saw you!
We weren't...
Listen to me!
I saw you!
She was mucking around.
I saw you! (Sobs)
She wasn't fucking doing anything.
(Nicole sobs)
DOOR SLAMS
I can't believe this.
Mum...
Don't... say anything to me.
(Sobs)
SOMBRE MUSIC
ANSWERING MACHINE: Hi.
You've rung Heidi and Nicole.
If you want to leave a message,
then please do so after the beep.
Beep! (Laughs)
BEEP!
How much is it to Jindabyne?
$78.
I've got a student pass.
$39.
It doesn't leave for two hours.
Thank you.
MELANCHOLY PIANO MELODY
TRAFFIC HUBBUB
(Men laugh and chat)
DISTANT SIREN
Hi. Um, can I speak to Eddie, please?
WOMAN: Yeah, hang on.
Eddie!
Hello. Eddie speaking.
Hi. It's Heidi.
Who?
Heidi.
You said to call if I, um...
if I ever came to the snow.
No, sorry, I don't remember.
We met in Canberra.
Please don't call here again.
(Hangs up)
I thought that...
DIAL TONE BEEPS
(Replaces receiver)
BO Y: Hey, babe. How are ya?
DISTANT ROCK MUSIC POUNDS,
GENERAL CHATTER
INTENSE ROCK MUSIC
(Spiderbait sing) # Hey, you
# You never should've ran
# You wanna make something
that can take you down again
# This time you say you're just fine
# You need a little something
that can make you smile again
# Come on
#Yeah
# It won't take long
# Hey
#You're never gonna need it
when you hear that sound again
# It's a sin
You're looking kind of thin
#You need a little bit
so you can impress everybody
# You're still in a daze... #
(Converses inaudibly)
# Hey, you
# I know you like to prance
# So get up for a dance
so I can spin you round again
# Take your time
You're looking just fine
# Let's do a little shuffle
that can make you smile again
# Come on
#Yeah
# It won't take long
# Hey
#You'll sing your little song
until the sun don't shine again
# But every time
you say you're just fine... #
MUTED CHATTER
WIND WHISTLES
DOOR SLIDES OPEN
It's cold in here.
Take your top off.
Fuck, it's freezing!
Oi! Come on, get up.
(Groans)
Hey, girl, better get up.
We're leaving.
Shut up, Sean.
Where are you going?
Um, back to Sydney.
Do you reckon I might be able
to come with you?
Um...
I've kind of got a...
He's got a fuckin' girlfriend.
BELL TINKLES
CLICKING
MAN: Hi.
Can I help you with something?
I was wondering
if there were any jobs available.
No, not at the moment, sorry.
Are you sure there's nothing?
Yep, I'm pretty sure.
What are you doing?
The tag was sticking out
of yourjumper.
Sometimes it might get really busy.
Yeah, sometimes it does get...
pretty flat out.
BELL TINKLES
But I don't have anything,
so best of luck, hey?
BELL TINKLES, DOOR SHUTS
BIRDS SQUAWK
UNEASY MUSIC
DOOR OPENS
(Starts engine)
MUSIC INTENSIFIES
BILLIARD BALLS CLINK
HORSERACING COMMENTARY ON RADIO,
GENERAL CHATTER
SOFT ACOUSTIC GUITAR MUSIC
(Groans)
See you tomorrow.
You've got something on your cheek.
Look.
It's glitter.
I'm Joe.
Heidi.
Would you like a drink, Heidi?
Where are you from?
All different places.
What, different to this?
It's nice here.
Nah, it's alright.
It's just full of fucking tourists.
Like me?
No, not like you.
I saw you here dancing last night.
I saw you too.
Where was I sitting?
I saw you at the bar buying a beer.
No, you're lying.
Maybe I had a dream about you.
'THE LOVED ONE'
BY THE LOVED ONES PLAYS
LAUGHTER
MUSIC CONTINUES
SONG: #Yonder she's walking
# She comes my way
# Red dress on
Her long black hair... #
Did you find it?
Yeah.
They're nice.
They're bluebirds.
Did your boyfriend give them to you?
I don't have a boyfriend.
What about last night?
I wouldn't go out
with someone like him.
He looked alright.
You can't tell what people are like
by looking at them.
Yeah, I know. You can't.
Underneath, people are...
are different.
Like, bad different.
How can you tell?
'Cause I look at you
and you don't look too bad.
Well, I've done bad things.
Yeah? Like what?
You say a bad thing you've done
first.
I ran over a dog the other day.
Did you mean to?
No.
Yourturn.
I kissed my friend's boyfriend.
Is that it?
Yeah.
I don't think that's too bad.
I think running over a dog is worse.
I got to go.
Do you want me
to drop you somewhere?
No.
See you.
# Red dress on
Her long black hair... #
CAR APPROACHES
What are you doing?
I want to come with you.
(Stops engine, pulls handbrake)
Don't worry.
I'm not fucking worried,
but you can't come with me.
Why not?
I live outside town, Heidi.
I don't mind.
You don't mind.
(Starts engine)
BELL TINKLES
(Speaks inaudibly)
Yes.
BELL TINKLES
You want a drink?
OK.
(Pours drink)
I can see your breath.
Yeah?
(Switches on TV)
This is a nice place.
(Sarcastically) Yeah, it's a palace.
I like it.
MAN ON TV: Progress was made
despite the difficulties.
This man here
enjoyed the ground position
to wave happily to old friends.
NOSTALGIC MUSIC PLAYS ON TV
I don't think this is a coincidence.
No?
What is it?
I don't know.
It's like fate or something.
Aren't you tired?
Go to sleep, then.
I can't sleep.
Why not?
Don't know.
Just can't.
I can feel your pulse.
I can feel it there.
THUNDER RUMBLES
SHOWER RUNS
Hello.
I'm so bloody late.
The old man's gonna kill me.
Oh!
Heidi, it's just that...
I'm pretty busy, you know?
Yeah, me too.
Why are you putting hot water
in there?
To melt the ice.
See you.
DOOR CLOSES
WISPY MUSIC
DARK, ATMOSPHERIC MUSIC
WOMAN ON RADIO:
Snow FM. Who's this?
MAN: It's Josh here.
How you going, Josh?
MAN: Where you calling from, man?
Jindabyne.
Is it chilly down there?
Yeah.
DOGS BARK
Hey, Dad.
Morning.
I stayed at Stuart's.
Yeah, I thought you must've.
Yeah.
See you down at Riley's.
See you there.
(Starts engine)
You didn't order breakfast.
No.
You can get something in town.
You want a cup of tea or something?
Yeah.
So you're a friend of Joe Cameron's?
Sort of.
A sort-of friend?
He's nice.
(Laughs)
I think a lot of girls
think he's nice.
That's 'cause he is.
You want more toast?
No, I'm OK.
What's your name?
Heidi.
That's an old-fashioned name.
I'm Irene.
That's an old-fashioned name too.
Hmm.
Do you work here on your own, Irene?
Yeah. I do now.
Do you need someone to help you?
Nah, thanks.
I don't need anyone to help me.
Irene, is anyone staying
in my room tonight?
Your room?
Mmm.
Why? You want to reserve it?
Yes.
OK. That's fine.
Do you reckon I might be able
to pay you in a couple of days?
There's no jobs left
up the mountain now.
OK.
Just tonight. You pay tomorrow.
Thank you.
PHONE RINGS
Hello.
Um, can I speak to Joe, please?
OK. Thanks.
PHONE RINGS
Hello.
Um, can I speak with Joe, please?
Yes. I'm a friend of his.
Heidi.
Uh, yes. Can you tell him to call me
at the Siesta Inn Motel?
DARK, ATMOSPHERIC MUSIC
DULL THUDDING
DOG BARKS DISTANTLY
Mum?
CLOCK TINGS
MAN: One of those old trees.
See where the irises are?
See all the sparrows?
Mmm.
Joe, you know Richard.
Yeah.
Sorry to hear about your dad.
Thanks.
Mum says you're selling up.
Yeah, the whole lot.
Just showing Richard the garden.
You couldn't help Richard
with his tractor, could you?
Yeah. It's, uh, completely bogged.
How'd you manage that?
I'm out of practice, I think.
Will you stay till lunch?
No, I've got to get back.
I've got an auctioneer coming round.
Must be awful,
people picking over everything.
Oh, it's not too bad.
So I'll come around tomorrow.
Yeah. Great.
See you, then.
Oh, Joe, a girl rang for you.
Heidi.
OK. Thanks.
She said it was important.
(Laughs politely)
Whoa! It's hot.
Yeah.
$2, thanks.
Um, is there a job going here?
Yeah.
Is it a job working
behind the counter with you?
Yeah, just serving people
and packing shelves and that.
Oh, right.
Look, you should just ring Pete
and speak to him.
On that number?
Yeah.
Hey, could I borrow that pen?
(Keys entry into machine)
How much are the red ones?
They're all five bucks.
I'll take the red ones.
Just take them.
(Giggles)
Can you cut them?
(Sings) # Miss Mary Mack, Mack, Mack
All dressed in black, black, black
#With silver buttons,
buttons, buttons
#All down her back, back, back
# Miss Mary Mack, Mack, Mack
All dressed in black, black, black
#With silver buttons,
buttons, buttons
#All down her back, back, back
# She lost
her mother, mother, mother... #
DARK MUSIC
(Rehearses) "Hello.
Um, could I speak to Peter, please?
"Um, I can work a till
and I'm very good at serving people.
"Yes, I've worked in
a service station before."
Hi.
(Deeply) "Hi.
"I just couldn't stop
thinking about you.
"I had to come over."
Yeah, I was thinking about you too.
"Your eyes are intense."
So are yours.
"Fuck, I love your mouth."
I love your mouth too.
"I want to kiss you."
Yeah, I want you to kiss me.
"I love... you so much."
PHONE RINGS
DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS ON TV
Did you hearthe phone?
Yeah.
Well, can you ask that girl
not to call here at this hour?
Yep.
Goodnight, then.
'Night.
(Sighs)
It's alright, Mum.
You're not mixed up with anything,
with the police or anything?
No.
Hmm.
I was thinking, for a few weeks
until you find something,
'cause you have to pay rent,
you know.
(Knocks on door)
That's your bathroom in there.
My son used to stay here.
DOOR CREAKS
Phew! It's musty.
Ah. That's better.
Where are your mum and dad?
My mum... she passed away.
Oh.
Do I have to water this plant?
(Laughs) It's hardly alive, love.
My husband died. Last year.
He was Croatian.
Worked on
the Snowy Mountains Scheme.
Do you miss your mum?
Sometimes.
There are some... jumpers and things.
Is there a phone?
Yeah. Payphone in reception.
And if someone calls...
They can leave a message.
So I'll leave the key here, then.
Thank you.
GENTLE MUSIC
DOG BARKS
RICHARD: Hang on.
Hang on. Slow down.
Is is right?
Yeah.
(Revs tractor)
Fuck, you've got a lot of stuff.
Are you selling everything?
No, just some of it.
Well, most of it, actually.
My sister Lucy's taking
all the big furniture
and the rest
we'll either auction or give away.
Mum said you lived in France.
I did, yeah. For 10 years.
Did you miss it?
What, France?
No. Being here
when you were over there.
Yeah. I... I did.
Yeah. I missed the smell, I suppose.
What, the smell of sheep shit?
(Laughs)
(Laughs) Fuck, you're an idiot.
(Sarcastically) Oh, shit. Sorry.
You been overseas?
Yep. Yeah, after school,
I went to Europe.
In France, I got the worst
fucking food poisoning.
What did you eat?
Dirty rabbit.
Yeah. Never touching it again.
It's fucking peasant food.
(Laughs)
Why did you come back?
Lucy's wedding.
She married a Jew, didn't she?
Yeah, she did.
Yeah, well, good on her.
Fucking shook everyone up a bit.
Yeah, it did.
Are you married?
No. I'm gay.
I thought you knew that.
I don't know.
Yeah, maybe I did.
What about you?
(Laughs) No, I'm not.
(Laughs) No, I... I just mean,
do you have a girlfriend?
PHONE RINGS
No.
Hello?
Yeah, I had
a bit of a tractor problem...
No, it was kind of bogged.
With spray-paint?
Oh, no, I told the guys
about that... (Voice trails off)
(Groans)
(Laughs)
So, besides serving people,
we ring through orders, like
the pies and sausage rolls and that.
Do you have family in Jindabyne?
No.
Why did you come here, then?
Um, I met this guy in Canberra.
He has this store thing
selling parkas and stuff
and he told me to call him
about a job.
You know my parka?
Yeah.
Well, he gave it to me.
Just gave it to you?
Yeah.
Sort of.
You know, I was thinking
I'd work up the snow
but... then he didn't remember me.
You didn't want me to get the job,
did you?
I don't care.
Hi. How you going?
WOMAN: Good, thanks.
It's a bit cold out there tonight.
A little chilly.
Just these ones?
Yes, thanks.
Can you bag these?
SCANNER BEEPS
Heidi?
$15, thanks.
There you go.
Thanks. See you next time.
Hi. Just the petrol today?
WOMAN: Yes, thanks.
'Bye.
See you later.
Hey.
Just the petrol?
Yeah. Thanks.
That's 28.
What time do you close up?
10:30.
Oh, right.
Well, don't work too hard.
(Joe whistles)
Is this your dog?
Yep.
What's his name?
Rex.
Hey, Rex.
He must get cold sitting in the back.
He's alright.
GENTLE MUSIC
CAR ENGINE STARTS
PEOPLE CHATTER
Smells like honey.
(Laughs) Fuck.
What?
Nothing.
Well, here we are.
Yeah.
Do you want another one?
GENTLE ACOUSTIC POP MUSIC
(Giggles)
What about the dog?
No, he's alright.
He's cold.
Seriously, he's alright.
I feel bad for him.
(Sighs)
'MY COO CA CHOO' BYALVIN STARDUST
PLAYS ON STEREO
SONG: # Coo! Coo! I just want you
# I really love
the things that you do
# Come on, and love a-me too
# Oh, won't you be my coo ca choo?
# Sweetness, I like your dress
# I love the way
you know you're the best
# I'm in love and I'm in a mess
# I really want you, coo ca choo
# I love you
Yes, I love you
# Yes, I love you, coo ca
# I want you
Yes, I want you
#Yes, I really do
# Tomcat,
you know where it's at... #
SILENCE
HEIDl: Walking through the jungle,
'X' marks the spot.
Stab. Blood running up,
blood running down.
Blood running up...
(Laughs)
...blood running down.
Cool breeze.
Tight squeeze.
Egg on top...
...will make you pop.
(Joe starts car engine, drives off)
BO Y: Oh, nice shot. Nearly got it.
Oh.
Oooh, missed.
Wasn't even close.
Go for the 11.
(Giggles) What was that?
PHONE RINGS
IRENE: Hello, Siesta Village.
Oh, nice shot.
IRENE: And was that
a single or a double?
(Plays tentative note)
(Plays more confidently)
PIANO MELODY CONTINUES
(Claps)
PIANO MELODY STOPS ABRUPTLY
GENTLE MUSIC
COWS MOO, DOG BARKS
Fucking freezing.
It's getting there.
Hey, your dad told me
I should start charging you rent.
Where have you been staying?
None of your fucking business.
It's that Italian girl, isn't it?
No.
I knew it was.
No, it's not, alright?
Well, who, then?
You wouldn't know her.
It's a big secret, is it?
Well, I'll see you.
Yeah.
I fucking hate you.
You're just
jealous.
It is that Italian girl.
I'm fucking the girl from the servo.
Bullshit.
(Starts engine)
Hey.
Hi.
Here. Pete made you this.
Does that mean I got the job?
Guess so.
Bianca,
how much are those doughnuts?
80 cents.
I might have one.
You don't have to pay
for stuff like that.
And you can have a drink
or chips or something.
Can I have a doughnut?
Yeah, if you want.
Mmm.
It's delicious.
CAR HORN BEEPS
See ya.
'Bye.
Mum wants to know
if you want a lift.
I'm OK.
Come on.
This is Mum and Karl. This is Heidi.
Hi.
So where's home?
Um, I'm staying at the Siesta.
Look what I got you, Karl.
Ta.
We've got a pony.
What's his name?
Her name is Elsa.
Must be expensive,
staying in a motel.
Oh, no, I've got a flat.
A flat?
Yeah, it's out the back.
It used to be Irene's son's place.
Did she tell you about him?
Nuh.
He's in jail.
Bianca.
Well, he is.
You can have a ride of Elsa
if you want.
Aren't I too big?
You're alright.
Thanks for the lift.
Any time.
See you, Bianca.
Hi.
Do you like being here?
Yeah.
With me?
Yeah. Otherwise
I'd be sitting here on my own.
I like holding hands with you.
Yeah, I know.
Do you like it?
I'm not a big hand-holder.
No.
What do you do if you like someone?
I like to touch them, I suppose.
Like what?
(Giggles)
Like that. (Laughs)
Yeah. What else?
Like that.
Is that all you do?
No. That's just for starters.
What do you do?
Um...
I touch them.
Yeah? Like how?
Maybe on the hand.
What else?
I look at them.
How?
Show me.
I can't.
Yeah, you can.
(Laughs)
Just like that.
DOOR OPENS
(Whispers) Hey.
Where'd you get that?
I found it on the path.
No, you've got to put it back.
I'll get thrown out.
No, I ordered it.
She knows you're in here, then.
Yeah, I suppose she does. Yeah.
(Softly) Open your eyes.
SOFT MUSIC
CAR HORN HONKS
Hey.
Hey, mate.
What's happening?
Johnny Gordon's hired a place
up at Thredbo. You wanna come?
We're going to dinner.
How romantic.
Yeah. It is.
So aren't you going to introduce us?
This is Heidi.
That's Stuart, er, Jake, Claire.
Rachel.
Hi.
So Joe tells us
you're working up here, Heidi.
Yeah.
Whereabouts?
Um, at the BP.
Oh, right. At the servo.
That must be interesting,
real mixed bag.
Mixed bag.
You know - mixed bag of lollies.
Oh, yeah.
(AII laugh)
Well, we better go.
CLAIRE: See you, Joe!
'Bye.
Nice to meet you, Heidi.
Have a good night.
WOMAN SINGS SONG
IN CHINESE LANGUAGE
Do you know what you want?
Hello.
Hi.
(Softly) Oh, fuck's sake.
What?
Do you like duck?
Can we get the sizzling king prawns
and, um, the Peking duck?
Is that OK?
Yeah.
And can we get
some fresh chilli with that?
We've got chilli sauce.
Well, I've had fresh chilli
here before.
I'll see.
OK, then. See.
Do you love me?
(Laughs) What?
I just wondered, that's all.
Jesus, Heidi.
Am I your girlfriend?
I don't know. We've only just met.
How long will it take
before you know?
Don't know.
I think you do.
You're just too scared to say it.
I'm not scared, I just don't like
being fucking interrogated.
Spit 'em out.
(Retches and vomits)
DOOR OPENS
DOOR CLOSES
LAIDBACK ROCK MUSIC
GENERAL CHATTER
He was a weird kid, eh?
He was from Japan or something.
Anyway, he made us sushi
just out of these mats.
Just put this rice down
and just rolled it up in the mat.
My brother went to school with you.
Yeah, probably.
Said you used to sit out
smoking dope the whole time.
Nothing's fucking changed.
Where are you staying?
Er, in a lodge
up at Charlottes Pass.
Has it got a sauna?
Yeah.
Yeah? How about a spa bath?
Sounds alright.
Shame you won't get to see it.
Think I could probably make time.
(Laughs) Gee,
was that a pick-up line?
Do you want it to be?
You're going to have to try
a little bit harder than that.
I'm pretty busy this week.
Yeah, he's fuckin' flat out.
Oh, really?
Yeah, he's fuckin' a girl
from the servo.
What?
You're a fuckin' dickhead.
What? That's the reality
of the situation.
What situation?
Nothing like a bit of rough trade.
She's not rough.
Oh, really?
You wouldn't have any idea
about her.
Oh! I've hurt his feelings.
Shut up, for fuck's sake.
You're acting like an idiot.
This is the smallest,
most bullshit part of the world,
you think you're king shit.
What are you talking about?
Nothing. Don't fuckin' worry.
You think fuckin' some cheap slag's
gonna make you any different?
Why are you so interested?
'Cause you couldn't get a fuck
even if you tried?
You know why they hang out with you?
So they've got someone
to fuckin' laugh at.
Go on, then.
(Urinates)
Hi.
Thought you might
like to have a drink.
Did you?
Yeah.
Look like you've had a good night.
Yeah, it was great.
It was a birthday.
I don't know why I said it was great.
It was pretty bad, actually.
Better have a drink, then.
When do you leave?
In about a week.
Come back for the auction.
Yeah, looks like you've been doing
some packing.
Yeah, I had some friends down
to help.
Should have got you round.
I was only a phone call away, mate.
Yeah, I'm sure.
I helped you with that tractor.
Yeah.
(Laughs) Yeah.
You did.
With Stuart.
Yeah.
We just had a fight.
You and Stuart?
Yeah.
Just a stupid fuckin' pussy argument.
About?
Oh, a girl that I know.
It's a... a friend.
A friend?
We're sleeping together,
but she's not like a close friend
or anything.
Yeah, I've got friends like that.
Yeah, it's nothing too heavy.
But you were arguing about her.
Yeah.
You know, when you were a kid,
did your mum ever used to spray
perfume in the air
and sort of walk through it?
Yeah, I think she did.
Yeah, well, she's like that.
Like perfume?
No.
See, when you leave,
you can still feel her on your skin.
(Sighs) Fuck.
(Thumps down glass)
I'm full of shit.
Have you got a boyfriend?
Yes.
Would you like me to give you
a lift home?
No, I'm alright.
You're too pissed to drive.
If you're looking for the bathroom,
it's down the hallway on the right.
Um... got you a blanket.
I don't want a blanket.
I don't think you know
what you want.
UTE ENGINE HUMS
BIRDS SCATTER
DOG BARKS
Hi, Dad.
Morning.
Some coffee in the pot
if you want it.
I'm alright. Might have a shower.
Probably a good idea.
(Sobs)
I'm drunk. (Laughs)
Yeah, I can see that, Joe.
GLASS CLINKS ON TABLE
Don't wake your mother.
Good morning, miss.
Hello, Irene.
Did anyone call for me?
No, love. No-one called.
You expecting a call, are you?
Sort of.
Aren't you working today?
No.
Where'd you get
all that lovely hair?
I don't know.
My mum, maybe.
See you.
See you, love.
What about this one?
Angry.
Good boy.
(Laughs)
What about this one?
Very sad.
Good boy.
BIANCA: Hi, Mum.
Hi.
Hello, there.
Do you want a drink?
Yes, please.
Hi, Karl.
Do you remember Heidi, Karl?
She came in the car with us.
Yep.
What about this one?
What do you think he's doing?
He ate something
that didn't taste good.
Maybe. What else could he be doing?
Growling.
What's Mummy doing?
(Laughs)
Smiling.
We're both smiling. (Laughs)
She's got lovely eyes.
Yeah.
Does Karl ride her?
Sometimes. He talks about her a lot.
He's sort of obsessed
with his rabbits.
He's got Asperger's.
What's that?
Do you know what empathy is?
Kind of.
It's like if you feel pain,
I can understand,
or if I'm happy, you can tell.
He can't tell,
so he can't make friends.
Oh, right.
He just says
exactly what he's thinking.
He doesn't know how it's gonna make
the other person feel.
What else does he do?
Well, if you tell a joke,
he waits for everyone else to laugh
because he doesn't know
what's funny.
WISPY MUSIC
DOOR OPENS
(Playfully) Get out!
(Laughs)
This is Heidi, Roy.
Hello, Heidi.
Hello.
Wanna stay for dinner, Heidi?
We've met before, haven't we?
You came in looking for work.
Yes.
Mum, can you take us
to the video shop?
After dinner, then,
eh?
Hey, I think I might go.
Why?
I'm just a bit tired.
I'll give you a lift back.
I'm on my way to squash.
You'll be early.
So, where are we off to, then?
Um, the Siesta.
Ah. You're staying there, are you?
Yeah. I've got a flat.
I didn't know Irene had flats.
Just one.
Nice, is it?
Where are we going to?
I want to show you something.
Pretty, eh?
And you are a very pretty girl,
Heidi.
Thank you.
(Laughs)
You know, when the Hydro-Electric
flooded the valley,
they... they left the old town there.
Yeah. All the houses and the roads
and the shops.
They're all there, under the lake.
Town's under the water?
Hard to imagine, isn't it?
All of thatjust... sitting there,
under the surface.
You know, Bianca's had
a pretty rough trot of it
moving down here.
We moved from Queanbeyan.
Did she tell you?
She's a very good girl.
She's really nice.
You know, she's basically got
her whole life in front of her.
And her mum and I...
...we don't want anything to...
mess that up.
Do you know what I mean?
Yes.
I think it would be better
if you don't see her outside work.
I just think
you're two different types of girls.
(Weeps gently)
You understand me?
Yes.
Hi.
Want a hot chocolate?
No, thanks.
Pete told me to tell you
to stop eating so much stuff.
I thought we were allowed.
Yeah, we are.
Within reason.
Within reason?
OK.
It was fun yesterday.
What's the matter?
What do you reckon?
I don't know.
Roy told me what you did.
What?
(Scoffs)
What did he say I did?
I didn't do anything!
What did he say?
You know!
I didn't do anything!
(Screams)
ANTHEMIC ROCK MUSIC PLAYS
Are you a local?
Yeah.
You're not.
No.
(Laughs)
GENTLE PIANO MELODY PLAYS
So, do you often bring strange men
back here, Heidi?
Only rich, fucked-up ones with dope.
That's fucking great, then.
We know we belong.
Cheers.
To us.
That's a stupid thing to say.
You two make such a lovely couple.
I really wanna smack you
in the head.
(Sarcastically) Mmm!
So...
Madam.
Well, isn't this nice? (Laughs)
Very nice.
Have you got a television?
No.
Do you have a DVD player?
Do you have an Xbox?
She hasn't got a TV. Why would she?
Do you have
'Weekend at Bernie's II'?
(Men laugh)
(Mock gasps)
Shoes off.
Are you alright?
(Laughs) Oh, man. She's fucked-up.
You're alright, aren't you, Heids?
(Groggily) Yeah.
Oh, fuck it, man. Man, this is...
this is bullshit, man.
She's fuckin' off her tree.
Let's just go back to the pub.
Oh, John! (Laughs)
Oh, John, man, what are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing, man?
Oh, Johnny! (Laughs)
Man!
Let's take a bath.
I don't thinkwe're all gonna fit
in thebath.
I'll just run us a bath.
Relax. Relax. Relax. Relax.
Relax.
Shh.
(Laughs)
(Gasps)
KNOCK AT DOOR
(Mock Indian accent)
Oh, don't open the door.
No, no, no.
It's not your boyfriend, is it?
I don't have a boyfriend.
(Laughs)
Hi.
TENSE MUSIC
I think you better leave.
Yep.
That's what we're endeavouring
to do, man.
Sorry, man, we didn't...
we didn't know. (Laughs)
What didn't you know?
We just want to leave, alright?
Or maybe we could stay here
and have a really big party.
John, shut the fuck up.
What did you just say?
(Mimics deaf person)
Oh, what I said was...
John, shut the fuck up.
...perhaps we should all stay here
and have a party.
John, shut the fuck... John, John.
Are you a macho man?
TENSE MUSIC
(Groans) Owwww!
THUD!
(Groans)
Come on. Just get up.
She fucking wanted us here, man,
alright?
DOOR CLOSES
(Kicks sideboard)
I just want to tell you that...
...if you ignore someone
and you don't call them
then you can
really hurt their feelings.
Is this what happens
when someone hurts your feelings?
Jesus Christ! It's a slight
overreaction, don't you think?
You go out, get drunk,
you fuck anything that moves.
Do you think that's normal?
(Tearily) No.
Then why did you do it?
I didn't want to be by myself.
Do you know how fucked-up you are?
It's like you've got a big problem.
This big fuckin' problem.
And if I was you,
I'd get some sort of help.
And you don't have any problems,
do you?
You think I'm gonna sit here
and tell you about my problems?
No.
You're too scared.
If you're close to people,
then that's what you do.
You tell them things,
and you know that no matter what,
that they're still gonna love you.
You're not close to people.
You just let them fuck you.
I'm close to you.
No, you're not.
Joe...
Just fuck off, alright?!
Just get the fuck awayfromthe car!
(Revs engine)
SOLEMN MUSIC
(Pounds on glass)
I told you when I gave you this room
I didn't want any trouble.
Yeah, I know. I just...
You just what?
I'm sorry, Irene.
Oh, you're not sorry.
You'll be saying sorry till the cows
come home - that's your type.
It was an accident.
An accident?!
Walking around naked and drunk
at three o'clock in the morning -
that's an accident?
Yes.
You can pack your things and go.
I need the room back.
Why, is your son getting out ofjail?
(Gasps) What?
Is he getting out?
No.
He won't be getting out...
for a very long time.
He must've done something really bad,
then.
Yes, he did.
What?
What did he do?
He killed a man.
He walked into a 7-Eleven
and shot a young man in the stomach.
Is that what you wanted to know?
(Sniffs and sobs quietly)
(Sobs)
POIGNANT MUSIC
(Hums)
BELL TINKLES
I just wanted to say thank you
for everything.
That's alright.
Here's the key.
Yeah, thanks.
My mum's not dead.
What?!
(Tearfully) She's not dead.
I make stuff up,
and before I came here I did
something really, really bad.
I kissed my mum's boyfriend.
And she looked at me...
...she looked at me like
she didn't know who I was anymore.
I'm really sorry, Irene.
She knows you. She knows you.
I think we should ring your mum.
Hmm?
She wouldn't want to see me.
(Sighs) No matter what you've done,
love...
...your mum will want to see you.
Tell me the number.
What's your mum's first name?
Nicole.
It's, um...
BITTERSWEET MUSIC
Hi.
Can I come in?
You've packed up.
Yeah.
Where are you going?
Home.
My mum's coming.
That's good.
I think it's good that we met.
See you.
Heidi.
BITTERSWEET MUSIC
(Whispers) I missed you, sweetie.
(Starts engine)
SONG: # I see your bright light
in there