Sorry. Haters.
S-s-sorry. Haters.
Gotta go.
But even those two things
is still not the reason why
this is the favorite room.
So let's show you.
Excuse me.
Um, is it much certain if I deposit now
the money is banked for me tonight?
Only thing can say is
ain't mad at ya.
Sorry. Haters.
Gotta go.
Please, officer.
If I have ticket,
it make the whole day I work for nothing.
Mm-hmm.
Can you just drive uptown and I'll let you
know in a minute where we're going?
Uptown, the west or east?
We have passed
93rd Street, miss.
Uh, Englewood Cliffs.
In New Jersey.
Um, I can give you directions
if you need.
Just pull over right here.
Can you stop here, please?
Thank you.
How's the painting
coming, sweetie?
Um, would you mind
if we just sat for a while?
Miss, I'm sorry, but, uh, it is late.
No, I'm gonna need to go back
to the city.
Just not now.
Just in a minute or two.
Okay?
Look, whatever amount
you made last night,
I'll pay you
with a 15% gratuity, all right?
I think that's more than fair.
So, h-how much do I owe you?
Um...
Uh, I made 160 last night, miss.
And I think
that you can pay me half now.
That is to me fair, too.
Mommy's here.
What do you think?
Should we keep it? Huh?
You know how to tell
whether a car's good or not?
You gotta kick the tires.
I prefer that if you're gonna cheat me, that
you don't insult me at the same time, sir.
'Cause there's no effin' way...
There's no effing way
you made 160 last night.
I'm sorry, but I told only the truth of it.
Look, I don't care, okay?
I don't care, because if I were you,
I'd be cheating all of us, too,
every second I got.
So, can we go now?
Can we go?
No, hold it.
48th and 10th, please.
And I do appreciate that you waited.
Miss?
Uh, Mrs.
Madam...
Uh, w-w-would you mind this much?
If I could stop to drop something.
Sure.
Oh, I've gotta make a stop, too.
You want something?
Oh. You sure
you need something just now?
Oh, yeah.
Sorry.
You forget how things are
so much cheaper outside the city.
Oh, and, um, she doesn't have to
go to all the trouble to dress the baby.
You know, if you wanna go up,
I can wait down in the cab.
Vous parlez français?
Uh, no.
No, I don't speak it.
Three years of it in school.
You know, I pick up a word or two
when I hear it, but no.
You might try to speak it, you know.
Languages are one of the many best thing
each person can have.
Yeah, well, let me keep working on this.
We'll see how brave I get.
Um, can you just leave some music on
or something?
Oh, I'll be just a minute.
Sorry, but I need my same keys.
Hi. Okay.
Okay.
Ow.
Certified postal check.
Mm-hmm.
- Okay?
- Non.
- Okay.
Merci.
Okay.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
I just... I forgot to give you something.
I am coming down.
We can go now.
No, no, I didn't bring it for you.
L... I got it for you to give to the baby.
I'm sorry, but I got it at a liquor store,
so it has a rum sticker on it,
but it's still sort of cute.
Yeah.
Um, would you mind
if I used your bathroom?
Please? The toilet?
Uh, no.
Great. Okay?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought you wanted to be home.
Yes, but I don't live here.
Oh. Well, then I'd best
make it quick. Okay.
I also have... I have an extra one of these
if anyone's game.
I don't know.
Can I hold him?
Can... Will you ask her
if I can hold the baby?
Um...
Here. Hi.
Is this your only nephew?
Uh, uh, in the United States, yes.
But where... where's your brother?
Doesn't he live here, too?
N-no, no.
But... we think soon.
I'm sorry.
I know it's rude of me to pry.
It's okay.
She... she like to know
if you really are fan of the Q-Dog?
Um, it's complicated, but mostly
because I'm responsible for it now.
Um, last year I was made
head of programming,
which means that I choose
all the new shows, so...
W-w-we don't understand so much.
Ask her is she's seen any
of Sorry. Haters.
It's my biggest hit.
It's about how rich and famous people
spend their money
on the most ungodly cars and houses
and diamond-studded scooters
just so everybody who can't get that stuff
feels like nobodies.
Sh-she likes that show.
Thank God, because
if it doesn't stay hot, I'm finished.
You know what?
Let me just run through this.
It's interesting that you ask
because I just wrote all of it down
yesterday from the shrink.
So we make fat kids
wanna kill themselves,
we make high school kids spend their
college money on nose jobs and implants,
made it cool for grade school boys
to call little girls
and their teachers B's and H's.
Historically speaking, we've now
reassigned the birth of Christ to 1981.
Humiliating reality shows,
and last but not least,
we've made sure that music sucks
progressively every year we've been on.
And that, good people,
is all I've got to show for my sorry life,
so what do you guys do?
I mean, I guess
I know what you do, but...
Oh, no.
I... I have a PhD in chemistry.
In Syria,
I work with... with the casting of metals.
Wow.
So are you submitting resumes
to U.S. Companies now or?
I hope to start again sometime, yes.
Wow.
Aw.
Everybody's a crybaby tonight, huh?
But I think I'm still the champ.
Don't you?
I was surprised that you didn't kick me out
of your cab back in Englewood,
so... thank you.
It's not our life.
We can ask if you don't want.
You better
hold him a minute for this one.
Anyway...
Long story short,
the man who was my husband
wanted to paint.
Uh, art?
While I wanted to be a big, fat success.
And it's all we thought about.
It was...
But eventually, we beat all the odds,
and we both won.
And we rewarded ourselves
with our daughter
who came to us
seven years ago tomorrow.
Oh. Almost today.
Ah, well, happy birthday, Smitty.
And it's funny,
'cause we agreed with you, A-shade,
that languages are truly
probably the most important...
Ashade.
Sorry?
Oh, Ashade.
Sorry.
Okay. Ashade.
So, we wanted Smitty to learn Mandarin
as all us hip couples do these days.
And we hired a native Chinese tutor,
and the first year,
this woman worked very hard
to win my daughter's affections over me.
And then the next year, she worked not so
hard to win my husband's affections, too.
So sorry, Mrs. Maclntyre.
Oh, so sorry. So sorry.
Um, uh, now, uh, your daughter,
she's not with you?
Not as yet.
No, not as yet.
She's, uh...
No, I was doing my job and...
you know, which for me means
that I smoke
an occasional marijuana cigarette
with whoever today's
rapper/convicted felon du jour might be,
and Paul got it on camera,
and in so doing,
he got my daughter and the house
and a nice fat allowance
to share with his little yellow Yoko.
Uh...
Is that right?
Is that... did I say that right?
- It's her turn?
- Yes.
Come on.
We don't need to stay too much.
It's to us a family problem.
And mine wasn't?
Has she lost her husband, too?
P-please don't...
If I can, I would like to pray
and drive you home.
Oh, yes. Yeah.
Ashade.
No, no.
Uh, you know, you should let me see it.
'Cause I'm very good at proofreading,
and maybe I could help somehow.
Yes.
Hello?
Harry, are you there?
It's me... Philly.
Listen, please call me
as soon as you get this,
'cause, um, well,
'cause I've got some new friends, Harry,
and they need that favor you owe me.
Actually, it's on a complete freebie,
because we've got, I don't know,
probably about, oh,
about a whole $720 for ya,
which is a lot more
than you're worth these days.
Anyway, the deal as far as I know it is
that my friend's brother
is from Syria originally,
but is a Canadian citizen.
Uh, more than 10 years.
For over 10 years living in Canada,
and was changing planes at JFK
and just because many years ago
somebody he hardly knew
witnessed a lease he signed,
and that guy is on some FBI list,
they took him to Guantanamo
as a suspect.
Uh, second tier.
A second tier suspect,
which means
that they just deported him to Syria,
uh, where's he's probably
gonna be tortured and maybe even killed,
and they know that.
Um, so his wife has now written a letter
to the state department,
which we want you to execute.
She's here, she's Canadian,
and she doesn't have a Visa.
So we wanna know if we need to have it
sent to you from Quebec somehow.
You know what? Just call me as soon
as you get this message, all right?
And I'll be up late. Okay.
All good.
MAN ON RADIO:
# see the clock in shadow #
# And see your face #
# You and me belong
in the same time and place #
# People never celebrate
the things they've got #
# Honey. Without you.
Wouldn't have a lot #
# feel beautiful #
Yeah, I've got a place not far from here,
but like I said,
I'd like for us to sit, wait for a bit.
You don't have to do that.
I mean, honestly, Ashade,
it would kill me to see you
give your money to some other lawyer
that's just gonna rubber stamp
some papers.
And Harry will call soon.
I know it.
You want coffee?
Oh. I would like much
if I get it for you.
Oh. Thank you.
I have some cream and sugar.
Oh, no, black is good for me.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
You should know that Eloise is so happy
for what you do for us.
She doesn't sleep.
But maybe now she knows
that there is nice people, too.
I just... I feel so horrible for her.
I ca... I can't imagine.
Can't imagine.
Their first baby and everything.
What?
My brother also has 20-years son
from the time he married before.
Ashade, that needs to be in our letter.
You're right, but my brother
and the first son of his
were together at the airport.
And we believe they are together now.
Jesus. Ashade...
In my country,
when they do some torture,
they do it by the mind.
They... they show you your mother
or your son
and then they take them in the next room
and you know nothing.
You hear things,
but you don't know anything certain.
Just your imaginations.
Can you take me to my office now?
Now?
Did you think
it was gonna break down?
I know.
I've been here 11 years.
A lot of things break down,
but never the elevator.
Anyway, this is it.
My creative team's over there,
my PR guys there.
Accounting in here.
Those clowns you need to avoid
like the plague.
You can leave the door open.
Oh, sorry.
Have a seat.
Oh, yeah.
There it is.
Please, sit.
Hey, Harry Fine.
It's me, Philly again.
Listen, um, I left you a really long message
on your other number
about an urgent situation,
so just call it, get it, call me back.
Got it?
And you know what?
I'm gonna beep you, too,
so don't make me wait.
Just to show you I'm not
a bitter woman through and through.
That's me and Paul
and our daughter
and the lovely little homewrecker
on the left.
So, Ashade, is it like a Muslim rule
that you have to wear the beard?
Oh, no, but, um...
uh, as a sign of my devotion.
I try again.
Well, I can't blame you for trying,
but you know, you're not an old man.
No.
And the man has to wear the beard
and the woman has to wear the...
Wow.
Allah must really be something, huh?
He's not something.
For us, we find him...
he's everything.
And he's not passive,
like a lot of the other ones.
I really like that.
- But Eloise is not Muslim, right?
- No.
No. And that's not a problem
for your brother?
I would not say so much,
but, uh, the whole family loves Eloise.
So it's all very complete.
Mmm.
But you would never find yourself with
one of us Western women, would you?
Um, do you have... do you have a wife?
Or a woman somewhere?
At the moment, I'm sending money home
and keeping watch of Eloise.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I can see that.
See what?
Oh, nothin'. Nothin'.
Um, when was the last time?
That you had a girlfriend of your own.
Not so long.
Are you lying to me?
'Cause, remember,
I caught you once before.
160 bucks?
Shoot! We have to go.
Otherwise, I have to
fill out papers till dawn.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
We're gonna go to the roof.
Hurry.
Okay.
Don't worry,
they never come up here.
Oh.
Yep. He's stuck at the beach house.
I felt it vibrate when we were running.
So...
You think you can
call Mr. Fine still or no?
Yes, I can.
If you still want.
Yes.
I feel that you feel he will help us.
I do wanna ask you a question, though.
But don't take this as anything
but a simple question.
Are you sure that your brother
is completely clean?
Clean?
That he doesn't have anything to do
with any kind of threats?
Oh, of course, no.
My brother is a holy man.
He's a doctor.
Okay.
Hey, Harry.
So you thought you could run away
for the weekend already, huh?
And you got my message?
What do you mean you looked into it?
How do you look into it at five...
Well, call him back!
Yes! And tell him
that my friend's brother and his son
probably have got their testicles
hooked up to a car battery
in some Damascus basement.
What? I shouldn't have to
spell out for you
how much money I generated
for your firm this year, Harry.
All right, fine. Fine.
You go back to sleep,
but you think long and hard
about who really paid
for that little beach house.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
It's not okay.
I just... I feel bad
that we let us rely on him.
But you know why
he's not interested?
Because he knows we can't win.
Even if we get your brother back,
unscathed, where is our satisfaction?
What do we have to show
for his pain and suffering?
Please, don't go to be too stressed.
It's all right.
What do you want me to be?
You want me to be passive?
I mean, come on, Ashade.
Don't get me involved
and then expect me to just roll over
because some Jew boy
doesn't wanna do his job.
Ashade, do you...
You hate Americans, don't you?
No.
- No?
- No.
With you,
I'm disappointed very much, but, uh...
Disappointed?
Did you really just say that?
How...
I don't understand.
Do you really care,
what they're doing to your brother?
In any country and in any religion,
the punishment is supposed to
fit the crime, right?
Your brother has committed no crime,
so there is a miscarriage of justice.
And in turn, where there is an injustice,
there needs to be a retribution.
L... I don't understand "retribution."
I'm not talking about doing
anything more or anything less
than what they've already accused
your brother of doing.
I'm not talking about hurting anyone.
Really, I'm not.
I am talking about
causing a little damage, symbolically.
Now, I don't know anything
about munitions,
but that's what the Internet's for, right?
So that people like us can learn things
that they don't want us to know?
I want to go now. Thank you.
You're gonna need a code for that.
So, let me just finish.
Okay?
Look...
We do an act of retribution,
we get you out of the country,
we tell the people that sent your brother
to Syria what you've done,
they have to let him go.
They will listen.
I'm telling you.
You dial the code,
and I'm go home now.
Go ahead. I'm not your doorman.
342 is the code.
Oh, and I hope you have fun telling
the security guards what you're doing here.
I'm sure they're gonna believe
every word you say.
I'm going to fucking kill you,
you little punk!
Go, go, go, go!
Oh, sir, yes, yes. Yes.
Yes, you will have certified
postal check today, yes.
Yes. And for you,
I have almost, uh, uh, 500...
O-oh, sir, sir.
L-I'm sorry to be bother, but...
If I may, I call back.
L... I will soon. Sorry.
Ashade.
Hi.
Okay, pretty dog.
Let the lady put her things down
and we'll take of you and only you.
This is the stairway to my room.
Keep it stocked
for the late night booty calls.
Can actually see Japan from here
if needed to.
This is my collection.
These are my toys.
That's my home base. Q-Dogs.
Sorry. Haters.
You gots to go.
I think stainless is masculine...
All right, Q-Dogs.
We're gonna keep rocking.
Moving on to the '90s.
# Tell me that you wanna hold me #
# Tell me that you wanna bore me #
# Tell me that you gotta show me #
# Tell me that you need to slowly #
# Tell me that you're burning for me #
# Tell me that you can't afford me... #
Come here, Smitty.
Come here.
Don't ignore me.
Yes?
Ashade?
T's me. Philly.
How you get to this phone?
Your number is listed
on the letter that we wrote,
which I still have, by the way,
and which I still think
it would be very smart of you to use.
Are you there?
I am, yes.
Listen. It's the money
you're mad about. Isn't it?
I'm sorry about that, okay?
But Harry is a very good lawyer,
and he does require a consulting fee.
And he will help my family?
Well, no. See, the fee was for
what he did the other night.
For making that call
about what the laws are.
You return our money.
I need this money for us today!
Okay, listen,
I can get you some money, okay?
That's not a problem.
And I realize that it was wrong
to leave you with nothing,
but first I feel like we should talk...
about what I was suggesting.
Just want the money
returned to me!
Why could you try to hurt us more?!
Hurt who. Ashade?
I mean, do you really think
that we can get something done
by just writing a bunch of letters?
Depending on lawyers is for losers,
and I'm just not one, okay?
Now. would just go
and get retribution on my own.
But it wouldn't mean anything unless
people believed a brave Muslim did it.
People are terrified of you, Ashade.
You have that power.
You stop, you stop, you stop!
You stop!
You know what?
You don't make any sense.
Unless your brother
did something to hurt you.
He did. Didn't he?
He got to be a doctor while you need to
drive a cab so you can send money home.
Bet you're just so jealous of him.
'Cause he gets to have sex
with sweet white Eloise
if we bring him home.
And all you get to do
is masturbate to her
if you get ten minutes
to yourself. Right?
Never you call to me again, okay?!
You apologize to me right now.
Do you hear me?
- You apologize to me right now.
- Fuck you!
Fuck you! You crazy!
You bitch! Fuck you badly!
You know that I don't speak like that,
and I don't wanna be spoken to like that.
Do you know who I am? Huh?
You little cabby nobody.
You sorry little camel jockey.
You apologize to me right now
- before I find a reason to hurt you.
- You bitch!
Merci.
I got it.
Listen. We know
that's his cab, all right?
If he's hiding somewhere in the building,
we're gonna find him.
Mrs. Mouhanna.
Shh! Shh.
Shh.
Just relax, ma'am.
Your son is fine.
No!
#... breeze like a motherfucker #
# Young thugs and OG's
like a motherfucker #
# Got a girl that roll deez
# But no cheese. Oh. Please.
You's a motherfucker #
# He don't care. 'cause
'm a dawg like a motherfucker #
# Small talkin'.
And got charm like a motherfucker #
Um, can you drive uptown
and I'll let you know where in a minute?
Sure. Why not?
I'm on till midnight.
You know what? Um, can we
just go to 48th and 10th, please?
Never mind.
I'll just get out here, okay?
Here you go.
Keep the change.
If it's true that you really don't
speak any English,
we'll find an interpreter
for you tomorrow.
An A-shade somebody.
Medallion number 67 GDT34.
The phone call she's talking
about here, it may be you.
... oveneard him talking to a woman
on his cell phone
about causing some real damage
and waking up the arrogant Americans.
Thank you.
Ma'am.
Aah! Motherfucker!
I imagine it's for you.
No, not at all.
I don't have that problem.
Oh, geez. I wish.
Yes?
This is for me to deliver to Philly.
Who?
Uh... Philly.
You mean Phyllis?
Phyllis Maclntyre?
Oh, please.
Nobody is helped if we waste the time.
# Ten. Twenty. Thirty. Forty #
# Tell me that you wanna scold me... #
Next time, make sure they call
so have it scheduled.
So after everything Q-Dog
did for you last year...
Have a seat.
She'll be right with you.
You gotta give me the cover.
Listen, I really hope that this is
the last time we have to go over this,
and I left all the info
on your other number,
so call it, get it, call me back.
Got it?
Uh, so, who was it
that told you to call me Philly?
It wasn't Caymen, was it?
Hi. Come on, 'fess up.
No one's called me that in ten years.
Um...
Phoebe? She was the one
who told you to call me that?
Yes.
You're joking.
And how do you know Phoebe?
W-we passed the night once
a few days before.
Really?
God bless you, man.
Someone needed to take her
off the shnide, didn't they?
I'm sorry. That was mean.
It's okay.
So is that for me
to listen to, or, um?
Oh, no, no. Uh...
I was only trying to
see Phoebe a moment.
She was to help me
to write a letter in English.
Oh. Yeah.
She was always good for that.
Myself, I can't even write a postcard
without one of my secretaries.
Scott, can you help us out
and, uh, get Phoebe Torrence up here
before she runs away to lunch?
MAN ON SPEAKER:
Sure thing. Philly.
Okay, don't call me that.
Please, sit down.
It'll be just a second.
Hello. It's Mac for Connors.
Connors. Maclntyre.
Good news.
Yeah, 'cause we got the cover.
Thank you.
I am a genius.
Oh, 'cause it's gonna be perfect.
We're talking about perfectly with...
Connor, you heard
the good news, didn't you?
Well, that's okay,
'cause I already bumped them.
No, I bumped them from...
you know, to October's cover.
It's not gonna be that big of a deal.
'Cause I... you know, because I promised
the girls in marketing.
That's how we got the cover.
W-well, it doesn't matter.
I've seen them five times.
I've already given up my tickets...
Phoebe, I'm very sorry
I don't call you first, but, uh...
I have lost the number
for the home you have in Englewood Cliffs.
That's fine. That's fine.
It's nice to see you again.
Hey, Phoebes.
Hi.
Glad you could find my office.
Oh. Yeah, no, I stopped by
not too long ago, but you weren't here.
Yeah, right.
I'm so hard to track down.
So, um...
Habib.
Habib says you spent a night with him...
helping him write a letter.
Oh! Yeah.
Uh, I was helping him, and, um...
but I thought we finished.
Well, according to what he tells me,
um, you're not.
Oh.
Well, I'm sorry.
It's just for the long hours,
it's hard for me
to do a lot of edit work.
Oh. Right!
Like you're so busy now
that the tax report is already filed.
Oh, I was just, uh, you know,
making sure that he was okay with you.
L... You didn't introduce me
so I didn't know what to think.
Oh. No, it's... it's fine.
So are you guys going to lunch?
Paul and Devon are on their way in,
so you're more than welcome to join us.
Oh, today's not so good.
Oh, hey. You always say that.
Look, if you have to feed Smitty,
uh, we can even go to Peppe's,
and you can just run upstairs.
How's that for accommodating?
Phoebe...
Paul's gonna have his guy who does,
you know, his frames for him there.
- Okay, okay.
- Great.
I'll see you guys downstairs
in a couple of minutes.
Oh, uh, very sorry. I can't.
Um, but, uh, it was very nice
to see both of you.
- Very nice.
- Oh, okay.
Phoebe.
If you leave our letter for me down,
I will pick it down from there tomorrow.
- It's nice to meet you, Habib.
- Great.
Bye.
Uh, Phoebe.
Wait, Phoebe.
- Yeah?
- Are you okay?
Yeah.
Was that not cool?
Like, l... I'm sorry, I didn't know him so...
No, no, it's fine.
I'm just helping him out a little bit.
Write a letter.
And did it work?
I... I...
Well, if it's a legal thing,
I could just call good old Harry Fine for you.
Oh, good.
I'm so glad you're coming to lunch.
I'll meet you down there, okay?
Someone might pick this up tomorrow.
- There she is.
- Hey!
Let's run for pasta.
Run for pasta!
- Up on the curb!
- Wow, that was pretty high.
I just don't think it's gonna be a problem.
I think you have enough pieces for January.
- It's not a matter of quantity, it's quality.
- I know, but it's a great...
Paul, don't talk to me about quality.
Your stuff is so great.
Yeah, you tell her.
Paul and I mentioned
a couple of times, that Gary,
the guy we're meeting for lunch,
he might not be a bad hookup for you.
But, you know, don't worry, because...
He's a very nice guy,
but there's no pressure.
If you don't wanna see him again...
- No. Fine. Fine.
- Good.
I'm gonna go feed Smitty really quick.
I'll be right back.
We'll wait for you,
so you don't have to walk in alone.
Okay.
What do you want for lunch?
Meatballs?
- Spaghetti and meatballs.
Spaghetti and meatballs.
He's here.
Here, I got it.
You wanna hold my hat, honey?
I want you to be totally honest.
Not about the paintings,
but about the pictures.
This is a part of a new series.
Very clean. Very simple.
- That's at...
- An insane asylum?
Yeah, upstate.
The New York Times Magazine
is doing a story
on artists who've moved out of the city
to get more room.
Oh, wow.
Phoebes,
don't you know that menu by heart?
They didn't suddenly fly in a new chef
from Bologna or anything, did they?
So, did you, uh...
did you go to school for accounting?
It's just something
that I thought I could do, you know?
How many years have you
worked at, uh... at, uh, Q-Dog?
Well, actually, we started
the exact same day eleven years ago.
They used to call us
the Phoebe and Philly show.
Paul didn't tell you that?
No.
Wait, you were an accountant, too?
Worse. A sales rep.
You're not serious.
I was just this, uh, little
loser nerd girl from Queens.
It's true. She was.
And, uh, Phoebe was this...
can you believe this?
This straight-laced Calvinist
from Buttstuck, Michigan.
They just stuck the two oddballs
together in the same cubicle
because they didn't know
what the heck else to do with us.
I don't even really know anymore.
I was talking to my shrink about it,
and about how people are saying
that the reality of what we do
is making, you know,
fat kids wanna kill themselves
and, you know,
little girls wanna get implants...
Oh, wait, I'm sorry.
Hold on... I just...
Oh, it is. It's time for my wife to try
talking like she hates her job again.
Oh, oh! Okay!
You know what,
I don't hate my job, all right?
I answer to no one, and I'm
very well compensated for it, thank you.
Actually, if you want to know how well,
you can ask your new friend in accounting,
because she can probably
tell you to the dime.
I'm good, though.
I'm pretty good at it.
Anyway, I thank God
I have a life to go with it,
and a very dear old friend
to thank for it.
I still owe you my life, sunshine.
No, you don't.
Oh, no.
Oh, you bet
your sweet little tuckus I do.
You know, the truth is is that Phoebe
was the first to meet Paul
when she took
a painting class for fun at...
- At F.I.T.
- F.I.T.
God, man, if it wasn't for that,
I would've never had
my shot at the prize.
- The prize?
- Yes.
I'm a trophy husband.
Yeah. You're like a...
you're the heavyweight champion.
Mmm!
Actually, no.
Sorry, you're not the prize.
Devon is the prize.
Devon's the prize!
- Who's gonna eat one more tortellini.
- Yes.
- No.
- Come on, one more.
You hate him, don't you?
Who, Gary?
Of course you hate him.
Look, I know he's no heartthrob,
but, you know, I think he's at least,
you know, a good boost for you.
Anyway, I promise I'll run interference
on the way out of here.
Oh, no, it's fine.
It's fine.
- Oh, I can make it.
- Are you sure?
Yeah. It's fine.
Hey. Hey.
I really miss hanging out with you.
Don't you?
Oh, you're vibrating.
Oh, shit.
You know, it's our car mechanic.
- Do you mind?
- No.
I'm so sorry.
Hi. Yes.
Just let me get out of the restroom.
I needed it by... lf you can't have it for me
by this weekend,
then you need to park it in front of
my house before 9:00 A.M. On Monday.
An entire week
to paint one lousy door.
Phoebe, can you believe this?
The night that I brought
the new Lexus home,
you know, the one that's
supposed to shine like a diamond?
- Have you seen this car?
- Oh, no.
But you saw a picture of it, right?
You're not a Jazz fan, are you?
Honey, I didn't tell you.
The day that the ratings came out
and they gave me the car,
Connor sent a picture of the Lexus
to everyone at Q-Dog,
letting them know
that he rewards exceeding expectations.
It looked pretty good
for about a minute and a half.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
Some jealous kid
from the neighbonood
scratched A-L-Q-something
into the side door,
which I guess is supposed to mean
All Q-Dog, all the time.
Or Al Qaeda.
The car's all right now, though, right?
- Oh, it's fine.
- Listen, thanks for lunch.
Oh, but, Phoebe...
Where...
Smitty?
Where's my dog?
Call to him.
Please do.
I left your money at the desk!
Don't tell lie.
Call your dog.
What did you do to my dog?
What did you do to my dog?!
He did nothing to you.
Harry Fine is a real lawyer.
Ashade, I promise he is gonna
help you and Eloise, I swear.
You stop!
Call your dog!
Smitty!
Smitty! Smitty!
Call your dog!
Smitty!
Go outside, okay?
Go on, pretty dog. Go on.
Go to your spot.
It's okay.
If you're praying, don't do that here.
You're not better than me,
and I don't need you being better than me.
If you came here to fuck me,
then fuck me.
If you came here to kill me,
then you oughta just do it!
Do it!
I don't want it anymore.
I just want
what I deserve from you over with.
All right, fine.
I'll do it myself.
Oh, no.
Oh! Oh!
No!
Oh, no.
It would help me much
if you could tell to me why.
Why is it you could?
Why?
Tell me.
No! No, no, no, no.
No! Please! Tell me why!
Tell me why!
I have come here only to know.
No, it's Maclntyre.
It's the lawyer calling.
- Stop it.
- No, it is. It's the truth.
- Stop it! Stop it!
- It's the truth.
It can't be anyone else.
Ashade...
She said she'd call Mr. Fine for us.
Look.
Why?
Why you hurt me?
Why you hurt my family?
I have nothing now!
Not an idea what can I do for my life!
I have nothing!
You don't know why?
Well, you should know.
You should know.
Were you here that day?
Were you?
Well, I was here.
And I was piecing myself together for work
and the phone rang
and it was Philly.
And she was scared.
She never calls me when she's weak,
but she did.
She called me on that day.
And I had a dried-out cigarillo
from when her daughter was born.
And I smoked it and I felt fine.
I felt just fine.
Can't you see?
Can't you see what a cruel joke
that I'm stuck with?
Every day I ring up huge money
and never once is it mine.
Never once.
No savings,
no inheritance, no prospects.
And not a soul alive
that gives a hoot about me expect my dog.
So I think maybe all I can say
is that I just...
...hate me.
I just effing fucking hate me.
And I know it's wrong.
I know it's wrong
what I did to you and Eloise.
It was wrong.
And I know I need help.
I know I need help, Ashade.
It's just that day,
that day I wasn't a failure, okay?
I was not a nobody.
I wasn't powerless
because everybody was powerless.
Everybody was.
I just wanted that day back.
I just wanted it back.
Can you do something for me, please?
Can you let me show you my phone?
You see what it says?
At least today I'm not a liar.
Yes.
You know that for Eloise...
I did nothing.
Not a... a thing of what you say.
But I think of her...
...in the wrong ways in my mind.
Too many times.
It's very good
my brother should come back to her.
Smitty? Pretty dog.
You in your spot?
Come here.
Come on. Come here.
Okay. Come on.
We have to go get breakfast.
How is it today you speak French?
Well, isn't it obvious?
It'd be too difficult in Arabic.
Oh, there's no ham.
Oh. I'm not worried.
Only hungry.
Mmm.
The message from Mr. Fine
only said to call to him, no?
Oh, no, the message said
to contact him first thing.
But it's up to you.
I don't have a problem
with going down to the office
and just waiting until he can see us.
What do you think?
With you I can go.
- C'est bonne?
- Mm-hmm.
It's delicious.
Um, Phoebe Torrence
left an envelope for me.
I think Harry's office is there.
Okay.
Come quick.
I just want you to look nice.
Jealousy!
You stop that right now!
You can't go into Harry's office
dressed like that.
You get in here.
There you go.
Okay.
Wait.
I have something for you.
What is this?
Something my parents gave me and for
some reason, I want you to have it.
Guy, you all right?
Go! Go! Go!
Go! Go!
# Tell me that you wanna scold me #
# Tell me that you adore me #
# Tell me that you're famous for me #
# Tell me that you're gonna score me #
# Tell me that you gotta show me #
# Tell me that you need to sorely #
# Time to tell your love story #
# Time turning over and over #
# Time turning four leaf clover #
# Betting on the bull in the heather #
# I feel beautiful #
# Because you love me #
# I water the tomatoes
and I think of you #
# No one's ever watered me
the way you do #
# I feel beautiful #
# Because you love me #
# I feel like a creature
that is sleekly groomed #
# Not some poisoned soul
that is alone and doomed #
# I feel beautiful #
# Because you love me #
# I see the clock and shadow
and I see your face #
# You and me belong
in the same time and place #
# People never celebrate
the things they've got #
# Honey, without you,
I wouldn't have a lot #
# I feel beautiful #
# Because you love me #