Do not be like a hypocrite,
Who thinks he can hide their tricks
Over the loud chanting of the Koran
Hafiz, Iranian poet of the 14th century
Film Cyrus Nowrasteh
Based on a true story
Stoning of Soraya M.
... since the fall of the damned Shah
... Iran undergone radical
changes and improvements ...
Book adaptation Freydona Saebdzhama
Kupayeh, Iran
Stop here.
Could you please help me?
This radiator. Overheated.
Road heavy for them.
Watch the car tomorrow.
Listen, I need to get to the border at night.
I'll pay you over.
It is not a question of money.
I do not work today.
How Come?
I'm tired.
Watch later.
See what I can do.
Just take me to the border.
Yes I Am. To the border. I got it.
I'll fix, if I can.
Yonder Cafe?
Yeah, up there.
Thank U.
I speak in English.
You say in English?
I have to talk fast.
In this village there is such,
what you do not know.
They can not get away with it ...
these devils.
Do not pay attention to her.
It is old and sick.
These are your ancestors are old and sick.
Despicable woman.
Now talk to strange men?
Go Away! Be hid from our eyes!
Go away!
Sir, as the head of the village,
I welcome you.
I and Sheikh Hassan, our mullah, would
to share with you our breakfast.
As a representative of the authorities, I have
welcome guests of the village.
Thanks, but I'm only here for those
to my car repaired.
And I need to work on.
And what kind of work?
Just paperwork.
A paper work.
You accountant?
Journalist.
Your accent ... Where is he?
I'm going back to France.
I live there.
Our Ayatollah,
blessed Imam Khomeini
visited in France.
His well received there.
Of course you have to eat. Come on!
I am grateful to you, but no thank you.
Then, maybe, tea?
Maybe another time.
You saw someone?
What is it?
Are you fine. I love you, girl.
Come on. Look. He is our guest.
I'll make him tea while you play.
Come on, my dear girl.
Do not worry. I'm here.
Sorry them. They have been through so much.
Yours?
They daughter of my niece.
Soraya.
I Zahra.
Zahra.
Zahra,
Are you crazy?
They think so.
And then ...
and invite a stranger into your home ...
I tend to agree.
Sit down, please.
I'll pour you tea ...
and then you decide who is crazy:
me or them.
Do you smoke?
Ayatollah does not prohibit women from smoking?
Today I am old ...
a hundred years older than yesterday.
But I can tell right from wrong.
What happened here yesterday,
was wrong.
Yesterday.
The Devil himself visited the site ...
Allah the Merciful and knows it.
God willing, and you know it too.
Turn on your machine.
Voices of women are not taken into account here.
I want you to take my voice with them.
Why should I listen to you,
If, as you say ...
voices of women anywhere in this country
are not taken into account.
First, listen to my story.
You'll learn why you should listen to.
At this point, there are men,
that - wild dogs.
Their hunt began not so long ago,
Soraya with her husband ...
Ali.
Soraya agree, when you realize
it's good for her.
Yes, but women can be stubborn.
You ought to know this about his wife.
You have to convince her.
God willing.
No! Convince her. She has no choice.
Do not tell me this is your "God willing."
You're no more mullah than I am.
I have proof of your prison of the past.
You, those who committed a crime in the reign of the Shah,
now free ...
... but we will not forgive the crimes in the future.
Are you threatening me?
Just remember ...
who knows about you the truth.
We are with you at the same time.
But that thinks Soraya, I'm unsure.
So influenced on it.
Convince her.
Look who's talking.
Our "holy" Mullah.
Peace to you, woman.
Soraya?
How are you?
Ali does not.
I want to talk to you.
What a beautiful girl.
Ali, you complain.
He says that you do not talk to him ...
ignore it ...
completely abandoned it.
He is your husband.
He has every right, you know.
All right.
You can not him in anything to deny.
Ali, my husband for 20 years,
set up our sons with him against me.
He met a woman whom he wanted to marry,
but he can not have two wives.
He will give you a house, furniture, girls ...
and some land for cultivation.
However, the more he will not give you any of the material.
This tiny little house and rocky ground
not be able to provide me and daughters.
His proposal - generous.
Something else.
With Ali's nothing you can do.
I will provide you and your daughters.
With all due respect, of course.
I will visit you ...
and we can get to know each other better.
After some time ...
you know this word - sigheh ...
temporary wife.
Fully sanctioned by Islam.
Get Out!
What is it? This is a private conversation.
Leave this house right now ...
Sheikh Hassan Mullah, whoever you was ...
or I'll pick up the entire village.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
You dishonor the Holy Book, which you wear.
Zahra, you misunderstand.
I respect Soraya.
I came ...
with pure intentions.
The only thing clear - this is your lust.
Sigheh ... holy whore?
How dare you?
Let God's fury spilled on you rain.
Let the undertaker will take you and your three generations.
Get Out!
You witch.
Your poison will return back to you and poison you.
And you, too.
Wait and see.
You will see both.
What happened to your marriage?
Ali still admires prostitutes?
Who is this other woman?
You're sleeping with him?
You give him what should?
Goes the rumor that will not let.
Answer me.
He takes what I owe him.
I have nothing left to give.
Divorce.
Give him his.
And be sigheh Hassan,
and my children will starve?
No, I can not do that.
This girl from the city. Who is she?
Mehri.
Her name Mehri.
She is 14 ...
burning eyes.
Her father - a doctor.
He has money. He was hanged.
Ali promised to help him.
In exchange for a daughter?
I'm sure they have everything agreed.
death
How do you know?
He boasts of his sons ...
as if they should admire them for that.
They plan everything - Ali and the mullah.
We have to keep an eye on all of this.
You shamed me, woman.
In my own home.
Before the man of God!
I ridicule, an object of ridicule.
How dare you?
Let her be quiet.
Mullah Hassan came here today to offer ...
divorce for your mother,
and she refused.
The woman did not put meat on the table.
You're not giving me money.
I can not make the meat with rice.
In Mehri on the table always eat meat.
And even more than that.
She knows how to be a wife.
Not to speak about it.
We could move to the city,
closer to my work.
You could be the guards of the revolutionary regime.
Enough.
Father, we go with you?
Of Course. Here you have nothing.
But this woman does not want to see her husband
and sons happy.
Why will not you let us go?
Only boys?
What about our daughters?
I do not want my children to go hungry.
You have responsibilities.
As her husband. As a father. According to the law and before God.
You can not leave us.
And what about me?
Your wife!
Your Mullah gave me a proposition.
Yes I Am.
As if I'm a slut.
What have you for a husband?
Where's your honor? Your dignity?
Do not say that my father!
Get.
Get this mess.
Well!
You owe me for this 25 fogs.
This is the world of men.
Never forget this, guys.
Where are you?
- Come on.
- Where are you?
Do not look at me like that.
Do not look at me!
Where the hell are you?
Where are you ?!
If he wants a divorce, you will have to pay.
He will not pay. I know him.
I'll talk with the head of the village, Ebrahim.
He listens to me.
After the death of my husband ...
he wanted to marry me.
When I was a child, my parents
forced me to work for a man ...
so they do not have to feed me.
He did with me what you want ...
Is that not fuck.
Do you understand what I mean.
Neither I nor my daughter in all of this will not come back.
So protect them.
Do not provoke. You're on this dishonor.
Remember that.
Can we stay here with you?
No. Staying here will ignite only
his reproaches neglected.
At home, they do not sleep quietly.
You have to help me.
- My wife.
- What happened?
She is ill.
The doctor went to the city,
so I ran here.
Yes of course.
I'll go too.
No. Remember what we talked about.
Come on, Hashem.
God bless you.
God bless you, Zahra.
Yes, I'm glad to help.
Back!
Hire us too!
Can you believe it?
Stay here.
Zahra would do something.
Your mother is not feeling well.
Mohsen, stay here, son.
She is very strong.
She gave birth to a child after 30 years of marriage.
Nobody thought that she could,
but she managed.
Thanks to God, she was born Mohsen.
Tell me what it's all right.
Hashem ...
I have to clean up the body for burial.
I'm so sorry.
No!
You know the custom.
The body of a dead woman can not see nobody,
even her husband.
Her body is still here.
This looting is unacceptable.
You should be ashamed.
For what? She can no longer use it.
- Put your back.
- I first saw her.
These things belong to Hashem.
They may need it.
Sewing machine?
Yes, he does not know what the needle!
I said, put it back.
His wife died. And he's still alive.
To do their work.
Zahra!
- Yes I Do?
- Come here!
Zahra ...
Hashem told us how you were good
to him and his dear wife last night.
We are grateful.
It should be taken to hospital.
Someone could take her there.
For example, you, Ali.
In this your luxury car.
But there are more important for you to passengers.
Not now, Zahra.
All this does not matter.
This is a time of trouble, and we worry about Hashem.
Its not even buried.
I did not want.
Zahra, Hashem will not be able to cope alone.
Cooking, cleaning and Mohsen ...
Such a boy without a mother,
take care of it quite hard.
Could you talk to Soraya?
We thought it might help him ...
when she cope with her chores around the house.
As a community, we care about each other.
Oh, that's so, then how?
You care, and it does all the work.
Talk to her yourself.
Zahra, she will perceive better
if it is going to come from you.
She perceive better if you ask her to pay.
Of Course.
Naturally, it will be paid.
That will be better, and it should be a good payment.
And this will be her money.
Her one.
Okay. What else?
Any food or gasoline,
nor your women.
You're sharp-tongued witch.
Ali is good in shock, I guess.
Enough! With this decided.
Soraya will work on Hashem.
You go too far.
This is not like the old days.
Shah was no more.
How well I understand that.
I warn you as a friend.
Hold your tongue.
Cooperate with them.
Respect them.
Give them what they want.
This is exactly what you do, Ebrahim, is not it?
But at what cost?
You thought about it?
You stopped them when they were examining her things.
God bless you.
She spoke of you as a good friend.
Put it somewhere safe.
Mohsen, where are you?
Give Soraya leave.
You will return to cook dinner?
Do not worry. I'll be back.
- Okay.
Stand still.
This is ridiculous.
I do not need a new skirt.
You could make it to the one who will pay.
Hashem said that I can do with fabric
whatever I want.
I ride for you.
Turn Around.
Hashem is well with you drawn?
It's boring, but nice.
God bless him.
In fact, ...
Could you keep it for me?
This is what I have earned a long time.
Each Rial.
I want to keep them safe,
in case ...
If a pig is hungry?
This is the beginning.
Your chance to get away.
Good For You.
Beautiful.
I look like a real lady.
Thank you very much.
She's beautiful.
Okay, guys, well done.
When we go into the city, Father?
Coming Soon.
Thank you, boss.
What about Mom and the girls?
No problem.
I'll take care of everything.
Go home.
I think between Soraya and Hashemi something there.
Soraya? She is not the type.
How do you know?
It works in his home ...
he is a widower ...
they spend a lot of time alone ...
What are you talking about?
Treason is punishable by stoning.
That you want?
If she dies, I will not have to
keep it, right?
But she now earns money.
After some time, it will give you a divorce.
Why so extreme?
Because I can not wait!
Who are you to be so right?
I know the facts about you.
One word - and that you stoned.
But we will have to convince Ebrahim.
He wants the evidence of witnesses.
He has long known Soraya.
I am a witness.
Why do not you be a witness?
I can not. The head of the village and I must
preside.
You need someone else.
Let us find someone.
First, raise the noise in a factory ...
... this shitty town.
Good morning, Zahra.
I am at your service.
The new skirt?
It looks like the fabric that I have seen in Hashem.
Yes, she is.
My niece sewed.
I see you've still got the ring wife Hashem.
Why is it?
Unless he has a new woman
to give it to her.
You hinted at Soraya?
What is it you?
Do not pretend innocent lamb.
You all his life and spread rumors.
Zahra law.
You gossip.
Shut up if you do not know what to talk about.
Maybe that, and I know.
There's nothing to know.
I know that Soraya rejects Ali.
Why else did he amuses himself with other women?
Because he's a dishonest man.
Ha! He as well as any man.
Feed him and he is happy.
Leave him hungry, and he will take what
thirsty, and you will also be blamed.
I know Soraya. She's a good woman.
You're married to her?
You can not blame Ali for the frigid wife.
Nobody knows what happens between husband and wife.
You ought to understand this, Leila.
Beautiful, Mom?
Yes, dear, very beautiful.
Mom, who am I?
Dai guess.
Cow?
Not a cow.
Maybe the elephant?
Mom!
Enough. We need to return to prepare lunch.
I'm a rabbit!
See ...
Angels, Mom!
Soraya.
You scared me.
You're early today.
No work.
Too few machines here.
Where Mohsen?
Lay down to take a nap.
He fell and tore knee.
Cried, cried and fell asleep.
Nothing serious.
Just a little scratch.
I with all govern.
Dinner on the stove.
Smells nice.
Yes, today was fresh lamb.
Can stay ...
sing with me?
No, I really should go home.
Of Course.
Sometimes I ...
I do not like to eat alone.
Mohsen soon wake up.
See you tomorrow morning.
If you expect from me as from the head of the village,
trial ...
I want meaningful, honest witnesses.
Not your friends or gossips,
who do not like Soraya.
Islamic law says that anyone
witness can testify.
Give me the facts, not rumors.
- Ebragim.
- Not now, Zahra, I'm busy.
I know you involved in intrigues with respect to
Soraya and Ali.
This does not intrigue! Just complaint.
Ebrahim, I'm warning you.
I will not harm my niece.
It would be necessary to wear muzzles women, not dogs.
There is no better wife and mother than Soraya.
We all wondered why she ...
spends so much time in Hashem.
I want to know what is happening.
It's none of your business.
What do you mean, woman?
And I thought to marry you.
However, Ebrahim.
You have become a servant.
You're no more than a slave, sigheh! Temporary wife!
The wife of a monster!
This intrigue. I do not know what they are,
but they turned against you.
I just get a wife.
Hardly deserves some intrigue.
These men are up to something.
You have to quit work.
You can not return to Hashem.
Quit work? This work - my
only hope. I can not leave her.
You can not stay on it.
These same men offered me the job.
And now this is my job.
I will keep it.
Ali complains about you.
- He always complains.
- And what did you tell him?
It'S Nothing. If I say something, he beats me.
You're not listening. And they can hurt you.
This mullah could persuade a snake
swallowing its own tail.
Enough!
This is not the plot, it's just with my aunt
imaginative.
You could never hear between the lines!
Dear ...
... door.
Look, Hashem ...
we want with you something to talk about.
Ali saw Soraya input-output from you.
He is a man suspicious.
And do not trust his wife.
In addition ...
as you know ...
I have ...
before our Ayatollah enact
all standards of virtue ...
orders as Sharia.
Islam makes such a claim here.
Of course, you could cause a judge from Tehran.
But then it would not be in my hands ...
but in the hands of an official who does not know you.
Read here.
I can not read.
Hashem ...
Are not we old friends?
Yes, we ...
Frankly.
Man to man. Tell the truth.
My wife is sleeping in your house?
No, Ali. She's home every night.
This is not the answer. It happens, lie down?
I do not know.
Hashem, be honest. You should know,
she was asleep or not.
I'm a simple man. I do not know where
you will go to such matters.
- Sit down, Hashem.
- No, I have to go.
I'll go, bye.
Mohsen, give me a wrench.
The key number 10.
Next to the box with tools.
Thank U.
No problem.
How are you, Mohsen?
It's okay, son? Good boy.
Hashem.
We need 2 witnesses.
One we already have.
We can talk to the boy -
if he had seen that Soraya goes home.
He does not understand what you're saying.
Of course, does not understand.
Yes, Mohsen?
Good boy.
Not to involve him in this.
We can not.
If my wife is obscene to you,
perhaps you enjoy it.
Such a man could also be charged with ...
... and punished.
In some cases, stoned together with a woman.
What will happen to Mohsen ...
if his father is not around?
Psychiatric Hospital?
Or ...
I could take him to jail and
personally take care of it.
Mohsen, tell us.
What is Soraya doing at home?
It touches you?
Enough! Enough!
Stop it!
Soraya lies in your bed, right?
Why are you doing this?
This is wrong.
God sees.
Hashem, tell us what Soraya sleeps in your bed.
Okay.
I do not know what she was doing.
May be. When I was not at home.
May be?
One day I came home,
and she lay down to take a nap.
She had a headache.
She spoke the word, is not it?
Words that used to say to me.
Words that should be heard only her husband.
You see what I'm saying?
My God, my God.
Lord, forgive me.
My wife - whore!
Bitch!
You're a whore.
How Come?
She dishonored me!
Help me.
She has disgraced me!
In my own home!
Ali, leave it!
It's none of your business!
She's my wife!
This shameless behavior!
She is not worthy of your protection!
Slut cheated on me!
Are not you ashamed to gather here?
She was with another man.
- With whom?
- She slept with Hashem!
She knows.
This is true.
Calm down.
Quietly.
Come to my house.
Ali, only you, me and Soraya.
Bit, bring Ebrahim.
We will solve this like civilized people.
Come on.
The old woman! You do not do this show!
This is between me and my wife.
So you beat her in public?
In my house. Come on, time is so important.
See how it changed me?
My wife is a traitor!
We can not leave this crime unpunished.
It should pay for it!
You ok?
Run!
See you again in the spotlight.
What is it this time?
She was unfaithful to me.
With Hashem.
I suspected it. Now I know.
I caught them.
Soraya, is that true? You changed it?
No, not really.
Why do you lie?
Everyone knows.
You go to Hashem every day
to sleep with him.
He is lying.
I'm married. I never thought about this.
You say you changed it.
Then how?
They stood close, whispering.
I saw they touched each other's hands.
The next day ...
Again they were whispering.
And smiled.
This is true?
I told Hashem that wash house ...
then come back to cook dinner.
We smiled at each other.
Hashem here. Now we know the truth.
Talk to your employer - not a crime.
To speak with a man - not a crime.
Smile? Smile is not illegal.
Hashem, when you and Soraya whispering ...
what are you talking about?
We do not whispering!
She was going to wash some clothes ...
then come back to cook dinner.
then lie down for a nap.
I never said.
I do not have time to lie down.
I have too much work.
Hashem, listen to me carefully.
I want a straight answer.
Yes or no. Got It?
Lee says Soraya
that would like to relax in your house?
Yes, I say.
How was it. She kept me at home.
She lies down in my bed.
Says these words, which are only for the ears of her husband.
This is a lie.
I never stayed for a single extra minute.
And the door is always open. I Swear!
Why are you doing this?
Why are you talking about?
I loved your wife.
I took care of your son.
These men asked me to work for you.
I have not done anything wrong.
Hashem, a man accuses his wife of infidelity ...
can cause rage all over the city.
Such crimes are not lenient.
You have to be sure.
He speaks the truth.
I'm telling you the truth.
Ali himself - I told him ...
and Mullah Hassan
so the entire city ...
even gossips know.
Nothing they do not know. They just repeat what
they hear.
That does not make it true.
I saw them whispering. They were holding hands.
No! I smiled. I'm all smiles.
As the village idiot.
All I know. I am honest.
They say you're pregnant.
What? Pregnant?
Wait 9 months and you will see that all
I am not pregnant.
Soraya, two men accused you ...
... of misconduct,
unworthy wife and mother.
Can you prove your innocence?
To prove?
How do I prove my innocence?
They accuse me.
They have to prove it.
When a man accuses his wife ...
she must prove his innocence.
It's the law.
On the other hand ...
if a woman accuses her husband,
she must prove his guilt.
Do you understand?
Of course, it's obvious.
All women are guilty,
and all the men are innocent.
Right?
Hold your tongue.
Enough!
Bastard.
We've known each other all their lives.
You can not lie to me.
It's a conspiracy.
This is because of the girls, whom he wants to marry.
No, it's a crime.
Serious crime.
Crime against her husband ...
... father of two sons ...
the whole village.
And all of Islam.
That's what we are here, woman.
Now let me begin my duties.
What's wrong?
Ebrahim sent us to stay with you.
He gathers men for discussion.
Who is with him?
Of course, Ali and his friends ...
Both your son, Soraya ...
and Morteza Ramazani.
My own father.
He would agree with everything that they decide.
All men do so.
Did they ever intercedes for us?
At my age the only penalty
for an offense against morality
were fines or work on the community.
Here another.
You need to relax.
I'll be back soon.
Why are you wearing a black veil?
I'm sorry. I'm nothing like that meant.
I know what you're thinking.
She was found guilty.
Guilty.
She is guilty.
Zahra!
Yes I Do!
Salam, Zahra ...
This is from Mullah Hassan.
He asks for your signature.
He wants my signature?
Yes I Am.
Come quickly!
What did they decide?
- There is no time.
- Tell me.
We have to leave.
Where?
We have no car, no money.
They're going to score you stones in an hour.
Do you understand?
Hurry!
Sister!
Sister, stop!
Go on, do not stop.
Stop! Where are you?
Leave us alone. We're leaving here.
You do not go anywhere.
So he still did it.
He got rid of me.
I want you to always wear it.
Do not lose, my dear.
Understand?
And this is - you, my dear Kataneh.
It belonged to my mother ...
and to her - her mother.
Someday you will give him his eldest daughter.
Come here.
I am afraid that my daughters will be as follows.
Protect them, aunt.
Only now they have value.
Do not worry.
When they are older, tell them about me.
And they will not be ashamed of his mother.
Soraya, I will tell them the truth.
I tell her everything.
I will tell it to the world.
Dear God, help me.
If what we are doing, according to the will of your ...
then give me the strength to continue.
Help me to do the right thing.
But if it is against your will ...
then give me a sign ...
so I can stop it.
Are you afraid?
Not death.
But to die ...
stones ...
it hurts.
Mom.
Mom, why did you have to die?
In spite of this, son.
Do not have anything to do with.
You did something with Hashem?
I did not do anything.
Your father wants to get rid of me.
Behave like a man, a fool.
My dear Reza ...
Sit down.
Cry all you want.
They are here.
Get Up.
Bastard! I got something for you!
And even more. Who else wants?
Show respect, please
a bit of decency, for God's sake.
Soraya Manutchehri ...
after numerous discussions
we passed sentence.
Unanimously.
Sentence - death.
Death! Death! Death!
Justice decided to ...
that today, in Kupayehe, you'll executed.
This woman ...
defiled our village.
She has to pay for his sins.
With each stone that you throw,
Your Honor returns.
Greetings to all-all-all!
Good afternoon, dear!
We heard that in your village market day ...
come and entertain you after heavy day's work.
Come one, come all,
including children.
Do not you see that we are doing?
Stand back and not interfere.
After your prayers.
We'll be around here ...
Come see our show.
Take a felon, and follow me.
The time is now.
Take off her veil.
I will not cry.
And do not you cry.
Pray hard.
God and heaven are waiting for you.
Pray and for us too.
Waste.
Soraya Manutchehri, if you have something to say ...
now is the time.
This is your last chance.
How can you do it?
If you do not know me.
I Soraya.
I was in your homes.
I share your meal. We were friends.
How can you do this to me?
I am your neighbor ...
your mother ...
your daughter ...
your wife ...
How can you do this to anyone else?
This is the law of God.
God is great!
God is the greatest!
Close the ears, girls. Tightly. Like me.
Enough. Stand aside.
Morteza want to say something?
What can I say?
It is no longer my daughter.
I'm not her father.
Let us bring home this to the end and be done with it!
No! Do not do it!
Get away from there, woman!
Stoned me! Instead it -
her young children.
I'll take her place.
Please Ebrahim, stoned me!
Get away, Zahra. You have nothing to do with it.
Please Ebrahim, I beg you.
I'll do anything.
You do not do anything.
Give me more!
God help me ...
kill the whore.
Ebrahim!
It's a sign. Stones do not hit ...
because God knows that she is innocent.
Do something!
Everything is fine, old man,
I'll take care of.
The bastards!
Murderers!
Come on, guys. For God.
Get to it!
Throw it in!
More bitch alive!
All take the stones!
That's all.
Ebrahim, surely God Almighty forgive
you for what you did today.
Is There.
They did not allow us to bury her.
We took her body and carried it to the river.
In the city they celebrated.
It happened yesterday.
This morning, before dawn ...
I returned to the river ...
and buried what was left of her dog.
Ah, there you are.
Your car is ready.
Thank U.
What happened?
It'S Nothing. He goes to pick up his car.
We can not let him go so easily.
He committed no crime!
He is a journalist and writer.
Such things must remain within our borders.
We need to know that Zahra told him.
Be prepared.
What happened?
Are not you going to marry?
Marriage will not. Her father was executed.
And I like it.
Then why all this happened?
For nothing!
You made me lie.
You beat her with stones on the area for anything!
What are you saying?
They scare me.
They said that my son will be an orphan.
All this was a lie.
Leave me alone.
Do not look at me like that.
You, too, was involved.
That's not true!
You lied to me!
What a lie! You are the head of the village!
You led the proceedings.
We can not let him leave.
I hope Zahra not rob you of time?
Not at all.
She is mistress to tell.
Such imagination. Why, Ebrahim?
Yes I Am.
Sometimes it is difficult to determine who is lying,
and who is telling the truth.
I'll leave it to you, gentlemen.
Why the rush?
What do you have in the bag?
Excuse me ...
I have to pay my bill.
You have already paid.
I can not let you leave.
What do you mean?
You wrote it?
This is my property.
There is no private property.
And we do not allow foreigners to interfere with us.
I am not a foreigner.
How dare you?
I probably will in the near future a government agency.
Do what you want.
Grab it!
- Now Ride.
- And you?
I'll take care of her daughter. Do not worry,
they will do nothing.
Not so hard, my friend.
Get away!
Ebrahim, what are you afraid?
Justice has been done, is not it?
God, whom I love, great.
Is our village ...
was not going to be an example for the whole country?
Now the whole world knows.
Yes I Do! The whole world knows what happened here.
Yes I Do!
The world will know!
When the Franco-Iranian journalist Freydona Saebdzham
published "The Stoning of Soraya M."
the book became an international bestseller and drew
attention to the practice of stoning in Iran,
as well as there are no rights for women.
Despite the denial of the authorities of this fact,
countless people, mostly - female
continue to sentence to death by stoning
in many countries around the world.
It is the only surviving photo
this Soraya Manutchehri,
did when she was 9 years old.