Downloaded From www.subscene.com
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Ringo...
They're looking for you. It's
the end of the world for you.
What's that sound?
Thats the sound of the
Gion Shoja temple bells.
What?
You know, them
Heike and Genji boys?
On a distant island, these two clans
split into the Reds and the Whites.
To wage a war...
Sorta like that a "War of the
Roses," you know? In England...
Who won?
The Whites?
This high noon battle,
was waged in Dannoura.
Near the Heike Clan and Red...
Got themselves hog-tied by
the Genji Clan and White...
Their story, it goes a
little something like this...
The sound of the Gion
Shoja temple bells,
echoes the impermanence
of all things.
What bells you say?
The color of the sala flowers reveals
the truth that, "to flourish is to fall. "
You okay fella?
The proud do not endure,
like a passing dream.
On a night in Spring.
The mighty fall at last...
See you in hell!
To be no more than
dust before the wind.
Ringo! That's why I love you!
Presented by
komag
Hey! Nothing back there!
You ain't heard me?
It's a nothing town!
Bet you came for the gold too!
Well, there ain't none!
Which are you? White or Red?
You Genji or Heike?
Which of you is gonna buy it?
My reward's one third...
If there is no
treasure, no pay!
Benkei! Show him...
No doubt about who is
going to be left standing.
But best not get any ideas
about playing Yojimbo!
You gotta be alive to
defend your money...
Stranger!
Kid's got a heart,
and balls to match.
No! Join us!
We'll do better than a
third! We'll give you half!
Half?
We'll give you everything.
But with us, its a
lifetime contract.
Don't know about that, I don't
stay long... in one place.
Suits us fine!
We'll give you half
for this one time deal!
How 'bout it?!
Not too shabby.
Hey! Boy!
Hey hey...
If you're such a quickdraw,
you don't need them!
Take it all, and tell them to
shove their lifetime contract.
Stay out of it! You old bitty!
Us grannies can't
help but meddle!
Boy, don't rush yourself!
Make your choice after
cooling your heels.
This town can't offer you food,
but I can offer you some Soba.
At my place...
Come with me!
Hey hey hey hey!
Hey!
Follow him!
Bah! Forget that!
Bring him here...
I'll teach her good.
So the Reds rolled
in first, eh?
Yeah, how'd you figure that?
Simple, the Sheriff.
They say the law hitched
with the weakest side.
Must mean, they made him
an offer he couldn't refuse.
Of course not.
Maybe he's looking for
a chance to switch sides.
How long's it been like this?
Two months, since
the Heikes rolled in.
And before that, gold
prospectors started coming around.
(Idiotically) What're
you doing here?!
(Idiotically)
What?! What the hell?
But what they couldn't
figure out was,
why so many
people and why now?
At the end of last month,
a town with the same legend!
From the motherload,
the country's gone crazy!
Those Heike gold terrorizers!
Every nook and cranny of every
town with the same treasure legend,
is swarming with prospectors!
Its genuine gold rush!
You can't touch this
land, you'll be cursed.
Ha! We'll take that
curse off your hands!
No!
You see?! We're raised hearing
the legends all our lives!
And we can't fight which is why,
as you lay waste to our land!
In the beginning, we
expected them to be a Godsend.
Because they were
Heike, like us.
But so soon they started.
The Heikes ran off the
prospectors and started digging!
Look!
Kiyomori!
Boss Kiyomori! We found this!
Instead of that wood marker
that read, "Fear the Curse!"
I knew it!
So they figured the
treasure must be somewhere,
and the Heike have
been here since.
From today, you're one of us.
Think of it as
being on vacation.
Yes, I've been meaning
to take some time off.
Get a little sun myself.
Akira!
Stop, stop! Don't
do anything stupid!
Daddy, I'm scared!
Stop!
Heihachi, son...
Men need courage
and resolution.
I'm scared daddy!
Let's go home!
Let's go... let's go!
They ransacked the resting
place of our ancestors.
I go and get help.
Daddy!
...daddy!
Boss Kiyomori.
But his reign of
power didn't last long.
Dang, you boys are a day
late and a dollar short!
This is our town!
Dang!
Genji's...
Shigemori, you got too
fat when you were a boy.
Huh?
Boss Yoshitsune
The Genji's didn't make a
move against the Heike's.
They left the gold
digging to them.
Sat back and waited for their
chance to steal the wheat.
Finders, keepers.
After that, people
began to leave.
Just a few families are left.
On the way here, I
met a guy leaving town.
He said there wasn't any gold.
Ah, we might as well hire you.
But all the town can
offer you is this.
Something.
Hey, try this.
Hey, hey! Welcome back!
This is my grandson, Heihachi.
So, you boys got it yet?
Give it a go.
Death, isn't to be feared.
Don't watch the blade!
How many times do
I have to tell you?
Don't follow the blade with
your eyes! Don't see it!
Feel it!
Thats the essence
of Mononofu training.
Mononofu training
ain't somewhat ancient.
Being a Samurai is a
philosophical way of life.
But the life of Mononofu
means a life of fighting!
If you ask me, Samurai are
still wearing their skippies?
They're vein, they're still
concerned about their looks.
That's tits on the
pool thinking! ^_^
But if you peel away that last
layer. So you... are naked.
This and a real
fighting spirit is,
Warriors luck in life.
This realm...
Our realm!
Is deeper than the Samurai's.
Now...
You will come at
me, or whistle dixie.
Why...?
Why were we born in
this spineless age!
What's it gonna be?
Take this handsome
man to the Reds,
or hand him over
to the Whites.
You know?
I must say...
I don't know.
Depends on him.
Today's special is the Whites, with
a side of mashed potatoes and soup!
Forget about the Heike gang!
They're boss Kiyomori smells
like a dead dog on a hot day!
He's lost so much
he's getting dumber.
Goddamnit! Sheriff's late.
The sound, of the...
Gion Shoja temple bells.
Echoes the impermanence
of all things.
You follow?
Yes, I... uh...
It means, everything in
this old world changes.
It means we can never
call ourselves out.
We'll finally restore the glory of
our family name, and then ride in high.
The Genji gang will
be left in ruins.
The color of the sala
flowers reveals the truth,
that to flourish is to fall.
Thats it.
Its a law of nature, the
Genji's are going down!
From today...
I read this.
What's that?
Shakespeare... Henry the VI.
The War of the Roses.
War of the... Roses?
Camel boy, don't you
know your Shakespeare?
Its a story about the
Reds winning the war.
The Reds... win?
Yes, we'll win!
Yea! Kiyomori!
What?!
Kiyomori...
Don't ever call
me Kiyomori again!
From today...
The name's... Henry.
Mwahaha!
Hey quit that shit!
Okay, you got it!
From today you
are Henry!... Boss.
Henry! Henry!
Now?
Side with the Genji's!
They got a lady, a young
fine ass cream gravy!
That lady used to be a dancer!
She's the kid's mama,
but still mighty fine.
Hasn't aged a bit.
A woman of true Genji lineage.
He's Genji and Heike?
Huh?
Oh... the kid?
Yeah, he's a half-breed.
And his father?
Got himself killed.
You of the same stock... boy?
F- F-F...
Fine, fine!
Nani?!
He can't talk no more.
How do you, after
seeing your dad murdered.
What's his mother
doing on the Genji side?
To begin with, that granny's
boy went to work in the city.
Then one day that
boy, her son Akira.
Brought a Genji woman home.
Mama, the days of being Genji
or Heike... are done with.
I don't know how or
where the two met.
But his mother
blessed their marriage.
So Red and White got hitched.
And they figured crossing roses,
literally with both colors... was romantic.
And they raised Heihachi.
Their Red and White treasure.
But then the fighting
started again.
Finders keepers...
Kiyomori!
Get out!
There ain't no gold here!
That's it?
Take it all!
If you want it? Take it!
And get out!
Daddy!
Heihachi!
Red rose...
My favorite color
looks good on you.
Folks say a Genji
woman painted Red,
was a flaming hymn.
I teach you well!
I show you!
A good time!
I know! I know!
So she ran to the hideout
of her own flesh and blood.
Was it to protect her son, or
get vengeance for her husband?
You too, Sheriff.
Sure! Don't mind if I do.
How much for the lady?
Say what?!
How much you got?
Depends on how much
you're payin' me.
Keep it in your
pants, little liver.
The tougher man gets the girl.
Do what you like.
Do it here, or upstairs.
Wherever and
however you please.
You're the second calling wolf I
ever really wanted to draw iron at.
Who was the first?
A legend...
One I heard, when I was a kid.
Oh yeah?
The bloody...
Benten...
Bloody Benten
The Fighting
Goddess... legend.
Shit!
Now I really want
to draw iron at you!
Nice... huh?
Ain't fine, but it
hits you deep down.
The Anasazi play that music.
They were here
before any of us.
They still keep, the old ways.
You'll do fine.
I want Kiyomori dead.
You've sold away your
body... everything.
All for revenge.
So what?!
Don't pity me, I don't need
useless compassion from you.
Good, I just mumbled
something you don't understand.
Do you want me?
Yes.
I want you... very much.
But be careful, Yoshitsune's men
left town to get that powerful weapon.
Yoichi wants you dead.
They'll likely
be here by sun up.
When the shooting starts,
take Heihachi and
escape to the mountains.
You're not gonna run?
Oh, you got something
against them too?
I got my reasons.
Have the roses bloomed yet?
What are they named?
Love.
They're cold.
Here in my scabbard,
meditating that.
[They are reciting lines from
Henry VI; Act 2, Scene IV]
Shall dye your white
roses in a bloody red.
Here...
Meantime, your
cheeks do... count-
Counterfeit our roses, for
pale they look with fear...
as witnessing the
truth on our side.
No, Plantagenet, not
for fear but anger
that thy cheeks
blush for pure shame
to counterfeit
our roses. And yet!
Thy tongue will not
confess thy error.
That Sheriff's late!
Bring him here you idiot!
Somethings you
gotta see through.
What're you gonna do now?
I bet Kiyomori is going nuts.
Maybe he hasn't figured
out he's been betrayed yet.
He may be dense,
but he ain't stupid.
No, no no no... He
hasn't got a clue.
As long as we...
So you want go
back to their side?
Too late for that.
You said it!
So what do we do now?!
Don't get impatient.
He ain't going
nowhere for awhile.
You reckon?
You just watch.
At least, as long as we
stay here, we're safe.
We got time.
Why don't you take a dump?
And have a think?
Howdy Sheriff...
A special weapon
will be here soon.
Can't let the Genji's get it.
Tell the Heike to
obstruct their wagons,
if you don't we'll
all be killed.
Sorry...
What are you doing boy?!
Shit, well get off your butt!
Hold your horses.
Instead of telling
the god awful truth,
don't you reckon we'd
better high tail it?
I ain't listening
to you no more!
Kiyomori!
Boss Kiyomori!
Name's Henry!
Where have you been?!
I was spying on the Genji's.
And things are getting
really out of hand.
Excuse me...
Come again?
Stupid cow!
I told you we should've
skipped town...
I told you.
Shit!
Go!
Fear nothing!
Watch it!
Thats dangerous!
Shigemori!
What?!
You did this!
Fire boys, he's
climbing out the window!
How'd he pull that off?
Come!
Ichiro, Matsui!
Follow me.
What happened?
I'll tell you later, we're
going to the old man's place!
Heihachi! Come on hurry!
This way!
Watch your step.
Take Heihachi
and go without me!
What did you forget?!
Something important!
What... who?!
Forget them you
don't need them!
No! They're...!
They're...
They're... my... ours!
No matter what, one
of you's gonna die!
Heihachi!
Please, please, please!
If you want them to live...
Drop... your... guns!
No more!
Quit your bitchin'!
The time is now!
Hey, hey!
Die!
Lucky me...
Henry!
Shigemori... I won't
die until we win.
Payback's a bitch!
A she's the shit!
Before you die...
I have something
sweet to show you!
You want some bitch?
You animal...
Toshio! Throw it here!
Can't be...
Bloody... B-
Heihachi!
What are you doing?
Open your eyes!
See for yourself!
You can't close them!
Open your eyes!
Heihachi!
Heihachi! Open your eyes!
What were you
doing acting alone?!
You got balls, but no brain!
Ruriko, why did you
hide this from me?
I thought we were friends.
Sorry but...
Could you visit this address?
And stock up on these.
If he is still alive.
My signature here,
should help you out.
I wish I could go, but I
can't leave the boy alone.
Ruriko...
But these are guns?
Tell him, I need
help and he owes me.
You are the only
one I can depend on.
So she's still kickin' eh?
What's BB?
When this devily talented
goddess, used to played music...
she would hold her
instruments in both hands.
But when she was
on the warpath,
she held her weapons
in eight hands.
When the fire of her
vengeance twittled in her eyes
this smothering
goddess was wide awake
and everything in her
way got stained blood red.
The Bloody Benten
Nickname...
double B for short.
I was the one who
educated her in killing.
And it was tough going.
You like it?
Too sweet.
There's too much sugar.
This is Sukiyaki
not a damn pot!
I- I-I'm
so sorry!
How many times do
I gotta tell you,
before it sinks into that
thick skull of yours...
That you draw the sweetness
out of the Chinese cabbage.
And this Tofu...
its not authentic!
B
- But the Tofu was sold out!
Excuses!
Go on!
Darn excuses!
Dang useless woman, why I ever thought
I could make a gun fighter out of-
Listen up girl.
If this were a gun fight.
You wouldn't be sayin you got bullets
that shoot beans instead, now could ya?
That'd mean dud to me
and you wouldn't it?
Hmm? Wouldn't it?
That's my girl, there you go.
Never let your guard down.
The Grim Reaper hisself grows
in that pot, don't forget that.
I
- I...
The sugar!
Sugar helps me.
Lordy lord...
You ain't pregnant is you?
I reckon it will
be a bouncing boy.
*Sigh*
Aw heck!
You mean Akira?
Akira, how the lovely sound
of that name brings me back.
What can I say.
At the end, I am an
enemy of the cold dagger.
What?
How's my boy?
I saw...
That's why you've
come for them irons eh?
You tell her this for me.
"Sayonara dake ga jin sei da"
Life is all about goodbyes.
We are in your debt!
I'm surprised.
He's still alive.
I guess.
Every man's got
his own reasons.
For why he had
to keep on living.
Got a cold?
Don't you have one too?!
Amazing...
You are some freak of nature.
The old man's
medicine did the trick.
Thank ya.
You going, huh?
Yeah.
Going... where to?
To settle a score.
What score?
The town's got
nothing to do with you!
Shit just happens, thats all.
So the meaning of rivalry
is shit happens, heh?
Well I don't wanna run
from... "The Shit" anymore.
Shit...
If you don't take the cake, sorry but
could you fetch the treasure for me?
There is one?
Ruriko... what
about the town law?
As anyone who has been
getting around here knows,
he was chosen to guard it.
That's the town law.
I thought Heihahi would
be the next chosen one.
But he is too weak.
I reckon he was born
at the wrong time,
and in the wrong place.
He does have a gift
for music though.
But tenderness alone
won't get you far in life.
What're you going to
do with the treasure?
Settle this, once and for all!
If we lose, they can have it.
If we win, you can have
half... how about it? You game?
Suits me fine.
Okay then.
This way!
No! This way!
I ain't gonna listen
to you no more!
That's my line! I kill you!
Smells like victory.
Got the Mr. Gatling
riding shotgun.
And now a shield.
A shield?
If you won't fight,
it would be perfect.
Mwahaha!
Hey hey! Hold on!
Come on now!
Hey! No!
Shit!
If I get taken down... will
you get this to Heihachi for me?
I'll think about it.
If and when you die.
Hey! Hey!
I'll carry the
treasure for you.
I carried the gun, and
if the end carries you!
Then let me do it!
If you weren't the most
stubborn man I ever did meet.
Let him take it.
A man's gotta do
what a man's gotta do.
Go, go!
We get shot, and you are the one
thats gonna get smoked. Not me!
You die first!
No! You die first!
We die!
Ok we die, we die... I die, you
die, he dies, she dies, we die!
Everybody dies!
It takes truly something
for people to finally learn.
The way to your loyal
heart, with love.
Yoshitsune...
I'll make you...
Notice me.
Here is...!
The treasure!
How about it boys?!
Winner takes all!
Hey look!
Gold!
Spread out!
Yoshitsune!
B
- Benkei?
So re!
Yoshitsune!
I think I sprained my ankle!
Where're those Heike boys?!
Here we go!
Yeah!
No!
Get down!
You've got a new toy?
Yoshitsune!
This time, we win!
This time...
That's for the mayor.
I win...
I win!
I ain't dead.
'Til I beat you.
This is for Akira.
Its all mine!
Its mine!
Its all ours!
I... always...
Don't say it...
No one in the world
ever saved Benten's life.
Except for you.
You...
You're Ruriko.
My... Ruriko.
Now this...
Is what I call class.
So that old granny,
was Bloody Benten.. eh?
I'm glad I came here.
Hell, I'm glad I was born.
Finally, with a
worthy opponent.
I can risk my
life to the death.
Victory...
...or death!
That's plenty for me.
You keep the rest.
Just do me one thing.
Tend to the roses for me.
But when it doesn't
feel right, you can stop.
Now you've got money, you got
the gun, and the roses too.
Heihachi...
Son, no matter what
the times may be.
No matter where you are.
What matters is you, and
how you deal with this world.
And there ain't
no running from it.
Don't run.
Decide for yourself
what tomorrow's gonna be.
Love.
Your mother was a
mighty fine lady.
www.subscene.com
Downloaded From www.subscene.com
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org