Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Elaine!
You're never gonna sleep again.
That's the point.
Right.
Let me know if you
want to switch seats.
We're close.
No, this should'a been all ours...
Fucking Feds come in here,
we don't even make the local news.
I'm jacked! Three surviving witnesses...
Feds...
I'm fucking jacked!
Wow... handsome... looking good.
Coffee's on.
No, no, no... this is
for the little one...
Hot chocolate.
Here's where we come in?
Easy now. Both of you...
And a little girl, she's 8 or 9...
and I guess she's not saying
much right now.
They're guessing.
With kids, it's different.
I'll be fine by it.
How about you?
She's gonna be a mess.
We don't know what she saw.
Fuck, Anderson!
We know.
Listen...
They call 'em witnesses
because they've seen things.
So we go in, find out.
- You good?
- I'm good.
You real good...
You know it.
Let's do it.
- Billings...
- Agent Hallaway.
And this is Officer Degrasso...
Officer Wright.
Agent Anderson.
Up-to-date witness files,
they all describe the same thing.
Hasn't gotten us much of anywhere.
We're pretty sure we know
what were dealing with here.
And they all arrived together,
late yesterday?
Yeah, that's the way it happened.
One of our Officers brought them in...
he's in there too,
he's also a witness.
I understand one of your
officers was killed?
Yeah. Jim. Jim Conrad.
Now, the young woman she seems to
be intoxicated or in shock; the child...
The 'young woman' is high
as a fucking kite.
As I was saying...
The child hasn't said much of anything.
However, she has bonded with
the young woman...
Bobbi... Bobbi Prescott.
And is this all she said?
Yeah, only what we took notes on.
The things that have happened to her,
you can't blame her.
And you have no female officers
here, is that right?
Have two of you always
been present?
Well I was there...
Hi, I'm Janet.
Welcome, I could,
can I get coffee for any...
That little girl's name's Stephanie...
'cause Officer Bennett told me
that her name was Stephanie.
We'll need to separate them
for the interviews.
They really should have been
kept apart during the night.
I trust my Officer.
I never said I didn't.
You know, I'm sure that proper
procedures were followed, Hallaway.
It's interesting that you're the one
that brought up the trust thing.
Great. Sam? I'm gonna take
a minute with the little girl, Sam.
Take a few minutes.
So, we brought equipment with us,
while I'm in talking with her...
you guys set it up...
rooms... cameras.
Everybody work together,
we're gonna get going faster.
Right in here? Do, do you think
if I brought in some coffee...
Why don't you ask him?
Stephanie, my name is Elizabeth...
and we're gonna try and talk
about what happened, okay?
And it's gonna help you feel better.
- You F.B.I.?
- Yeah... yeah...
You gonna bust me?
For now, no. No.
The only role is in how it affected
your perception of the events.
I know what I saw.
So whatcha got there, Stephanie?
A video game?
You like playing games?
So...
There's a pair of pants under
that skirt, huh?
You know the equipment
she was talking about?
- It's in the trunk of my car.
- I'm on it!
Actually it's quite a bit of equipment,
Captain, so... maybe...
Degrasso. Give Wright a hand.
C'mon now.
Agent,
can I ask you a question?
It's just procedure.
I like to separate'em, put'em on tape.
I know one of your officers
is in there, but...
there's only one way to unfold
a note, so to speak...
without tearing the paper.
Yeah that's what I figured.
So let's look and see what we're...
Well that's not what I wanted
to ask you.
You got a cigarette?
No, sorry.
Stephanie?
We're gonna talk, right?
- I want to go home.
- I know you do, Stephanie.
I know.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Janet! Could you get us
a light in here?
It is fucking dark in here.
There's no light!
- Right... Yeah, these were...
- These shouldn't be here, take'em down.
Yeah. You guys give me
a hand when you're done?
Do you have some crayons in your bag?
They were in the car.
I have some crayons in the office.
Oh, great.
Could you get those, Janet?
Yeah. And some paper...
and I think I'm gonna bring
back some more marshmallows, okay?
Stephanie? So while we're talking you
could do some drawing for me, yeah?
- I gotta go to the bathroom.
- Okay. In a minute.
That agent lady, you know,
she wants these for the little girl.
Crayons?
Those F.B.I. Agents think of things
no beat cop ever would.
What is the matter?
What, are you two years old?
So you know, right?
I'm sorry?
These two...
fucking... masked fuckers...
Officer?
I know you've been through
a really rough time...
but let's work towards making this
a safe space.
I'm gonna ask you to watch
your language.
I really have
to use the bathroom...
Okay, Bobbi, you can go.
Go on.
Hi.
Use the toilet.
So how we doing?
We're all just fucking swell Mr. F.B.I.
Officer Bennett?
Agent Hallaway.
I gather you two...
swooped into town all suited
up to finish what I started?
I see the tensions between our
departments are alive and well.
My partner and I, we have many months
invested in this case...
My partner invested his life
in this case.
His and your involvement in
these incidents will not go...
uncredited.
The hand... how are you doing?
Like I said...
'we're all just fucking swell'.
Next time
you need to pee...
someone goes with you.
- I'm a witness, not a suspect.
- I know what you are.
And I also know how to pervert
a cavity search.
Wow, I haven't done a girl
since art school.
It's just like riding a bike.
Yes, Ma'am.
Okay, girls, we'll do the interviews
separately, so...
Janet and the officers
will show you where to go.
Jack...
Sam... Go easy.
- Easy?
- Yeah. Remember why we're here.
I remember
why we're here... Agent.
I'm good.
Real good.
Janet worked the mushroom lamp
for the ambience.
Really livens the place up, doesn't it?
It's alright, sweetheart.
It's just a camera.
FBI man...
Can we please have Officer Bennett
take his seat at the table, please?
C'mon Jack.
Take a seat in the chair.
Everyone? We're gonna
be starting with yesterday morning.
Jim and I...
were having coffee...
Richard Ramirez.
Jeff 'Hungry-Man' Dahmer...
- Oh. Died in prison!
- Amen, buddy.
Yeah. That'll teach you to sweep.
John Wayne Gacy.
Fucking Manson Family.
- We'll get ours...
- Yeah...
I'm still kinda drunk.
I do so love the ladies.
We pulled the driver over...
He said he'd been
delivering groceries on Camrose...
Said he'd seen something.
Something terrible.
Wasn't like you'd think.
So Johnny and I drove all this
way to see this guy about a job...
What's up, "Bucket"?
Mister Horns?
- What's going on?
- Hey. Have a seat.
- Who's your friend?
- This is Bobbi.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Yeah, I am...
Speaking of...
can I get the usual?
And... we had our interview.
You want a drink?
Got some leftovers in the refrigerator.
God no, we've actually, we gotta
get going. So...
we'll see you later.
Just a sec.
Bucket... you alright?
Raise your hands above your head...
not you.
Jesus Christ...
Bucket!
Oh shit.
The interview
ended pretty abruptly.
Whatever doesn't fit
in your pockets, goes in my purse.
Got it.
Shit. Get the lighter. Lighter.
Get the pipes.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Well, I'll talk to you soon.
C'mon.
See you!
We were pretty sure
we didn't get the job.
Wait, wait, wait...
You mean he didn't just
hire you on the spot?
Oh. No. We weren't
interviewing to be cops.
Alright, alright. Let's go on.
That's it. We left.
He took four days off of work,
plus a weekend...
so we could have a vacation.
- Everybody doing okay?
- Yep.
I think you wear this 'father'
thing pretty well.
- Well with these kids, it's easy.
- Thank you.
My mother kept saying over and over
what a nice thing it was for him to do.
It's good for people
to get away sometimes.
I guess. But I liked
where I was to begin with.
Look what I drew.
Oh! Look at that! Oh, honey.
- You are so talented.
- Thank you.
It's great... the ants.
- No, honey, they're bears.
- The bears.
- Beavers.
- The beavers.
Officer Bennett?
Yeah.
Yeah. You and your partner were first
on the scene, am I correct about that?
That's correct. Right after
the grocery delivery man.
If you could continue, Officer Bennett?
Keep going.
The guys from 'Crime-Scene' showed
and we left.
What are you thinking?
She's good-looking.
He used to be, too.
So we're driving along...
Good girl!
Yes!
That is some good shit.
- Ok, ok, c'mon!
- Shit! Sorry, I forgot who's driving!
Who am I?
Ok.
Let's see...
we stopped.
To stretch.
That's good. Stretching.
It's good.
And that's when we first
saw the little girl, Stephanie.
Stop! Seriously!
God Damn it, stop!
Why, do you have to pee?
Don't act like an asshole.
There's a family.
Hey, it's the elephant
at the rest stop nobody talks about.
Oh, ok, 'Bill W.'
Oh. Hello.
Where a grisly discovery
was made.
Police feel certain that
this is the work of the two suspects...
who have left a series of victims
across the country.
A press conference is scheduled
for later this afternoon...
after further examination
of the scene...
and the body discovered inside.
Police urge all citizens of the area
to keep their doors locked...
and to immediately report any activities
that appear out of the normal...
as well as any sightings of the missing
woman, Elaine Meyer, pictured here.
I'm not allowed to watch
the news at home.
Some things children
shouldn't see.
That's what my Mom says...
I mean...
Said.
I'm so sorry, Stephanie.
That poor little girl.
Children can be very resilient.
I think it's a shame making
her re-live all those things...
No, I mean, I know, of course
you're just doing your job, I know that...
it's just, you have to do this, right?
I have to know what they've seen.
Every detail, right?
Oh yeah... Every detail.
Oh God, I just...
You need the information
and speaking of...
It's the Coroner's report.
I'm 'friends' with the Coroner.
Yeah.
Well... thank you.
You're welcome.
No lab results?
No, no, he's rushing those...
but he said it's just going to take
him a long time to collect it all.
Did he say what he's collecting?
I mean, did he mention...
ballistics?
No. But you know he is big on hair
and fibers.
It's kind of his specialty.
Apparently they left a lot of that.
You know what I'm wondering?
Why would they be so sloppy?
- They're likely to improve.
- Of course. Yeah.
Unless, Ma'am...
They just don't give a shit.
Oh my God... what we do to each
other, huh?
What are you two doing in here?
The uh, the girl, Bobbi?
She had to piss.
Why don't you go and make
sure she gets back in the room?
- Go on now...
- Okay!
And why don't you go keep an eye on him.
Alright. Then?
We have areas we patrol.
Nice shot!
Look at him!
Alright.
Pick your fucking personality.
I get to pick?
I am clearly 'Good Cop.'
Thank you very much.
Friend to the people!
'Good Cop'!
We patrolled them.
I look forward
to working with you
Hello Officer, looks like
I had a tire blow...
That's what it looks like, huh?
I got a solid spare, so...
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you
to get back in the vehicle for the moment.
Is there a problem, Officer?
- Well, Sir...
- Keith.
Oh. Keith. Okay.
Hi.
There's no problem with me,
but you see my partner back there?
Yes Sir.
He looks upset.
Yeah. Well...
We got a couple of killers loose...
everyone's wound up pretty good about
it but Jack there...
he's wound especially tight.
We heard something about
that on the radio...
Oh no, it is worse than they're saying
on the radio. Trust me.
And Jack there is, like I said,
pretty wound up...
and we saw you guys coming
down the road...
and he swears that you
were pulling too much speed.
Oh, jeez, I wasn't speeding, Officer,
really I was going... not speeding...
No. No. No. Relax, Keith.
That's what I said.
You're 'preaching to the choir'.
That's what I told him.
- It was just a normal speed...
- Yeah, I know. I know. I told him.
And he didn't like it when I did.
Here he comes.
Act casual.
Get down on the fucking ground.
Get down on the fucking ground! Now!
Get down, Keith!
Whoa, whoa, whoa... Ma'am!
Please return to the vehicle.
- Keith, honey?
- Please don't shoot me!
- I'll be in the car, honey.
- Please Officers.
I'm going to ask you to get your
wallet and give it to my partner.
Keith, it's best to do what he says,
because when he gets like this...
it's just really crucial
that he feels like you're listening.
I'm listening...
Please don't shoot me, Officer!
We let him
go with a warning.
You know how people
get out here, Captain.
The way they start driving
in the desolate stretches...
like the race car drivers
they always wanted to be.
Speeding is the number one cause
of traffic fatalities, you know.
Not this week.
I'll be getting back to it now.
That's an excellent plan, Wright.
You getting coffee?
Light and sweet for me, there, Chief.
Something I can do for you, Degrasso?
Just enjoying your work.
How about you let
me enjoy some of yours?
Go on...
I think making him angry
is a really bad idea.
Oh, gee Mom...
tell Dad I'm real fucking sorry.
Hey.
An attitude change, please?
Is there any more hot chocolate?
Of course there is.
Can I keep this?
I drew it for you.
It's great.
I'll go get you that hot chocolate.
You'll be alright, on your own?
I'll be right back.
- Having fun?
- Yeah! Yeah...
This is what it's all about.
- Beautiful day.
-Yeah!
Yeah, it's perfect.
Hey...
I'll be damned...
Yeah, I thought it was pretty
amazing myself.
- She hasn't said much.
- Well, I'm working on it.
You're good with her.
Yeah. Well, I was once
a sad little girl myself.
Don't go getting emotionally involved...
that's not what this is about.
It's bringing up
a lot of stuff...
A lot of...
You can't save her...
I know.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Watch... it's kind of hot.
You like being a cop?
You like being a fuck-up?
Hey, Degrasso...
I don't like this... Lady.
Really? No?
Let's keep the pace, Officers.
Yeah. Let's... keep the pace.
You heard the Agent, Bobbi...
Chop! Chop!
So, we were just driving along...
- One for you...
- No, I don't want another one!
Do you want me to drive the car or do
you want me to go into cardiac arrest?
- Okay, one more.
- Okay.
I'm not doing another one, no way.
You do it.
You do it. You're doing it.
I'm not doing it.
I'll grab your fucking tits right now.
I swear to God I will.
Oh then I'm really not doing,
I'm done. I'm so not doing it.
Bring it on!
Promises, promises...
Oh, shit!
I'll do it...
- I love this song.
- You love every fucking song.
Mom! Mom, I saw something!
- Oh, now we're talking!
- Old school!
Mom!
Why can't I get just one kiss
Why can't I get just one Kiss
There may be something
That I wouldn't miss
But I look at your pants
And I need a kiss
Why can't I get just one screw
Watch the road!
Believe me I know what to do
But something won't let me
Make love to you
See now this is music, David.
This is rock!
This rocks, baby.
Why can't I get just one fuck
Just one duck!
Cover your ears...
- You guys are great.
- One duck!
No one heard me.
People just weren't
themselves yesterday.
Finish up, Jim.
We got one.
What do you know...
Mother Fucker is speeding.
You gonna take that?
Guess.
Unbelievable!
That's supernatural.
I'm a little hard right now,
I gotta tell you.
Neat.
- So let's try it again.
- Well this is the real thing.
We stopped to help...
Shit! Fuck!
I almost just had a heart attack.
Like this. So close.
That is close.
You should have seen Bobbi's face.
She was so scared.
I'll bet you were all scared.
Flats suck.
I don't wanna see anyone
else die today, please hon'?
No shit... God.
The lady is a fucking saint, right?
Yeah. She is.
We stopped. That's what matters.
We gave them a hand.
They were fucking stranded.
Oh God...
Where you going?
I was gonna go start the paperwork on
"Little Miss Shitty"'s Good Deed Award.
He needs a woman.
Me too.
Let's go do some bad.
It could have been a real mess,
Captain. I'm telling you.
Hello, dad.
Oh my God, his shirt says
"Mischief Sausage".
No, it does, look at it,
it says "Mischief Sausage".
- Whatever, man.
- Look at him!
- Oh my...
- Oh man...
Oh we're fucked.
- Oh my God.
- Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck...
Hand out of nose!
Finger out of nose!
Want another one?
Just keep it real.
Seriously. Don't look back.
- Want another one?
- Don't look back!
It's okay, Officer,
it's a flat. That's all.
Listen up, folks. Get back inside
your vehicle and leave the engine off.
We're going to fuck in the clink.
You know it.
You're doing great, sweetheart,
I know it's not easy.
I don't know honey...
it's probably procedural.
Officer...
Hi. Fine.
What are they doing?
Don't look back!
- I'm not!
- What are they doing?
- How would I know if I can't look back?
- Just shut up!
Fuck. Now the charge is dying.
Great.
David, watch your language.
Do I got shit up my nose?
Do I got chunks?
Do I? No, look!
- Dad?
- It's okay, honey. Just sit tight.
I saw something...
Well I see something too, Bean.
Honey pass me the insurance
and registration will you?
I'll take the Station Wagon, you take
the Duster, and then we'll switch.
Oh, dig it. Alright.
I can't fucking believe this!
Watch your language, Mom.
Alright. You really wanna
poke the bear, David?
Okay settle down!
Where the hell is he?
Oh shit!
- Hi.
- How ya doing?
- Good.
- Kinda snuck up on ya, didn't I?
- You did!
You know, you were pulling
a pretty big number.
I'm sorry, you know, I just...
I didn't even notice.
You guys were driving pretty fast.
She's pretty. But we weren't
driving fast.
Oh... come on.
I'm soft when it comes
to the speed limit.
I grew up here... pulled a few
race car moves out here myself.
We're awfully sorry, Officer.
Yeah I got that, and I understand.
See, there is one issue, though.
My partner.
You're timing's bad because my partner...
last year he lost his family
in a traffic incident like this.
He lost his wife and son
to a speeding collision. It was horrible!
He had a wife. Had a couple o' kids.
And now he goes home
and he eats a TV dinner.
And you can't imagine
the depth of grief.
No.
He wept in a fetal position
for over a year. I held him tight.
Oh, it's hysterical, isn't it?
- No. It's not.
- Yeah. Give me your fucking wallet.
My I. D?
No. I'll, I'll need your wallet.
We've moved past I.D. To wallet.
I'll need your wallet as well.
- Yeah. Okay.
- I'll be right back.
Thank you. You know what they say
about guys who drive red cars?
No.
- I'll be back in a minute, alright?
- Okay.
They don't say that about guys
who drive red cars...
Bad news.
Speeder killed your family.
- Yours, too.
- Hey, single again.
Those kids are high. You know,
you might wanna search the car.
- You smell money?
- No... just beer.
Aw fuck it, then.
Check out the Mom. She looks
like that skirt from Wood Shop.
Oh! Alright...
- Shit.
- What?
Don't worry about it.
- Here comes my party.
- Great...
Where's the fucking fire?
Fucker...
Shut up!
Oh 'hey' what?
Get your fucking ass on the ground.
Alright. Now you
be real fucking quiet...
or else I'm gonna blow
you a new shitter. You understand?
Oh fuck...
Put your hands on the wheel.
Look at him.
Tell your junkie boyfriend...
tell him you don't love him.
- I don't love you.
- Mean it.
I don't love you.
- Fucking mean it!
- I don't love you!
He drive like
this all the time?
No, no, never, I swear...
Aw, you're protecting him.
That's sweet. I get it.
- You settled, didn't ya?
- What?
I mean, you know, you get scared.
I get it.
Say...
'I hate you'.
I hate you.
Fucking mean it!
- I hate you!
- Mean it!
I hate you! Fuck...
Look the other fucking way.
Alright. C'mon. Gimme
a little sugar.
C'mon. Gimme a little bit.
It's okay.
Don't cry. It's okay.
You're gonna be alright.
Eesh... what a day!
You don't fucking move. And you get
your fucking ass outta the car, whore!
It's beautiful out here, huh?
Sometimes I come out here just to think.
You know, get my head straight.
You know, we're in this sad predicament
because you drive too fucking fast.
Right?
Now, I'm cool... but I'm fair.
So we'll let it go.
You smell good!
What is that?
Louder.
Fifty-five saves lives.
Okay calm down.
Now we're gonna do one last thing,
just so I'm the boss guy, right?
I want you to put this right
in your fucking mouth...
C'mon, open your mouth.
Fucking open up your mouth.
Open up your fucking mouth!
Do it. Do it.
Now slap me in the face.
When you get back in that car, you're
going to drive at a safe speed, right?
Okay.
I'm all about safety.
That's how I do it.
- Okay.
Now I bet the kids are
a little worried, right?
So let's make a 'snow angel'
right now, go ahead.
Snow Angel!
C'mon. You and me. Snow Angel?
No! Fuck...
Get back in the car.
Don't!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. Fuck...
I didn't mean it,
you know that, right?
Look at him, even high
in his driver's license picture.
They'll be gone in a few minutes.
It's almost over.
- Steph just got out of the car!
- Oh shit!
Get back in the car, sir!
My Mom said you'd be gone
in a few minutes.
Well yeah... in a few minutes.
I tried to tell my parents but
the music was too loud.
Tried to tell them what?
- I saw something bad...
- What did you see?
There was a white car and a blue car.
And the blue car had smashed-up
windows and blood all over it.
- You been watching scary movies?
- My Mom doesn't let me.
Alright. Thank you for telling us that.
And we are gonna take care of that okay?
How about you and me go back to your car?
Your dad looks worried.
I know what blood looks like.
Your daughter's a brave little girl.
Good news.
We won't be ticketing you for speeding.
Alright? I took care of that.
You know,
I could report your partner.
But he won't!
I would just let this go, Sir.
With my apologies.
You know, I don't know what
you said to him...
but it really did the trick, because
he is grinning like a monkey!
You folks got
a good spare in the trunk?
We sure do, Officer.
We'll be just fine.
So thank you for that, 'cause I gotta
ride with him all day.
Well here you go.
You all have a great day, alright?
Alright. Take care.
Fucking asshole.
Steph...
honey...
what did you say to the Police Officers?
I told them I saw something.
You weren't listening.
You could have really gotten
your father in trouble...
He's not my father.
You know what I meant.
Fuck.
Mom, 'are we there yet? '
Alright. Thin ice, David.
Wanna do another one?
Yes. I do.
Stephanie, where is your father?
We should contact him.
My father's dead.
- Soccer Mom's thirsty.
- Bring her a beer.
I'm fine, I'll be out
in a minute, okay?
Okay.
- Here ya go.
- Thanks.
Cheers!
How's the vacation going?
I'm not really having a very good time.
Okay...
I'm suing them.
- No you're not, Steven.
- I am suing them. That is unbelievable.
Steven, we're lucky to be alive.
They're all corrupt.
Yeah, no, yeah...
I mean, I was petrified!
I don't know if it's the uniform,
or the gun...
Hey Mom... maybe I'll be a cop.
David, grow up!
Problem?
Ah, this fucking...
take the wheel a second, would you?
Jesus...
show off.
- Damn it!
- Look at that.
Tight-ass pants.
What, do you have to feed
that thing mice?
Ridiculous. I'm serious.
- Baby fucking deer-fawn.
- Unbelievable...
It's like a puppet.
Ah... whatever.
- Cheers!
This is a goddamn bullet hole!
So you think Officers Bennett
and Conrad shot out that man's tire...
I don't know, I guess it could
have been a bullet.
Are you fucking stupid?
No, I'm telling you,
that's what the guy thought it was.
Well, the guy's a fucking asshole!
You're the man who'd know.
Are those... little floating dead people?
Yes.
Hey Sweetie, we're almost finished.
- I wanna go home.
- We're not going home, Sweetie!
We're, we're on vacation.
We're having a great goddamn time, okay?
We got blood!
Aw fuck.
They were right behind us.
You shot the tire out.
The girl told us about the cars.
She said there were two cars.
Yeah, well, you know what?
We're missing the white one.
And what happened to Keith,
or 'Candy Pants'?
You're describing the Taurus that
you pulled over earlier in the day?
My partner and I pulled that Taurus
over earlier, yes.
They were speeding,
blew a tire...
And then you, the two of you, left the
scene with the couple alive and well.
Is that your statement?
I see what you're doing, Agent.
So then it was just moments after
you left...
that the unknown killers came and took
advantage of the couple's predicament?
Fine. That's your statement.
Keep going.
Hey, it's his job to shake all our
trees and see what falls out, huh?
Fuck him.
- A van just passed us.
- A white van.
I didn't warn my stepfather
about the van.
No one blames you, Stephanie.
I don't blame you.
Even if you didn't
tell him on purpose.
Stephanie, where are you going?
Stephanie!
David?
David!
Mom?
I got you.
Mom!
I got you. I've got you.
I got you.
Hey fuck face! You just
killed my best fucking friend!
Get out! Get out!
What the fuck is your problem?
Oh shit. Shit!
You alright?
Wait, lady, I'm coming.
I'm coming!
I think it's the missing woman.
In here!
Stay right there!
Hold on, I'll be, I'll be right there.
Get off the van!
Okay, one second.
- Back up, Mom.
- Fuck!
Shit!
- Hey, get away from the van crack-head!
- Fuck you.
Aw, Jesus, Jack...
where are our fucking guys?
Fuck! Damn it.
Hey, get outta the way.
Hang tight, ma'am!
Aw fuck! I could've killed you!
I'm doing my job!
Go get that woman outta there.
I'll check around.
- Alright, pretty fucking great huh?
- Yeah...
Police officers!
His hands...
were taped to the wheel.
The guy from the Taurus.
And his head came up...
You're saying Bennett just dove in?
Minus one good hand, yeah.
Cool.
Fuck!
Mother fucker!
Get to the back!
Get to the back, Jim!
- Fuck!
- Shut up!
Fuck!
This is my fucking shooting
hand, Keith! Fuck!
God damn it!
It was like a fucking building
had just dropped on me.
Wait a minute... she... on top of you?
Jesus, lady!
It's not her!
And I can, I can hear Bobbi
yelling that it wasn't the woman, and...
Hostage is a suspect!
So the mom and the kid just go down.
It's fucked up.
Hey little girl! Come here.
Quick, quick, come here,
we're gonna hide...
c'mon okay get in get in,
head down, head down, head down...
And I was almost out the back doors...
Jack.
Jim took a bullet.
I went to him...
No! Oh shit.
Oh fuck.
Oh. No. Jim.
You're gonna be okay.
Oh shit. Oh shit. No.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
One of them clocked me from behind.
I know you're keeping
a secret, buddy.
Oh yeah.
I have to go to the bathroom.
I can go alone.
I'm almost nine.
Alright, you can go.
Hey, you.
Get going...
Yeah, you should see it, it's amazing.
They're just so good at what they do.
I'm sad, of course...
the little girl.
But it's exciting.
Everyone's so nice, yeah.
I just want to be here
in case anyone needs anything.
I'll keep what
you said in mind.
Yeah. I'll do the same.
C'mon.
Housekeeping!
Ok what is it? Blue?
Blue Dove?
Ok. Blue Dove Motel.
3 bodies? Oh my God.
Two men. One woman.
Right. Right.
And then... okay.
Less than...
24 hours, okay.
I'll give it to the Captain
right away. Bye.
There goes my dinner date.
Janet. I'll take that.
Great.
I'd better deal with this.
Ladies and Gentlemen...
Why don't you go ahead and stretch
your legs and we'll meet in the corridor?
There's been a development.
Agent Anderson, I'll need to speak
to you before I update the others.
- Ah, this is unfortunate.
- Yeah... boy...
You like that man
you work with.
Agent Hallaway?
You called him 'Sam'.
I did?
Well...
we've worked together
for a long time.
That's the way my Mom looked
at my stepfather...
before they were married.
They thought it was a secret.
But it wasn't. I knew.
Captain?
Yeah, I'll have
everyone sit tight.
Here you go, Agent.
You gonna tell us
what's happening?
Apparently a maid has discovered
bodies at The Blue Dove Motel.
Who's going?
I'm gonna take Wright and Degrasso,
see if it's relevant to the case.
Get your stuff.
What's going to happen now?
I'm going to have to go someplace, okay?
- You're gonna stay in here with me.
- We can finish this later.
No, we're gonna finish it now,
I have some questions for you.
Just do as you're told and everything
will be okay.
Ladies, I have some questions for you so
if you could step inside, please?
- Come on, Jack
- Yeah, yeah, yeah...
Where's Janet?
- She's talking to the Coroner.
- Well, that could take awhile.
C'mon.
Shotgun!
- You're gonna be riding in the back.
- Yeah, I'll do that.
Nice work, Degrasso.
Pick it up...
Busted.
Fuck you, teacher's pet.
Ah, shit, buddy!
Would you just sit down?
You're driving me fucking crazy.
You gotta stay here.
Fuck you!
C'mon Jack... take a load off.
I'm gonna be in there in a minute,
Stephanie, go on.
I don't want to be in there.
Look. It's almost over, kid.
It's almost over.
Just let me tell you something, first.
What?
I figure with this under my belt...
pretty good candidate
for any job I want
My mother's gonna
shit herself with pride.
- She'll be real proud of you.
- I hope so...
Well...
okay...
Give me your piece, Bennett.
I need you to give
me your gun, Officer.
Fuck you, you need my fucking gun.
I need the Officer
to give me his weapon... now.
Give him your weapon, Jack.
I'll give it back to you
after I finish talking.
This is fucking bullshit.
- It's crazy bullshit.
- Really.
Not really...
Alright. Why don't
you take a seat, Jack?
'Cause I wanna go back to the crash...
right, just before your partner was
allegedly, brutally murdered.
Don't you fucking talk about my partner.
Hey. C'mon. I think it's gonna
feel good to get if off your chest.
Agent Hallway, look...
I'm a little confused.
You should be used
to that by now.
Look, if there's any question
as to how Jim Conrad died...
There's no question here,
that our Officer Jack cannot answer.
None.
Isn't that right, Jack?
Hold that. Hold that thought...
because I think we all oughtta
have a smoke.
Let's all just have a smoke now, alright?
Yeah. Missy?
No thank you.
- You never smoke?
- No...
Alright... I guess so.
Captain?
He quit.
Yeah but this is a special occasion.
C'mon.
- You lied.
- Smoker's privilege.
You can quit after you had this one.
Yeah...
Alright. Jack?
Smoking kills.
No.
No. You do.
You don't know what you're talking about.
- Don't I? Hmm?
- You weren't there.
Oh, wait.
I was there. Yeah.
Help...
Surprise!
You were a little out of it 'cause
you had your hand opened up, and...
Bobbi...
that was great, all that screaming stuff,
that set the whole deal up.
That was great, it was a lot of drama,
and then you were really good, too.
Really. You jumped right back
into the game.
You got a lot of gas in your tank,
don't you?
Now I want you, I want you...
to take it from there, huh?
- Hmm?
- Fuck!
You think there's a medal
in this?
I hope there is.
It'd be sweet...
Fuck!
You fired into your partner and you
opened him up like a can of soda.
- Head rush, Captain?
- Yeah.
It'll pass.
Fuck!
Sit on the chair, missy.
Thank you.
Jack... c'mon.
Let's go back.
Okay?
What's that smell?
Don't you hate that smell?
Quite a smell.
Oh yeah...
I gotta take this.
Baby?
Are you smoking?
Wherever you are, I want you
to come back to me...
and bring the butter,
we're having toast.
Just the way you like it.
Hello...
Fuck.
What was that?
Come here...
Come here.
Come here, come.
I didn't hear that.
What was that you said?
I said she was way too
fuckable to be F.B.I.
There was something else.
I said she smelled like you.
I like that, and I want you to tell
her that when she comes back in.
Okay. Let's get back
to where we were, alright?
Come here.
You wanna hear this.
Let's go back.
Wanna go back to the point we
were talking about?
'Cause this was my favorite
part of the day.
You and your bitch can go fuck yourselves.
I know what you're looking at, we're
gonna deal with the gun later, alright?
It's fun now. Okay?
'Cause first of all, even though,
regrettably...
the Captain here is unable to hear your
admission, that would've been perfect...
I want you now to admit that
you killed your own partner.
Fuck you.
No. That's not the right answer.
Bye, baby...
You killed my partner.
Oh, please.
Jack, you okay?
It's, it's not the missing woman,
it's one of the fucking killers!
- Jack!
- Hostage is a suspect!
I may have orchestrated it
but they were your bullets.
This is kind of amazing.
Fuck you, you
fucking drug-addict whore.
Hey, no, she's impressed!
The little girl was impressed, too.
No! No! No! No! No!
I'm not...
having a very good time.
It's hard to impress children with
that shit...
they get all slobbery and uncontrolled
but she didn't go that way.
But you, hey, Missy...
are you fucking soft or something?
C'mon, she's gone... she's gone.
You were gonna say something,
go ahead, spit it out, please.
I'm a good cop!
Oh... that's a total oxymoron.
And remember, I was there.
When you realized what you'd done.
Oh fuck... fuck...
You went all 'crazy cop'.
You started shooting at everything.
And, of course, you fired at my girl.
Fuck...
I wish I hadn't missed.
Oh shit!
Well that's the second time I've knocked
him out. You'd think he'd see me coming.
But he's still with the party.
Good.
- You want a little nap, too?
- No...
Right. Yes, go ahead.
You ever let anyone go?
You probably read the end
of a book first, don't you?
Yeah.
That is no way to live.
Honey... I'm home.
Hey. Come on, baby, come on.
Oh yeah.
- How was I?
- How were you?
We know your ears work.
How the fuck was I?
Was I scary?
- Will flattery save my life?
- Don't be stupid.
- How about a blowjob?
- Answer me.
You were scary as shit, hey man...
just the whole thing was amaz...
I just wish I could tell people.
Maybe in your next life.
Baby!
I fucking love you.
Baby, we can start the party.
- Hey...
- Hey!
God, look at you.
You smell so good.
You don't have to hurt me.
We're not hurting you.
We're loving you.
You're gonna fucking love this.
She's so fucking pretty, Jesus.
Look at these... they're nice.
Do you like these?
Do you like them?
Would you touch my tits?
Oh, God... that's right.
Yeah, c'mon, that's right.
Oh God, you're...
Just let it go, it's okay,
just let it go.
She's ready!
Oh yeah, baby.
Surprise!
Oh I love a...
I always wanted to be blonde.
C'mon, we gotta ride...
Yeah, hey, it's Ralph,
I'm still at The Blue Dove.
I've identified the missing woman,
Elaine Meyer.
But I'm looking at some F.B.I. Badges.
How many Agents are we supposed
to have in town right now?
Are you hurting much, baby?
No... just feel jabbed.
Hmm... stubborn.
I know who you are.
Baby...
Ah, she was on to us, so...
I thought 'that's fun'.
Let her go free.
I think that's the most romantic
thing ever, in the whole world.
Oh baby...
Baby, oh...
www.pootzforce.org
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org