Okay, go ahead.
Can I see the sign-in
sheet, please?
Thank you.
M'am you need to
sign it right here.
- Can I use the phone?
- Sure, go ahead.
Hello?
I'm gonna do this
alone aren't I?
- How could you not be here?
- I don't need to be there.
I don't need to watch.
But, uh...
I packed all his
things for you.
What?
- Why would you do
that Ana? I don't...
I can't just throw them away.
Nothings gonna change.
This isn't gonna
bring him back.
None of this will
bring him back, Ana.
You know it's... I'm
hanging up now okay?
Ana?
- Noun.
- Electricity...
- Color.
- Black.
Adverb.
Mom, do I have to go again?
Yeah we do.
Why?
Remember when we used to
go to the zoo together?
Yeah. We're going
to the zoo now?
No, Honey.
You know, the uh... Remember
those big gorillas...
how they'd play behind the
glass and make faces at us?
And make us laugh?
- Remember that?
- That was fun.
But they always had to
stay in their cage right?
These people might
forget, they...
might think... oh, you know:
He's okay, he's a nice
animal. He just wants to play.
And they would let 'im out...
and terrible things
would happen.
Really?
Yeah, the man's
an animal, Jesse.
To make sure people
won't forget that.
He's a monster and I
have to make sure...
people won't forget.
Okay.
Can we stop this time?
Please can we stop?
Yeah, absolutely.
I think I'm gonna stay here.
Okay fine, I'm gonna get out.
Lock-It-Up mini-storage.
Yeah, it's him.
No.
No, after thirty days
it's gotta be cash.
Hear that? That's
your customer.
- What's going on?
- Take a guess.
I thought, I might need
another week. Okay?
Look, let me make it
real simple for you.
If you don't pay
you can't play.
You have until tonight's
game to pay up.
Then it's over...
- What's that
supposed to mean?
Use your imagination! Over.
Chuck, come on man.
What if I...?
Hang on, hang on.
All right, have fun.
Remember you can
look, can't touch.
Place a bid, place a bid
on everything.
Start at 50 bucks
- 55 -60...
70.
75.
80.
85.
85. All right,
you're the winner.
Fill out at the top, please.
Okay, here it is...
- That's it?
- That's it.
250.
250?
Yeah...
Come on, I need
more than that.
I'm sure you do.
250.
You know what, take it.
Girls, stay in the car.
Harry...
Well this certainly
explains a few things.
Yeah, it was just uh, bunch of
stuff that would've been...
auctioned anyways.
Bunch of junk.
So you're not stealing from
our customers, really.
Just me.
Look, I uh...
I'll pay you back... all
right? All of it, I promise.
Your word on that right?
There's no such thing as
selective honesty, Saul.
I want you out by morning.
I don't care where you go.
But I want you out before
opening, tomorrow morning.
Or I'll report you.
Alright. Alright.
I'm very sorry. A bit
crazy this morning.
To the point, then.
Mrs. Nichols, we've
decided to recommend
Jesse to special education.
What?
Harrison has a very
effective program.
We feel they're
better equipped...
to deal with your son...
than we are.
What are you
talking about...
'better equipped'?
He's a child!
His maturity level is
equal to a five year old's.
As is yours Mrs. Bachanas.
I'm still dealing with you.
No, I've seen those classes.
He does not belong in a...
special ed class.
He's not special ed!
You know what that'll do to...
him? Putting him
in that class?
We simply don't have the...
resources to make
this work here.
I know it's not a
perfect fit, but...
it's all the
district has left.
He'll be able to understand
instructions. He can succeed!
You know what he
needs? He needs...
a teacher who's willing to...
see him as an individual
with individual needs.
Individual ways of processing
information. You know!
You know that!
He understands!
He just gets...
distracted, he gets
a little bored...
He's not interested in
regurgitated facts.
Just let him think
for himself, please!
He doesn't listen!
He distracts...
himself and the entire class!
He does listen. He hears
every word you say.
Nonetheless Mrs. Nichols,
this is the decision.
Friday will be
his last day here.
I can't afford private school.
Then starting Monday, Jesse
will have to attend...
the classes at Harrison.
I am sorry, but you...
no longer have a
choice in the matter.
No, he's my son! We'll
always have a choice...
Mrs. Nichols...
No, don't please.
Come on.
Oh, Jesse, come on!
But I did a triple
knot this time.
All right, just take
your foot out. Come on!
I'm trying!
I know you are. All
right. Let's go...
What about my shoe?
We'll get another
pair of shoes.
Jesse!
Oh yeah, sorry.
No, honey your feet, take
them off the coffee table.
Sorry.
All right, sweetie.
Let me get in there.
Are we done?
Yeah, we're done.
Have you tried
the card club?
I'm not going back there.
How do you spell 'mirror'?
You ever worked
there? 2 'r'-s honey!
- You haven't told him yet?
- No.
How do you spell 'faces'?
With a 'c', you
know that one Jess!
What? What should I do? You
know? You have an easy answer?
There's no easy answer!
He wouldn't understand! What
am I gonna do when he...
asks me 'what did I do wrong'?
'Why can't I hang
out with my friends?
Why am I reading the same
book I read 3 years ago?'
I can't put
him in that class
Well, you can't
just not tell him.
I know, I know. I'm gonna
figure something out.
- Mom, it's not working!
- I'm coming!
- Mom!
- Yes, honey?
- This isn't working very well
- No?
- The pencil keeps punching...
- All right, let me see.
It's 'cause it's a soft chair.
I don't like soft chairs.
Look, we'll put a
hard book under it...
What do you think?
'You can do it.' Plus, plus,
plus. Heart.
Exclamation point.
Smiley face.
- Hey dad!
- Bud.
So I figured you'd just
give me a lesson plan,
and I'll follow it.
You'll make me a list of stuff
I gotta buy to
get him started.
And you know, just do it!
I don't know! I
don't know if you're...
What?
You don't think
I'm smart enough?
Here we go, that's not
it, and you know it.
Well no it isn't, you've
just said that I'm not...
cut out for it...
How is it more
complicated? We...
can't put him in a
special ed program.
Of course not, can we just
talk about this tonight?
Please, I've just got 34 7th...
graders who need
their tests...
by 5th period.
Oh, I'm sorry. I don't want to
interrupt your students'...
education. You know...
- I've called in.
- What about your 7th graders?
You really wanna do this?
No, I don't think
we have a choice.
I'll go partime again.
I guess, I'll do nights.
I can get my shift back
at the resource center.
Why can't they just teach him?
'Cause they're idiots.
All teachers are idiots.
Well, we all are.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hi, Saul.
Just a minute.
Is she coming?
I would imagine so.
They won't let me
see her will they?
There are reasons
for that, Saul.
Yeah.
Do you think she hates you?
And would you,
if you were her?
Maybe.
Probably, yes.
But, I'm not her.
I didn't know you then.
Neither did she.
She just looked at me.
That's it. She
just looked at me.
Do you want her to hate you?
I pray to God she hates me.
What?
You're almost out.
Here, take those.
You take 'em!
- Pop?
- What?
- I need to talk to you.
- You need to work.
There's no work, pop. There's
no appartment, nothing.
We're done.
What are you talking about?
We've got everything we need.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Come on.
There's more to your entire
life than this one act...
from your past.
There's more to you
than this right here.
Well, if there's
something more,
you know, it's kinda we're...
running out of time.
God's plan is something
you'll find in yourself.
God's plan?
Yes. Yes, God's plan. He's
got a plan for you, Saul.
For you and for me?
For you, for me, for every
living creature on this Earth.
How does that work,
exactly, Steven?
How does God choose,
who gets what plan?
So you've got the plan
with a mother -...
wakes up every morning,
makes you breakfast.
Sees you off to a
nice day at school.
The one where your father
comes home from...
his modest 9 to 5 job.
Takes the time out of his
day to throw the ball around,
help you with your homework.
Read you a story before bed.
What happens if I get that
white picket fence plan?
And you sit here. Across
your one and only visitor...
who happens to be a minister.
Determined to convince
you that even...
the worst of
God's creatures...
can find a meaning in life?
Would you feel
the same way then?
You do not have the right to
tell me about God's plan.
There is no plan.
I was born alone, and
today I'm gonna die alone.
And everything
between was my choice.
Do not tell me
about God's plan!
Let's see, laundry,
dusting, mopping...
That's...I mean
that's what I...
that's what I did
since I had...
my son, you know.
That's what I 've been doing.
- Give me those!
- Why! ?
Put 'em down,
just put 'em down.
Please, can I have it, Mom?
Mom!
Okay now, listen. When
I say stay on the chair,
I don't mean climb on it -
I don't mean climb
on the railings...
and touch the
chair once in a...
while, I mean stay
on the chair!
I've been there for 5
minutes. You're not a baby!
I was always touching the
chair! I never let go!
No, you know what
I meant. You...
know exactly what
I meant, Jess.
Okay, just listen.
Listen to me!
But Mom...
No Jess! I need your help,
I can't do this, okay?
I need you to help
me. Can you do that?
Do you want the
rest of my root beer?
No I'm good buddy, thanks.
You don't like
root beer, do you?
I like good Pizza.
'If then God so
clothe the grass,
which is to day in the field,'
'and to morrow is
cast into the oven;'
'how much more will
he clothe you,
O ye of little faith?'
And the rest?
The rest?
'Sufficient unto the day
is the evil thereof.'
If God is in control...
Why didn't he stop me?
We can't know all
the reasons, Saul.
Only he sees the big picture.
His omniscence is his alone.
All right, come on
man. Come on man!
You can't hide behind that!
It's bullshit!
Forget about me! What
about the little boy?
Was that in God's plan?
Did he deserve it?
I don't know. No one
could ever know that.
Why?
- Why don't you tell me, Saul?
- 'Cause you couldn't.
- Well, that's bullshit!
- Really?
2 grand?
Yeah.
Straight up? All at once?
Pretty much.
I don't know, Saul. I'm not...
really into giving
second tier loans.
And at the end of
the day, I'm...
betting on your
card skills -...
which seem to be at present,
not too performance-oriented.
Tell you what.
Why don't you work for it?
Minimize my risk,
avoid double debt.
It's a win-win.
I appreciate that.
But it's not...
gonna work for me.
What's not gonna work for you?
What's your problem, Saul?
Why don't you take some
responsibility for yourself?
Some accountability?
If I may be frank, your work...
ethic is a little
back assward.
I don't think you understand.
I don't have the time.
Ok, look man, do me a favor:
don't think, it's not...
your strong suit. All right?
I'm not sitting here offering
you a full-time position.
Tell you what man, come back
next week, maybe we can...
There's no next week! Okay?
There is no tomorrow.
I need 2000 dollars tonight.
That's it.
All right.
One job, one
hour, one payment.
When you're done of course.
I think I know what
it is you need Saul.
And I'm telling you this
job will match your...
needs with my resources.
Synergy, Saul.
Yeah.
Go around!
What?
- You're serious?
- Absolutely.
I want him to rot in hell.
You make this
trek every year?
Yeah...
- Why?
- Because it's what I do
It's my responsibility.
It's the most
important thing I do.
It's sort of like
your calling?
I didn't mean it. I just...
People think justice comes
back in the courtroom,
when the sentence is said.
But it doesn't.
It's meted out
slowly, continually.
Year after year.
Are you gonna watch?
Wouldn't miss it
for the world.
So what weight is your
trailer rated for?
Because I still
think it's too heavy.
What? I don't look a mechanic.
I don't know. It's a blowout.
Can you fix a blowout?
Does the phone work?
Can I call, please.
Mom! Mom!
Look at these boots! They're
so cool, aren't they?
Are they comfortable?
Yeah! They're
really comfortable!
'Cause you know they gotta
be for every day, you gotta...
be able to wear them
for every day, right?
But they look
really big, honey.
I'll grow into them.
Let me try 'em on.
I don't think
they'll fit you...
You don't? Do
you want to bet?
I'll bet when you try them on.
That's not a bet,
that's a sure thing.
Wow, you look good in them!
You should buy them too!
Aren't they
really comfortable?
No, they're...
They're like hell.
Can we just try, these cool
kind of shoes, please?
Why? Those aren't cool.
These are really cool!
They're cowboy boots.
Look, I'll get the right size.
Jess!
Told you, you can
wear it in the rain!
Don't you at least want
to take the tags off?
No way! I'm saving
them for school!
Come on you vile monkey.
Ow, that hurts!
- Why are you dancing, huh?
- Bread and butter
Get out of my car!
I sent the payment
yesterday. It's my car!
You tell him to
leave me alone!
Gimme that quarter over there.
Just give me one of 'em.
Here, hook 'em up.
That's your customer,
why didn't you do
what I tell ya, huh?
Hurry up, you...
Don't you roll
your eyes at me!
Thank you.
Here you go.
- Want anything?
- No, no thanks.
- Missed us, huh?
- Oh yeah, horribly.
Got a 6 to 2 shift,
you'll be perfect for it.
It's a tougher crowd, I
need tougher people...
- Monday through Friday?
- Wednesday through Sunday.
Did you hear, what
you paid me today?
- No. You wanna tell me?
- 200, buddy. 200!
Now this is what we need
more of around here, Sam.
Don't let this one get away.
My niece thinks she's
ready for the tables now...
for the likes of you.
- Tommy, get over here!
- Yeah, I'm coming.
It is what it is, sweetheart.
You out of anybody
should know that.
Yeah, it's been a while.
That's right, which means...
Darla's gonna have to train
you all over again.
Which means, if we do this,
I'm gonna need a 6
month commitment.
Minimum.
Saul.
Saul?
Yeah?
I know.
If you're the sole controller
of your own destiny...
you really believe that God
is unavailable in that world?
Yes I do.
Why are you so
determined to resist...
goodness in your life?
You can't have it both ways.
You can't be the victim
and claim to have peace...
I'm not the victim. I've
never claimed to be...
a victim.
Then you're not a victim.
But you want peace.
You claim to be
powerless to achieve it,
and yet you want to be the
sole owner of your actions.
Oh for God's sake!
So you want to
claim all the power?
You truly want peace?
Then allow yourself to
believe for a moment,
that someone in this
world loves you.
- Who? God?
- Yes.
Yes, God.
God loves you.
And for that alone,
your life has value.
If you want peace, why
are you so adamant...
that it's not possible?
If God doesn't want
to bother with you,
why is your heart so heavy?
Where do you think
this guilt comes from?
- It's a lot warmer in here!
- Are you driving?
I still gotta go to
the grocery store...
before dinner.
We'll drop you off
and then Jessie and I...
will come back.
I want to go with
Dad! My Moto-Father
I'll take him with
me if you want.
No sweetie-pie, he's
got a lot of work...
to do before dinner.
Come with your Moto-Mama
In the back.
- Thank you.
- I'll see you in a bit.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
See you!
Bye!
Mom? Mom!
We have to go, honey!
Come on, sweetie.
Hi.
Hi!
Can I stay here?
Sweetie, I can't see
you from in the store.
You gotta come with me.
Please, I just wanna read.
No, get your coat.
Come on, let's go.
It's so boring in
the store, I hate it.
Don't be hatin'!
Can I bring the comic?
No, leave the book.
Put your jacket on.
It's not so bad, 10
minutes in the grocery store.
I know, but that's 10 minutes
in here, why can't I just...
That's the point!
I can just stay...
It's just 10
minutes in the car.
Boots go on your feet.
I'm saving these for
school, remember?
- So, what are we getting?
- Cereal
What are you going for?
Really? I was kind
of hoping for...
something with a
little more sugar.
Sugar is bad for you.
How are we doin' there, buddy?
Well, we have 4 folders.
You've got spirals
in the binder?
So you're in the
middle of the ocean.
It's clear for like 200 feet.
And even before you hear...
the song of the
whale, you feel it.
Yeah, like this vibration.
It's right here.
You watch 'em, okay?
Don't let anything happen
I'll be right here.
So, it should be
a while before...
you really find... Right.
Can you hold it for
a second please?
Can I help you?
Yeah, I need a prescription
for my father.
Gregors, last name.
- First name?
- Benjamin.
Hi, do you have any employment
application forms?
Make sure he takes
these with a meal.
These are your instructions.
20 dollars, please.
Do you have another pen?
This one isn't working.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I uh...
I need 2000 dollars now!
What are you doing! ?
You hear me?
Just stay there!
Don't move!
Just stay there, okay?
Just stay!
Just give me the money!
Go, go, go! Come on!
Put the phone down!
Now!
Come on, hurry!
You! Stay there! Don't!
No! Just stay there.
Jess! No!
No!
Please, let him go!
- Honey, it's okay
- Mom!
Mom!
Honey, it's okay.
It's alright!
I'm leaving now, okay?
Nobody call the cops!
He's gonna be fine. Stay!
- Please stay!
- You give him back to me!
No! No!
10 minutes...
- You take me!
- Give me 10 minutes!
Jesse!
Look, your mommy's
coming, okay?
Be quiet
Mom, mommy! No!
Help! Get me out of here!
No, don't call!
Please, he said not to call!
Can you wait? Please,
can you just wait?
Just 10 minutes.
- Let me out!
- We're almost there, okay?
M'am? We need to call!
He said not to call! I
don't know what to do...
We need to call the police
He's my son! He's
my little boy!
Please don't call the police!
I don't know what to do
You'll be okay.
Get out of the way!
Hang on!
I'll let you out
in just a minute!
All right? We'll
be right there!
You okay? You alright?
'Yea, though I walk through...
the valley of the
shadow of death,'
'I shall fear no evil:
for thou art with me;'
'thy rod and thy
staff they comfort me.
Thou preparest a
table before me in...
6421 returning.
'thou anointest my
head with oil;...
my cup runneth over.'
'Surely goodness
and mercy shall...
follow me all the
days of my life:'
'and I shall dwell in the
house of the Lord for ever.'
All clear?
Hang on! Hang on!
Just a minute!
Okay.
I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to do.
Come with now!
Okay, go ahead.
Can I see the sign-in
sheet, please?
Thank you.
M'am you need to
sign it right here.
- Can I use the phone?
- Sure, go ahead.
Jesse! No! Let me see him!
Let me see him, please!
Jesse, I'm here, honey!
He is my everything!
Please do something...
Please do something!
No!
You need something?
Yeah. I wanna see him.
Excuse me?
I wanna talk to the prisoner.
I'm sorry Mrs. Nichols,
I don't think that's possible.
No, it's entirely possible.
Call your supervisor.
I don't think he's gonna
give you a different answer.
Mr. Runyan, call
your supervisor.
Are you in charge?
I understand you'd like
to see the prisoner?
No, I wanna speak to him.
Well, that's not a good idea.
I just wanna...
I need to talk to him.
Look, I understand
what he did to you,
what he did to your son.
And it must be very difficult,
but I can't... I'm afraid...
You have no idea.
I pray every night
that he suffers...
the same pain I endure.
Every morning when I wake up,
I don't see my son, I
don't see my husband.
I wanna see him.
Is it illegal for
me to speak to him?
No, it's not illegal.
Stand right here.
I need to search your purse.
Feet shoulder-width apart,
hands against the wall.
- Ready, Ma'am?
- Yes.
I'm sorry
I'm so sorry.
I've tried to
imagine what you...
who you are.
What your day was like before.
I've put together
your entire life...
from a single moment.
I feel like I know you.
I don't know who you are,
or what I've taken from you.
Even then, I'm so sorry.
I've tried for so long
not to give you a face.
It's so much better when
you don't have a face.
All these details
of you in my mind,
in my imagination.
And I think I have
pieced together...
your whole life on
the drive here.
I'm sure it's all wrong.
I'm sure it doesn't matter.
I forgive you.
I have to forgive you.
Sorry.
Subtitles by 'ElDorado80'