Don’t jump in the pool.
The water we put in
next week for the summer.
...in South Vietnam
ground war.
The U.S. Command reports 148
Americans killed in the war last week,
the lowest weekly figure in six
months. 1,612 Americans were...
...they barely look
like they've been warned.
There was exchange
of fire south of
the Sea of Galilee and
across the Suez Canal.
These exchanges and raids are
now a daily part of Israeli life,
and the country is
prepared for anything.
NBC news correspondent,
David Burrington, reports.
In spite of all
the border turmoil,
Israeli intelligence officers do
not expect all-out war this summer
unless the Arab
nations get reckless.
And that's the
main worry here,
that Arab frustration
will suddenly explode...
In a day
of intensive activity,
Captain Neil Armstrong
and his crew
entered the final
phase of preparations
for the July 16th
launch of Apollo 11.
NASA officials report
that the third and final day of
launching pad tests proceeded smoothly,
while inside
the training center,
the astronauts performed simulated
moon walks in their space suits.
What? Excuse me. I can't possibly stay.
This establishment isn't
fit for human habitation.
Fine, go. Yes, well, here's your key.
It didn't fit the lock, but
the door was open in any case.
You went into the room?
I did, yes.
And now I must insist
on you returning my $8.
After you already
used the room?
What kind of scam
are you running?
And besides...
Well, this is ridiculous!
The so-called air
conditioner was just
an empty plastic
box in the window.
The room was filthy. Indeed, I
discovered a small hair on the pillow.
There wasn't even
a towel in the bathroom.
Ma.
What?
Please, we're late already.
My son,
thank God you're here.
This man is threatening me for a refund!
I'm sorry. You're over $5,000
in arrears on the mortgage.
The home office is
breathing down my neck.
Mr. Spiers,
the El Monaco Resort...
It's a resort now?
...and Motel is my
parents' lifeblood.
With the addition
of the swimming pool
and these new town-wide
marketing initiatives...
Initiatives?
As you know, I have been
elected the President
of the Bethel
Chamber of Commerce.
The youngest president
in their history.
We've decided to erect a tourist
information booth, right off 17B.
I have agreed, on behalf
of the El Monaco,
to lease at no cost some
road frontage to the endeavor,
which should coincidentally drive
heavy tourist traffic right to our door.
In addition...
Please, Elliot,
you know I do everything I can to help.
We even bought one
of your paintings.
But don't try to sell me
on those singles weekends
or the culture festival
or whatever other schemes
were supposed to dig
you out last summer.
We've decided to go classical
with the festival this year,
maybe a string quartet, more
contemporary, like Morton Feldman?
Very avant-garde. And we've got
a theater troupe in the barn.
You have a theater
troupe in the barn?
The Earthlight Players.
Vassar graduates, some of them.
They live in the barn?
They do everything
in the barn.
You haven't seen the sign? What sign?
The sign in
front of the barn.
Mr. Spiers, my God, please.
We come here, begging,
begging for mercy,
and what do you give us?
This fixation about the barn.
What is it with you and the barn?
I was just... I'm an old woman,
Mr. Spiers. I've suffered.
I walked here all the way
from Minsk, in Russia,
in 20-foot snow drifts,
1,000 miles across Siberia.
I escaped the pogroms,
the Tsar's secret police,
with nothing but cold
potatoes in my pockets.
Mrs. Teichberg, please...
And for what?
For more persecution!
It's because we're Jewish.
I know it, isn't it?
Mrs. Teichberg, please.
This is the Catskills.
Half the summer colonies are
Jewish, they're all our clients.
Until the day they need you,
and then on goes the gas!
Ma,
calm down, please?
Jackson, just give us
a couple of months.
The summer season's coming up, I
honestly do have some real money
owed me from my interior
design business in the city.
Please?
Mother-son ballroom class will
start immediately after, at 11:00.
That's kinder-dancing for
the kiddies in 10 minutes.
Dad, you gotta
get Ma to lay off
the Nazi stuff and
let me handle this.
You think I can tell
your mother what to do?
I gotta get back to the city.
I'll see you Friday.
We'll get the money.
Let them take
this miserable dump.
I'll die in peace,
in Florida.
Mr. Tiber.
George.
I admitted your sister
some time ago. Thanks.
And some gentlemen
from the moving company.
Oh, yeah.
There you are.
Hi, Sis.
How did it go
at the bank?
How do you think it went? Till
the end of the summer, that's it.
What about the money
those mobsters owe you
for that nightclub
you designed?
They have a surprisingly strict
policy about paying designers.
They don't.
You want some
more paintings?
No, I already have 10 of them.
And you know Joe hates them.
Of course you're broke,
after all the money you've sunk
into that hellhole of theirs.
And I bet Ma's never even
said a word of thanks, has she?
No, but I can sense it.
The special way she
sometimes looks at me
with just her left eye,
you know.
Elliot. Now is your time
to go to California
like you've always wanted,
to paint and design. Be free, stop
throwing your life away up there.
I can't give up on them now. Why not?
I'm the one they
still want around.
I guess that means they
love me more than you.
That must be a great
consolation to you.
Dad, that's bleach
for laundry.
It kills the germs.
What's the difference?
Elli? What? What are you
doing with those sheets?
They're dirty.
Let me see. Nothing.
Those two, they didn't do nothing
in there. Shake them, put them back.
But, Ma...
Electricity, detergent,
who's paying
for all that?
And you, theater girl,
get back in the barn!
All of you!
Lazy people.
Let's call to order.
Come on, everyone.
Last meeting, we all said we'd each
bring some new ideas to the table.
Well, okay.
We got a lot of dairy farms
around here, right?
And a fair number of bulls.
Okay, you've all
heard of the running
of the bulls in
that town in Spain,
Pampoona.
Pamplona.
Well, no one's doing
one in the Catskills.
Seems to be a big
draw over there.
It would be very amusing
to see all those Jews
from Levitsky's
summer colony,
you know, the ones with the
black top hats and the curls,
running for their lives
chased by our local livestock.
Wouldn't that be
a wonderful sight!
We're writing it all down.
Any other ideas?
What about the monorail?
Marge, you can't bring
that up in every meeting.
I've written
to the Governor,
but I think a letter from
the entire Chamber of Commerce
would be much
more effective.
A monorail linking downtown
New York to White Lake
would be a tremendous spur
to the local economy.
Jesus. Look, people, I said I
would come back to these meetings
if you could stay out of
cuckoo land, just once.
We have some serious local
issues, serious business to do.
Such as?
For starters,
I need a permit
for the town landing
for a fish-toss
tournament next month.
I knew it. I knew it. You're just
back here for your own purposes.
Now, come on, Marge. All right,
let's see the application.
I got it here.
Yeah, that's all
in order. $1.
Here you go.
And I've got my
application for our annual
El Monaco summer
music and art event,
which will also inaugurate
the first season
of the tourist
information kiosk.
Annie, if your grandson and his
friends want to play again this year,
tell them to
give me a call.
Okay.
Do I hear a motion to
approve these permits?
I so move.
Okay. Seconded?
Seconded?
Oh, for crying
out loud, seconded.
Good night.
Good night, Annie.
Night, Elliot.
See you, Elliot.
Bye, everyone.
Night, Elliot.
Good night, Carol. Fuck! Fuck!
Take him down, motherfuckers!
Jesus! Billy, get back in the car.
What?
Back in the car.
Hey, Billy, you're back.
That's great.
Yeah.
Staying with big brother Dan
and his beautiful wife Carol here
till I get my own pad.
Yeah, 'cause
little brother Billy
made a tiny little
pit stop in Bangkok
and blew all his Army pay.
Didn't he, Billy?
Bangkok, man.
Fucking Bangkok.
Come on, we gotta go.
Great seeing you
back home, Billy.
Hey, Elliot.
Dave.
The usual?
Extra bacon, please.
You got it.
Hey, Elliot.
Max.
I hear you've moved
up here permanently.
Just helping Mom and
Dad for the season.
Well, I hope you have
another one of your festivals.
Miriam and I just love listening
to your records out on that lawn.
Sure, Max. This year, I'm going
to try to get a live quartet.
Looks like you're gonna
have some competition.
What, there's a recall vote
down at the Chamber of Commerce?
This says here
that Wallkill's
gonna have
a music festival, too.
Some hippie thing
got thrown out of Woodstock
so they've set
themselves up in Wallkill.
Wow, Janis Joplin.
Guess that beats playing a
bunch of records on a lawn.
Then again, it'll probably turn
into some kind of antiwar riot.
Let Wallkill have them.
Extra bacon.
You want your receipt?
Thanks, Dave.
See you later.
See you tomorrow, Max.
No, no, no,
that's horrible.
Tonight's dinner
will be roast turkey
and for dessert,
an apple tart.
I killed it!
That clock was
our mother's.
Your mother.
Maybe I didn't break it. Maybe
it only looks like I broke it.
Maybe we only think we
exist, when really we don't.
Hi, Elliot.
Thank you, Elliot.
It hasn't been touched
since my glory days
in the Midwood
High School band.
How's the show shaping up?
We're really getting into it.
Great. Hope you guys
are prepared.
You're probably gonna
outnumber the audience.
Only takes one extra soul
to make it theater, man.
And theater
is transformation.
But it's hard,
concentrating.
Concentrating on?
We're just,
I don't know, hungry.
Hungry? As in...
Yeah,
as in hungry, you know.
For, like, foodstuffs.
You don't have any potatoes
or sunflower seeds or anything?
I can barter some
very special grass. No.
Me and grass,
you don't want to know.
But let me see what I
can steal from my mom
and you guys can pay us
after the first show.
Or not, I guess.
Front row seats, man.
On the house, for you.
I'm bored! I'm bored! I'm bored!
That house was ours,
not his.
But he took out
that mortgage,
and now his wife
has all the money.
I can't take it any longer!
I can't! I can't!
Please throw me out, just
throw me out! I can't take it!
Hello?
Hey, Elliot.
Steven, hi. What are you
doing calling long distance?
I just made bail.
The pigs raided the bar
again. Can you believe it?
But you should come back. I think
we're going to have another riot.
Come up here. You can start
a riot here in White Lake.
It would be wild.
I was just calling,
you know.
New York hasn't been
as much fun without you.
I mean, it hasn't been as depressing,
but, you know, in a fun way.
So, me and Marcus, we're hitching
a ride with the art dealer.
Do you remember him?
The one with the doll
collection? Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
We're moving to San
Francisco, man. You wanna join?
Elliot? You there?
Yeah, I'm still here.
Hey, thanks for the call.
It's good to hear your voice.
And drop me a line
when you get there, okay?
Okay.
Elli. There's something
moving in the bushes!
Take cover, man.
Billy.
What is it?
We're surrounded, man.
Can't you feel it?
It's like, when
the radio was busted,
and we fragged
that fucking sergeant,
so then they just
leave us out here.
But someone's gotta go back
and call in air support,
'cause I gotta
stay with O'Connor.
He doesn't have
any feet, man.
It's okay, Billy.
The radio's working
in the office.
I can call from there.
And you can cover me, right?
And I'll do some
recon with the squad,
they can send up
some reinforcements,
and the VC
will never see me.
And I can call in
the coordinates.
What the fuck you
talking about, Elliot?
I don't know.
I thought maybe I could be in
your flashback or something.
If it made you
feel any better.
That's cool.
You all right?
Man, I am fucked up.
You think I should take those
pills they gave me at the VA?
I should probably just
take those fucking pills,
but then I just
sleep all the time,
and then there's the
fucking nightmares. Fuck.
Never thought I'd end
up back here. Me neither.
I'm thinking, maybe I
should do another tour.
That doesn't sound
like such a good idea.
Over in 'Nam, I'm fucking normal.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Hey, you should join up.
Me?
Yeah.
No. They wouldn't
take me even if I wanted.
Yeah?
Flat feet.
Right. Feet.
Fuck.
Yeah, you're not fucking
normal, Elliot. No.
I guess not.
All I know is we're
fucking surrounded here.
Eat.
Thank you, Elliot.
For the backdrops you painted for
all of us. Everybody loves the colors.
It's like a Mandela. Actually,
it's not like a Mandela.
Well, the colors,
it's more like M&M'S.
You're welcome, Dev.
Hey, you guys
want some? Cholent?
Maybe next time.
No, I'm cool.
Hey, man,
what's up with this?
The festival.
The locals killed it.
They pulled the permit.
In Wallkill?
The Wallkillians killed it. Bummer, man.
We were all hoping to score
some tickets and go over for it.
Could have been beautiful. Joan
Baez, Grateful Dead, The Who.
Maybe even Dylan.
Yeah, Dylan.
Dylan.
Can I get that
paper for a sec?
Is everything
all right, Elliot?
Operator.
Hi, Alice. Can you connect
me with something called
the Woodstock Ventures
in New York City,
a gentleman by
the name of Michael Lang.
Elli! What is this
with the sheets?
What does it look like? I'm
making a big cross on the lawn!
With the clean sheets?
Jake, our boy's gone crazy!
Making a Ku Klux Klan
rally on our property!
No, it's so they can find us. Who?
Hey, man. Good to see you. Hi.
You don't remember
me, Elli?
Do we know each other?
Bensonhurst, 73rd Street.
I lived down the street from
you, man. We played stickball.
I'm Michael Lang,
you're Elli Teichberg.
Yeah, yeah, I kind of
remember, yeah. Mrs. Teichberg.
Hey, it's Michael, from
the neighborhood. Excuse me.
You! Cover your parts!
We have company!
In the barn. Get in the
barn! All of you! In!
Get inside!
Far out.
So, here we are.
Right.
Yes, as I mentioned
on the phone...
You have a permit.
That's very cool, Elli.
It's a start.
Very cool.
Please.
Mr. Teichberg.
Hey, people!
Welcome to Elliot's place.
Hey, Elli, can we
take a look around?
Of course, I'll show
you the whole place.
You've got some
open land here, right?
Absolutely,
just up here and down.
So...
Shit!
Michael, for Christ's sake,
it's a swamp.
Maybe we could get some bulldozers
in here and level it, right?
You're kidding me.
He owns it.
He's got a permit. He's the
President of the Chamber of Commerce.
And because of that you wanna
drown thousands of kids in a swamp?
Look, honestly, you guys can
do whatever you want to here.
That's fine
with us, really.
You could... For example,
you could detonate
an incredible amount
of explosives
and it would dry
everything out immediately.
And then you could just compact
the ashes down, you know,
and people could
sit on that.
Radical thinking, Elliot. I assume
you got a permit for that, too?
Or... Okay,
we get some big cranes
and hang, like, a parachute over the
field, and everyone could sit on it.
No?
How about you just
nuke the whole place?
Hey, don't lose
that creativity, man.
Jake, they are leaving!
Elli, have you offered
accommodation to everyone?
We may not have vacancy for
everyone, as the season is...
Ma, they're not staying.
Stay! Stay! Look.
My husband is
bringing refreshments.
Here. Thank you, Mrs. Teichberg.
Here. Try some of this.
It is the best chocolate milk in
New York. Made just down the road.
Have some water.
Or some chocolate milk.
What's his name? Or her. Lou.
Wow. That is excellent
chocolate milk.
Yeah, it comes from
the local cows. Far out.
They eat local grass. That
must be some healthy grass.
And there's a lot of it,
in big fields,
just a couple of miles
down the road from us.
I've always been a big supporter
of Elliot, here in Bethel,
and I always enjoy his
music festival every summer.
That's why we're here. Miriam and
I donate the yogurt and the milk.
It's fate.
It's beautiful.
Although some of the local
young people, the music they play
can be a little trying, if
you know what I mean, honestly.
Yeah, but it's the effort
that counts, isn't it, Miriam?
And they do
enjoy themselves.
There's a lot of joy
in music, Mr. Yasgur.
And we'd love to bring that joy to
your beautiful farm, wouldn't we?
Now, I know it's going to be
something of an imposition,
but we're more than
willing to do anything...
You say you want to
use these fields here?
Then you'll be needing the
land beside the barns as well,
I'm guessing,
for access to the roads.
And parking.
Probably best
across 17B.
I own the piece down the road,
but there are a couple of lots.
You'll probably want to
avoid dealing with the Browns.
And you'll clean up after
yourselves, I'm hoping.
Of course.
Well,
would $5,000
do it for you?
Five?
But you'll have to tidy up,
and you'll have to pay
for any damaged crops,
of course.
Sure, Max.
That sounds fine.
Good. Wonderful.
Well, why don't you all come into
the house for some chocolate milk?
Far out.
You know, we're gonna need
a place for people to crash
while we prepare
the festival.
Your place looks
pretty cool.
How many vacant rooms do you
have for the next couple of weeks?
Well, it depends on
how you define room.
You know, how many
people can crash with you.
What do you guys charge?
Let's see. It's $8 a night,
but that can be for doubles,
and we give a weekly
discount, of course.
Plus the cabins, you can
get cots, so four people,
about 150, I'd say.
You can get about 200 people.
Hey, man, let's make it easy.
Why don't we just buy the
El Monaco out for the season?
Just figure out the costs, write
it down, and we'll take a look.
And if we don't
use all the rooms,
you can rent out
the free ones.
We need to keep some cleanup
crews around afterwards.
And if you've got
some bigger spaces,
for offices,
that kind of thing.
We need to put in some phones and
have some space to park vehicles.
You know where we're going?
There you go.
That's the...
Looks like we can work
with this, Elli. Cool.
You know, I was thinking, I've got
that theater troupe in the barn.
A theater troupe
in the barn?
Yeah, the Earthlight Players.
It's okay if they stay, right?
Maybe you guys could find some
work for them or something.
They could really
use the pay.
They're all hired, man. Not
a problem. Great. Thanks.
And I hope you don't mind,
but we like to pay cash
in advance.
And not only that, he made me a local
community liaison for the festival,
and we're going to be the
exclusive local ticket agency, too.
They think at least 5,000 people
are gonna buy tickets, or more.
Five thousand coming
here to White Lake?
Elli, you're an idiot.
Twenty people, thirty,
okay, for a weekend.
But 1,000, 5,000?
They'll steal everything.
Ma... We'll be sued in
court by the neighbors.
What kind of meshuga, hairy, barefoot
person comes here in a heliocoptic
that we should lay our good white
sheets on the grass and ruin them,
and then plot and
revolutionize to take our hotel.
Ma, he pays cash.
Everyone pays cash here,
you shnook!
No, Ma, really.
Open it.
That's $5,000 for the rent, and another
$5,000 for my services as liaison.
Plus, think of the money we're
gonna make off of commissions
From the ticket sales!
And also...
El Monaco International
Casino and Bar Mitzvah Center.
Elliot?
Hey, Max.
Hi. Well, the phone hasn't
stopped ringing since you left.
And they're saying...
I know.
...thousands of people might
be coming to this thing. Yeah.
Well, you know,
that's gonna cost
quite a bit to put
things back in order,
and to get the cows situated and
so forth. I can understand, sure.
Now, Elliot,
you know I don't wish
to mess up your festival.
You know that.
'Cause I think what was done to
those young people in Wallkill
was just plain wrong. But
I've been talking with Miriam,
and we think if you could just
go back and tell those people...
How much? Seventy-five
thousand. Not a penny less.
Okay, I'll let them know.
Okay, good. Bye-bye.
What?
Don't spend any of that money.
That was Max. The deal's off.
What? Impossible!
Ma. Ma. Ma.
Elli, don't try to stop her.
She can't get far.
And I read in the papers,
you've already sold
thousands of tickets,
and that's a lot.
And so you'll be
needing to use,
practically, my whole place
here, not just the alfalfa fields.
Now, wait a second.
I mean, I could...
I mean, I could buy a farm for the
kind of money you're asking for.
I could buy five farms.
From what I read in
the papers, Mr. Roberts,
you've already spent a
million dollars in Wallkill,
and you've only got until
the 15th until your festival.
Now, I'm sure a wealthy
young man such as yourself
could, indeed,
buy a lot of farms.
But that's neither here nor
there. All I'm saying is...
Yeah, all you're saying is that
you've got us over a barrel.
Well, if I didn't, you wouldn't
be on your second carton
of chocolate milk
now, would you?
But I tell you this, fellas, when
you make a deal with me, it's a deal.
Okay? So long as you promise
to put things back in order,
I'll stand by you 100%.
These people
are my neighbors,
and I know how
to deal with them.
I won't let them run you off
like they did in Wallkill,
'cause this is my land,
and let's just see them try.
Wow, Max, that is very
cool. And you're right.
We're going to
have a lot of people
come here and
enjoy your place.
Michael, if I may, I wouldn't
describe $75,000 as cool.
$5,000 is cool.
Hey, it's your bread, guys.
I'm just trying to put you
together here with Max's vision.
Right. Look, Max, if we were
willing to consider doing this,
you're really gonna have to
let us make it work.
Mike, listen, really, if this
doesn't shake out with Max...
I'm sure we're
gonna be fine.
John and Joel and Max, they're
all gonna come together.
I can feel it.
Good vibes.
He won't let them near it.
Smithson? Who's Smithson?
I don't own the property down
there. You don't own the property?
I own this
and I own that,
which reminds me, I'm sure you'll
be willing to put up a bond,
just in case there's damage.
I was thinking $75,000.
Fuck!
A $75,000 bond, too?
Can I ask you a question? Please.
Is Mike for real?
I mean, he's so relaxed.
Michael, yeah,
he's totally real,
so long as
the cash is real.
And the cash is real so long
as John and Joel are real.
And I guess John and Joel
are gonna stay real because,
between us, they've already
sold 100,000 tickets.
And who wants 100,000 freaks
coming after them for refunds?
So Mikey is trying
to sell those six acres.
It's got a lake?
Yeah.
Hey, Dave.
I'll have the usual.
Geez, sorry, Elliot. I
think we're out of the usual.
Out of the usual?
Wow, that's unusual.
For crying out loud, Elliot.
How could you?
Okay, then I'll try
the waffles.
"To ensure three days of peace
and music, we've left Wallkill
"and are now in
White Lake, New York.
"Certain people of Wallkill decided
to try to run us out of town.
"Our new site, it's twice the
size of our original site. "
You did this, Teichberg.
You know what those hippies
are gonna do to our town?
They'll be high on drugs.
Robbing us by day and
raping the cattle at night.
We ought to run you Jews
out of town. You and Yasgur.
We're gonna boycott Yasgur's
milk. Shut the hotel down, too.
Get out of here, you hippie.
You're disgusting, Elliot.
You know what, Elliot?
You're not the only...
Elliot! God bless you.
Hi, Annie.
You can't imagine
what happened this morning.
What? I'm fully booked! Every room!
Yeah, me, too.
For the first time
since Herb died.
Thank you, Elliot.
You're welcome.
Hi.
Those motherfuckers in
there wanna fuck you up, huh?
That seems to be
the sense I'm getting.
Well, you're gonna have to carve
some fucking hearts out, man.
Fry them on a stick
over a fire pit
and then sit down and eat
them, before those motherfuckers
do the aforesaid
fucking to you, man!
Billy, can you just stop
with the motherfucking this
and motherfucking that.
Please?
Fuck.
Yeah. Fuck.
This could really
be a down trip.
My brother and his wife, they're
getting fucking organized.
Then what should I do?
Get fucking organized
yourself. Rally your troops.
Do I have troops?
Fuck, yeah.
You got your mom, don't you?
She's a fucking battalion.
And the Chamber of Commerce. This
whole thing is about commerce, right?
Right on!
Right on.
I'm off to HQ.
At ease, men... Man.
Go fry those fuckers.
Elliot!
We were in Wallkill.
Hanging with some friends,
making the scene.
Rapping on each other. And
they said this is where it's at.
So we rode our thumbs
up here. Can you dig it?
Elli, help.
It's these two.
They want a hole.
To dig their thumbs.
After they hit each other,
they made a scene in Wallkill!
What are they
talking about?
Just looking to score,
you know, the magic tickets.
Dad, get the tickets.
To the festival.
Okay, Neil, we can see you
coming down the ladder now.
Heading back up
to that first step.
But it's adequate
to get back up.
Roger. We copy. Takes a
pretty good little jump.
Hey. Hi, Tisha. What is it?
You've got
a couple of visitors.
Hello? What can
I do for you?
Mr. Teichberg?
Yes.
Here. That's 47 citations. Wiring,
plumbing, health code violations.
Quite a place
you've got here.
It's humble, but it's home.
Away from home, I mean.
And here's 14 more fire code.
You're way over the occupancy limits.
You've got five days
to pay up and repair
or else we're shutting
you down for good.
Have a nice day.
What's going on?
Your mother says we
can triple our money.
Three times the rooms.
You're kidding me.
They don't seem to mind. Honest.
These people, they like it.
I'm finished here,
you start on the bunking.
I don't know. White Lake
sounds better than Wallkill.
Don't ask me why
they call it Woodstock.
Everyone's gonna drive
to the fucking real Woodstock
and be really bummed
when they get there.
DOT's letting us put signage
up. Just not on the Thruway yet.
But we're working on it.
We're gonna want to run lines
all the way
back to the fence.
Can you trench here?
No, man. Everything,
water pipes, juice,
all the cables
gotta run aboveground.
I got the specs from
Hanley, for the speakers.
That's a lot of juice.
When Hendrix lights up, there won't
be a bird left in Sullivan County.
Hey, I spoke to Wavy Gravy
and the Hog Farmers.
Wavy?
Yeah.
His real name's Hugh. He's
got 80 freaks, the Hog Farmers.
They've got a commune
in the desert.
They drop more acid
than Timothy Leary.
There's 80 of them coming
in on a jumbo jet next week.
Hey, man, I can't find
the keys to my room.
Ask my mom.
Hey, how's your room?
Fine, man.
Trip tents? Yeah, where
the kids can come down...
From the trip. Wait, wait.
What have you got here?
No, no.
Don't put it down there.
He and his people are willing
to work with you on security.
You know, they really like your
non-confrontational approach.
You know, they wanna
call it a "Please Force. "
Not sure how Fabbri's
going to like that moniker.
We're still going
to need real police.
Hey, Mike,
do you have a second?
I'm just feeling
a little anxious.
Did Tisha tell you about
these code violations?
Hey, Elliot. Just the
man I wanted to see.
You know,
I'm getting the feeling
that we're really
going to be able to use
your community
relations skills.
My what skills?
Because, Elli, the rumors
are already swirling,
and we need to put a local
face on the reality here.
And you, Elli,
are a local face.
I'm a local face, yes,
but about these violations.
There's not a hotel around for
miles that could pass inspection.
Those inspector dudes?
Don't worry about that, Elli.
Tisha told me all about those
guys. Just give us the papers.
We've got some
heavy lawyers. Right?
Heavy lawyers. Right.
Because right now,
Elli, I need you to focus
on the positive message
that we're sending.
You know, rapping with
the local townspeople,
finding some time
with some of the papers here.
Wait, you mean like
a press conference?
A press conference. Yeah.
Radical idea, Elli. I love it.
No, actually, you don't.
Me and public speaking,
I can guarantee you,
not one of my strong suits.
I'm speaking from
experience here.
Hey, Michael. Hey. I
want you to meet somebody.
Let me introduce
you to Reverend Don.
He's helping with
our community outreach
and he'd love it if
you could help him
get to know the locals. Hi.
It's really great to meet you.
I don't know how
much Michael's told you,
but we're thinking
of putting on
a little free concert
for the local people here,
and we thought it
would be a great idea to
include a scene from
your theater company.
Do you think
they'd be open to it?
Yeah, they'd love that. But
you said it's for the locals?
Because the play's
very contemporary. Cool.
Hey, hey, you guys,
the phones are alive.
Mike.
Hey, your dad wants you.
I'll get some paint, but they're
just going to do it again.
They set foot here again,
I break their heads.
Dad, let me call...
Call who? That little
putz in the green shirt,
he's the son of
that state trooper.
I could boil him and his
putz of a father in tar.
Just, Dad, let's just get this
painted before Mom sees it.
Then you can start
warming up the tar.
Thanks.
Put some more of
those in the cooler.
Dad, this is all we got.
You didn't order more?
I did. And I called Karpen's,
too, for the kitchen.
I asked them all to
bring 10 times our usual.
Well, when they
come tomorrow,
you tell them to
bring 20 times more.
No, 30 times.
Where are we
going to put it all?
These people, they eat
and drink like animals,
and there's more of
them every minute.
It doesn't matter where we
put it. It'll be gone in a day.
Yes?
Couple of Buds, please.
$2. Thank you.
You got that thing working? Yeah.
Don't touch those wires.
Let's see what you got
to put on. Nothing much.
Judy Garland live. Haven't
heard this in a long time.
It's hard to
believe she's gone.
Actually, I can believe
it. I met her once.
Wow. Was she fun?
She was brimming over.
I'm Elliot.
Hey. Paul. Construction. You
seen the stage we're building?
No.
It's huge.
Wow. Do you want
another beer?
No, thanks.
I've got a thing going
with some Lebanese Red
right now.
Your old man doesn't mind
if we light up in here?
He can't smell.
Too much roofing tar.
Cool.
More. More, come on.
Okay, okay.
Good. Good, good, good.
$40.
Ma.
Ma. Tisha says you're trying to charge
extra for pillows and soap again.
We talked about this.
Don't accuse me!
I got nothing to sell anyway,
not even toilet paper!
Which leads me to ask, where
do you think all these people
you're renting space to are
going to do their business?
You've got to stop, Ma.
Enough with the money.
We just paid
off the mortgage.
Think about it!
Can't you just be happy?
What're you doing?
Hey!
No! No!
No shtupping in the bushes! Ma, come on.
Come on.
Excuse me, when does
the ticket office open?
Not yet! Soon!
Good morning. You must be
the lovely wife and child.
What's up, Dad?
We were just
telling your pops here
it looks like you guys are
getting some nice business.
Yeah?
So, it looks like
you can use some help.
He's talking
nonsense, Elli.
Something about exclusive
transportation and security for $10,000.
I get it. No, you
don't get it. We get it.
You got live entertainment
happening here, beverages, etcetera.
Yeah. We cover the hotels around the
racetrack in Monticello. We cover you.
And what if I say
you don't?
Charlie, what do we
do if he says we don't?
You're trespassers. Get
out, or I make you get out.
Is that so?
You hear this?
Enough with these bums!
Dad, what're you doing? Stop.
Hey, come on. Hey!
No, stop!
Come on, get...
Christ almighty!
Go on.
Get out of here!
Jesus! You people
are like animals.
Get out!
Get out of my property!
I'll show you!
Get off my property!
Get out! Don't try
to come back here!
Next time we
won't be so nice!
My arthritis is killing me. I told
you not to stand at the bar all night.
Dad, Ma,
you're superheroes.
Far out.
You didn't
tell me anything.
How would you know what
I tell you? You're deaf.
Hey, Elliot.
Hey.
What do you think
of the mess we're making?
It's...
Wonderful, isn't it?
It is. Yeah, Max.
I'm just sorry everyone
in town hates our guts now.
Yours more than mine.
If that's even possible.
Sorry? Hell,
these kids are fantastic.
I've heard more thank yous and
pleases in the past three days
than I've heard in a
lifetime from those shmucks.
And believe me,
no matter what they tell you,
they're all trying to make
money off this thing, too.
I saw Bob charge
a dollar to fill a bottle
with water for
one of these kids.
A dollar?
Yeah, can you believe it?
A dollar. For water. Geez.
Four extra.
Four.
Yeah.
Elliot. You're
Elliot Tiber, right?
Yeah, that's me.
How can I help you, Miss... Vilma.
Vetty Von Vilma,
but you can call me Vilma.
Vilma.
What brings you here?
I'm supposed to
say hi from Steve.
Steve?
From the Village?
Steven?
He's gone now.
Off to San Francisco with a flower
in his hair on his sugar daddy's lap.
Yeah. Actually, my ex-sugar daddy.
Good riddance. He does
like them mean and rich,
doesn't he, our Steven?
He's very...
Anyhow, he said you might be starting
some sort of a gay resort here.
Well, resorting as well as
reclining is my specialty.
And as I was on my way to
visit my mother in Buffalo,
I thought I'd stop by.
Look what I stumbled into.
By the way, those clowns you and
your dear parents chased off...
Not nice people. I know.
I was playing the horses,
if you know what I mean,
over by the racetrack
in Monticello.
Nice bedroom community,
actually,
until that bunch tried to
confiscate my earnings.
You think they'll
be back? Here?
All I can say is you need
help. What kind of help?
That's nothing. You should
see what I'm packing up here.
My God.
I know.
But keeping to the subject
at hand for the moment,
you do need some real security
around here. And you're real security?
What?
Well, you don't look...
Okay, I may be a grandfather,
but... You're a grandfather?
I married young, the night
before I shipped out for Korea.
You were in Korea? Semper
fi, you little prick.
Sergeant, U.S. Marine Corps.
No kidding.
Yeah.
That's me with the cigar. The
other one was the love of my life.
Killed. Sniper.
I went out on patrol, found
the Chinese pissant who did it,
and broke his neck with
my own hands. Jesus.
Actually, I made
that last part up.
But I would have if I'd gotten
a hold of the son of a bitch,
and I'd do it today
if I found him.
Vilma, you're hired.
Thank you.
Welcome aboard.
You won't regret it.
Do you need some kind of
uniform? I've got uniforms, baby.
Hey, Elliot.
She's a beautiful ride.
Great way to
commute to Max's.
That's a nice suit. It's
for the press. Conference.
Sure.
You okay?
A little nervous.
Got just the thing.
You know, actually, I'm
feeling a little nauseous.
Hey, grass is a perfect
cure for nausea.
Really?
Seriously.
Well...
Yeah.
It's good shit.
Very good shit.
...and in these next few days
before the concert,
we'll also provide
daily briefings
and we're all here to
provide any follow up.
But without further delay,
here is Mr. Elliot Tiber,
the proprietor of
the El Monaco,
President of the Bethel
Chamber of Commerce,
and a community liaison for
Woodstock Ventures. Mr. Tiber.
Good afternoon, ladies
and gentlemen of the press.
Do you have a legal permit
for the concert in White Lake?
There will be a music and arts festival
held here on August 15th, 16th, and 17th,
part of my ongoing yearly
music and arts festivals
that have made White Lake the truly
international cultural center that it is.
As evidenced by the fact that
you wonderful ladies and gentlemen
of the press are
here to report on it.
I have been proud to be the
artistic director of the festival
in its prior incarnations,
and I hope that...
Yes, but do you have a
legal permit for the concert?
Of course.
Need I remind you,
I am the President.
I am the President of the
Bethel Chamber of Commerce.
Would a leading civic leader
such as myself break his own laws?
That doesn't make sense.
Do you realize that the
police are now estimating
that perhaps as many as 100,000
people will attend the concert?
What will your people here in
White Lake think of 100,000 hippies
and what they
will do to the town?
My people?
You say my people.
Native White Lakians
cannot be considered people,
you know,
mine or anyone else's.
Can you tell us something
about these free programs
for the local community
happening this week?
Will there be a cap on
the number of tickets sold,
and how will you deal with
people showing up without tickets?
You are asking
about freedom.
The very essence
of the enterprise,
of all enterprise,
especially free enterprise.
And freedom
could be considered,
and is often considered, you know, to
be just another word for being free.
Therefore, there will be no train to
freedom. Train has already left the station.
How can the music be free when the
people of White Lake are enchained?
If one song is not free,
then all songs are not free.
That is why we are going to
free all the songs in White Lake.
Any idea what the hell
is going on here?
Wow, Elliot.
You stood strong up there.
That freedom rap, yeah.
That was heavy.
Thanks, Mike. You smell good.
Like an apple fritter.
Far out.
What's happening?
Didn't you hear?
It's free, man.
Come on.
The concert's free.
Come on, let's go.
Stop. Here.
That's it.
Come on. Let's go. Let's
go. Come on, let's go.
Dad!
Let's go.
Come on.
We've got an artist here.
He's been out here two
hours already. Won't budge.
All right, come on.
Come here. Just wait.
All right. Hold it!
Your dad says
you're a painter.
When did he say that?
I had him give me a tour of the property,
you know, getting a lay of the land.
He talked a lot about you,
about Brooklyn.
He showed me some of his favorite
places, the oaks down by the lake.
Nice.
Wait.
Are you sure that was my dad?
Maybe it was somebody else's?
I mean, he doesn't have any
favorite places here, he hates it.
He doesn't talk.
I didn't say it was therapy or
anything, you know. It was just chatting.
Chatting?
His mind must be going.
Don't worry, Elliot.
I'll keep an eye on him.
If he starts to laugh or smile
or anything suspicious like that,
I'll let you know.
Yeah. You do that.
In fact, I have to go collect
his bat, we've got dawn patrol.
Vilma?
Does my dad know,
you know, what you are?
Elliot.
I know what I am.
That does make it easier for
everyone else, doesn't it?
After the concert, we've got
tables set up near the barn.
I understand your mother
is preparing her specialty.
Cholent? Oh, no.
And the Ladies Auxiliary
has made dessert.
We just have to make sure
somebody rations them.
There's a lot of hungry
kids out there.
Don, I just want to say,
I have a feeling.
Feelings?
Feelings are good.
Get over to the south field,
find what-is-his-name,
and round up all those...
They don't really know where
to put all the sunflower seeds.
How many sunflower seeds
did they buy?
How many sunflower seeds can you get into
the back of a triple-axle trailer truck?
I'm not sure. I'm sorry. We
actually have another meeting...
Everybody's working
hard for...
Yes. Very hard.
Hey, John.
That's him.
That's the prick who told
everyone that the concert's free.
Fuck the alfalfa...
Considering that we haven't
managed to build a ticket booth yet,
can't really
argue with him.
It's incredible. Knocking down
the walls, and all kinds of stuff.
Well, we gotta make
some space in here, but...
Doris? Doris,
he doesn't... Doris?
He doesn't even know
what a purchase order is.
I'm trying to help organize
moving everybody
from here in the horseshoe
up to the site.
Trucks, trailers,
everything, gotta go.
Gonna miss this place.
Yeah, well,
we'll keep some rooms here.
The one concern is the big
towers for the speakers.
They're not staying up?
No, they're good. Solid.
It's just that if there's rain,
lightning, well, might get a little...
A little what?
Electrical.
We're working on it.
Yeah, we don't wanna
fry too much of the audience.
Yeah, that's a good point,
Joel. Thank you, John.
Hey. It's August.
It's not gonna rain.
Remember, okay?
Rice, bananas,
anything that's gonna
keep them from shitting.
Because I'm worried
about our toilet numbers.
Now we're together nearly
every single day, singin'
We're so happy and that's
how we're gonna stay, singin'
No, no one stole the car, I just
gotta keep it for a few days.
Sure, it's legal.
Everything is fine, Mom. Don't worry.
I've met so many beautiful people here.
Thank you.
Hairy Pretzel, thank you.
It's so great that you have
let us share your music
with all your friends and your
parents, here in White Lake.
Now we would like
to introduce to you
the resident theater artists,
here at the El Monaco this summer,
the Earthlight Players,
who have adapted Anton
Chekhov's classic, Three Sisters,
to a contemporary,
happening interpretation,
and they would like now to share
a part of that experience with you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Earthlight Players.
Artifice and imagination!
Truth and fiction!
The players play!
But you, the audience,
you sit and judge.
You sit and judge.
But the revolution requires
the roles must be reversed!
The players
are the judges now.
Your revelry must end, and your
souls will be bared for all to see.
Christ who died for you,
but not for me!
Now we are Christ!
Our nakedness
will reveal your own.
Indecent legions of decency!
Fascist pornographers!
Racist warmongers!
Republican cocksuckers!
Indecent legions of decency!
Fascist pornographers!
Put your clothes back on.
Billy. Billy.
Jesus Christ.
Racist warmongers!
Fascist pornographers!
Billy!
Get your ass down here!
Everything is gone...
Annie?
Elliot. Namaste.
Hi, Elliot.
Namaste, dear Elliot.
Hey, Georgette.
How are we doing?
Hey, Elliot.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
Here.
Thanks.
All right.
Where we going with these?
Barn.
Stan and your theater guy set
up some medical volunteers.
The combination of the bare
feet and the brown acid...
Real.
Yeah.
Anyway, I hope you don't mind, we
just were grabbing everything we can.
And your mom gave me
these blankets.
My mom? Gave?
Yeah. She's cool.
Hey.
Hey, Dad?
Dad.
The New York State Thruway
has been backed up all the way
from the George Washington
Bridge to the Catskills exits,
and from there,
it's basically a parking lot.
Police are now planning
to put into effect
a first-ever emergency
closing of the entire Thruway.
We go now to John Stevens,
who is in the field...
Ma, you okay?
The nisht-gute...
Evil!
You seen the chicken legs
on some of these hairy people?
Mom, they're kids,
not evil spirits.
You don't know!
They've made all the roads one-way
now, Elli, one-way just to Max's.
God forbid,
what if your father
should have a heart attack
from all this running around?
He couldn't get
to the hospital.
You're really worried
about him, aren't you?
Him? It's you
who brought this.
How will you live
with the guilt?
Hit him in the kisser, hit him
in the guts, nine, ten, out!
Hey. Give me three.
How you doing, Dad?
How should I be doing?
I haven't slept in three days, my hip
is killing me, and the beer's warm.
So, you're good? Yeah, I'm
good. Hand me that bottle.
You're ready for one?
I thought you'd never ask.
How you doing, kid?
I haven't slept in three
days, the beer's warm,
I'm actually not making this
up, but my hip is killing me.
So, you're good?
Come on, Elliot.
I'm standing near the
intersection of Route 17B and 55,
where state authorities now estimate
that perhaps half a million kids
have already made it
to the White Lake area,
and there's another million trying to
get here who will just never make it,
putting upstate communities in an
uproar at this major hippie invasion.
Bob!
What's this all about?
We got the permit pulled, you idiot!
We're shutting this thing down!
But there's a half a million
people over at Max's.
How do you think
they're gonna react?
That's the same thing
the cops said...
Before they laughed at us
as if we were children.
So we're doing it
ourselves!
Right.
Hi, Elliot!
Come on.
Not so tough anymore,
are you?
Come on, you.
Go to hell!
Fuck you, old man!
You get off my property,
you thugs.
You faggot freak.
Hippie lover!
This is where
we rinse the sheets.
Hey, brother.
You hear that?
It's starting.
Elli,
you should go.
What?
To Max's.
I can't.
You guys would...
We can take care
of things here.
Dad...
You go.
Go see this thing.
Go.
See what the center
of the universe looks like.
Yeah, sure.
Bet you thought you were just gonna
drive right up to the thing, huh?
Actually, my family,
we own the motel here.
The El Monaco, huh?
So you're the guy they're all
blaming for bringing all this here.
Governor just declared this
whole county a disaster area.
Yeah, it's a disaster. I'm
the disaster guy, officially.
No kidding. I was looking
forward to just coming up here
and clubbing a bunch of
hippies over the head.
But instead,
I don't know.
I must be getting
high off the fumes.
Peace, man.
See what I mean?
Groovy.
I think I'm gonna head over
and check it all out.
On foot? It’ll take you
all afternoon with this crowd.
Here.
Thanks.
Officer.
What do you say to all those
young men fighting in Vietnam
while you're here
enjoying yourselves?
We're waging peace, man. We're
teaching peace to the world.
You think they're gonna understand
that? While they're bleeding and dying?
Why won't they...
Find your buddy, girls!
The innocent people
of North Vietnam...
Bombs for peace!
War bombs for peace!
Yeah,
dream on there, buddy.
Hey, it could happen.
I know you can do it.
Come on, just for fun.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you, Sister.
Peace to you.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Come on, burn them, sisters!
Burn your bras and read this!
You've gotta join
this demonstration.
Stop the pollution.
Keep our rivers clean.
Hey, man.
Hey.
You look thirsty.
I am.
Thanks.
Have you guys been down
to see the festival yet?
We're cool,
and we'll get there again.
We got to the top of the hill,
and looked down at the sea,
and the tiny little people on stage
with their waves of tiny electric voices.
Like ants making thunder,
man. It was cool.
But you couldn't really tell
who was jamming down there.
And we left our trip
in the car.
And the shit they're passing
around down there, not quality.
Ours is beautiful.
I see you have California
plates. Is that where you're from?
There, and New Mexico...
And Oregon.
You're from everywhere.
We're from everywhere.
I'm from here.
You're from here, man.
That's so cool.
I guess so.
Man,
you're amazingly from here.
Here, man,
take a ride to here and now.
Eight miles high.
I'm actually
a little afraid of heights.
What the heck.
Hey.
Come on in, sit.
So...
Yeah?
You sure that was acid?
I didn't really taste any...
It just takes a while.
Hey, let's listen to some
of our own sounds.
What? What's that?
Hey, it's okay.
Just breathe.
Hey, it's okay,
just breathe.
It's okay, just breathe.
Just breathe.
Hey, it's okay.
It's okay.
Just breathe.
Where are my arms?
Where's my arm?
It's right here.
Just breathe.
Hey. Let's go down to
the ocean. Let's go swim.
Elliot. You look well.
I want you to meet the ladies
from St. Paul's in Liberty.
They made 5,000 sandwiches!
Vilma,
don't exaggerate.
We made 4,000.
Honey, please. Anything more
than one is a miracle in my book.
My God! Look at him! Where
have you been all day and night?
How was the concert?
Well, I met some friends
on the way there.
It was great.
Are you hungry?
I'm starving.
So I was thinking,
when this is over...
What a mess.
It'll take months
to clean up.
We can keep some of these
new people on, right?
We can afford the help now.
And with the place paid off,
maybe it's time you thought
about some permanent staff.
Some people to help run the
place, make some improvements.
What are you talking about?
That's why we have you.
I'm just saying. I was thinking when
this is over, with all the money now,
I could take a trip. And where
did you get those pajamas?
You're not going anywhere
dressed like that.
We've made brownies. Wonderful
brownies. Very special brownies. Elliot?
We'll take a pass.
Right.
You see, Jake?
That's just like him.
He doesn't want dessert, but
does he think to ask his mother?
You know what?
That's enough.
You know, I'm the only one here,
out of hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of thousands of people,
who's having breakfast with his parents!
Do you think Janis Joplin's mom is
standing backstage telling her to tuck her,
I don't know, her whiskey bottle
back into her pocket or something?
Or Jimi Hendrix's mom is
telling him to wash his hair?
I'm gonna lie down, then I'm going
to Max's and I'm gonna enjoy myself.
And you know what? Go ahead. I'd
love to see you eat a brownie.
You should have two!
Elli!
Hey, Elliot.
Hey.
See you guys later.
Billy?
Man,
I remember this hill.
Remember remember, or, like,
Vietnam flashback remember?
Remember remember, man.
Homecoming. Senior year. We
fucking massacred Monticello.
I caught like three touchdown
passes. Rum and Cokes.
And we fucking tipped
three of Yasgur's cows,
man, right there,
at the top of that hill.
And Shirley Livingstone,
man, right there,
at the top of that hill.
Wait a second.
That was you?
Was.
Is.
And that's
the Shirley Livingstone,
the one who works
at the animal hospital?
Yeah.
We were engaged, man.
Come on, man.
I love this fucking hill.
Billy!
I love this hill!
We love this hill!
The prodigal son returns.
Well, you know,
I didn't quite,
you know, go.
I got it.
I'm happy to see you,
Elliot. Come on.
I want you to meet some
very, very groovy people.
You gave them
the hash brownies?
They told me
you said I should.
How many?
Four each.
Elliot! My baby!
Her baby!
My little baby. My filthy baby
boy. Give Mamma some of that dirt.
Dad.
She got up in her sleep,
walked over there and...
What's with the money?
We've been depositing everything
that's come in this week.
Where did
all that come from?
Ma, what the hell?
Don't come near me,
you two.
But what...
This is mine.
It's my savings
for 20 years.
It's my savings.
Jesus,
how much you got there?
None of your business.
$97,000.
Dad, did you know
about this?
You think she'd tell me?
You'd have let
the bank foreclose?
Let me put all my earnings
into this place.
And you...
Elli.
Why does it matter?
We're rich now.
Elli, I was scared.
Mom.
I've got to fix your father his lunch.
Hey, man. What do you
think of the kids here?
I think it's great. I got one here
myself and I got one in Vietnam,
and I wish he were
here in the mud.
Hey, Elliot.
What?
Just come around.
Stay on the wood.
Yeah,
everything's electric now.
What are you up to?
Thought I'd try to see
the concert finally.
Maybe later. They can't get
anyone to play right now.
There's too many shocks.
That's a bummer.
How's your day going?
Yeah.
No, no.
My family, you know...
Sorry.
It's trivial compared to what
you guys are going through.
Maybe it's the most important thing
happening in the whole universe.
How do you know?
I'm pretty sure it's trivial,
you know, in perspective.
Perspective is what
shuts out the universe.
Everyone with their
little perspective.
It keeps the love out.
I'm so tired. I'm starting to talk
like that swami what's-his-face.
Far out.
Anyway, I'll see you.
Yes?
Come on in.
You're up early.
I couldn't sleep.
Hey, Dad.
I was gonna come say
goodbye. I hope that's okay.
Listen.
Sit.
A month ago,
I was a dying man.
I would think to myself, "It's
nice of Elli to come back here
"to tend to a dying man. "
Who knows?
Maybe tomorrow I'll be dead.
But now,
I'm alive.
You understand?
No.
It's because of you.
Because of you I'm alive.
And what should I want now, but
for you, my son, to live, too?
That's not so much to ask.
No, it isn't.
They're all starting to
leave, the young people.
Who knows where?
They don't even know.
And now you're one of them.
You go.
I'll stay in touch.
I'll be back.
Yeah, sure you will.
Elliot.
My hip, my...
Elli, that business
with your mother...
Don't worry about it.
No.
Dad, can you just
tell me one thing?
What?
How have you done it?
I mean, how have you lived
with her more than 40 years?
I love her.
Hey, Mike.
Elli, you made it.
Yeah, finally.
It's amazing.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Hey, thanks for calling and welcoming
us to your international resort, man.
The whole world came, and now
everyone's pulling together.
Yeah. It's all just like
you said, Mike, isn't it?
Yeah, three days
of peace and music.
So what happens now?
Man, who knows?
Everybody's gotta chase
the money now, right?
Yeah.
We're all probably gonna sue
each other, but that's cool.
We'll figure it out.
What about you?
I don't know.
I put all my stuff in my car.
Hey, that's a sign.
If your car moves, come look me
up. I'm going to San Francisco.
Me and Chip
and some of the guys,
we're gonna help out
with a truly free concert.
It's gonna be even more
beautiful than this one.
Wow.
Yeah.
The Rolling Stones.
Rolling Stones?
Yeah, Stones.
Beautiful.