Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Marcus.
How are you?
It's been an hour.
I thought I'd try...
one last time.
You should have stayed
in San Francisco, Dr. Kogan.
By signing this consent form,
you'll be donating your body to a noble cause.
You'd...
have a second chance...
through my research
to live again.
You know what I did.
My brother and two cops
are dead because of me.
I'm not lookin'
for a second chance.
But I'm not the only one
with a death sentence, am I?
Do you think I'm gonna kill
your cancer this permanent?
I'm not worried
about myself.
I'm worried about
the future of the human race.
I'll sell it to you.
For what?
A kiss.
So that's what
death tastes like.
You are doing something
very noble.
I'm guilty. Just cut me up
until there's nothing left.
That I walk through the valley
of the Shadow of Death.
I will fear no evil.
For thou art with me,
thy rod and my staff,
they comfort me.
Do you have
any last words?
Bag Art, this is Black Hawk Six. Result in outer
Skynet target. TTO 11 seconds, taken close.
- Come on, come on!
- Move, move!
Connor is on the ground.
This mission
is a quick in-and-out.
Command teams the information on those
computers should be at the highest priority.
Connor, there's no sign
of the machines. They're gone.
We too quiet. It's almost like
they were waiting for us.
What the hell's that smell, man?
Whoa! You're seeing this?
Olson. Objective located.
There's something else you'd have to see.
We got what we came for, Barbaros.
The clock's ticking.
Spread out, secure the perimeter.
I got a big gap over here.
Why didn't we know
about this?
Sir, I think this is what Command's
looking for. I'm in their source code.
These people are being taken
up north to San Francisco.
Some sort of R&D project,
for a new Terminator.
Send it to Command.
It's uploading,
I need two minutes.
Wait, wait, wait.
Go back. Go back!
Stop!
- T-800.
- A new Terminator.
Thought you said
it would be...
It's worse.
Connor, get your nose out of that.
None of your business.
You're not
leading this mission.
Alright, let's cut these
sorry bastards loose. Come on, let's go!
- Kirk, come in.
- What's that?
Connor,
get your ass top-side.
Remind those men
they need to answer me on the radio,
even if they're dead.
Connor,
get those men to respond.
Olson,
something's wrong up here.
Top-side, come in!
Help out enemy aircraft,
I'm in pursuit.
There are human prisoners
aboard there. Get after 'em!
Pay to transpond the plane.
Connor, we're joining you, top--
Bravo Ten, Bravo Ten.
Do you copy? Over.
Eagle White to Bravo Ten.
Bravo Ten, do you copy? Over.
Bravo Ten, Bravo Ten,
do you copy? Over.
- Here.
- Bravo Ten, identify. Over.
Connor!
We'll send units
to the extraction point.
How many survivors are outside?
Over.
One.
Copy.
Return to base, sir?
- RGB?
- Negative. Take me to Command.
Command!
Roger, re-routing.
Request has been denied.
Command doesn't want to give up their position.
- Radio cogs, over.
- Are they down there?
Request
has been denied, sir.
Need to go home.
It's straight from the top.
You open up that ramp!
And you tell them...
I need divers for a log-in.
- Now!
- This is crazy.
John Connor,
prophesied leader of the Resistance.
Soldier, you put every man
and woman in this sub
in jeopardy with
your little frogman stunt.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- What did we find down there?
You'll be pleased down
the need-to-know basis.
Well, I need to know, because my men
died down in that hole.
What did we find
down there?
We found the solution,
Connor,
that can end this war,
once and for all.
We know the machines use short-wave
transmitters to communicate.
Our intel has located a hidden signal
under the primary channel.
It allows for direct control
on the machines.
Skynet's a machine, and like all machines,
it has an off-switch.
- Does it work?
- Will it work? Yes.
Have we field-tested it?
No.
Give it to me.
I'll do it.
I'll test it.
Connor, you can stay Comm unit.
Have a nice one record.
Alright.
Leave Connor top-side.
Prepare for lock-out.
Connor,
we do this right...
The war is over.
Remind our offensive
in 4 days.
Connor...
These are the codes
for the signal.
- Good luck.
- Why four days?
A kill list was intercepted
from Skynet.
It says everyone in this room
will be dead by week's end.
You are number two
on the list.
- Well, who's number one?
- I don't know.
A civilian.
Kyle Reese.
Barnes...
My brother...
He didn't make it, did he?
This is tape number 28.
It's Sarah Connor to my son, John.
What's most difficult for me
is trying to decide what to tell you
and what not to.
Should I tell you
about your father?
Will it affect your decision to send
him back in time to protect me,
knowing that
he is your father?
And he'll be younger than you,
only a teenager,when you meet him.
Kyle. Person could go crazy
thinking about this.
But if you don't send Kyle,
you can never be
and Skynet will win the war.
Want to talk about it?
Kyle is out there
somewhere alone
and Skynet
is hunting him.
What about the signal?
What do you think?
- If it works, it's incredible.
- Yeah.
- We have to be careful.
- I agree.
- But we have to try.
- Okay.
Alright then, start with something small,
something more familiar with.
We should try to capture a Hydrobot,
bring it in for testing.
What is it, John?
Kill Kyle Reese,
reset the future.
No John Connor.
Come with me
if you want to live.
What is that?
She doesn't talk,
but you need to start.
Where did you
get that jacket?
The other guy
didn't need it.
You see that red?
It stands for blood.
It's a symbol of the Resistance.
You're obviously not a Resistance fighter,
so take it off!
You oint a gun at someone,
you better be ready to pull the trigger.
I'm going to ask you
one more time.
- What the hell was that thing?
- A Terminator.
T-600.
What day is it?
What year?
2018.
What happened here?
Judgement Day happened.
I gotta get outta here.
You can't go on foot.
Machines will cut you down.
You need speed.
I need a car.
Look, there's some by
Griffith Observatory.
- I don't know now.
- Take me.
Get down!
That was
a Hunter Killer.
Thanks to you,
they know we're here.
What's your name,
kid?
Kyle Reese.
Come on.
We burn down the transmitters
so it can't talk to any of its pals
that it can still recieve.
Turn it on!
You got it?
Hold it down!
Hold a bit...
Get me a strap.
Holy shit!
- Just hold it tight.
- The signal has to be continuous.
If there's
any interruption...
Let's rig up
a portable shortwave.
I need to test it on something larger
in the field.
Destroy this thing.
- So where are the cars?
- You don't want to go out after dark.
Hunter Killers have infrared.
Hunt better at night.
We'll all go
tomorrow morning.
- What is that?
- Two-day old of coyote.
Better than three-day old coyote.
- Grab it.
- What?
Grab it.
Magic.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
- Does this radio work?
- No.
My dad tried to fix it, but...
he could never get it to work.
Hold that.
- Where is everybody?
- They're gone.
So why are you
still here?
'Cause we're the Resistance.
L.A. branch.
Welcome
to the headquarters.
Resistant to what?
Machines.
Skynet.
- Just the two of you?
- Yeah.
How come you're not wearing
one of these?
'Cause I haven't
earned mine, yet.
I hope
he's listening to this.
We've been fighting a long time,
and we've all lost so very much,
so many loved ones gone.
But you are not alone.
There are pockets of Resistance
all around the planet.
We are at the brink...
Do a sea magic trick.
Hold that up.
Press the button.
If we had to finally...
less than 100 meters.
We've had a lot of firepower but the T-600's
are heavy, and slow their primitive design.
Who is that?
If you can help or no...
then you have one option.
Their motor cortex is partially
exposed to the back of their neck.
A knife to this area will disorientate
their tracking device
but not for long.
Above all, stay alive.
You have no idea how important you are
and how important you will become.
The machines are advancing
even faster than I told you they would.
I've seen it with my own eyes.
They were inventing new Terminators.
New ways of killing us.
Skynet is planning
something big.
But the Resistance
is planning something bigger.
This is John Connor.
If you're listening to this,
you are the Resistance.
John Connor.
We gotta find this guy.
So...
You get it working?
- Almost.
- Good.
Look, I figure
we head east, right?
We go through the desert, then we can
connect with the Resistance there.
- I'm heading north.
- No. No, no, no, no.
The machines control the whole
Northern Sector upto San Francisco.
That's Skynet's central.
I have to find someone.
There's a lot that you don't
understand about Skynet, okay?
It's just too dangerous
for us to go there.
What about
the L.A. branch?
Come on, man.
We need to get out of L.A.
[ Song: Rooster
Band: Alice in Chains ]
What is that?
Something my brother
used to listen to.
Star, get out.
Don't look at me
like that, Star.
Get out.
Get out!
You're leaving?
You're gonna leave us?
Ah, I get it.
Do you want to know the difference
between us and the machines?
We bury our dead.
But no one is coming
to bury you.
Air attack!
- It's a chopper of a Terminator.
- Go! Drive!
They must have heard
the music.
- Keep the steering.
- I've never driven before.
This thing is pissing me of.
I'll drive!
We're seeing a lot of
enemy movement in L.A.
Any more people
in the area?
No one on the ground. Two 8-10s
in the air. Williams and Marhadi.
Send the birds down.
Guide them to a safe area.
Roger, Coward 6-7
in console.
Ten miles to bring.
Lima-Alpha, 1-2-5-7-9-0-3. Over.
- Copy that.
- Roger, Wild Eagle. Final copy.
Hey, there's someone here.
Get down, now! Move!
Drop your weapons.
Is there a problem?
Hey, we saw
your Resistant sign.
The old lady put it there,
not me.
What do you want?
We're looking
for fuel.
The dark season's coming.
We only got enough
for ourselves.
You point that gun at somebody,
you better be ready to pull the trigger.
Put your guns down,
everyone.
Look, we just came
to find the Resistance. That's all.
The Resistance?
What a joke!
Fighting those machines
is impossible.
We keep our heads down,
they ignore us.
You keep your heads down
and they'll come for you eventually.
We help you
and maybe they will.
These people
aren't gonna help you.
Let's go.
You're not going anywhere.
Not until this one
gets something to eat.
Bring me a basket.
Here you go.
Come on, help yourself!
Eat up.
Are you alright, son?
It's our food.
Our fuel.
It's not your choice
to make!
Star, Star!
Damn!
You brought them here!
You brought them here.
- Stop, stop!
- Come on, wait.
- Head for the tunnels!
- Truck!
We can't
just run for it.
Shoot it!
Go, go, go!
come on!
It didn't work.
Shit!
Throttle Terminators!
Shoot this
son of a bitch!
Marcus,
turn right up here.
Hold on!
Where is the other one?
Come on!
Star,
give me the gun.
Hang on!
- Drop the ball!
- Uh, alright.
Kyle!
Marcus! Marcus!
I got my eyes on
two targets.
We've got two bogeys at 270ş. They've never
come this deep before. They're looking for something.
H.K. is down.
We've got an "H.K" porching our six.
Come over by. Breaking off.
Evasive maneuvers
now!
It's got a lock on you.
Break off.
- Eject, Williams, eject!
- Punching out.
There's your transport,
headed northwest,
bearing 2-8-9
towards San Francisco.
First,
test the signal.
And pray it works.
You okay?
Get my knife.
It's in my left boot.
- What's your name?
- Blair Williams.
What's yours?
Name's Marcus.
You can let me down now,
Marcus.
- That thing, where'd it go?
- The transport?
Skynet.
Where the hell are you going?
After it.
Hate to break it to you but, if you've got
friends on that thing. They're good as dead.
The same with you
if you keep walking in that direction.
They've only been dead a while
and I am getting used to it.
Why don't you come with me
to my base?
Connor might know why.
Listen, if you've got a problem
with the machines,
he's definitely the guy
you wanna talk to.
- How far is your base?
- It should be 1 or 2 days hike.
It's that way.
What are you saying?
Speak English!
I was telling him...
It is not true,
- the part of machines killing us.
- They're gonna kill us.
They're gonna kill everyone.
We are in a cattle cart, or we're on
our way to the slaughterhouse.
Calm down.
You're not helping.
The most important thing
that we can do right now
is stay alive.
In here and in here.
Alright?
Just stay alive.
Over there.
Find something that can burn.
We'll be at my base tomorrow.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
What you got there?
Just some antibiotics.
Antibiotics are hard
to come by these days.
Listen, I don't have much, but...
you're welcome to whatever you need.
We've been watching you.
Looking for this?
Come on, guys.
Machines are the enemy.
We're on the same side.
No, no. See, I've got
a couple of friends on my side.
Maybe they can carry you home...
when I'm done with you.
You might want
a chamber around.
Kill me,
you ain't gonna win this war.
Oh, God!
I'm a little cold.
Relax.
I just want
some body heat.
You have
a strong heart.
God,
I love that sound.
Thank you...
for saving me
back there.
I don't meet a lot
of good guys these days.
I'm not a good guy.
You are.
You just don't know it, yet.
Do you think people
deserve a second chance?
Yeah.
I do.
This is it.
Skynet's Valley of Death.
We've never been
this deep before.
We've got to be sure
this thing works in their territory.
On the bigger machines.
That will bring them in.
H.K.
They're coming.
Turn it up!
It works, man.
The signal works.
It's beautiful!
- Commander Ashdown.
- Connor, tell me it works.
It works. That is affirmative.
The signal works.
Good.
The attack commences tomorrow
at 0400, worldwide.
Your unit will be at the board
of a bombing in Skynet Central.
What is the extraction plan
for the prisoners?
Extraction plan?
There is no extraction plan.
We're gonna level the place.
Negative, I told you. Skynet Central
is filled with human prisoners.
This is war, Connor.
Leadership has its cost.
You, above all, should know that.
Ashdown, come in! Ashdown, Connor.
Ashdown, Con... Damn him!
- Blair.
- What?
This is us.
The mines are magnetic.
If we head due west
at this point of entry, we're good.
I'll go first.
Let's go, Marcus.
I'm starving.
This is the beginning
of something wonderful.
The son of a bitch is here.
What do we've got here?
He stepped on a landmine.
- Start a large four IV. Keep it open.
- Patient needs more morphine.
- What's his name?
- Marcus.
- He's got a prosthetic limb?
- What?
Okay, pulse is dead.
Let's see what we've got here.
Barnes...
The Devil's hands
have been busy.
- What is it?
- It's real flesh and blood.
Though it seems
to heal his off quickly.
The heart is human,
but very powerful.
The brain too,
but with a chip interface.
It has a hybrid nervous system.
One human cortex. ...
- One machine.
- What the hell would have they done?
Who built you?
My name is
Marcus Wright.
You think
you're human?
I am human.
No!
Where were you
manufactured?
I was born...
August 22nd, 1975.
I know you.
I heard your voice
on the radio.
- You're John Connor.
- Of course you know me. You were sent here to kill me.
Kill the leadership.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Then why are you here?
Blair said you could help me
find who I'm looking for.
Now let me down.
If I let you down...
you'll kill everyone in this room.
Just you, Connor.
'Cause I ain't
give a shit about you.
I didn't even know your name
until two days ago.
No?
You and me...
We've been at war,
since before
either of us even existed.
You tried killing my mother,
Sarah Connor.
You killed my father,
Kyle Reese.
You will not
kill me.
Kyle Reese is on a transporter,
heading to Skynet.
If I wanted
to kill him,
I would have done it
in L.A.
Where did you
find that thing?
You sent Mariah and me
to provide cover for some civilians.
He was
one of them.
Was there
a teenage boy?
I honestly don't know.
They were taking him to a transport.
- He was the only one left.
- Not he, Blair. It.
It was the only one left.
Don't be naďve.
It saved my life.
Kate, what's gonna
happen to him?
Disassembled.
You mean killed?
It may have information
on Skynet.
I know
he's not the enemy.
I've been shot at by the enemy.
That's not him.
That machine saved you only
to gain access to kill all of us.
We're gonna be okay.
Don't worry.
For my brother.
Connor wants
to see you.
What for?
Like he's going to tell me,
Barnes.
Let me see that.
- You want me to tell Connor you're not coming?
- No.
Watch him.
I told you everything
I know, John.
Skynet is ruthless
and unpredictable.
They will use the best part of you
against yourself,
and they will have methods
I can't imagine or predict.
That I can't
help you with.
And when you're unsure,
which just always follow your heart, John.
I love you.
Goodbye.
There's nothing on the tapes
about machines with organs.
That thing in there...
I thought I knew
our enemy.
But that thing...
That makes me feel like
I know nothing.
I looked in its eyes,
and it believes,
absolutely believes,
that it is human.
It believes in everything
that it says,
and it is telling me
that Kyle Reese is in Skynet.
If that is true...
The Command is about to bomb my
father and the rest of those prisoners
and I cannot stop them.
Thank you.
Come in!
Barnes.
What about Blair?
- She made her choice.
- Get down!
Let's move.
- Put a light out there.
- We're back in the minefield.
I have a plan.
- Blair, you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay!
- Get your team back!
- There they are!
Run! God!
Now what?
M-My plan stopped
at the jeep.
I'll draw the fire.
You take out the light.
Keep your head down!
Go, go, go, go!
Come on!
- You alright?
- Let's get you out of here.
There they are!
Alligator, this is Cockpit 5-1,
we have eyes on the machine.
Take my gun!
Check the river.
You see him?
I'm going down!
Fall!
Give me your hand!
I know what you are,
even if you don't.
Enough!
That gun ain't
gonna stop shit!
Nobody shot you in the heart, and I see
that thing beating a mile a minute.
Kyle Reese...
He's in Skynet.
You do that, he's dead.
I can get you in.
How?
Look at me.
That's why
I don't trust you.
I'm your only hope
you have.
I need to find
who did this to me.
So do you.
Make your choice.
You kept being...
You tell me
where I can find Kyle Reese.
- Yeah?
- I will.
Contact me on that.
Let me know
he's still alive.
- What are you?
- I don't know.
Hey,
he's over here.
You alright?
Any sign of him?
He's gone.
What'd you do?
How's your leg?
I'll live.
Let me go!
Connor.
Command for you.
- This is Connor.
- Connor,are your men ready?
Negative.
Nobody is ready.
We are not,
you are not.
We must abort the attack.
The game has changed.
What are you talking about?
All our elements are past the release point.
They are in assault position!
Then delay the attack.
At least, delay the attack.
I have a chance to infiltrate Skynet
and rescue those prisoners.
Give me
that opportunity.
No, absolutely not!
This is not the time
for a rescue mission!
What you ask for will
undermine the whole operation.
Skynet has Kyle Reese.
And that is his fate.
No, it's our fate.
I have to save him.
He is the key!
The key to the future,
to the past.
Without him,
we lose everything.
No!
You stay the course!
If we stay the course, we are dead!
We are all dead!
As of this moment,
soldier,
you are relieved
to your command.
You are no longer
a part of this Resistance!
I didn't catch
that last statement.
This is John Connor.
If you're listening to this...
you are
the Resistance.
Listen carefully.
If we attack tonight,
our humanity is lost.
Command wants us
to fight like machines,
they want us to make
cold, calculated decisions.
But we are not
machines.
And if we behave like them,
then what is the point... in winning?
Command is going to ask you
to attack Skynet.
I am asking you
not to.
If even one bomb
drops on Skynet before sunrise,
our future will be lost.
So, please. Stand down.
Give me the time
to protect our future,
that all of us are fighting for.
This is
John Connor.
What should I tell your men
when they find out you're gone?
I'll be back.
I'm coming for you.
Come on, Marcus.
Okay.
Signal broadcasted
with full thrift, sir.
Good.
We have a green light
for the attack.
This is Bakersfield.
That's a no-go
on your last. Out.
Standing down. This is Reno.
Negative on your last.
Eugene, Reno, Bakersfield,
they're all standing down.
They will not attack.
Unless Connor gives the order.
Kyle Reese?
Get to your transport!
Is Kyle Reese here?
Welcome home, Marcus.
We knew you'd be back.
After all,
it was programmed in you.
Oh, and you executed
that programming beautifully.
What am I?
You are
an infiltration prototype.
The only
one of your kind.
We resurrected you.
Advanced CyberDyne's work...
amended it.
what is it?
Calculations confirmed the serene code
on this face isn't easiest for you to process.
It can be others
if you wish.
Marcus, what else could you be...
if not machine?
A man.
The human condition
no longer applies to you.
Accept what you
already know...
That you were made
to serve a purpose.
To achieve what no another
machine has achieved before.
To infiltrate,find a target,and then
bring that target back home to us.
We've been at war since before
either of us even existed.
You tried killing my mother,
Sarah Connor.
You kill me...You tell me
where I can find Kyle Reese.
Yeah, I will.
Kyle Reese!
You, move!
In times of desperation, people will
believe what they want to believe.
And so, we gave them
what they wanted to believe.
A trick, in the form of a signal,
the Resistance thought would win the war.
And they were right.
It will end this war.
Put the attack to
Skynet's Central back online.
I want our aircraft in the skies,
immediately!
Sir, sir, we got a bogey with a very large
radar signature closing in on our position.
The signal?
We have destroyed
ourselves.
Skynet tracked our signal.
We led them straight to us.
Our best machines have failed,
time and again, to complete the mission.
So we made you. We created
the perfect infiltration machine.
You, Marcus.
You did what Skynet
has failed to do for so many years.
You killed John Connor.
Don't fight, Marcus.
Remember
what you are.
I know what I am.
I'm better this way.
You will not be given
a second chance.
You cannot save
John Connor.
Watch me.
We got a message
from Connor!
He's in Skynet.
Needs air support.
Let's go!
Scram for the aircraft.
Stop!
Stop, no!
Come on!
- What's your name?
- Kyle Reese.
Stay with me!
Back!
Come on, Star,
move!
- T-800s.
- There's so many of them.
Be careful!
What are these?
Fuel cells.
Life source for the T-800.
Nuclear.
Enough to level this place.
Cover us.
You ready?
Run!Come on,
come on! Let's go!
Come here!
Come on!
We got to get
to the transport!
- Where are you going?
- I gotta end this.
I'm not gonna
leave you!
You didn't!
Who are you?
John Connor!
Hey, John Connor's
in there.
- Where?
- You show me there.
John Connor's in there!
Come with me!
Connor!
Help!
Connor, it's Kyle!
You son of a bitch!
Come on!
Let's get out of here.
John...
We can't make it back to base.
Center's down and they never say so.
How long?
His heart...can't take it.
He's going to be okay.
He's going to be okay, Kate.
Kyle?
Take it...
You earned it.
Kate... Take mine.
Marcus?
Everybody deserves
a second chance.
This is mine.
What is it
that makes us human?
It's not something
you can program.
You can't put it
into a chip.
It's the strength
of the human heart.
The difference
between us and machines.
There is a storm
on the horizon.
A time of hardship
and pain.
This battle has been won,but the
war against the machines raises on.
Skynet's global network
remains strong.
But we will not quit,
until all of it
is destroyed.
This is John Connor.
There is no fate,
but what we make.
Transcript: VeRdiKT
[SubScene.com]
Synchro: Badri_10 (Badreddine)
www.moviesubtitles.org
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org