Boss, I need a bathroom break!
Please.
Dear Lord, help me!
Get the hell out of here.
Well, that's what you get for
drinking on the job, Sloane.
Hey, Sloane, take it easy!
Sloane! Sloane! Damn it! Sloane!
You can do it!
Sloane. Sloane.
Uhh...
Dear God help us.
He's so beautiful.
That's the ugliest thing I ever saw.
Don't worry about it, Tommy.
You don't have to look pretty to
work down at the slaughterhouse.
What is that diseased
freak still doing out here?
We closed for good now.
Uh, I think he likes it here, sir.
Ain't no reason for that
ugly beast to still be here.
Jess, we need to get that oversized
retard the hell out of here.
We, sir?
Just you.
Hello, Hewitt.
We're shutting down the place today.
You know that 'cause I done told you.
Shutting down for good.
We ain't packing no more meat.
Ain't killing no more animals so...
You just leave the equipment.
You just get on home now, okay?
You gotta go, I said!
You gotta get the hell out
of here, you dumb animal!
What are you doing?
Shh! Keep your voice down.
This is how you sneak up on 'em,
How you catch 'em. Catch who?
Gooks in the swamp.
Eric, the only thing you're gonna
catch in this water is disease.
Chrissie, come on. No, I'm
not going in that water.
Consider it the last wish of a soldier.
Oh, no.
No, you've been getting last wishes
this whole past week, G.I. Joe.
And you call yourself a patriot.
You know what I think
is patriotic? What?
Me driving you across state
to go to Vietnam. Again.
You goin' all the way to Vietnam, baby?
No, honey, base camp's far
enough for me, trust me.
Just try to relax, baby,
'Cause today I'm going to use my tongue
In ways the Lord never intended.
How's that sound? Okay.
Mmm...
This may come as a shock
to you, but most men
Are into this kind of thing.
I'm sorry.
I'm just a little distracted, Bail.
I mean, I just keep thinking,
How does a person go back there?
You know, how do you do that?
It doesn't make him any more
heroic than you, baby, okay?
Yeah, but he thinks I'm
going with him, Bail.
Eric thinks I'm going
to Vietnam with him.
Well, he's your brother, he loves you.
You know, he'll get over it, okay?
Just close your eyes.
Let me see your hand.
You're gonna love this.
Can I look?
Yeah.
Eric, you got that
from a Cracker Jack box!
Wha... I... I had to eat 17
batches to find the one I wanted.
How many?
Two. Okay, girls or boys?
One of each.
And what are their names?
Bonnie and Clyde. No.
Come on. Bobby and Janis.
And where are us and
the kids gonna live?
California. Right by the water.
Don't leave me.
I ain't never gonna
leave you, beautiful.
I'll give you everything you want, baby.
Starting with this.
This is what you're gonna tell him...
You're going to walk right up to Eric,
And you're gonna tell him
that you're going to Mexico
And you're not gonna join
him in this stupid war,
No matter what some draft card says.
Okay?
Get your bony ass ready,
soldier! Moving out at 1700 hours.
What's 1700 hours?
You better be getting some, Dean.
What the hell are you still doing here?
Go home. We're out of business.
You and your family are
the only ones stupid enough
To still be living in this town.
Your kind belong in this shithole.
Operator.
May I help you?
You're gonna have to
speak more clearly, ma'am.
I don't understand. You're
gonna have to speak more clearly.
I'm your friend, Hewitt.
Come on, y'all. Look alive now.
Take one last look at
that motel over there
'Cause this here's your
lodging for the next two days.
What, are you gonna put
mints on our pillows too?
I'll tuck you in special every night.
We're going on a road trip!
So what are you gonna miss the most?
Hmm? When you're gone,
What are you gonna miss the most?
Fishing for compliments here?
No, never.
She is fishing. I am not.
Come on, tell me.
Besides you?
Nothing.
I mean, family and all, sure,
But Dean's gonna be right there with me.
Right, Deano? Hoo-Ha.
Thomas in there? No, he ain't here.
We got a... we got a
situation on our hands here.
I just came back from
the slaughterhouse.
That 'tarded nephew
of yours killed a man.
Now I'm gonna have to apprehend him.
I thought you might
want to accompany me,
Help finesse the situation, as it were.
Anyway, staying around this town,
There's no more jobs, no more money,
No more food. It's downright suicidal.
And I'm the last bit of
law enforcement that's left.
Hell, I'm moving to Michigan next week.
I often ask myself, "What
makes a man a killer?"
I don't mind saying: You
raised that retard right,
Me and you, we ain't
taking this drive right now.
You can't have a creature
like that around normal folk,
That's what I'm saying. He ain't
retarded. He's misunderstood.
Oh, shit, there he is! Jesus Christ.
You stay put.
I'll let you know when I need you.
Put down the weapon, boy!
I seen what you did back there, Hewitt.
This doesn't have to be
difficult unless'n you make it so.
Just put the weapon down.
Don't be stupid.
I think we've got a problem, Sheriff.
Shit, I just killed the whole
fucking sheriff's department.
Damn, I wondered what that felt like.
You really think you're something
in that outfit, don't you?
Here's your pants.
Supper's on the table.
Ladies love a man in uniform.
That slaughterhouse meant more to this
town than them fools will ever know.
Just a matter of time now
Before this town's overrun
by bikers and hippies.
Us, we're staying right here.
We will never abandon
the place of our birth.
We're on our own now, people.
And alone
We will rise above it all.
People may not remember
what we say here tonight,
But they sure as shit
gonna remember what we do.
Thanks to the good sheriff here,
We ain't gonna go hungry tonight.
Matter of fact,
We ain't never gonna starve again.
Mm-Mm-Mm.
Charlie, say grace.
Mama, I told you Charlie's dead.
It's Hoyt now, Sheriff Hoyt.
Oh baby, look! Come on,
can we stop at that store?
It's just like the one
in California. Please?
Yeah yeah.
Come on, Bail, you'll love this.
These places have tons of character.
Y'all have some beautiful
things in here, ma'am.
Okay...
It'll take you a little while
to get used to things in 'Nam.
The people,
The smells, but...
But what?
You'd be amazed at the
things you can get used to.
Um, is everything
okay with you and Dean?
Uh, what do you mean?
Bailey, come on. You guys have been
exchanging odd glances this whole trip.
Oh...
Excuse me, ma'am, can you tell
me where the bathroom is, please?
Through the back.
Come on, Bailey.
Look, we've been through a lot together.
Whatever it is, you can tell me.
Me and Dean are going to Mexico.
He's not gonna go with Eric.
And uh, he's not going to Vietnam.
Chrissie...
What do you have to say? I say, go.
Get the hell away from this war,
okay? Just cling to what you got.
Then why are you letting Eric go back?
It's just in him. What's in him?
The war. What do you mean?
Look, you do something long enough,
eventually you start to like it.
Hah!
Bitch. Scared the titties right off her.
God damn it.
Broke my mirror.
You think the girls
are gonna be all right
Driving back alone
after they drop us off?
Oh, I'm not worried about them, Dean.
Are you sure you got nothing to tell me?
Can we go?
You all right?
Yeah... let's just go.
You didn't even buy anything, baby.
Yeah, it was... it was nothing
like the one in California.
I guess we'll just have to
go back to that one then.
What are you doing, man?
What the hell are you
doing? I'm not going, Eric.
What do you mean, you're not going?
I'm not going, Eric!
You think I don't
hear you at night, man,
In your sleep, wailing from
what you've done over there?
Now, how could you want that for me?
I'm glad Dad's not here to see this.
What, his son the coward?
Well, guess what,
Eric, I am not like you!
All right?
I am not ready for this
shit! I have no problem
With the Vietcong over
in Vietnam or whatever...
What the hell do you think
I'm going back for, huh?
I'm going back for you! Stop it!
You think you're the only
one who's ever been scared?
You think I wasn't scared?
You think I'm still not scared?
Shut up!
What does she want?
Pull over! Pull over!
Oh God. Jesus Christ, don't pull over!
Shit, she's got a gun, Eric.
Eric!
Shut up! Stay calm.
What are we gonna do?
Eric, she's pulling...
Oh my God!
Look out!
God...
Chrissie.
Buddy, Dean, Deano...
I'm gonna get you help.
I'm gonna find Chrissie.
Chrissie!
Wow, man, I am impressed.
Y'all are tougher than I
thought. What do you want from us?
Oh... everything.
How about we get this robbery
thing out of the way, huh?
Fuck.
You play along, and I won't have to
kill this fucking cop or you. Get up!
I'm glad you're here, officer.
Oh, I just bet you are.
Whoa!
Sir.
You sit down and you stay right there.
You kids okay?
Why don't you step out of
the car, if you don't mind?
He shot her! He shot her! She
can't move, sir. She needs help.
Sir, I can't find my girlfriend.
Get a grip on yourself, son.
Sir, I can't find...
Now, that was for your own good.
Okay, come on kids. Let's
get out of the car now.
Sir, she's... she's really badly hurt.
Right, well okay, kids.
I'm gonna ask you nicely one more time.
Get out of the fuckin' car or I'm
gonna blow your fuckin' head off.
Come on, you can make it. Ooh-Ee!
You kids must have been hauling ass.
Look at the fucking mess you made.
Hey....
There ain't no fire in this accident.
Which one of you assholes
burned his draft card?
Get on over here, boys.
Come on, get over here. No.
God damn it, get over here!
Which one of you boys'
name is Dean Hill?
Honey, you're name ain't Dean, is it?
I am, sir...
I'm Dean.
Well, hey, dean. Good to meet you.
You kids took one
Big, nasty, giant shit
Right in my backyard.
Now we do know that you're
a coward, right, Dean?
I'm gonna to give you
a chance to die a hero.
All right, get her
in there, God damn it.
I'm starting to think you
like wasting my time, blondie.
Hurry up!
I saw Chrissie. You did?
She's okay. Just don't say anything.
Where is she? Shut up.
Hey, Monty, come pick
up this damn wreck.
It's about a quarter mile
south of Hodd's place.
There's a motorcycle too.
Is having a dead biker chick ride
shotgun proper police procedure, sir?
Honey, if that was your mama,
Would you want me to stick her
in the trunk like a dead animal?
I just think this is bullshit.
You got something to say about
this bullshit, do you, Dean?
No, sir.
You wouldn't lie to me, would you, Dean?
Where is the gun?
You look through all
this shit on the road?
Is that how we agreed you'd address
me over official FCC airwaves?
No, "Sheriff."
Oh...
Pretty little rascal, ain't you?
And what brings you kids here?
Sir, we were just passing through,
On my way to reenlist, sir.
You look kind of young to me.
Where was you stationed?
Vietnam, sir.
Vietnam. Really?
You kill any commies?
Uh, a handful of gooks, sir.
Where are you taking us?
Where are you taking us, sir?
How was it over there?
Well, it's a... it's
a different culture.
But you'd be amazed at the things
you get used to over there, sir.
You don't say.
This the sheriff station?
No, it's Mama's house.
Oh! Don't even think about it here.
What are we gonna do?
I'm gonna kill this motherfucker.
Hey!
You kids best not be making a mess
in my car or you'll clean it up.
He knows, Eric. What?
He knows you're not me.
No, he doesn't, Dean. Hey, Tommy!
Stay the course. We're out here!
Come on, boy, get over here!
What is that? Get the
lead out of your ass!
Come on, big guy!
What is that?
Go ahead, get her on out of there.
Come on, private!
Oh my God.
I'm gonna get us out of here, okay?
Dean! Stay with me!
I need you to be a soldier.
People are gonna come
looking for 'em, I know it.
You have made a big mistake!
Boy, are you dumb.
Nobody's gonna miss those
creatures, not one person.
Not now, not when they gone.
Let's see. Anything in here?
A bunch of shit.
Oh...
You little bastard, I know
you've got more in there.
Come on, Tommy, ain't no
different than the slaughterhouse.
Meat's meat, bones bones.
Get it done.
My daddy always told me
That if you want to be a good farmer
you gotta keep your livestock clean.
Clean goat is a happy goat.
What the hell do you want from us, man?
Are you happy yet?
Hey!
H... hey, help us. Help us down, please.
I don't get involved in his affairs. No.
Please, help me.
Please, please.
I didn't know. Didn't know what?
I didn't know you were
going back there for me.
Let's figure out how to
get out of here, Dean.
By God, I'm gonna make
a soldier out of you yet!
No! Please, please!
Are you ashamed of your country, Dean?
No, please! No!
What do you think, soldier?
What would be the proper
punishment for treason?
Just please let him go, sir. No!
I can't make out a word you're
saying, you know it, asshole?
You're killing him, sir! Please!
No no no! Please, sir!
Ain't nothing I hate worse than
a draft-Dodging hippie protester.
I'm Dean!
It was my draft card!
And you'd just stand
here and let him die.
Sir, could you let him breathe, please?
Please, can you let him breathe?
My apologies. Eric!
Oh shit!
Well, so now you want to
play soldier. Is that it?
Your brother saved your life.
I'm gonna fucking cut your head off.
Yeah, you just keep
sweet-Talking me, dumpling.
Help me!
Back in 1952, Korean War,
Yours truly was a P.O.W.
That's "prisoner of war" for you,
And I know what in the
hell I'm talking about.
Back in those days
there wasn't no rules.
No regulations like there are today.
You got captured, you had two choices:
You starve to death or survive.
Now, you had to eat.
Rations were scarce.
So, well, about once a week
Some poor soul was chosen.
Chosen?
Why are you doing this?
Got to get you cleaned up.
We're gonna have company.
You don't want to look
dirty for company, do you?
Huh?
This is your lucky day!
How would you like to just
stand right up here today
And just walk right on out of here, huh?
I'd like that, Sheriff.
Yeah, well, freedom ain't free.
You know that, right? I tell you what...
10 push-Ups stand
between you and freedom here today.
This shit is what heroes
are made of, you know?
Well, come on, I'm waiting!
Let's get with the program, sunshine!
Come on, you can do it!
Get those push-Ups now!
No!
Shh, now don't cry.
Don't cry.
No.
No!
You shut your cocksucker,
you son of a bitch!
One!
Whoa, that was a really
fine push-Up there. One...
Two...
We've got ourselves a regular
American hero here, ain't we?
Three.
Come on, sweetheart.
Ow!
Eight.
What's it gonna be?
You're gonna be the
motherfucker who eats?
Or are you gonna be the
poor sorry motherfucker
Who gets ate?
Don't give up, Dean!
Show this motherfucker!
Show me that you ain't as fucked up
As the rest of your
useless goddamn generation.
Eight!
Come on! Nine...
Go!
That's only half of one.
That don't count, boy!
Don't give up, Dean!
10. Yeah!
Don't cry.
No!
No. I never had me a little girl.
Got more guts than I
thought you had, boy.
I'm a man of my word. You're free to go.
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
My money says he ain't going nowhere.
Stop!
Please, stop!
Please stop!
Look... my friends, they...
They have my friends, okay? They're in
a house over there through the woods. I...
Look, they have your friend.
They took your friend.
I saw you both at the store.
He shot her. The sheriff shot her.
Show me where.
Weather has been so hot lately.
It's important to drink
your liquids, you know?
The body needs to hydrate.
Yeah I see.
I got me some of that breakfast tea...
Jar of ice with plenty of sugar.
Tastes like heaven.
Dean. Dean!
Dean, you did good.
But we gotta hide, okay?
Come on! Come on!
Do you have any idea
where the hell we're going?
Yes, it's...
It's here somewhere.
Sometimes...
I just can't stop eating
them little chocolates.
They're so good.
I put coconut in them.
Oh, sweet Jesus.
Hoyt! Hoyt!
Come here! Hoyt!
Eric!
He's in here! Eric! Get me out of here!
Shut your mouth! Oh, my!
He's here! He's here! He's here!
Help! Help!
There's keys over there on the counter.
Damn you! A man's home
is his fucking castle!
What the fuck are you
doing in here? Oh no!
Hey!
Find the truck. Go! I'll
get Dean! I'll get Dean!
Unlock the door!
Thomas, Thomas, get up here! I need you!
Come on, Dean, come on.
Hey! Get back here, you skinny bitch!
No!
Come on, we're gonna get out of here.
Dean, go! Go! Come on!
Shoot me, you asshole!
You're not a soldier! You hold
that gun like a fucking girl!
Get out of my way.
You're not a candy-Ass,
are you, Sheriff?
Pull the fucking trigger!
I ain't finished with you yet.
Well... let's just go
see if we caught anything.
Well well well...
It's a good thing you
didn't go to Vietnam.
Something like this might've happened.
You don't like playing with
me anymore because I'm a pussy.
That's what you said.
Well, my nephew Tommy ain't no pussy.
Maybe you want to play
with him for a little while.
That's it.
Okay, so what are we gonna do?
We? I'm gonna get my girlfriend.
No no, look. What about my friends?
What? My friends.
Fuck your friends.
You're on your own.
You asshole!
Shit.
Dean, Dean. Oh fuck. Thank God.
What happened?
Chrissie. Oh, thank
God. Oh, Jesus Christ.
No no no. Don't! I'm sorry.
Just stay still. Okay,
are you okay? You're okay.
They're psycho.
Come on, where's Eric
and Bailey? Come on.
In the house.
You need to go get help, Chrissie.
Okay?
There's no help to go for.
I have to go in there. You're gonna
stay here. I'm gonna come get you, okay?
Okay.
Don't you think you're
gonna go anyplace, huh?
I love you.
No! Come on! You don't... you
don't have to do this, man, please.
No! No. No!
No!
You don't have to do this.
You son of a bitch!
Fuck you!
Fucker.
Huh?
What the fuck...
Oh shit!
Uh, he shot me! Uh! Shut up! Shut up!
Where's the girl?
I'm gonna blow your head off.
Tell me where the girl is.
I'm shot! Shit!
How many times I gotta tell
you not to play with guns?
Oh, Jesus, oh...
Now look what you've done to yourself.
I didn't do it. Stop your
damn whining, Uncle Monty.
Mama, get some towels in here.
Uncle Monty made a mess.
Sheriff.
Who in the hell are you?
What do you want, boy? I want my girl.
Take me to her or I'm
gonna blow your head off.
Okay, all right.
Where is she? Thomas!
Hey! Do not fuck around.
Where is the girl?
Come on.
Help me!
Thomas!
Thomas, where're you at?
Eric, are you okay?
What are you doing here?
You gotta get out of here.
You're... you're gonna be
okay. How bad is it? Tell me.
No! No! It's all right. I can't feel it.
I'm gonna get you... it's
okay. Did he cut it off?
It's okay. I can't feel it.
No! No!
I'm cold.
How... how many?
Three. Boys or girls?
All boys.
What are their names?
Paul and Christopher...
And Eric.
Okay. Okay. It's gonna be okay.
I promise. I promise, okay?
Take it easy. There she is.
Help me.
That's not her.
Shit, that ain't her.
You don't want to see the other girl.
Just shoot him!
You dumb son of a bitch.
Get him, Tommy, come on!
Damn it! Come on, Tommy.
This is one of those assholes
Who used to fuck with you
in the schoolyard, Tommy.
Come on, Tommy, get over
here! Get that thing going!
Let's go, Tommy! Come on!
Crank it up! Let's go!
What it is, asshole!
Yeah!
You beautiful bastard, you!
You fucking asshole!
You son of a bitch! Comin'
in my fucking house...
Oh, God.
You have to get out of here.
No no no! Get out of here.
No! Yes, Chrissie, please.
Hide!
What are you doing?
Don't. No. What are you...
No!
Thomas! Tommy.
Thomas, quit playing with your
fucking dolls and get up here!
I'm glad you brought your little buddy.
Hmm, I like your new face.
Come on, Tommy, get up here.
Please! Please!
Help!
Please, please, somebody help!
Now this will take your
fever down, all right?
See what you've done?
You killed that sheriff and you
started up a whole whirlwind.
Mama, please stop your damn bellyaching.
Uncle Monty, I love you.
You know that, and I always do
what's right by you, don't I?
And you trust me, don't you?
Yeah, I trust you. Just do something.
Take care of you.
Get in here, boy!
Uh! Ow! Oh, I'm sorry.
Tommy!
Now, this ain't gonna hurt... Huh?
...much.
What's that on your face?
Mama, you get over there
and hold Uncle Monty.
Why? 'Cause he ain't
gonna like this much,
That's why.
No! What the fuck is this?
Surgery. Come on, Tommy.
No! Oh my God!
Oh, bullshit. Look at that!
Now, Tommy, that's goddamn sloppy.
That'll get infected.
Even him up. Come on.
Huh? What?
Sheriff, no, stop! No!
There you go. Nice work, Tommy.
What did you do that for?
Balance.
I'll get Tommy to wrap this up.
Please, somebody help.
Okay. Shh.
You're gonna be okay, okay?
Shh shh, I'm sorry.
It's okay. You're safe.
They know you're here.
I'll have Mama throw on
another plate for supper.
You... you can stay?
I think we need a little
more garlic in this one.
Mama, a little more garlic in this one.
I'll go set the table.
Oh, shit!
It's okay, Mama. Just
wash it off. It'll be fine.
Don't step on the fingers.
What the hell are they
doing on the floor, anyway?
Good thing you keep a clean house.
I wonder whose tongue this is.
That's that fuckin' biker.
Why are you doing this?
No talking until after
I've said grace, asshole.
Now...
Let's give thanks for the
bounty that's been given us.
Bow your heads.
I was hungry and He gave me meat.
I was thirsty and He gave me drink.
I was a stranger and He took me in.
This family has endured
through adversity and pain.
We have endured. Dean.
We have prevailed.
We will never ever go hungry again.
Amen.
I have a question for you.
One that involves the
family tree, the...
Lineage, if you will,
So I guess this one's for the table.
You guys fuck all your cousins
Or just the ones you find attractive?
You blasphemous bitch!
This is redemption,
lady! That's what this is!
Oh, you're all gonna pay
for your sins. That's right!
And especially you!
Mama... go take care of Uncle Monty.
You know what, Mama?
I don't think this
one likes your cooking.
But who gives a shit?
She's gonna be sucking
her soup through a straw
For some time to come now, ain't she?
Come on, Monty, take a sip.
You gotta have something
to build up your strength.
Please do it.
Just do whatever you're gonna
do, you bunch of degenerates!
I will not have you
speak ill of this family.
Come on, now, open your mouth.
No. No. No.
Set her free, child.
No! No!
No! No! No! No!
Take that one downstairs!
No, you stay away from
me, you fucking animal!
You get the fuck away from me! No!
Get your hands off me!
You dirty animal!
No! Dean! Dean!
Can't you see? Your friend
ain't with us no more.
No! No! No!
Here we go.
Dean! Help! No!
No!
Hey!
Where in the hell you going, bitch?
She's gonna tell them all what we done.
There comes a time when
every boy becomes a man.
You motherfucker!
Now we'll see what kind of
soldier you are, Sheriff.
One!
That was beautiful form, Sheriff!
Two! Halfway doesn't count, dickhead!
Three! Is that all you got?
Is that all you fucking got?
Fucker! You killed my girlfriend!
You fucking asshole!
Fuck you!
My money says you're not going anywhere.
Fuck.
Chrissie!
From 1969 to 1973
The Hewitt family murdered 33
people across the state of Texas.
To this day their killing
spree is universally considered
One of the most notorious
and perversely sadistic crimes
In the annals of American history:
The Texas Chainsaw Massacre.