(waves)
Sebastian came to me. I was coaching
the 11-year-olds and under.
He came to me when he was six
and said he could play.
I said, "No, you're not ready yet."
He said, "Dan, I promise I can play."
So I gave him a shot.
I didn't play him. I put him on the team,
but I never played him.
My best player fouled out.
I put him in,
and he was making moves that...
I couldn't describe them,
because he was six years old,
and I was like, "Oh, my God."
And we lost the game,
but we went upstairs
and I told my mother, "He can play."
I said, "A little work, a little help here,
a little help there, he can play."
And then he told me.
After everybody went to bed, we sat up,
he told me, "Dan, I really
want to play this game. I want to be good."
(shouting/ball bouncing)
(cheering)
(# "Moment of Clarity" by Jay-Z)
# Thank God for grantin' me
this moment of clarity
# This moment of honesty
The world'll feel my truths
# Through my hard-knock life.
My gift and the curse
# I gave you volume after volume
of my work so you can feel my truths
# I built the dynasty
by being one of the realest niggers out
# Way beyond a reasonable doubt
# From my "Blueprint" beginnings
to that "Black Album" endin'
# Listen close. You hear what I'm about
Nigger feel my truths
I mean, the kid been
making noise for years,
and they're talking about him like he's a
superstar already, which, in a sense, he is.
In the 'hood, he's a superstar to them.
He has a cult following. It's like people
are obsessed with seeing what he do,
because they've never seen it.
I've been here 37 years. I've never
seen a game like that in Coney Island.
He has a smile,
he's marketable, he's intelligent.
He has everything.
He has everything that a superstar needs.
# Thank God for grantin' me
this moment of clarity
# This moment of honesty
The world'll feel my truths
# Through my hard-knock life.
My gift and the curse
# I gave you volume after volume
of my work so you can feel my truths
Ain't nobody ending. Ain't nobody leaving
from the court. All day, 24-7.
I can't sleep sometimes. From my window
I can hear the ball bouncing all night.
All night. All night.
Right. This is MSG.
We call it the Garden.
So this is where all the talent comes and
plays. Everybody comes and competes.
This has been going on a long time.
It's the Garden.
Everybody knows
about the Garden in New York.
Back up, back up, man.
Hi.
- How you doing?
- (woman) Hi. How are you?
If there was a place
where I had to put my child,
and I wanted him
to be a basketball player,
I'd put him right in Coney Island,
anywhere in Coney Island,
from Stillwell to Seagate.
Every block,
there's a basketball court.
When you step out of the building you see
the court, and that's what your friends do,
so you've got no choice
but to play basketball.
And then having
Stephon make it out of the projects.
All the kids, we all saw that.
He pulled up with his Bentley,
and we know his mother has a big house,
and that's something that we all wanted.
Third floor.
That's my window right there. Third floor.
Stephon - fourth floor, you know?
That's where all the talent
comes from around here.
Sebastian's a mixture
of a lot of players from Coney Island.
He has the talent like Stephon,
he got a jump shot like me,
he got a handle
like the kid named Strawberry
that lives on 20-07, used to be here.
He's a mixture.
Give me five. Here. Here.
- I got money.
- Give me a dollar. Give me a dollar.
You don't want the ball?
He ain't from Coney Island.
What you doing to them in the house?
You gotta sleep with the ball. When
you're growing up, put it under your arm,
go to sleep on it.
And your dream will come true.
(Sebastian) Look. Rest in peace, Deuce.
This is his wall here.
Got killed on the streets. Gunned down.
He was on his way to Georgia Tech.
He lived right in this building right here.
So we definitely keep his name alive,
and every time we walk by,
we say, "What's up?" to him.
Like, "What's up, Deuce?"
(man) Everybody starts, but nobody
finishes when it comes to basketball.
One year half the team failed off.
They all decided that they wasn't gonna go
back to school, they wasn't gonna finish,
and they're still here not finishing.
That's why when we get one,
the whole 'hood embraces him.
(Sebastian) Give me five, huh? Whoo!
Give me five, huh?
This is my little brother Ethan right here.
Ethan, King Osiris, the mighty king.
He's next.
They're coming for you, little bro.
He'll go for a hundred million
out of eighth grade.
Whoo! Whoo!
It's a cycle.
He'll be just like me. I was just like him.
In one.
This is what we wanna do
for the rest of our lives - play basketball.
- I'm tired.
- You tired?
(laughter)
So you beat me.
- You beat me, son?
- You gotta win.
You gotta. You're the man.
You're the king of the clay.
(woman) OK.
This is my mother.
For all the reporters that call and
want to speak to my mother and see her,
here she is, right here, all right?
I'm making some lunch for the boys.
My mother's the best cook in the world.
If you don't know that,
you better ask somebody.
For real.
My mother's a warrior.
There was times... When we say when
we were coming up that we was poor,
it was not, like,
poor that we lived in the projects and...
We was poor, man.
We didn't have nothing.
We didn't have anything, really, so...
There was times...
I remember, and I always said -
I never said this on camera -
there was times
when I had no sneakers.
I would have a pair of boots,
and I had no sneakers.
So I had to borrow
a pair of sneakers from my friends,
or take my sister's -
we used to wear the same size sneakers -
or take her sneakers
and go to my games.
That was...
I remember those things.
I don't forget.
A lot of people would have made a bigger
thing about everything I was doing.
My mother helped
keep me levelheaded.
She'll be happy about it, she'll smile
about it, but she was like, you know:
"It's really nothing until you make it."
She's seen
what happened with my brother.
My brother had one foot inside the door,
then they snatched his dream from him.
- This is my big brother.
- I don't play that.
See? I said
I'd show you my big brother.
My brother...
Being in a poor family,
my brother had a chance to go to the
NBA, so she was excited about that.
Then when it didn't happen, that shattered
a lot of dreams within my household.
(Daniel) My brother Jamel
went to Providence. He went four years.
He led the Big East at scoring,
and he didn't get drafted.
That was never heard of.
I'd never even heard of that before.
(Sebastian) I remember that day.
We was in the house watching the draft.
We was reading in the magazines
he's gonna be between ten and 15,
so we just knew
he was gonna get drafted.
We all sat here and we waited for his name
to be called, and it never got called.
You look at the second round,
you'd think there's not a lot of good players,
but Jamel Thomas
from Providence, I like his game.
I think these guys are steals
if they fall down any further.
I was just thinking
that everybody was gonna be all right,
everybody was gonna be all right.
Unfortunately,
everybody just got hurt from it.
I didn't even get picked up at all.
The whole house was crying
and it's like, "What am I supposed to do?"
That experience
was probably the worst day of my life.
To be honest, when Steph made it,
I thought I made it too. I felt like I made it.
It was like, "OK, you made it,
everybody else is gonna make it."
And then when he bought his mother
the house, I had the same ideas.
Thought it was gonna be like that,
but it just didn't happen.
But I'd tell Sebastian, I'd say, "That's
why you must work hard every day."
"Put yourself in my shoes
and don't put yourself in Stephon's shoes."
"You don't want to happen to you
what happened to me."
You know, it hurt my mother so, and she
was so devastated, she just couldn't take it.
She wouldn't be able to take it
if that was to happen to Sebastian.
So that's why she's really shy
with the cameras and stuff like that -
she really ain't into it, you know.
(interviewer) How does that
fit into your motivation?
That's big, right there.
That's big.
I'm working for my mother,
to change that day around, that draft day,
for her, which wasn't good.
You know, for me to come
and put a smile on my mother's face.
And we're gonna do it too.
We've gotta go up the steps.
Good afternoon,
and thank you all for being here.
We're all here for one main reason,
and I would like to introduce him now.
Please welcome Sebastian Telfair.
Thanks. Thank you.
I want to thank everyone for coming
here today and showing support for me.
I appreciate it. Thank you.
To also, my family, I want
to thank you all for sticking with me.
I know it ain't easy. I watch you go through
everything I go through. I love you all.
Everything is gonna be good.
Now I'll tell you what
I came to tell everybody,
that I will be attending the University
of Louisville, with Rick Pitino.
I'll take any questions.
Right there.
(man) Physically, how will you
handle the rigors of college basketball?
It's very physical,
the conference that you're gonna be in.
- Are you prepared?
- Am I prepared?
Yes, I'm prepared.
I'm from Coney Island.
(laughter)
(applause)
Now, pick it up.
Good. Good. Better.
(man) Put the hands up! Good.
Give me the ball. Everything is good.
Get out the way. I'm looking for attitude.
This is all good. This is all good.
This is all good. Yeah, Jerry!
Good job, you. Good job, you!
That nigger nuked on a rebound!
(man) This season's a big season.
Last year we repeated as city champions.
If we win again.
It'd be three in a row.
Which would be the first ever
in PSAL history.
New York City's the Mecca of basketball.
If you can win three championships
in a league where Hall-of-Fame players
came from, that's unbelievable.
Ah! Game!
Y'all running
no better than that? Damn!
Stop!
This season it's real!
- (girl) Good luck.
- Thanks.
- Come on, buddy.
- Have a good one.
Good luck, baby.
Good luck. We need a shot of you,
kind of like you're walking to the game,
holding a basketball.
See where those people
just walked out there?
If you walk out,
but then walk my way.
(commentator) Rose Hill gym
at Fordham University. The main stage
for tonight's Edgewater-Lincoln game.
The task in hand.
Slowing down this man -
Sebastian Telfair
from Lincoln High School in Brooklyn.
Is he the greatest
or simply the latest?
One question that begs in the progressive
high school basketball classic.
(Daniel) We're the team
everybody came to see. All right?
These motherfucking lights is on now.
These motherfucking lights is on now!
(all shout)
- (Daniel) Aight!
- (all) Aight!
Let's do it, then.
(commentator) Darius Washington heats
it up. Nice pitch to Brandon Johnson.
Antonio Pena with a slam.
Ripping it again.
Feeling it. Spin cycle.
Telfair.
Coming right back with a little dunk.
You gotta love this.
(whistle)
(man) Hey, listen. Is it your back?
Your knee?
Maybe it's his ankle.
Suck it up, man.
- (woman) Is it his leg?
- (woman #2) His ankle.
(man) Come on, let's go.
Help him up. Let's go. Come on.
(applause)
The war's not over yet, nigger.
We're down, but we ain't out.
The war's not over yet.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
Argh! Hold on. Hold on.
Ah! See? No, no.
(man) You ain't got it up here, right?
You all right?
These niggers are busting your ass
so let's get to work.
Let's stop all the bullshitting.
'Cause pain is temporary.
Just go a little.
You're gonna have to walk it out.
Focus, baby.
You'll be smiling after this.
I'll be waiting to see you at the door.
(all) One, two, three, together!
- Where we at?
- I'm right here.
- We're on the floor right now.
We're on the floor right now.
It's time to shine, nigger.
It's time to shine, nigger. It's time to shine.
(commentator)
Telfair looking spry on a bad wheel.
Telfair got the switch.
Nice beat inside.
That's how you drop a dime.
Here comes Darius Washington.
And picked clean by Telfair.
Telfair with the left.
I'm liking some of that.
The lead is down to two. And Sebastian
Telfair has a menacing look in his eyes.
Telfair with 24. and the meter
is still running. And gets the charge.
Listen, motherfuckers,
when he runs through the screen,
hit the fucking nigger, you hear me?
Come on.
What the fuck?
(commentator) Telfair reeling.
Got it back on the give-and-go.
Hit the floor. That's a New York City shot.
And Lincoln has a one-point lead.
Telfair kicks it out.
Come on, let's go, let's go.
Congratulations.
That was a great game. What a game.
- You do a super job.
- (man) You do a great job.
Thank you for everything.
Watching him, I realize
that if he puts on a Louisville uniform,
he'll be the best point guard that I would
have coached at the collegiate ranks.
And you have Derek Jeter, Yankee
superstar come in. Then you have Jay-Z.
Then you have two or three professional
scouts, which makes me uneasy.
Jeter was great, Jay-Z was outstanding,
but the pro scouts made me a little uneasy.
So I left in a little bit of turmoil,
because that was probably the first time
since recruiting Sebastian
that I felt there was a chance
he could entertain the NBA.
Telfair, can I have
your signature, please?
Thanks, Telfair.
(Jamel) This year's
important for Sebastian.
To be honest. I think
that's a good decision to go to Louisville.
But I think as the season goes on,
I think scouts and gyms will bite.
They'll take him out.
I think he's that good.
But I'm on my way to Greece
to play professional basketball,
and the reason why I have to go,
because I provide the money for my family.
If you can't make it in the NBA
and you want to make money.
You have to take your talent
across the water.
(man) He did. Don't deny it.
(man #2) Nah, I can't.
Who are you going with? Who are
you going with? I'm the commentator.
Who are you going with tonight?
- Carmelo.
- Carmelo. OK. We got one for Carmelo.
Mr. Sebastian Telfair,
who are you going with?
- King James.
Oh, dunk that, Bronny.
Let's go.
We gotta get some more of those.
King James. That's all you needed,
the dunk. That's it. It's over.
It's just a game when you're playing,
but this is a business.
Definitely at the time that I'm coming up,
it's a lot different.
These guys like LeBron James, $90 million
for the sneaker contract, this ain't no game.
$90 million - 100, whatever he got -
for a sneaker?
That's not no game.
This is serious.
At a certain age,
a certain stage in your life,
if you're one of those people,
it turns completely into a business.
When I was in junior high school
I wanted a tattoo.
I wanted a tattoo or something.
My brothers shout me down:
"You can't get no tattoos.
It's not gonna be good for your image."
So that's my business.
I'm starting my business right there.
That's like a job.
Like, people get up and go to work,
I get up and go to school
and play basketball.
Your first business you're gonna get,
if you're one of the top basketball players,
is the sneaker market,
where they got a basketball camp,
like Adidas, Reebok and Nike.
The sneaker companies come and recruit
you and try to get you to go to their camp.
You're with them
through your high-school years,
and so when you go on
to college or the NBA,
you're friends with them and
that's what sneaker you'll sign with.
The first thing we in the industry do
is identify the kid.
Then you get the kid and he's on your
camp list, he plays in your all-star games.
He'll get every new product
that the company has. I guarantee it.
He's no different than Jay-Z
going into a playground.
He walks in, all the people know who he is
and you want him showing your logo.
But you gotta have
the high-school team,
because you have access to
the paraphernalia of the high-school kid -
all the uniforms that they wear, the gym
that they play in, signage everywhere.
It's a smart promotion.
That's a gift from Adidas.
Brandon, come over and help me with this.
Find me some 12s.
I think today's kid - the star kid,
the one that you've anointed through
the media and through your own intuition -
when he's given the goodies,
he is gonna be the man.
Whoo!
He knows it and the world knows it,
and the teammates know it also.
6-2.
- (man) What's on the line, Tiny?
- The sneakers.
They're playing
for the sneakers right now, man.
Anything goes.
Ooh.
Those sneakers.
Watch those shoes, man.
Here are the sneakers.
Big game.
We're going to Sheepshead Bay.
You know,
they always give us a hard time.
The atmosphere over there is crazy.
All the other sports,
they get a bus to go to the games.
The basketball team, we don't.
And we're, like, the best team in the school.
We don't get no love.
All these championships,
we should get a bus.
- It's cold out here, man.
- It's freezing.
(Nyan) I don't like coming through here,
man. Especially at night, man.
I don't like this stuff.
We gotta do this
every other game, man.
We'll be smacking teams,
'cause we'll be pissed off.
By the time we get there
we'll be mad already.
I think we got off
at the wrong stop, man.
(cheering)
He's gonna stop!
No foul! No foul!
He's gonna stop.
(Sebastian)
Yo, where are the uniforms at?
Where are the uniforms at?
He wants to play,
wants to help his team.
So...
I always tell him,
if it ain't broken, you can play, so...
Sebastian, please be careful.
(crowd chanting)
(buzzer)
I'm not mad because we lost.
I'm mad at everybody because...
Y'all motherfuckers don't sacrifice
for nothing. All y'all care about is y'all.
If y'all don't go out and fight for each other,
and dive on the floor,
and scratch and bite, whatever you gotta
do to win, together, we ain't gonna win.
We ain't gonna win.
Not fucking hanging around.
You're tragic.
You should be
the motherfucker busting your ass.
Ain't nobody gonna fucking fail me
with the college. Nobody!
You should be
the first nigger trying to do it.
I didn't go to college. All my brothers went
to college, but I put my foot in the ass.
All of them.
Wake up, man.
Better wake up.
You're only as good as right now.
Once it's over, it's over.
Once it's over, it's over, yo.
(Dan) These awards are my pride and joy.
This - "We present this award to our
assistant coach of the year Daniel Turner.
"From all your players."
This is all voluntary, what I do.
Everything I do is from my heart.
The big thing - my brother's there, so...
I told my mother
I'd take care of him, so...
That's pretty much why I do that.
I'm one of Sebastian's biggest fans,
so I put this together.
You know?
This is his first year at ABCD camp.
He turned it out.
His first year at ABCD camp,
he was with Stephon.
This one right here, he's 13.
That's when he first
really became noticed.
I don't know if you can get this,
but this is Stephon and Sebastian.
Sebastian was seven.
Stephon was still at high school.
That's throwback for you right there.
I think I sacrificed a lot
for my brothers.
And not just Sebastian,
for all my brothers.
That was my job, being the oldest,
you know, to make sure
they fulfilled their life.
You know, I live through them.
At the end of the day,
I'm happy 'cause they're happy.
That's all that matters.
(Tiny) Ten.
Doubling it - 20.
At least you got two vowels.
Is it your turn, Coach?
I'll be taking the lead.
What are you gonna spell with that crap?
Not with this, you gotta...
- I know. I played Scrabble.
- All right, then.
University of Louisville.
Hey, what's up?
- What up?
- What's up with you?
Sebastian, how are you, man?
How you been?
In the zone, buddy.
In the zone.
This shit's crazy.
We need some equipment
at Lincoln, man.
If I get a chance, I'm gonna
get Lincoln some equipment like this.
This is nice.
This is the dorm at Louisville.
We're trying to see what's up in there.
Know what I mean?
(Sebastian) This is for the players.
I'm gonna show you this room.
Damn, I ought to pass my classes.
- Oh, this is hot!
- (Sebastian) Oh, this is crazy.
Yo, this whole wall...
this whole wall right here's a TV.
Look. This comes down.
See that thing there?
- Are you serious?
- This is crazy.
- Mom. What's up? It's Sebastian.
- (news report on television)
I'm fine.
Yeah, everything's good.
Yeah, they're treating us real nice. There's
a lot of fans out here, so it's real nice.
We didn't play.
We play tomorrow at 5 o'clock.
Cardinal fans will get a glimpse of
the future tomorrow after the U of L game.
Brooklyn point guard sensation.
Sebastian Telfair.
And PRP big man. Terrance Farley.
Will share the floor at Louisville Gardens.
The two future teammates talked about
Saturday's game in a news conference.
Telfair trying to put the talk about him
heading straight for the NBA behind him.
- I will be at Louisville.
- (man) Is that a definite?
Is that a definite?
Yeah. If I'm alive.
(newscaster) Tipoff
for tomorrow's game is 5pm.
What's up? Look at this.
So cute.
"Bassy buzz."
I like that.
"The Bassy buzz."
(cheering)
I named my cat Bassy,
because he's our favorite player now.
It's packed out there.
Louisville is not playing around.
They take it serious.
So going here, it's about... I went around
and saw seven teams' NBA scouts there.
- (man #1) Man!
- (man #2) What?
I've seen B.J. Armstrong,
I've seen Danny Ainge.
- That got me nervous!
- I don't know who B.J. Armstrong is.
He's, like, a scout for the Chicago Bulls.
This is a big game, son.
(cheering)
- What's up, Bassy?
- What's up, man?
(commentator) Number 31.
Sebastian Telfair.
(commentator) Sebastian Telfair.
And that's the ball game. Final score:
Lincoln. 77. Beavers. 69.
(man) OK. Thank you.
Say thank you.
Thanks.
Only doing T-shirts. If you don't
have a T-shirt, please get out of line.
- "Chosen one."
- That's for you.
- That's not to sign.
(Sebastian) Thank you.
And can you sign this?
Get them Cardinals to the nationals.
After the game, I got a call from
Sonny Vacarro and I'm speaking to him,
'cause he's somebody that always helped
me out all through my years at high school,
and I get a lot of information from him.
So I'm thinking, "I just had a good game."
I'm not thinking,
"OK, NBA guys is looking at me now."
He spoke to me.
He was like, "Things is turning."
I was like, "What do you mean?"
He was like,
"I think you got a shot of going to the NBA."
So I laughed.
I called my mother.
She was like, "Oh, yeah, yeah.
Don't listen to that."
We was all together.
We heard something like shots.
We didn't know what it was.
My mother was nervous
and Ethan was hysterical.
There's ten of us in my family.
It could've been any one of us.
And my little brother Ethan plays
in this hallway, running up and down.
This hallway's haunting me.
It could have been anybody.
Let's hope God
takes better care of them than we did.
You know, there's tragedy everywhere.
This past weekend
it hit so close to home.
That's something you want your family
away from, and that's what I'm trying to do.
Where they don't gotta witness things like
people getting murdered, things like that.
I was sitting and thinking
and I asked myself, you know,
what I feel is best for me and my family.
You know, you hear everyone
and, you know, what they got to say,
people, you know, filling your head with...
You gotta be true to yourself.
'Cause if someone believes in me and
I don't, then that doesn't mean anything.
You know, me, personally,
I do think I can play in the NBA.
But I'm still in the projects.
My mother's still gotta struggle
in the projects.
I'm still broke. You know.
So I'm still grounded. Just trying to.
You know... Just waiting for my chance.
(man) A lot of people out here
dying for stupid reasons.
I've seen a lot of people die out here,
close friends' demise.
You know, I used to be a knucklehead
when I was growing up,
so if you get a chance to live, do it.
There's a lot of people that wish they could
sit here and tell a story like I'm telling it.
But they're not.
Out here, basketball saves a lot of us.
A lot of young people will say
it gives you something to do.
Everybody wants to be a baller.
Everybody growing up out here
wants to be an NBA player.
(interviewer) What would life here be like
without basketball?
There won't be no life.
It would be nothing.
There would be nothing out here.
I'm calling my man Tick Tick Boom over
'cause he was striving to go to NBA too.
He's still out here,
you know, trying to do his thing.
My man, what's up?
It was fun at school,
but after you get out
and you realize you're not as good
as you wanna be or you thought you was,
it becomes a burden because
you're trying to be the best you could be,
and your best is not what people want.
When it hit me, it was like,
"I'm not gonna get paid for this."
It felt like I'd lost my life.
Basketball was my life.
As you get older,
you know it's just a game.
When you're young, you're thinking this
game's gonna get your mother this house,
get your family out of here. Once you see...
That was the biggest burden.
That's why it's hard to explain, 'cause once
I didn't, I knew my mother'd still be here,
my sister'd still be down there,
my brother'd be over there.
So that was, like, the hardest thing.
I just wasn't doing this for myself.
Then once you fail,
you really feel like you failed your family.
I'm still here.
It's pain.
As long as I'm here, it's pain.
No lie.
- Do what you gotta do.
- (cheering)
(# "Radio Free Brooklyn"
by Pete Miser)
(man) Oh, yeah!
Yes, baby!
(commentator) Telfair spins
right through the defense.
Two defenders came up there to help.
It didn't matter.
Stay down, Nyan!
(commentator) Inside there.
Howard extends and flushes.
- Ooh!
- (whistle)
(commentator) Howard spinning right.
Telfair knifing through the defense.
And he finishes.
Hey, take your time, boy.
It's like walking in the park, boy.
(commentator) Now the final 11 seconds.
Telfair controlling.
Here we go.
They get it to Telfair.
Telfair.
The step-back three-pointer.
- He knocks it down!
- (cheering)
Where's my mother?
Where's my mother? Where's Mommy?
You did it again.
(Sebastian) Yeah!
- We don't gotta count this strip too long.
- I know.
That was one shot I'll never forget.
That was my first buzzer beater I ever hit.
When you know the NBA's there and
everyone's around, they're looking at you,
they wanna see if you're that player
that they're reading about,
like my brother Dan says,
when the lights is on, it's time to perform.
My nigger!
I wasn't expecting to come out and play
well and get the attention that I'm getting.
Not how it's going now. I think it's
a lot better than I thought it would ever go,
but, you know,
it's here and it's happening.
He raised a big stink about it,
and then he said,
"I guess it's taken care of."
'Cause someone showed him the check
and now it's kinda fine.
It was always fine.
He just was attacking me
because he wanted direct communication
with players and I wouldn't give it to him.
I don't know why
people have got hard feelings.
I don't know why people don't think I've
been around. My record speaks for itself.
(Tiny) It's no worse than anybody writing a
story about you that got the facts mixed up.
I don't see no problem. I'm only doing
what I was taught - what was done to me.
When I was coming to high school,
people used to try to recruit people,
or give us free sneakers here and there.
People just blow it up
because I'm winning and I'm young,
and I'm not the prototype
high-school coach anymore.
I look like... I dress like, you know, the kids,
because that's my environment.
And if I was put in Wall Street,
I'd look like somebody in Wall Street.
I'm from Coney Island,
so I'm looking like I'm from Coney Island.
There's a lot of people out there
that have got so much negativity to say.
"Oh, he's driving an Escalade."
"Oh, his brother wears a diamond watch."
"Dan got a Rolex."
So what? I mean, we all work
and we want nice things too.
When you're dealing with project kids,
we're being fathers, we're big brothers,
sometimes we're even being mothers.
We feed most of these kids every day.
You know, and it's sad
that I had to read that article about Coach.
That hurt me,
because I'm with him all the time,
so I know he don't do
the things they say he's doing.
You know?
I know since my brother's been here,
he's protecting my brother
like it was his brother.
So, you know, it's a real situation
that people just don't understand.
Do y'all understand? In the history
of the Public Schools League,
no team has ever won
three straight championships.
Motherfuckers want y'all like...
Y'all are targets.
"One...
"and we done!"
That's some scary shit, son.
Five games to win the championship.
Don't get nervous on me, son.
He's shaking with nerves.
All the other games we played,
that don't mean shit.
That buzzer beater that he shot?
It's over.
Done.
# Get up, I get down
Get up, I get down
# All right
# It's all right
It's all right
# She's got a light-skinned friend,
look like Michael Jackson
# She's got a dark-skinned friend,
# I'm gonna play this Gladys Knight
# Me and you gonna get right
to Baby Remington
# And we can set this party off right
Let's go, y'all.
OK, y'all, it's playoff time here.
It's playoff time. We don't get to stand here.
Let's go and tear
this motherfucking gym up.
(applause)
OK, you're scared, nigger.
You're scared.
Get that shit outta here.
Get the fuck outta here.
Run! Run! Run!
Tony! Tony!
- (man) No play.
- (whistle)
What the fuck?
Where's the ball?
Shaking his fucking head, man.
Fuck y'all niggers, man.
- I'm driving the ball. I'm driving it.
- Go right up to the post!
I don't want you to play,
I want you to score! Play later.
(Tiny) We can't play with them at all, man.
There shouldn't be tricks
until all-star games or citywides.
- That's how I play.
- If you complete the plays, it's all good.
I do complete the plays.
He called.
- You don't understand.
- I shoot, you make a face.
It's a team thing.
It's not about me.
But you don't understand.
You really don't understand.
I could have kept
Nyan and Eugene in the game.
They got two fouls.
They could've got three.
So when I put the subs in the game,
you gotta be very aggressive to score.
'Cause it could be Boetsa, Cardozo.
They got two fouls, first half.
Now I got subs in the game,
and you gotta be very aggressive to score.
- Let's go warm up.
- Let's go, y'all.
You should be on 30 right now.
(Tiny) Do you know who that is?
L.A. Clippers.
One move,
you could fuck everything up.
One bullshit playing around, it gets twisted,
you know what I mean? Don't understand.
Fuck.
Always say something.
(whistle)
- I'm going.
- (Tiny) Squeeze the ball.
(whistle)
Get the fuck outta here.
Fuck these niggers, man.
Hey, Sebastian, look right here.
OK, just put one finger up.
(cameras click)
All right, this ain't
no photo shoot, man.
Hey, you got a wristband, man?
My brother's a fan of yours, man.
Thank you.
That's one step.
Let's go to the next step.
I'm gonna do what I gotta do.
Don't mind me.
That's all I got to say.
I'll see you all tomorrow.
There's a guy, Mike,
a photographer.
He's a genius. This is, like, our third
or fourth time working with him already.
- Cold and crazy.
- Good to see you.
- How are you doing?
Oh, shit! Oh!
I thought I was gonna be in the sand.
We're going on the trampoline?
You want me to do flips?
- Yes, I want you up there.
- All right. I know you do.
We're all on there, man.
We're all on there.
Here we go.
Keep going, man.
Keep going.
Just be creative.
Just bounce it, man.
Oh, shit.
If I cut your head off, I'll be crazy.
I love that. Keep doing that.
This is insane.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. Again.
I'm loving it.
Cross your legs and then let go.
You know, something like that. Just let go.
Give me a smile.
(Dan) Oh!
Number one.
Yeah, but I want him to sign them.
He didn't see them yet. He doesn't know.
- Yo, that's crazy.
- Yes.
Oh!
That's mine right there.
Say, "Thanks, Coach." For everything I did.
- "Thanks." This is mine right here.
- Yeah. OK, but wait.
- How'd you get this?
- Don't worry.
Thank you so much.
My mother will be so excited.
It's the picture.
You got Coney Island in the background.
You got the smile, so I was very happy.
You're always making sure I smile.
They want to know
if there was any more posters for the team.
- (woman) Posters?
- Yeah, for his closest friends, like me.
No, but I'll order more if you guys want.
Do you guys want these posters?
- Yes.
- I'll order more. I'll get more.
All right.
- (interviewer) Show us that magazine.
- I'm gonna show it, because I'm proud.
I'm very proud of this.
People say, "Why's he smiling like that?"
Because that's him. That's why.
- He smiles all the time. Look.
- (interviewer) A million-dollar smile.
My brother prepared my image so
the Sebastian y'all see, that's 90% him.
(interviewer) How would you
describe that image?
Tiger Woods.
Tiger Tiger Woods, y'all.
Just clean.
Clean, happy, smiling all the time,
nice teeth, you know.
That's what it's all about,
being happy.
Even when we didn't have nothing,
we were still happy, for some reason.
We just had each other.
You know.
And I think
we're about to have a lot, right?
- A lot of what?
- A lot of just... Just a lot more.
You think so? Yeah, I think
we're about to have a lot more.
(cheering)
That's right. That's right.
That's right. Let's go.
Lincoln, Lincoln!
Lincoln!
(commentator) Sebastian Telfair.
Bassy, step up.
Go, motherfuckers!
Let's go!
Bassy! What's up, son?
What's up?
If you're tired, put your hand up.
I will sub you.
Don't fucking be out there if you're tired.
I'm a good coach. I can sub and still play.
If you get ripped at half court,
you're tired.
You gotta pick it up, son.
You gotta pick it up.
If you're trying to go to the league,
you gotta pick it up. That's all I got to say.
(whistle)
(commentator) That's a foul.
Number 31. Sebastian Telfair.
His fourth. The team's sixth.
(commentator announces scorer)
Yo, I'm ready, man.
I'm ready.
(whistle)
(man) Go, Lincoln!
(commentator) Eugene Lawrence.
Don't let these motherfuckers take this.
Don't let them.
I'm gonna take it,
I'm gonna take it from them. As always.
(commentator) Jamel Jackson.
(commentator) Sebastian Telfair.
Jamel Jackson.
(crowd cheers)
(commentator) Dwayne Morton
is on the way to Madison Square Garden.
Congratulations.
- Son, you did your best, man.
- Hold your heads up, guys.
Yo, hold your heads up.
You got nice shit.
You got nice shit, all right?
All right, man. Hold your head up, man.
It'll be all right.
You'll be all right, boy.
See y'all, man.
Whoo!
Tony, Tony, give me a hug.
I want my fucking hug,
you big motherfucker.
(Pitino) If his adviser doesn't say.
"You're going in the top 12."
If he doesn't feel like he's high
and that a potential shoe company
would have a lot of interest in him,
he's coming to Louisville.
So in that regard...
Now, if you ask me my opinion,
my opinion is we better get busy recruiting.
My coach, Rick Pitino, down in Louisville,
someone interviewed him for a paper.
When they asked him about me
and the NBA, he told them what he felt.
You know,
he felt that I'm a top-ten pick, you know,
and I'm maybe gonna play in the NBA,
so that's what he told the papers.
I'm in a barbershop,
getting my hair cut.
I need those cuff links.
I gotta leave in the next 20 minutes.
I got something to do with ESPN today.
It don't get no sharper than that.
Yo, are you ready?
I ain't made no decision yet.
Uh, you know,
I think, you know, the NBA, you know...
Me in the NBA, I'm fifty-fifty here.
When they come up and see me, I think
I'm performing the way they want me to.
But I think Louisville
still might be a good place for me.
So we're gonna see. But right now
it's looking real good for the NBA, though.
What up?
There's two pairs in there.
- Yo, get in the back of the car.
- Don't disrespect me. I'll kick this little...
Some cuff links
for my button-up shirts.
There's not gonna be any questions about
college or NBA or nothing like that?
I don't know who's doing... I don't know
who's doing the actual questions.
Let's go to New York. Sebastian Telfair.
All-American at Lincoln. Joins us now -
latest in the line of great New York City
point guards. Sebastian. How are you?
- I'm fine. How are you doing?
- You've committed to Louisville.
Have you made your decision
whether you will go to Louisville?
Or are you still making your decision
on being in the NBA draft?
I think I made a decision
when I signed the letter I sent to Louisville.
That's something I'm really excited about -
me and Rick Pitino.
This is a process we're going through
now. And I'm having a lot of fun doing it.
Sebastian. The word is that you're out.
That you're going to the NBA.
Are you saying now
that you will be at Louisville?
Well, you know,
if the team is definitely, you know...
If a team's saying they want me
and I feel comfortable with it,
and it's the best thing for me and my
family, maybe that would be the decision.
It's something me and Rick Pitino
and my family will work out.
Sebastian Telfair. Joining us from
New York. Best of luck wherever you go.
- Take care.
- Thank you.
Sebastian Telfair joining us.
Now to DeMarcus Nelson...
They didn't ask me about the game,
all NBA.
- All NBA?
- "Well, Rick Pitino quoted..."
"Rick Pitino quoted..."
Yo, every fucking day, man.
What the fuck, man?
- How are you doing?
- I'm all right.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Six foot and a half inch.
- You're the exact size as Isiah was.
- I'd say I'm six-one.
Exactly the same
as Isiah when he was in high school.
- That's your target. Isiah's your target.
- Isiah?
Down the road, you know.
That's who you wanna be like.
Yeah, I watched a couple of his tapes.
He was good.
The best six-one and under
that ever lived.
- Thanks.
- You got a great handshake.
- Nice firm handshake.
- Oh, yeah.
Good smile.
- Don't lose that, now.
- I won't.
- OK. If you need me, I'm around.
- I know.
I think Sebastian's
going through a whirlwind,
so many things happening at one time.
You know, I think that some of the things
are getting to him, he just ain't saying it.
My brother's about to do something
a lot of people don't get a chance to do.
Sebastian's a special kid.
He's a special kid.
And when we win, 'cause I'm hoping
we win and I'm praying we win,
I want him to stand in the middle of
Madison Square Garden and say, "I did it."
In front of everybody, "I did it."
(Tiny) Damn, look at that line, son.
- (Sebastian) That's the line to get in?
- (all cheer)
- They've come to watch us!
- I'm gonna take a picture.
Yeah!
14,000 come to watch us.
Whoo, the lights is on
and we're here!
The lights is on and we're here!
You have never been here. Don't act like
you're at Madison Square Garden. OK?
That means don't come in here
with no scared shit.
Yo!
- Let me hold that, man.
- What's up?
- Hold-hold-hold on.
- Huh?
We're here.
I'm back in the gang.
Show him the bullshit moves.
# You 'bout to prove my man wrong
I'm gonna play this Vandross
# You gonna take your pants off
I'm gonna play this Gladys Knight
# Me and you gonna get right
I'm happy and having fun, man,
but we got a serious game.
We got a lot of motherfucker
hating us today, yo.
That crowd is not here
to cheer you motherfuckers on.
They're here to see
you motherfuckers go down. Aight?
(all) Aight.
(all shout "Aight" repeatedly)
(man) Yeah, motherfuckers.
I'm black!
I'm blacker than...
Let's go! Come on!
- The lights is on. It's time to perform.
- I got you.
- This is where we wanna be.
- I'm onto it. I'm onto it.
This is where we wanna be.
Let's go.
I know y'all niggers, man.
Let's get it right, y'all.
We're here today, man.
We're here today.
Let's go, man.
We're here together, man.
Hey, y'all, we're here, y'all.
We're here, y'all!
(commentator) Telfair. Crossover.
Jump shot long. Off the glass.
Rebounded by Cardozo.
Ahead they go for the layup.
We gotta pick it up, man.
(commentator)
Dwayne Johnson will reset.
Now he spins inside
and he gets knocked hard.
And Telfair will be whistled
for that one.
Oh, this kid is unbelievable, man.
Fuck, man.
- (commentator) And that's his second.
- Nick, Nick, Nick, Nick, Nick, Nick.
What you taking me out for?
What the fuck
are you taking me out for?
(commentator) Cardozo back outside.
To drive in traffic.
Tipped up and in by Davis.
As we count 'em down in the first half.
Telfair's gonna come back in
with two personal fouls.
Eugene Lawrence with the basketball.
Hands to Telfair.
There's Telfair with the basketball.
Off a high spring by Pena.
Behind the back he goes.
Crosses over. Goes inside. Floats it up.
It's short.
Got his own rebound. Put it in!
And the buzzer!
Yo, it's over. Forget about it.
They're playing street ball against us.
Outscrapping us.
Bennie, you got zero.
We got one rebound, man.
You don't rebound, you're not playing.
Plain and simple.
I need rebounds.
I don't need no dunks, no jump shots.
I need somebody to say,
"Fuck that, I'm gonna rebound."
Come on, let's go turn it up.
(commentator) Now a pull-up jumper
by Telfair.
Hits the bottom of the net.
A steal. Lawrence.
What the fuck's that?
What the fuck?
And Victor Morris has it.
So Cardozo can take the lead.
Tries to duck. Great pass.
Yo! You gotta calm the fuck down.
Calm down! Calm down! Calm down!
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait, back down!
Stay in touch! Stay in touch!
(commentator) Telfair goes for the basket.
Lays that one in.
(crowd chants) Let's go, Lincoln!
Let's go, Lincoln!
Now, listen. This is it!
This is it, right here.
- Yo, yo, let's go!
- Yo, we gotta fight, y'all.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yo, right, y'all.
Now, listen, man. This is it, man.
This is for the history, man.
We's in it all here,
together on three.
- One, two, three.
- (all) Together!
(commentator) Telfair drives into the lane.
A little pull-up. It's good.
Telfair in the lane. Left-handed!
What a great drive by Telfair.
Telfair there. Open court.
He's got it in. Over the top.
Yeah. Let's go.
(commentator) And a steal by Sebastian.
Ahead to Lawrence.
Here's Boateng.
And he will crush it. And that should do it.
Clear the motherfucking road, boys!
(chanting and whooping)
Yo, yo, Tiny.
They wrote in the paper
that we wouldn't do it. But we did it!
- We did it! We went through it, boy.
- We did it!
Three! Three!
Three, nigger. Three.
- Oh, Lord, thank you, Jesus.
- We got it. We got it.
Thank you, Jesus.
I love you guys.
I love all of you.
What they gonna say now?
What they gonna say?
"Get Tiny, before you get
another championship. Get Tiny!
"Get Tiny, so somebody else lose!"
Yo, Tom. This here was a victory lap,
and I'm leaving.
(man on PA) Terminal one. Lower level.
Once again. Calling Sebastian Telfair.
Your party's plane.
Terminal one. Lower level.
- What's happening?
- How you doing, man?
I'm not used to being around
people that have jobs.
- Good to see you.
- Wow.
Go, go, go.
Can I have one of those basketballs?
- Where do you go to college?
- Louisville.
Louisville?
Tell Rick Pitino hello, all right?
- I'll make sure I will.
- All right.
- Louisville.
- Louisville? All right.
We'll see.
It's over. It's over!
- I could be in a magazine just like this.
- Pull the bad one.
- Definitely me. Definitely me.
- You can't seriously...
Look at that fucking smile!
Look at the smile.
And the number one pick,
for the 2004 draft...
(man on PA) Sebastian Telfair.
- Congratulations, man.
- Congratulations, Sebastian.
- You got quite the smile, Sebastian.
- Congratulations.
We missing anybody, Lisa?
Dwight Howard?
Al Jefferson?
- What up, country boy?
- J. R. Smith?
You're a country boy too.
Where you from?
I got people staying in New Jersey,
so I ain't really a country boy.
You still country.
You know your ass, country.
And shit,
you the most country person here.
You, country boy. If you ain't from
New York, you're from the country.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Brooklyn in the house without a doubt.
I'm the baller everyone talking about.
Kansas! Kansas! Kansas!
Kansas?
(commentator) Telfair with his first bucket.
Out of Brooklyn.
Telfair signing with Louisville.
Count that assist.
Hey, Coach!
Write that assist down.
- Coach, I'm trying to get that assist record.
- I know. Keep working.
Hey, man,
help me get that assist record, man.
- I don't know how many I got.
- I have no idea, but I'll find out.
Run! Run!
(commentator) Dwight Howard
off the great feed from Telfair.
- The record's 13.
- How many you got?
I need four, man.
I need four more.
I'm gonna go back door right now.
I'm there, I'm there.
Jamel, I got you back,
I got you back!
Hit that.
Hit my assist, baby.
I'm gonna go crazy
in that locker room.
You did exactly what you had to do.
Exactly what you had to do, man.
You're a forward general. That was
fantastic. You didn't have to score in this.
That's what everyone was looking for.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
I'll see y'all, man.
You see that man dishing the rock?
That's what it's all about.
I just want to say I had a great time
with all you country boys this weekend.
Wish we could do it again.
You were tremendous,
because you didn't try to do anything
except what you're supposed to do,
which is run the team.
You played the way
a true lead guy is supposed to play.
Nobody does that.
Except you.
- 'Cause you're a pro.
- Yeah, I am?
- Yes, you are.
- I hope so.
(Sebastian) When I got home.
I was at meetings till two in the morning.
Just trying to get
the sneaker contract on the roll.
(interviewer) So what happens
when you meet with the sneaker company?
I might as well show you this.
When you go to a sneaker presentation,
they take you through their whole history.
K.G., Tim Duncan,
guys there running, swimming.
And then the last couple of pages is like,
"You are the future."
You know?
Then they got a picture of me.
See those guns right there?
Of course, I'm wearing all Adidas right now.
That's that Adidas camp right there.
And that's me in Adidas,
with my yellow and black colors.
And those'll be
my sneakers right there.
Those'll be the Sebastian Telfairs.
I'm the first person to see this.
No one saw the sneaker yet.
I'm surprised.
I'm like, "Y'all want me?"
"Y'all want to give me a sneaker?"
Things like...
Ah, it's... It's like you see a movie,
and you're picturing that's you,
and you're like,
"That's not reality."
Then it's really, like, right there.
I'm sitting talking to these people.
I'm like, "They're talking about me?"
I'm not dreaming right now.
I was dreaming for the last 18 years.
Like, it's happening right now.
And it's right in front of me.
Yeah, we're gonna
have to meet anyway.
Today you got one of the biggest
announcements of your life.
I'll put my arm round you,
handshake, we'll do a photo op,
and then I'll back off again
and let you finish your deal.
The majority of it's gonna be you.
They don't like to hear it from these
corporate guys with the suits on.
We're gonna head around
the side of the building, so walk with me.
Right there, where Ron's at.
How do you want to be introduced?
I mean, do you want Ron to say:
"New York high-school legend"?
"New York high school legend Sebastian
Telfair to make two announcements"?
How would you personally like
to be kinda brought up to the stage?
Is there anything?
You could say "New York City legend,"
anything like that.
(Ron) And now, Sebastian Telfair,
New York City high-school legend.
(applause and cheers)
Thank you.
Thanks for coming, everybody.
I got a couple of announcements to make.
The first announcement is,
I'm the newest member of the Adidas team.
I'm gonna be signing with Adidas.
- (man) All right! That's good!
- (applause)
And now, every one of you really
came here to hear the announcement -
I will be entering the 2004 NBA draft.
(applause)
He brings that instant street credibility.
And so we're gonna...
- Instant what?
- Instant street credibility.
So street cred with the real urban ballers,
with the ballers,
so we're pretty excited about that too.
(woman) How do you plan
on using the college funds?
(Tiny) He's gonna probably go
somewhere and work out on his game.
And the world he's about to embark on
is gonna be so difficult.
He's still got a lotta learning to do.
A whole lotta learning.
Specially when you got money now.
Now it's really easy to mess up now,
because you're financially fit.
Everything you wish for, you got.
Now what you gonna do?
You wished for a car,
a house for your mother - you got it.
You wished for your own sneakers -
you got it.
Now, what is your intention in life now?
I want him to really realize
that he's about to be a man,
in a crazy business.
He's gonna go to a company.
And he's gonna be
the rookie of the company.
And nobody gonna care
who Sebastian Telfair is no more.
Now Sebastian Telfair is going
straight from high school to the NBA.
It's one thing to be LeBron James,
or Kobe Bryant, or Kevin Garnett,
it's quite another to be five-ten like Telfair,
with a spotty jump shot.
It's exactly
2:58 in the morning back home.
And we're going for our first workout.
So when I get up,
we'll be going to our second workout.
Focus.
(Jamel) That's the reason why I got him
out here in Greece. Just to clear his head.
When I was back home,
I saw, like, a confused boy.
And I didn't like what I saw.
He was too Hollywood, you know.
It's good to be in the limelight,
but sometimes you forget what you have
to do, you know, to stay in that limelight.
So he gotta do this other
hard construction work over here.
Little faster, little faster, little faster.
There you go.
Ah. Ah!
Five dribbles.
No six dribbles. Five dribbles.
Know you're gonna make the shot.
Never second-guess your shot.
Second guess is
don't fucking shoot.
You know how when we used to go work
out, and we didn't have no cars or nothing.
You know, we'd have to go
borrow people's cars to go work out.
We'd be the best people in the gym,
even the NBA players,
and we didn't have
no vehicle to get around.
Well, I just signed my Adidas deal
and I just bought my brother a 645Ci.
Brand-new BMW. I don't know where
it is yet, y'all know when y'all see it.
Soon as we get back to the States,
I'm gonna give it to him.
I ain't seen it yet.
I know how it looks, but I just ordered it.
We get home the second.
It's, like, the 20-something right now.
So soon as we get home I'm gonna
give it to him. I know he's gonna go crazy.
Shh!
(shopkeeper) How are you?
(Jamel) That's really sweet, right?
Are you trying it on?
How's it feel?
Is it all right?
- (shopkeeper) You like it?
- Yeah, I like it.
- I like that one right there.
- Nah, that's... That's...
You gotta be grown for that.
You gotta be at least 23.
- That's real gold, man.
- I let y'all play my budget.
- No, no. We buy expensive.
- (shopkeeper) Yes, I know.
(Jamel) That's about 18?
18 thousand?
- (Sebastian) That's what I want.
- Not one diamond.
(man) Why are
so many high-school players moving?
Because we have a deluded draft pool.
Sebastian Telfair is a young man
who I think may be making a mistake.
He is not a lottery-type player.
He is small. He does not shoot the ball.
And I think
he could struggle in the league.
Oh, fuck.
Step off the line, man. Stop getting
frustrated the whole fucking time.
Ah, damn. Ten fucking shots
and I didn't make a fucking...
Fuck!
Can't make a shot, man.
I missed the last 20 shots, man.
- Fucking...
- Well, make 'em, then. Shit. Make 'em.
Fix the shot. You're a pro, fix your shot.
Fix your shot.
There you go. Shoot like a pro, man.
There you go.
Back down. Back down.
(Jamel) Pull him, Drew. Pull him, Drew.
Pull him. Pull him, Drew.
There you go.
Yeah.
Ten seconds.
- All right?
- Last 20 seconds.
Go.
(Dan) I've been reading
a lot of negativity.
You know, there's a whole lotta stress with
seeing where he's gonna be in the draft,
you know, and hoping
that everything works out right.
And my mother, she's scared because my
brother Jamel been through a lot of stuff.
She's scared. Even after the Adidas
contract and everything, she's still scared.
She always talks about,
"I just don't want them to hurt my baby."
Jamel's saying...
He's the same way.
Like, "I just don't want to hurt him.
I just don't want them to hurt him."
Go, Nico.
You keep playing like that,
I'm gonna fuck you up.
- Keep playing like that I'll fuck you up.
- What have I done? Yes? Why?
Get the fuck outta here.
(crowd chanting)
You must sign me next year.
I play for you like the same.
You sign me next year,
I play the same for you.
OK?
You sign me next year,
I play for you the same way. Bah!
(boys and Jamel repeat Greek word)
(speaks Greek)
- Oh, you like that?
- Oh, my...
Yo, check this out. We're living good
'cause we work hard, man.
That's all we do, is work hard.
When I buy my mother her house,
we'll have a swimming pool
that my little sister
and little brother will go crazy in.
And that'll feel good.
Follow me on my first...
(man) So the next time I see you,
what are we gonna be doing?
I'm not too sure yet.
I'm gonna figure it out later.
Yeah, my little brother got me
a nice little toy, you know what I'm saying?
It's called the Little Bentley.
Well, it's just another day
in Sebastian Telfair's life.
He gotta prove everybody wrong.
Everybody said he was too small,
he couldn't do this, couldn't do that.
Now look at us. Kid from Coney Island,
about to be in the draft. Making it.
We're here now. You know what
I'm saying? We're a few hours away.
We're, like, seven hours away from,
you know, his whole life gonna change.
Didn't everybody say, "Get Tiny"?
Now what they gonna say?
We got Benzes and little Bentleys
and Maybachs. What they gonna say now?
All type of diamonds and stuff.
What they gonna say now?
They can't say nothing.
You know what I'm saying?
- Yo, this is draft...
- Yo! Hold on...
You know what I just told 'em? I say...
I'll put my seatbelt on,
before you try to get something on me.
I just tell them... Yo. I just say, "They say
'Get Tiny.' What they gonna do now?"
We're driving Beamers, we're driving
little BMs. What they gonna do now, Tiny?
We got all kind of diamonds and shit.
We got all types of shit.
What the fuck are they gonna do now?
Know what I'm saying? Now we got
all types of shit coming through,
'cause we got a millionaire nigger!
Now what they gonna do?
- Gonna tell me ingredients?
- Yes, yes.
Only thing about my mother,
she knows how to play dominos. That's it.
- Dominos.
- And cook.
- Nah, she can't do that no more.
- No, because I'm getting a cook.
We're gonna have a cook. So y'all
come on in, and we're gonna ring a bell.
I'll ring a bell, and she goes,
"What you want, Mrs. Telfair?"
So excited.
This is the biggest day in Coney Island.
Little man gets drafted,
everything gonna be real smooth today.
- Did the papers have a pick?
- Yeah.
- What pick? 23rd?
- 22nd.
- So who?
- What?
They got 22nd pick in there?
Yo, you gotta get your button-ups.
And get your polo shirts too.
- What pants?
- Bring all the stuff you bought yesterday.
Yo, not the suit.
Go onto the 64. And when you go
out the tunnel, take Canal Street.
(radio) With the third pick
in the 2004 NBA draft.
The Chicago Bulls select Ben Gordon
from the University of Connecticut.
- Hey, Mom. We're here.
- Yeah, we're here, Daniel.
... fourth NBA draft.
The Toronto Raptors select...
Rafael Araujo!
... the 2004 NBA draft.
The Golden State Warriors select
Andris Biedrins from Latvia.
(man) You all right? Huh?
You all right?
...Portland on the clock,
let's go visit with the commissioner again
to find out what the Trail Blazers
will do at number 13.
With the 13th pick in the 2004 NBA draft.
The Portland Trail Blazers select
Sebastian Telfair
from Lincoln High School.
(cheering)
- (man) It's all good, baby.
- You ain't gotta cry no more.
Sit up. Sit up. Sit up.
Oh, Lord have mercy!
Lord have mercy!
13, son!
- Relax, Daddy.
- (boy crying)
Let's go, boy.
Let's go. 13, boy!
Where's my mother?
Where's my mommy?
Sebastian! Sebastian! Your mother's
right here! Your mother's right here!
That's right. You made it, bro.
You made it, baby.
(all chant)
(chanting continues)
You got it.
- That's it, baby. That's it.
- (Sebastian sobs)
Don't cry.
I got it out already. I got it out already.
You all right?
Don't worry about it, I got it out already.
I got it out. I got it out already.
It all came out.
This is just the start
of a new beginning. All right?
Gimme some love, baby.
Well, this is where it's at right now.
Head out before school, start working out.
Making everybody see
that you're ready to play.
So we gonna go on this court,
we gonna do some drills.
Get ready, then get you some breakfast,
then you gonna go to school. All right?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Let's go. Because if you want to be better
than Sebastian, you gotta work harder.
Ready? Go.
Oh, you gotta see it. You gotta see it
going in. You gotta see it going in.
Good. Let's go.
See, everybody dreaming now.
They're dreaming now. We're working.
Yeah.
Gotta be one motion,
gotta be one motion.
Gotta be like you're dancing,
like you're skating on ice.
Good. Again.
Let's go. You getting tired on me?
This too hard for you?
No.
You can't be tired.
- No such thing as tired.
- Yes, there is!
- No, there's not! Let's go.
- Yes, there is.
Uh-huh. Good.
Yeah, yeah!
There we go.
There we go. There we go.
That's how you work.
That's how you work. Let's go.
# I stay in B-r-o-o-k-l-y-n
# And I intend to let the whole world know
# Next to blow, go ahead, test the pro
# Got every head nodding
till the last one left the show
# And yo, it's been a long time coming
# Been at it too many years
to wind up with nothing
# Shed too many tears, and still I hear
# That the future ain't crystal clear,
but that don't stop me
# The streets got me,
all my peoples got me
# Never by myself,
if I ever fell, my family caught me
# Faith in them, and their faith in me
# Be taking me places
that I couldn't wait to see
# Making me push beyond my limits
# Beyond the gimmicks,
I got hard work in it
# Coney Island, Flatbush,
all the way to Fort Green
# Brooklyn got me through the fire,
know what I mean?
- # Brooklyn turned it out
- # Without a doubt
# Look who's the player
they be talking about
- # Brooklyn turned it out
- # Without a doubt
# Yo, I'm the player they be talking about
# I see too many dark days
that almost got me
# Too many naysayers trying to knock me
# Too many haters who straight forgot me
# But I got too much heart
for all of them to stop me
# Too many hours in the power struggle,
trying to bubble and come up
# Doubled my efforts,
run from from sunup to sundown
# Blinded, shining when I come round
# Blinded 'cause I got dreams
of fellers trying to run down
# And this ain't easy, man,
believe me, I just make it look that way
# Twisting, left 'em shook that way
# Stay at it till I'm tapping
on the door of success
# More or less I never rest
until I'm gasping for breath
# And I won't stop till I drop
# Knowing most times in life
you only get one shot
# Going all out for me,
my family, and my team
# Their love got me through the fire,
know what I mean?
- # Brooklyn turned it out
- # Without a doubt
# Yo, who's the player
they be talking about?
- # Brooklyn turned it out
- # Without a doubt
# Look, I'm the player they be talking about
- # Brooklyn turned it out
- # Without a doubt
# Look, who's the player
they be talking about?