We go now. Where your friend?
He's outside taking a piss.
He'll be right back.
Gun no good. You give me.
No. It's a very good gun.
Give me your gun. You understand?
I understand. I'm just
not giving you my gun.
Give him the gun, Archer.
You're kidding, right?
Every 12-year-old in this
country is carrying a Kalashnikov.
Exactly why your pea
shooter ain't worth shit.
Give it to him.
Where are you from?
All over.
But I was born in Sudan.
Your English is very good.
So is yours.
What is your business here?
Ahmed asked me to come.
He didn't tell me.
I can't negotiate like this.
Negotiate what?
I have six crates of Semtex,
custom-built
detonators, in my truck.
Are you interested?
Please...
sit down.
I can also show you how to use
them without blowing yourself up.
Unintentionally, that is.
Unintentionally.
That's funny.
Samir. Ahmed.
He was just about to.
What was that all about?
The captain was impressed with the
SIG. I told him he could keep it.
My gun?
You gave him my gun?
A small gesture of good will goes a
long way in this part of the world.
Shukran. Let's go.
Come on! Come on!
Hello, Mr. Horn, I'm
Special Agent Clayton, FBl.
This is Agent Archer.
FBl?
Since when does the
FBl operate in Yemen?
We don't. We have no authority here.
You're under Yemeni custody.
Bad fucking news for you.
If you're willing to help us,
we may be able to help you.
You're gonna help
me with no authority?
They listen to us a touch closer
when it comes to terrorism.
Oh, I'm a terrorist?
I don't know. You tell me. You
been selling them explosives?
Oh, I sell to whoever
can afford to buy.
Like the United States government.
Only ours don't
kill innocent people.
Oh, yeah, they do, genius.
People just usually
have darker skin.
Let's skip the political debate.
We just want to know where
the Semtex was headed.
I don't know. I didn't ask.
But you knew where it came from.
Yeah. It fell off
the back of a truck.
Answer the question.
You need to take some
lessons from the locals.
Ohh!
Let me talk to him.
Sorry. Must have forgotten
my Bill of Rights at home.
It's clear to me that
you're not a fanatic, Samir.
An opportunist perhaps,
but not a fanatic.
So consider this opportunity.
You have an American passport, which
means I can get you out of here.
But I do need an answer.
You want to spend the rest
of your life here, in Yemen?
You go right ahead.
But you and I both know
that I'm likely to be
the last friendly face you're
gonna see for a very long time.
I don't have anything to say to you.
The only difference
between you and him
is he knows he's an asshole.
Why don't you just go
home, Agent Clayton.
- Nice guy.
- You shouldn't have hit him.
- He deserved it.
- That's not the point.
You get a suspect to talk
by pushing his buttons,
not by letting him push yours.
Nobody ever teach you that?
You are a traitor. You sold us out.
Then why am I in here with you?
Allahu Akbar.
Eh, eh, eh.
You understand me?
Do you understand me?
Mmm.
Ah, forget Allah.
They cracked the encryption
on that satphone you
guys found in Yemen.
Check out the call log.
14 calls to Rome in early January,
17 calls to Berlin in March,
11 to Amsterdam in early May.
It correlates exactly with
the Al-Nathir bombings.
Rome, Berlin, Amsterdam.
Where did the calls go?
Payphones located in largely
immigrant, Muslim neighborhoods.
What have you found on Samir Horn?
No criminal record.
I searched NCIC, state
and local databases.
Nothing so far.
Well, check with the
military liaison, too.
He sure as shit didn't learn to put
detonators together in high school.
Allahu Akbar.
It's time to finish what we started.
It's already finished.
Lay your hand on any of my brothers,
and it will mean your life.
Shukran.
Where did you learn to play?
My father.
How about you?
Boarding school in Switzerland.
- You win.
- You want to play again?
I haven't had anybody
to play with for ages.
Why don't you play with one of them?
They're soldiers, not thinkers.
Soldiers or martyrs?
You know, I've been
in a lot of battles.
And they may have felt like
a suicide mission at the time,
but we always had
a plan to come home.
You must be willing to
sacrifice some of your pawns
if you want to win the game.
- I don't know.
- I think you do.
You risked your life to share
your food with a stranger.
That's not the same thing.
I was just doing my duty.
- If I'd known there was-
- Jihad is also your duty.
Ahmed told me what you
have done in Afghanistan.
Tactics have changed, my friend.
Tactics always change.
You don't defeat an empire
fighting by their rules.
Once upon a time,
it was the Americans who were
terrorists to the British.
They've forgotten
the history already.
Allahu Akbar.
Piece of sh-
Senor?
All right, don't tell anyone
I said this, but you're right.
- The military had a file on him.
- Hmm.
Staff Sergeant Samir Horn.
U.S. Army Special Forces.
Trained at Fort Bragg.
- Engineering and Explosives.
- All right, skip to the next page.
Horn was his mother's
name. She's from Chicago.
His father was Sudanese.
Moved all over the Middle East. Had
ties with the Muslim Brotherhood.
Was killed in a car bombing in '78.
Not sure which side was behind it.
- Is that so?
- Oh, and it gets better.
The Army sent Horn to Pakistan in
'86 to train in the Afghan rebels.
It's where he got in touch
with his Muslim roots.
Decided he wanted in on the action.
When his tour was
over, he stayed behind,
and joined the Mujahideen.
There's been a bombing in Spain.
Eleven Americans dead.
They've got the bomber.
...an American tour group
was the target of the
attack, apparently.
The latest carried out by
Nathir, the Islamic terrorist
whose identity and whereabouts
remain a mystery to authorities.
Do you have a woman? A family?
No.
You don't want no kids?
I don't have a woman.
What language do you dream in?
English.
Me, too.
Really?
You know, it's funny-
I don't even feel at home
speaking my own language sometimes.
I don't feel at home anywhere.
Samir. Samir?
There is somebody that I want you
to meet when we get out of here.
We're in prison in
Yemen for terrorism.
I wouldn't make any plans, man.
This guy's got to be
in a state of shock.
He planned on waking up in
Paradise with 72 virgins.
Blow yourself up to get laid.
This has got to be some crazy shit.
Where I grew up, the Klan burned
crosses in front of people's houses
and called it "Christianity. "
And then my daddy and
the folks from the church
would drive over and put 'em out.
Seems every religion
has more than one face.
How you doin'?
Okay, I think I know.
You wish you were dead, don't ya?
You wish you'd been successful?
I've killed dozens of infidels.
But you're still alive.
And you don't strike me as a coward.
Of course I'm not a coward.
Well, some people are going
to think you lost your nerve.
I didn't.
You know, tomorrow's newspaper is going
to have your face on the front page
with a story about you being
captured and helping the police.
- That's a lie.
- You survived the blast.
You fell into enemy hands.
I don't think it is a lie.
Who do you think's gonna
have to pay for your failure?
So I'm guessing it'll
be your cousin, Hussein.
He's the one that got
you into all this, right?
Don't be surprised, Ziyad.
We know everything about you-
family, friends...
work, phone records.
We even know what you
listen to on your iPod.
Leave me alone.
There is a way out.
But you're gonna have to
give us some information.
Nobody knows you're alive.
If you answer my questions,
tomorrow's headline could tell
the world that you're dead.
Why should Hussein suffer for this?
Why should everyone
think you're a coward?
Come on, Ziyad.
You talk now or talk later.
The only difference is the story
that everybody's gonna hear about you.
Everything all right, brother?
Have faith.
And stay close.
No, no, no! No, no, no.
Stay down. Wait, wait, wait.
Now! Go, go!
- Sh- - No, no,
no, no. Wait, wait.
Come on! Come on!
All I know is I was supposed
to go to America, not Spain.
Nathir was sending
a whole bunch of us.
And how many made it in the U.S.?
I don't know
- 30, 40. Maybe more.
They were handing out student visas.
And that's all I-
Nice work.
The confession we got
in Spain was clear.
Now, the only reason Ziyad Hamzi
didn't make it into the United States
is because his student
visa was rejected.
But Nathir has sent
others and they are here.
Anybody else have
anything on Nathir?
About six months ago we
picked up an intercept.
Nothing solid but they did
talk about a Al-Nathir operation
code named "Risala"-
an attack with multiple
suicide bombers here in the U.S.
Hold on a sec.
You had intel on a domestic
attack and you didn't pass it on?
It was unsubstantiated.
Well how could it be
if you didn't share it?
Enough. I don't want to hear
anymore about people hoarding intel.
We're taking this threat seriously.
The White House is
gonna want action.
I'm talking about a major roundup
of guys who fit this profile.
And everyone works together on this.
- Kelly was pretty worked up.
- So?
So a couple months back he
told me that you were working
an asset inside on Nathir.
That was off the record.
Yeah. I'm just saying maybe, uh...
maybe that guy knows something.
He's gone silent.
For all I know, he's gone
over to the other side.
When the ship docks,
you have a choice.
You can get off and
walk away as a free man.
Our people can get you past customs.
Then you're on your own.
What if I stay?
Our path is not for everyone.
I understand.
I think of you as a friend, Samir.
So I will tell you this.
Do not decide lightly.
- Bonsoir.
Merci beaucoup, ma cherie.
What's the matter?
- It's halal.
- It's a Krug '95, actually.
Don't look so disturbed, Samir.
We shave, we drink alcohol,
and sometimes we even eat pork.
Hmm?
In the Qur'an, it's called Taqiyya.
"Become like your enemy
to deceive your enemy. "
That's not Taqiyya.
Excuse me?
With all due respect,
Brother Fareed,
the Hadith says that the prophet
Muhammad Sall-Allahu Alayhi Wa Sallam
told his followers that they
could lie about being Muslims
to save their lives
if death was imminent.
- It didn't mention- -
Is death not imminent now?
We're at war today.
And to be effective,
you need to blend in.
No one's even looking at us.
I told you, he's not
some foot soldier.
Samir is a man of faith.
Faith is good.
But you have to know how
to follow orders, too.
In one of the largest Homeland
Security operations to date,
ICS and FBl agents are
questioning foreign students
who were issued visas in
Middle Eastern countries
over the past two years.
In some major cities, where
there are large numbers-
A number of American groups
have protested the operation,
claiming that it unfairly
targets innocent civilians
and amounts to racial profiling.
The American Civil
Liberty's Union has filed...
...has found that the American
invasion and occupation of Iraq
has helped spawn a new
generation of Islamic radicalism.
Homeland Security
- a waste of time and resources.
We'll never find them this way.
There are 1.2 billion
Muslims in this world.
Only 20% of them are Arab.
These people could look like
anybody, except maybe you.
What, so you don't think we
should be profiling these guys?
I just think we should be
concentrating on the one suspect
that we do have.
We train to kill, but it doesn't
mean that we love violence.
We use violence only because
it has been used against us.
The crusaders have invade our land,
drop bombs on our people,
stole our natural resources.
We are fighting to
end the suffering.
We are fighting to end the
humiliation and murder of-
The Americans accuse us of
killing innocent civilians.
Yet they have been spilling the
blood of innocent Muslims for decades.
Does our blood not count?
Allahu Akbar.
History has shown us
that time and time again
no matter how great the empire,
no matter how difficult the odds,
a man who is not afraid to
die can never be defeated.
Allahu Akbar.
Thank you.
Your son is in a lot of trouble.
What sort of trouble?
He's involved with a
terrorist organization.
Do you believe in
God, Detective Clayton?
Uh, we don't use the
term "Detective," ma'am.
You didn't answer my question.
Yes, I do believe in
God. Why do you ask?
Because you will never understand
a man like Samir if you don't.
Would you describe
him as a devout Muslim?
He's Muslim.
I don't believe there
is a sliding scale.
Do you know what the
word "Islam" means?
"Submission. "
Yes. "Submission. "
Submission to God's
will is absolute.
Do you think Samir believes it's
God's will for him to kill others?
You carry a gun yourself.
Now, you didn't answer my question.
My son has seen enough death
to understand the value of life.
Who is it?
FBl, ma'am. It's about Samir Horn.
Now, the State Department hasn't
answered any of my letters for weeks.
I mean, I don't even know
what prison he's being held in.
Well, he's not being held anymore.
He has escaped.
When? A week ago.
It was a prison break organized by
the terrorist group he's working with.
What are you talking about?
I mean, this whole
thing is a mistake.
I'm afraid it's not,
ma'am. We have evidence.
- What evidence?
- That's classified.
- I can't tell you that.
- Yeah, of course it is.
You people are incredible.
How long has it been
since you've seen him?
I don't remember.
If you want to help Samir,
you should talk to me.
Do you think that every
Muslim man is a terrorist?
On the contrary.
I am, however, looking
for those who are.
Now if you have any knowledge
of what he's been involved in,
you do have an obligation
to share that with me.
Are you charging me with anything?
No, I'm not.
When you have something
more than secret evidence,
then I'll talk to you.
Uh, they just fired
him. No explanation.
But, uh, it was pretty obvious why.
How did Samir take it?
How do you think?
So why did you let Mr. Horn go?
Jeez, that was over a year ago.
I don't recall the details.
The information that we gather for
these types of background checks
is strictly confidential.
Look, as far as I'm concerned,
a man's religion
is his own business.
But when you wear a skullcap and
pray to Allah five times a day,
people are gonna notice.
Some of our clients complained.
Horn gets to Chicago when he's 12.
He's just watched his father
die. He's arrived from Sudan.
He's going through culture
shock. It's a classic profile.
He's caught between
traditional Islam and the West.
His test scores are off the charts.
But it said he had some
behavioral problems.
He was kicked out of high school his
senior year for getting into a fight.
About what?
Three white students were
harassing a black girl.
Horn intervened.
Two of the boys had
to be hospitalized.
Now he enlisted in the
military right after that.
His Army file was classified.
But here's a copy.
After he leaves the Army,
Horn fights in Afghanistan
for a few years.
The list of people he could have met there is
practically a who's who of Islamic terrorists,
from Abdul Azim to Osama bin Laden.
Now we pretty much lose track of
him until he shows up in Bosnia
where he meets Chandra
Dawkin, the photojournalist.
- Is she a spy?
- No.
The FBl tried to question her,
but my source says
she was uncooperative.
Last fall is when
things seemed to change.
He loses his job, spends more
and more time at the mosque.
Then he begins disappearing
on these long trips overseas.
Last one he never comes back from.
And somewhere along the
way he meets up with someone
who's connected with
Nathir and bingo!
You got yourself a terrorist.
Boom!
If this were the real thing, he
could have blown everybody up.
Come on, Omar. This
kid is too young.
He's not ready. I'm telling you.
I'm sorry. Let me try again.
No. Nobody cares
about you being sorry.
We cannot have mistakes. We can't
play around with this shit, Omar.
Bring me somebody who can do it.
Please. I can do
this. Give me a chance.
Is this mission important or not?
'Cause if it's important,
you need to bring-
Samir.
Let him try again.
Turn around.
All right. Let's see what you have.
There's a copy of the transcript
printing out for you know, sir.
I got something.
This guy made a call yesterday
from a phone in Marseilles
that we've been sitting on.
Claims he's been
selected to become shahid.
You picking up a little Arabic?
Ah, just your basic "Jihady".
Now Clayton, this one's operational.
This cat thinks he's gonna be in
Paradise by the end of the week.
Brothers, I know how
proud everybody is
about what we're going to do.
It's an honor to carry
out a mission like this.
But we have a problem.
Somebody talked about it.
Hey, guys. I'm sorry.
It was just my cousin.
Omar, I didn't tell
him anything specific.
I just wanted him to
know, to tell my family.
Omar, he can be trusted. I swear.
It wasn't for you to decide.
Okay. Okay.
It will never happen again.
Omar. Wait a minute.
Don't let them
- Guys, hey!
Bashir!
No! Laissez-moi!
Laissez-moi!
No!
Hey, stupid! You just
ruined the mission.
What the hell is wrong with you?
You gonna put the bomb on now?
Listen to me.
The boy was a liability.
Samir, we don't allow liabilities.
We are very happy to welcome
you, but it was not necessary
for you to come all the way
here over one phone call.
We have reason to believe that
this particular phone booth
has been used by Nathir's
operatives in the past.
This could very well be
their next suicide bomber.
Thank you for the
information, monsieur,
but the situation is under
control, I assure you.
We didn't come here to play tourists.
We came here to stop an attack.
So can we please dispense
with the horse shit?
Okay.
Ali Abbas Mukhtar.
He was born in Marseilles.
French citizen. 17 years old.
But... no longer a threat.
Why is that?
He was found dead Tuesday morning.
Omar.
Nathir is angry.
He wanted this thing
to go forward on time.
Well, it can still happen.
We have to start over.
A new target, a new bomber.
Look, a new target, yeah. But for-
Bonjour.
Look, I've been thinking about this.
I want to use a remote trigger.
Do you know how important
this mission is, Samir?
Nathir is watching.
He has plan for you.
He knows who I am?
So tell me your idea.
The American Consulate in Nice.
The American Consulate in Nice
has sustained major damage
in a bombing earlier today.
Police are still searching the site for
the body of a suspected suicide bomber.
This attack bears all the hallmarks
of other blasts earlier this year
conducted by a group
calling itself Al-Nathir.
Three or more charges
of high-impact
explosives were placed...
Samir.
- As-Salamu Alaykum, my
friend. - Wa alaikum assalam.
- Welcome back.
- Thank you.
Congratulations,
Samir. Job well done.
The glory belongs to Allah.
Look.
...American Consulate here in Nice,
victim, of course, of a
devastating terrorist attack
earlier this morning.
The death toll is now confirmed at
eight, with five people reported injured.
Well done.
What's the matter?
Eight?
I
- I thought there would be more, many more.
My brother, congratulations
are in order.
What you have done is fantastic.
Today you have struck a great blow
against the myth of American power.
Nathir is pleased.
I only wish to serve his will.
That's good to know.
But tonight, you relax.
Please, make yourself at home.
There you are, my brother.
Nice view, huh?
Yeah.
What you did, Samir,
what we are doing-
it's all about setting
our people free.
Even if you and I
don't live to see it.
If a man hasn't discovered something
that he will die for,
he isn't fit to live.
Who said that?
Martin Luther King.
Ah.
You're a very funny man, Samir.
Yeah.
Lab results are back.
Traces of PETN, RDX.
Semtex again.
Just like the other Nathir attacks.
Except all the other
attacks were suicide bombers,
and this looks like it's
from an RF Receiver, hmm?
Yes.
He used small charges.
One...
and two.
But just in the correct place
to make collapse the building.
This man, he knows what he's doing.
RF range is usually no
more than a hundred meters,
so let's pull the tapes
for all the security cameras
within a five-block radius.
No one there. Keep going.
More.
Back it up right there.
What happened?
There were no Americans inside.
The two dead embassy
employees were fakes,
bodies from the morgue
with false identities
just like we talked about.
Why is the news saying eight people?
There was some unscheduled
maintenance in a part of the consulate
that was supposed to
be empty, all right?
I didn't know they'd be there.
Listen, we couldn't
control everything.
Nobody was supposed to
die! I'm sorry, Samir.
Look, what do you want me to say?
We set off a bomb.
No, I set off a bomb.
Look, I know you paid
a price to get this far.
Okay? You're close.
You're very close.
I don't know, man. You tell me.
Do we stop?
What made you learn Arabic?
I took a class in
college and got hooked.
I even switched my major from
Religion to Arabic Studies.
You were a Religion major?
My daddy was a Baptist minister.
His daddy was a Baptist minister.
It's in the blood.
You know, when J.
Edgar were in office,
he never would have
let you into the FBl.
Wasn't my original plan.
Not a lot of jobs, however,
for Ph. D.s in Arabic Studies.
Oh, I get it now.
You were an egghead who got
dragged into a street fight.
Nobody gets dragged
into a street fight.
Welcome to Toronto, Brother Samir.
It's a great honor, Emir.
Please, sit.
Thank you.
- Tea?
- Yes, thank you.
Omar tells me that you play chess.
Only a little. Thank you.
In chess and in war,
the key to winning
is to anticipate what your
opponent will do in advance.
Think two moves ahead.
The art of asymmetrical warfare
is less about inflicting damage
than provoking a response.
Terrorism is theater.
And theater is always
performed for an audience.
Ours is the American people.
But we are dispersed
across a large country.
The question is,
how to convince them
that nowhere is safe.
Samir, imagine a bus
traveling cross-country
filled with average,
everyday Americans.
People from
- from all over.
From small towns, from the country.
Imagine the effect it would have
if that very same bus
were to suddenly explode.
Now multiply that by 50.
Fifty buses across the
heartland of America,
all at the same time,
on the same day.
We call this operation
Risala Shukra Al-hiba.
For years we've been planting
martyrs in their midst.
They are waiting for a signal,
instructions, material.
We need somebody who can move about
the country without drawing attention.
Somebody who blends in.
An American messenger, Samir.
He isn't capable of this.
I don't like having to
show these to you, Chandra.
But we need to find him
before this happens again.
Samir always said that these
people were Islam's worse enemies.
Oh, he fought a Holy War with
these folks in Afghanistan
and then again in Bosnia.
He was trained to kill.
He was a soldier, not a murderer.
I believe he deceived you
as much as anybody else.
His faith was a source of strength.
Not this.
- Welcome to the U.S.
- Thanks.
I'm a friend of Nassim's.
I'm here to see Iqbal.
Shukran.
They transferred the funds for the
Spain bombing the Middle Eastern way.
You give a thousand Euros
to somebody in one city
and their cousin or
uncle pays it in the-
Thank you, Mr. Hayes, we do
know what a hawala network is.
The money trail ended in London.
A Pakistani with some
shady business dealings
was the source of the money
for the Spain operation.
Yesterday he transferred
$25,000 to Los Angeles.
Do you have an ID on him?
We're close.
That's an encrypted phone.
You can call me on it safely.
Nobody can listen in.
Including the FBl?
Yeah. Especially the FBl.
When do you think you can get
in a room with Nathir again?
I don't know.
Probably not until I do what
it is they sent me to do.
Then you keep on going.
Well, the problem is,
to keep going means
I'm going to have to put real
bombs in their hands now soon.
If that what it takes
to keep your cover.
Do you realize how far I've gone
to protect your identity, Samir?
I have kept you
completely off the books.
My boss, his boss
- nobody knows you even exist.
Look, I don't give a shit
about any of that, okay?
We need to rethink things.
If you don't succeed, we
may not get another chance.
How far are you
willing to take this?
We've got blood on our hands.
We've killed innocent people.
Yeah, and if we stop now,
they'll have died for nothing.
This is a war.
You do what it takes to win.
You know who you sound like, right?
We're the good guys, Samir.
Oh, I know.
Hey!
Remember who you answer to.
I answer to God. We all do.
- Any problem?
- No.
Omar. Omar, Omar! Don't! Don't!
Can't blow up unless
there's a detonator in it.
- Don't worry.
- It still makes me nervous.
We gotta talk about how we're
gonna send these e-mails.
What do you mean? I thought
we decided to use coded e-mail.
No, no, we did. We did.
But the problem is e-mails
can get intercepted.
I got a better idea.
We're gonna give each of our people an
e-mail account and a password. All right?
Then when we're ready to
go, we log onto each one,
we write the instructions,
but we don't send them.
We save it as a draft.
The next morning they log on,
they check their unsent messages.
Nothing is sent.
There's nothing for
the FBl to intercept.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I like this.
Here are the names.
There's only ten.
We don't risk putting
them all on one list.
None of them even knows
that the other exists.
Ah. I like that.
As-Salamu Alaykum, sister.
Sorry.
That's okay.
They want that file
translated right away.
Sure.
From British Intelligence, huh?
Yeah.
Good night. Good night.
You have to get out, now.
Leave nothing.
Hold it right there!
Get your hands up!
Right there! Against the wall!
Mr. Raman, how are you?
Perhaps you haven't had time to read
the fine print of the Patriot Act,
but any person operating a
money transmitting business
must register with
the U.S. government.
Something you neglected
to do, Mr. Raman.
Now each transfer
in excess of $10,000
can be treated as a separate felony
and each count is punishable
by up to five years in prison.
And you moved over $2 million.
I mean, you are the money
guy. You can do the math.
Now if you choose to cooperate, the
charges against you will be dropped.
The choice is yours.
We'll give you five
minutes to think about it.
Wait!
You having some car trouble?
Yeah, it was making a funny noise.
I think the radiator's loose.
I got a toolbox.
I've been praying
for this day to come.
Your prayers have
been answered, brother.
Now these go to the
trigger mechanisms.
All you have to do is attach
it to the power source.
This e-mail account has your
final instructions on it.
Chandra.
- Samir!
- Don't, don't, don't, don't!
Pretend we're not talking. They're
probably watching you right now.
Just keep stretching.
Keep stretching.
Samir, what's going on?
I'm sorry. I never meant to
get you mixed up in all of this.
Mixed up in what?
I mean... you didn't have anything to
do with that bombing in France, right?
Just keep stretching.
Samir, I need to know the truth.
The truth is...
it's complicated.
Holy shit.
Get on the radio.
Hey.
Did you do
- Did you do what they said?
Yes.
Then you just stop it. Okay?
Whatever
- Whatever you're involved in.
- Chandra- - Whatever
you're doing, you just-
Chandra, listen to me. I can't
stop and I'm not coming back.
You have to forget about
me. Just forget about me.
- No, Samir, listen to me-
Samir- - Let me go. Let me go.
We're on the ground.
No, just keep him in your
sight, but don't move on him yet.
We're on our way.
We're at 128 South Randolph Avenue.
Continuing surveillance undetected
is going to be a problem.
We think he entered
that building there, sir.
Who followed him in?
Uh, we were waiting for backup.
You two go around
back. You take the side.
Come on. Let's go.
It's all right. We're
not here for you, fellows.
- I'll take the rooftop.
- Okay.
Ohh!
Agent Clayton.
You're a persistent son
of a bitch, aren't you?
You're a hard man to catch.
Turn around!
Not too late, Samir. We
can work something out.
Tell 'em to stay put.
You're coming out.
Basement's clear. I'm coming out.
Copy that.
We have something in common.
My father's a man of God, too.
Yeah? We're practically brothers.
Sit on your hands.
Sit on 'em.
I've read some of your
father's teachings.
He's a man of great integrity.
How'd you stray so far
from his way of thinking?
- Your father was a preacher?
- Oh, yeah.
Then you know the Lord's Prayer.
Say it.
Our Father, who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come-
Ohh.
He's gone.
And we had guys
everywhere looking for him.
But those basement tunnels-
they run under five
city blocks of buildings.
Yeah. He knew that, too.
He used to live there.
128 South Randolph.
It was in his file.
It didn't occur to me.
I wonder why he let you live.
Because I didn't try to beat
the crap out of him like you did.
Carter, you put a tracker on me?
- Are you crazy?
- The FBl's all over you.
- I'm on a meet!
- Come with me.
I'm on a meet, Carter!
Shit. Push me. Push me!
Let's go!
What the hell happened?
Who was that? It was a cop.
I went to see a woman.
An old girlfriend of mine.
And
- And they were watching her, and then the dude jumped on me.
I didn't even know he was
there until I got to the-
We have to get out of
the country tonight.
We've only made contact
with 30 of the bombers.
You better hope that's enough.
And when we see Fareed, let me talk.
Put your seatbelt on.
This is the car Horn
stole from the projects.
Two of the shell casings
have his prints on them.
The body's over here.
You say you had a federal ID on him?
Yeah. Intelligence contractor.
As-Salamu Alaykum, Brother Fareed.
Wa alaikum assalam, Omar.
- As-Salamu Alaykum. -
Wa alaikum assalam, Samir.
Good trip?
Um... we had a problem.
Samir has made a small mistake.
- He went to see a
woman- - Chandra Dawkin?
Yeah, Chandra Dawkin. Listen-
Yeah, but Fareed, the important thing is
that he carried out his mission successfully.
The important thing is...
that she was cooperating
with Federal agents.
No. No.
That's
- I'm sorry. You're mistaken, Brother Fareed.
I'm not mistaken.
We have a source inside the FBl.
Well then your source is mistaken.
There's
- No. She would never do that. I've known this woman for years.
Show Samir to his room please.
Omar and I need to talk alone.
Yeah, but he's an integral
part of our mission, Fareed.
Yes. But going to see the
woman has put us in jeopardy.
Oh, come on, man.
Who amongst us hasn't
faced temptation?
This isn't about temptation, Omar.
It's about security.
Leave aside your friendship
for just one moment,
my brother, and think.
Think sensibly.
What if he did it deliberately, huh?
Unfortunately his actions
have left us with a doubt.
And what does that mean?
We eliminate all doubts.
Ml5 has recovered some
files from a hard drive
in Nathir's London safe house.
One of them has a
record of an operation-
Risala Shukra Al-hiba.
Where have I heard that before?
Our phone intercept.
Your intercept only picked up
the first part of the code name.
The date of the attack is
in the full name. Leyla?
"Risala" means "message,"
"Shukra" means "thanks" and
"Al-hiba" is "the gift. "
So the literal translation is
"Message of thanks for the gift. "
Thanksgiving.
Exactly. That's when
they're gonna strike.
In two days time.
What about the target?
Well, we found traces
of Semtex in the vehicle
Horn abandoned in Chicago.
But that was purchased
in California a month ago.
And he could have been distributing bombs
right across the entire country by now.
We'll raise the threat level.
Double up protection on bridges,
airports, monuments, the White House.
Sir, I would also suggest that we place
Horn on the high-value target list, too.
He killed a good man.
You're not going to get
any objections from us.
- You let me win, Omar.
- No.
No, I swear.
You've gotten better, my friend.
Please, don't bullshit me.
You beat me enough times for me to
know when you're throwing a game.
Fareed has made up his mind.
Sorry. It's not your fault.
I did this.
We're only men, my friend.
I have a girl in Paris, Samir.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
She thinks I'm a music producer.
You know, it's true what they say.
War is the lesser jihad.
To overcome temptation,
to live rightly,
that is the great jihad.
And is that what we've been doing?
You ever ask yourself that?
Sometimes.
But Nathir is the leader.
And my duty is to follow.
Come, let's pray.
We've just received word
from our source in Washington.
It appears you're on the
high-value target list.
What is that? What does that mean?
It means I owe you
an apology, Samir.
That means that the American
government has put a fatwa on you.
They want you dead.
Hang on. This is
- The system's running really slow.
We need to get back on the road
and make it to Halifax by tonight.
Halifax?
They will be looking for
us big time after tomorrow.
We'll be cruising
across the ocean by then.
All of us.
Computer's frozen.
What?
Jeez, I gotta reboot
the whole thing.
- What do you mean?
- Good God.
- I gotta get some coffee.
- No, no, no. You stay here.
I'll get it.
Make sure you get the
numbers exactly right.
I want each person on
the road at the same time.
Got it.
That's it.
- Done?
- Yeah, we're good.
Let's go.
Aah.
You've got to be shitting me.
The U.S. is going to be attacked today and
we just arrived at the ass-end of Canada.
- Roy Clayton?
- Yeah.
This fax came for you.
What is it?
The county records for the
two State Department employees
killed at the consulate
bombing in Nice.
Well, these people died as infants.
Wait a sec.
These deaths are fake.
Yeah.
A few dozen ships in port right now,
but only these five are
scheduled to head out today.
All right, all these ships
are destined for U.S. ports
except for this one
- The Ivory Star.
- It's a tanker registered out of Aden.
- Yemen?
- That's gotta be it.
You want to board her, we'll need an
official request from the FBl in Washington.
We go through HQ, this information's
gonna get leaked right back.
Wait a minute.
Customs can search any ship that it wants
if it thinks it has drugs on board, right?
You have any friends
left in Narcotics?
We'll soon find out.
Good to see you.
Welcome, my friend.
This is going to be a great day.
It's almost time.
The Americans love to brag about how
their government represents the people.
So we should accept that every
American shares equal responsibility
for their government's crimes.
Nobody is innocent.
We're leaving harbor soon, Emir.
We have to stay below
decks for a while.
What's the matter with you?
Uh, I'm getting a little seasick.
I think I need to take
some air. May I, Emir?
- You're the head of security, brother?
- Yes, sir.
And how many men in your
detail guarding the Emir?
Seven crew members. Don't
worry. We're certainly safe.
Shit. Nothing.
I think he's leading
us on a goose chase.
That was the harbor master.
There's one more ship going
into international waters today.
Cargo carrier headed for Marseilles.
Which one is it?
Samir?
Wait, brother. Think
of your duty to-
Omar! Omar! Omar!
Don't shoot! Don't
shoot! Listen to me!
What have you done, Samir?
- I didn't come here to kill you, Omar.
- You are a traitor!
No! Nathir was the traitor.
Fareed was the traitor.
They betrayed Islam!
No! I don't want to listen to you!
- I'm gonna kill you, Samir!
- It doesn't matter.
I was dead as soon as I
stepped foot on this ship.
But I had to stop them.
I had to stop this-
What the hell are you talking
about? You haven't stopped shit!
Thirty buses are going to explode!
Allahu Akbarl
What are you doing?
Who are you?
- Allahu Akbar, Allahu Akbar.
- Why are we on the same bus?
What the hell are you doing?
I put them all on the same bus.
No. No, that can't be.
I saw you give them the bombs.
I saw the e-mails.
I changed the e-mails, Omar.
It's over.
I put my trust on you.
I thought you were my brother!
Omar.
I am your brother.
They used you, Omar.
They used me, too. All of them.
They used us for our faith.
Drop your weapon!
Omar. Omar!
Hold your fire. Hold your fire!
Samir?
Samir, where's Nathir?
Hang in there, Samir.
Call a paramedic.
It'll be okay.
Samir.
You wanna take a ride and talk?
We can talk right here.
Good to see you up and about.
Didn't know if you'd make it.
How's the shoulder?
I'll live.
I don't suspect anybody's
said this to you,
but this country
owes you a huge debt.
You came all the way out
here just to tell me that?
Come on, Clayton.
I'm going someplace.
What do you want?
I've had your file wiped clean.
Everything.
The bombing at France,
the bus, all of it.
Effectively, you're a free man but
there's still a lot that you can do for us.
I'm a free man?
This doesn't feel like
freedom to me, Clayton.
You think because you hit
"delete" on some computer somewhere
that that's it, it's over?
I made choices about people's lives.
- And I gotta live with that.
- I understand.
- Forever, Clayton.
- I understand that.
But you and I both know that
this fight is far from over.
You know, the Qur'an says that
if you kill an innocent person,
it's as if you've
killed all mankind?
It also says that if you save a life,
it's like you've saved all mankind.
You're a hero, Samir.
Look, whatever you want to call me,
I'm done.
Well, we know how
to find each other.
As-Salamu Alaykum.
Wa alaikum assalam.
And you should start the
conversation with that.