Before he died,
5 minutes before he passed away,
I was holding his hand
and requested him to
come back as a reincarnation.
Geshe-La replied that it all
depends on your all's prayers.
I know that Geshe-La
don't like me to cry,
but I just could not stop.
And Geshe-La said,
"Don't worry, don't cry.
"I have done everything in my life,
"I am totally satisfied with my life.
"Don't cry."
But still, I can't stop.
Look, pearl relics!
Oh, here, here.
- Tenzin Zopa, use both hands.
- Be careful, the ashes will fall in...
Oh, look here.
A pattern in the sand.
Now you can see it clearly.
What does it look like?
A footprint.
Here, here.
It points to the east,
in this direction.
Dear Tenzin, we know you were
especially trusted by Geshe-La.
There was an unshakeable bond
between you,
and since you were little,
he took care of and nurtured you
right up until his death.
We must find his
unmistaken reincarnation,
someone who will continue
his kind deeds
and help all living beings. Right?
Therefore, you should take responsibility
for finding his reincarnation.
As you may know...
we checked the smoke
direction during the cremation
and the sand pattern
under the cremation pyre.
We were also told that
many pearl relics were found.
These are significant signs.
I personally informed
the Dalai Lama
and he said:
"If there are such clear signs,
"we can start looking
for the reincarnation."
I was, I mean, totally confused.
There is joy hearing that
Geshe-La would definitely return.
His Holiness already confirmed.
But when I hear that I have to be
the main person, I don't want.
I just cannot trust my feelings.
I'm not Buddha.
If something is a visible object,
of course you can see it,
but this is something that
you need to see its inner quality,
whether this is the same mind
of Lama Konchog or not.
But to know that,
only Buddhas know within Buddhas,
ordinary cannot judge
higher than your state.
Last night, I had
a very interesting dream.
It's Geshe Lama Konchog's holy body,
the dead body is lying outside.
And from Geshe Lama Konchog's
dead body, one little boy came out.
And he's like quite fatty-fatty
and quite small, you know?
So then he called my name:
"Tenzin Zopa, Tenzin Zopa,
"give me your hand."
So then I passed my hand.
You know the feeling in the dream
was so joyous
and suddenly with that joy,
I was waken up.
Swambhu Shrine.
This is east from Kopan.
Towards India?
It's here.
This mountain is the
"Snow Minister", Ganesh Himal.
Now the astrological check
will be done.
Should I send it to Taiwan?
Yes, today.
For us, your disciples,
born from your holy teachings,
there is no other refuge than you.
How could you possibly
forsake us?
Come in your unmistaken
reincarnation to guide us.
In one moment,
after Geshe-La passed away,
I got this very, very lost feeling.
Almost like I want
to give up many things,
just don't know what to do,
and like...
Because I never planned
for my life, you see.
Everything was planned
by Geshe-La:
"You are going to do this,
you'll do that."
So I always say "yes",
just follow,
and I didn't think at all
about what is going to happen next.
- Heruka Center.
- Yes, in Taiwan.
- Oh, Lobsang Jamyang.
- Yes.
- You see...
- What it means?
My astrology check
pointed to three options,
but one of them is much more
significant than the others.
I checked for the reincarnation's
birthplace and the father's name.
What came out,
with a probability of 95%,
is that the father's name
begins with the letter "A".
You have to search for a father
whose name starts with "A".
As for the reincarnation's birthplace,
the syllable "TS" came out.
As you know, Geshe-La meditated
for years in Tsum Valley.
Most probably,
the child was born in that area.
Tsum Valley is my birthplace,
where I was born.
During that time Geshe-La
already moved to his third cave,
which is about an hour from
my village, up in the mountains.
Always, he's always like this,
you see, always...
Huge and, you know,
long ears, laughing.
Yeah, I used to be with him like this.
I truly believe
that his reincarnation has come.
However, there is a possibility
of finding a mistaken one
if the disciples lack merits.
Therefore, you should be
careful and meticulous.
You don't have the power to say:
"This is the true reincarnation
"or not."
So don't trust
everything people say,
don't take everything as true,
as people will tell you
many unusual stories.
If someone is labeled
as the reincarnation
and turns out
to be a strange character,
then all becomes strange,
and such things have happened.
- Please, Tenzin Zopa.
- You don't need to offer me.
- Please accept this.
- No need, give to the others.
- Oh, thank you.
- Good to see you again.
How kind of you,
thank you very much.
Hello, how are you?
Hello. Oh, thank you.
Have people here said anything
about his reincarnation?
We do pray for his reincarnation,
but the most important thing
is that the High Lamas
search and test.
We don't have clairvoyance
or realizations.
Please ask the High Lamas
to search for him.
So we can see him again.
You are his closest disciple.
When I see you,
he appears in my mind.
I miss him.
- Brother, where are you from?
- From Lokpa.
I see.
Is this the right way to Chulae?
- Yes, it's over there.
- OK.
Sister, where are you from?
- From Chulae.
- Chulae. I see.
In Chulae, are there any children
aged one to one and a half?
There are many children,
but I don't know.
However, nowadays people are...
you know...
You'll have to
see for yourself, brother.
OK, thank you.
Child. Come, come.
Here's a toffee.
What's your name?
Tsering Dhondup.
What's your father's name?
- Choepel.
- Choepel, OK.
Give one to your brother.
- Do you recognize this rosary?
- Yes.
Is it yours?
- Yes?
- A rosary.
Um... Is this Uncle's or yours?
- Uncle's.
- Uncle's? OK.
Touch your forehead.
Hello. How do you do?
Brother, come inside.
- What is his name?
- Him? Nyima Tseten.
- Nyima Tseten.
- Yes.
Nyima Tseten.
Are you Nyima Tseten?
For long life.
Want a balloon?
What's your name?
Nyima Tseten.
Oh, he isn't moving.
Like a yogi!
Do you recognize this?
He's smiling.
See you again, OK?
- Stay well.
- Thank you.
Any children aged one
to one and a half here?
Chulae, I see.
Pangdun is down there?
Chulae... Nyiloe...
OK. Thank you.
Touch your forehead.
Do you want to become a monk?
Do you want?
Can you recite the Mani Mantra?
I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know.
Don't know. Don't know.
He has long ears
and a wide forehead too.
He looks very fortunate and lucky.
What a cute boy!
May my venerable
Lama's life be firm,
Dispelling the darkness
of all beings in the three realms.
In all my future lives,
never separated from perfect gurus.
May I enjoy
the magnificent teachings.
Do you recognize it?
Between one and one and a half?
Tsering Paljor has a son of that age.
- I see.
- He's one.
- One and a half?
- No, he's not yet one.
- Not yet one?
- Right.
Hello, come in.
Son, sit up there. - It's OK here.
He is truly very good and obedient.
When her daughter was born,
several people helped.
But when this boy was born,
only her husband was there.
I see.
- An easy delivery, no?
- I see.
Before his birth,
I dreamt that I was herding cows
near Geshe-La's retreat.
The dream was very clear.
She was pregnant
when she had this dream.
OK, come.
You want to go?
Hey, he said no.
Such attitude.
What is this?
Do you recognize it?
In summer time, there will be a very,
very beautiful blue flower.
Blue, and the entire area will be
covered with flowers, even this.
All these are actually flower trees.
White, green, blue, yellow...
all different types.
And even these bamboo trees
will be more green,
and like, then windy...
And after that everything,
everyone is dancing.
Everybody will dance.
Every nature tree will dance.
The waterfall will dance,
trees will dance, you see here?
Dancing, dancing.
This is dancing.
Free dance.
Like this flower.
So beautiful, happy and free.
But sorry anyway, I...
I took permission from the tree.
So that's why I'm taking it.
Actually now it's not free,
before it was free.
I remember that
since the age of 3,
I used to run up to
Geshe Lama Konchog's cave up there.
So I usually run from
that juniper tree, up to...
Like this.
Day after day
and month after month,
even when it was snowing
I came up.
And my family put a full effort.
They tried separating me
from Geshe La.
They want me to be a householder,
they want me to get married.
This is at the age of 6 and 7,
they had already found
a girl for me.
I am totally not interested in this.
So then, one day I really
screamed at my father:
"Just let me see him, and I will
ask one last question:
'Geshe-La, can you accept me?
'Can you let me follow you? '
"If Geshe-La says 'no',
"I would never ever ask again,
"and I will follow Papa,
"but if Geshe-La says 'yes',
no one can stop me."
Nothing, nothing.
Nothing left but still,
I don't know,
due to Geshe-La's prayer,
he loved flowers so much,
rose flowers are left.
So many, you know,
so many about to come.
It will be beautiful.
Definitely that is the same flower.
It's 100% of...
200% sure.
I always plucked a flower
and quietly put on his ear.
Just like before, pluck flower,
and Geshe-La was meditating,
so I slowly put on his ear
and he doesn't bother.
Later on, when I sleep,
sometimes he slowly
put on my ear, like that.
It used to be beautiful.
I mean, the outward appearance
used to be beautiful,
but now everything is gone.
It's like...
Last time...
He insists to become a monk
and doesn't want to go to school.
Do you want to become a monk?
No.
What should I say?
Maybe, from Phurpae up to Nyiloe...
Did you hear of any unusual children?
I have not heard about anyone
with unusual signs.
You don't know any?
I haven't met any child
with an interest in the teachings.
Haven't seen... I see.
Hello. How are you?
Are you from Laeru or Ngagyu?
- You mean us?
- Yes.
We are from Choekhang.
- From Choekhang, I see.
- Grandpa Wangchuk...
I see. That's right...
- Is your farm over here?
- We are relatives, right?
I was away for a long time,
I slightly recognize Auntie's face.
In Ngagyu, do you know any kids
aged one to one and a half?
Maybe Ahpe.
- Ahpe...
- Ahpe has.
- Small kids, right?
- Yes, small.
- Over there is...
- There?
- Behind that one.
- I see.
Yes, behind that.
Is his son one or two?
He has two sons.
- One is not yet one.
- About one.
I see.
- Is there a way out from there?
- Yes.
Go that way.
Hello.
- What is the boy's name?
- Tsering Bhuti.
- His father's name?
- Yes?
Father's name?
- Ngodrup Gyaltsen.
- I see. Thank you.
Hello.
Where is Ahpe's house?
- Ahpe's house?
- There.
Over there?
Here, here. OK, take it.
Give me, give me.
Give me the rosary.
Is this yours?
Don't.
Give it to me.
In all my lives,
never separated from perfect gurus,
May I enjoy the magnificent teachings.
By completing the qualities
of the stages and paths,
May I quickly attain the state
of Vajradhara Buddha.
Finally, I left without
getting the rosary back.
He kept it.
- What did Geshe-La use his rosary for?
- For his morning ritual.
- I see. A crystal one?
- Yes.
Also, there was an apple tree
which was planted by Geshe-La,
it's now huge and bears fruit.
He has been watering it
every morning for the last year.
Oh yeah.
Seems like quite a unique child.
Since you were very close
to Geshe-La
and well acquainted
with his nature,
your inquiries
are very meaningful.
Tell both Rinpoches
about this, OK?
And we will come
and do more checks.
For now,
the boy should be kept clean.
Please keep him clean.
If we get more assurance,
then we will inform
His Holiness, the Dalai Lama.
Right?
To find the unmistaken
reincarnation of Lama Konchog,
this is my life's responsibility.
It's not just a responsibility
of just being an attendant,
it's a responsibility for
a very, very important person,
who is going to benefit
numberless beings.
Just, just, just...
Just having him itself,
just able to bring,
even if he is a baby,
I can bring him
and I can show to you.
I can show to people.
Just that itself, already is enough.
It's very important.
It's thousands and thousands
of times more important
than my own life.
Who is this?
A child.
A child. Who is he?
Yes?
Do you recognize him?
Tell me. Who is he?
- Is it you?
- Who is he?
Is it Big Uncle?
- Yes, it is Big Uncle.
- Is this Tenzin Ngodup?
Yes, this is Tenzin Ngodup.
Who is that?
It's Grandma...
Is that her?
Yes, it is Grandma.
I'll spray you.
Wait, wait...
Tenzin Zopa, you are called.
Come. Come.
Here. Prostrate like me.
Little boy, come here.
Let us begin.
Tell him to choose the bell
he used in his previous life.
Do you want to pick up your bell?
Yes?
Tell him to take the one
that he used before.
Ahpe, you tell him.
Tell him in his mother tongue.
Take the one you used before.
My little boy,
you are very obedient, right?
This one.
Right, that is the one.
Then? Next.
Which one?
This one.
Yes, that's right.
Now the rosary.
Which one?
This, this or this?
- Pick the one you used before.
- In your past life.
This.
Hand drum.
Now your hand drum.
Which one?
Not this one... this.
- Which one?
- This.
Ask him. Is this the one?
It is.
- He said it is.
- I see, that's good.
- Which one, this?
- Yes.
- This one?
- No.
Yes.
He picked the right one.
Thank you. What is your name?
Your name?
Don't go.
Lama Yopa Rinpoche got
a good impression
and decided to write a letter
to His Holiness the Dalai Lama.
In order to make very precious,
he wants the Dalai Lama to announce,
Dalai Lama to recognize.
So that's why Rinpoche has already
sent the name to Dalai Lama.
To check.
Both Rinpoches said,
even though he stays in family
for the moment, keep clean.
Keep clean... like that.
So today is one of the
shaking days for my life.
I want to go to Grandma Lhamo.
So this is the letter.
A letter from the Dalai Lama.
It was sealed by His Holiness.
"I received a request from
"the devoted Lama Zopa Rinpoche,
"on behalf of his monasteries.
"To check the reincarnation candidate
"of the late Lama Konchog
"Accordingly,
I conducted checks and tests.
"Therefore, with a comfortable mind
and very good divination,
"I recognize Tenzin Ngodrup
"as the reincarnation
of Gen Lama Konchog.
"Dalai Lama, Tenzin Gyatso,
"a monk of the Shakyamuni tradition.
"17th December 2005."
So, this is it.
His Holiness wants to see him,
so we must be ready.
Sit still.
Sit still and it won't hurt.
Don't cut my hair. Don't cut.
Don't move, OK?
I want to wash my head.
You are not allowing me
to wash, Big Uncle.
Ani's shirt got dirty, didn't it?
Your shirt is not dirty.
Don't move your head. Don't cry.
More water.
Wait a moment, OK?
Wait, we will wet it.
Catch with your hands.
Catch the hair with your hands.
It's falling on the ground.
My eyes are burning.
I will wipe your eyes. OK?
Aren't you a good boy?
Don't cut. Wash.
Are your eyes burning?
Don't cut, don't.
OK, nearly finished.
Wait. Don't cut.
Don't cut. - Wait.
Wait, wait.
It's almost done... almost.
Come to Uncle.
I want to go.
Where do you want to go?
Does it burn?
Don't you want to shave
before Grandma Lhamo arrives?
Shave the rest. Then when Grandma
arrives, you'll be clean shaven.
We will quietly shave in the tent.
Quietly in the tent.
- Welcome.
- He looks very fresh and clean.
In reality we must begin
by contemplating the teachings:
Consider whether it is possible
to become a Buddha
who is free from faults
and full of perfect virtues.
In general, liberation,
including the highest virtue
of omniscience, is a possibility.
When you recite: "In order
to benefit sentient beings",
you are not aspiring
to become a Buddha
or to have happiness,
with a selfish motive.
In fact, you are praying
to become a source for everyone
to have inexhaustible
well-being and happiness.
Zopa Rinpoche will go
and then we will go together.
Welcome, welcome, Rinpoche.
Here. Here. Like this.
OK, do it like this.
It's OK.
Now I will put it there.
It's alright. You can keep it.
There is no tuft on his crown!
Never mind, never mind.
Oh, like that.
It's OK now.
New name...
- What was his former name?
- Tenzin Ngodrup.
Was it Tenzin Ngodrup?
Lama Konchog
was called Lobsang Phuntsok.
Lobsang Phuntsok.
In his previous life.
His current name is Tenzin Ngodrup.
What was his name before?
- Gen Lama...
- What was his name?
- Lobsang Phuntsok.
- Lobsang Phuntsok, right?
That's right.
Then let's say Tenzin...
Then let's say Tenzin Phuntsok.
Now your new name is Tenzin Phuntsok.
Understand?
You have changed your body
and your new name is Tenzin Phuntsok.
Become a perfect holder
of the teachings.
Understand? It's OK now.
Where is Grandma?
Let's see if she is there.
Tenzin Ngodrup...
I mean,
Tenzin Phuntsok Rinpoche.
He is going to see his parents
this afternoon,
maybe at late evening.
They will know
that he was recognized
as a reincarnated Lama
and they have to consider
whether they can give Rinpoche,
give up to the monastery.
So I hope and I pray that
they will definitely agree,
because they have great respect for
the previous Geshe Lama Konchog.
- There, there.
- Yes.
Buddha. Buddha.
See how he closes his eyes.
What shall we do now?
Tell him not to cry.
- Shall I cry?
- You will not cry.
You are a Lama,
you will not cry.
The cow kicked me.
Kicked me with its legs.
I see.
Oh. What if I fall off?
I am here now...
Be careful. Get up.
- Where is the retreat?
- Up there.
- Where?
- The flags up there.
Up there, that is the one.
That one.
Big Uncle, you come here.
- From here.
- Yes?
- Up this way?
- Yes.
Dad will come up now.
Where is it coming from?
Oh, I think it is flu.
Wait.
- How should I wipe it?
- Wait.
- Wipe it at the retreat.
- What?
At the retreat.
- At the retreat?
- Yes.
Wait, wait.
Look up, blood is coming out.
If I look up?
Then the blood won't come.
Don't do it.
I am going to find some herbs.
Hold him.
Wait, wait.
Now Dad will come.
- What is the medicine?
- What?
What is it?
- Sangkhanpa.
- I see.
We need to rub it? Wait.
Put it up his nose.
- It's too much.
- Put it all in.
- Don't do too much.
- Wait.
Don't do too much.
- Now let's go.
- Go down?
No... to the retreat.
To the retreat.
Let's go.
My retreat. My retreat.
I need a white scarf.
- White scarf?
- Yes.
How did this hole get here?
Now there is a way to go.
Now it's very good.
You had a big body
and I was very small.
Come here, I will show you.
We used to sit like this.
You recited:
May the supreme jewel Bodhicitta
not arisen, arise and grow;
That arisen not diminish,
But increase more and more.
More and more...
Then what?
Lobsang Drakpa,
at your feet I make requests.
We used to sit like this.
All these flowers were planted
by you.
I will repair everything
for Rinpoche, OK?
- That?
- I will repair that too.
- All?
- I will repair them all.
That one?
I will fix them all
and build a wooden fence,
then you will recite prayers and
do meditation here again, right?
I want to stay here.
I want to stay in Tsum forever.
Lama Ngodrup.
Your father is calling you.
Slowly, slowly.
This is the letter of confirmation
from the Dalai Lama
recognizing your son,
Tenzin Ngodrup,
as the unmistaken reincarnation
of Lama Konchog.
His Holiness not only
sent this letter,
but also did his
hair-cutting ceremony
and gave him a new name,
Tenzin Phuntsok Rinpoche.
As a Rinpoche, he has to go to
Kopan or Sera Monastery. Right?
Will I get to see him?
I am not sure
if I will ever get to see him.
When someone is a Lama, he has
to be taken away to a monastery.
He is taken away even though
he is a family member.
We don't know when
he will return home.
I think it would be difficult
for him to return.
It would be difficult even to see him.
So how do you two,
father and mother, feel...
about your child... your child...
being taken away to the monastery?
How do you feel about that?
So what do you feel?
- I don't feel...
- You don't...
If he was an ordinary boy,
he would marry
and work in the fields.
But he is a reincarnated master
who was revered all over the world
and had many students.
Your son, Tenzin Ngodrup,
should assume those responsibilities.
So do you think
you can give the child up?
Yes, I can.
It seems Ahpe is not ready to give...
If he works for the benefit
of sentient beings,
then I can give my child up.
Otherwise, who could give up
his child for nothing?
Thank you.
Oh my!
How fortunate we are.
Where is Mochung?
Oh, my Mochung.
We had no information.
We did not know.
One piece, that's enough.
He is so cute.
I'm falling down.
No, I will hold you.
Oh, Grandpa. Bend your head.
Thank you. Bend your head.
May we meet our master
again and again.
The glorious Lama.
If he is not the wish-fulfilling jewel,
then who is?
Have a safe journey.
Welcome.
I imagine this as a Buddha field
and offer it.
You don't have to touch them all...
Rinpoche, touch your head.
Rinpoche, your bed is ready.
What does it look like?
Mommy, are you leaving now?
Yes, Mommy is leaving.
- Daddy?
- Daddy is leaving too.
Daddy, don't go.
Be good.
Behave for Big Uncle, OK?
Come, let's see them off.
Where are we going?
Wait, put a scarf on your daddy.
Then where am I going?
To Grandma's place?
We can go later, OK?
I am going to Grandma's place.
Touch your forehead.
I am going to Grandma Lhamo's place.
I am going with Mommy.
Touch my head.
To Tsering, touch lightly.
- To you?
- Strongly.
Bye-bye.
Where are we going now?
Now they are not staying here?
Come back soon.
Don't let them go.
Now I have no friends.
I have no friends.
Don't let them go.
You, don't let them go.
I'm going.
Do you really want to go?
I really want to go.
Put on your robe properly.
Don't let them go.
Rinpoche.
What is this?
This one is...
This one is me.
And this is me.
Who?
Both... me...
Both of them are me.
Let me, let me.
I'll do it, I'll do it.
May the supreme jewel Bodhicitta
not arisen, arise and grow;
That arisen not diminish...
- But increase more and more.
Increase, increase...