"The bride has blackened her eyelashes"
"and made up her lips"
"She was to the bathroom and colored her hair."
"She has put on her most beautiful dress
and all her bracelets
But she is still missing something
What is it?
-Her ring.
-No.
Her earrings.
"The bride has blackened her eyelashes"
"And made up her lips...
-You're so lucky.
Don't worry, Myriam,
you'll get engaged too.
Which one is he?
Guess!
-That's him
-Bingo!
What do you think?
He's just how I imagined him.
I'm bringing them to you.
May your girl Myriam
be next on the list!
All our friends are here.
Come on, let's hear it
for Nour and Khaled.
Look at it, look at it.
You're the fiancée!
Don't be ashamed!
-Nour, when is the wedding?
We'll wait until Khaled finds work.
Don't wait too long!.
My neighbour was engaged
for 10 years. Her fiance died.
She doesn't even have
a sheep for comfort now!
Take care.
-Come on, Antonietta!
No, I prefer Italian things.
Touch it, you'll like it!
To the grand Mufti of Jerusalem,
The German National Socalists
have always fought
against world Jewry.
They support
the Arabs' struggle for freedom.
notably in Palestine
against the Jewish interlopers.
THE WEDDING SONG
-How much are the tomatoes?
-Twenty centimes.
That's too expensive.
I don't have enough money..
Come on, let's go..
Oh, those Germans...
I've never seen men like them.
They are well-mannered.
and have blond hair and blue eyes.
Quite frankly, if one approaches me,
I won't let him go.
-Me neither
What did you study at school today?
-Nothing.
She's been expelled!
As if me being fired
wasn't enough!
She picked a bad day for it!
-You've got nothing to teach me?
-You know all you need.
You can sew and cook.
Khaled will be happy with that.
-My mother drives me mad.
-So does mine.
Say...
I've wanted to ask for a year now
But I don't dare.
Go on.  Say it!
Why did your mother lose her job?
Because of the French...
Why?
I don't know.
They don't like us anymore.
Tita!
Come here.
I hear you haven't paid?
I said I'd  pay next time.
You know to our situation!
You always say that!
You're like a sister to me
but I'm going to get angry.
Next time,
no money, no bath!
I'll will bring the money next time.
On my husband's grave,
I'll bring it!
It is difficult pull out a cent out of a Jew!
There're worse than the French!
Let's hope the Germans win the war
and rid us of the French!
They're going to win.
Myriam!
-Everything OK?
-Fine.
And you?
I can't sleep.
Me neither.
Want to sleep in my room?
Wait for me.
-Good morning.
Good morning.
Nour?
Come here, my girl!
Take this to Tita.
Husband
I wish to talk to you.
-What's the matter?
-Khaled want to know
the date about the wedding.
-Has he found work?
-No, not yet.
-No work, no wedding!
Come on, he's our cousin!
How will he provide for her?
No work, no wedding.
May God forgive me!
What are they doing?
-They're laughing.  Really?
Come and help me now!
There are dresses in my room.
-Antonietta!
-Yes, dear.
I'll sew it
so you can pay the grocer back.
-Tita?
-Yes.
-My mum sent this.
-Thank you, Nour.
What's wrong?
You haven't turned the radio on
for us this morning?
Come on.
Come with me.
Come let Tita cuddle you.
Ah, Nour, the world is cruel.
Wait here, I'lll get you
some  Molokheya.
What's wrong?
I need your help.
I have to see Khaled.
Can you help me?
What's that red dress?
Try it on for the synagogue.
I prefer the blue one.
No, it makes you look pale.
-It doesn't.  -Enough!
-Heed my advice to attract Raoul.
-I don't want to.
You'll have to
after what you did at school.
Is this a time to sing songs
against Marshall Petain?.
Please Nour, tell her to try it on.
It isn't sewn yet!
You can finish it tomorrow.
No time.
I have to work with Nour.
As if the Germans
will let you go back to school?
The Allies will.
Sew away
while you wait for them.
Our concert today was brought
to you by the Galeries Barbes
and we hope that you enjoyed it.
Your satisfaction
is the goal of our store.
For you, we hire
the top music hall stars.
For you,
we have developed
our quick-dry wax polish,
the polish with the instant shine
Free catalogue.
I'm the little wooden man
from the Galeries Barbes...
Anglo-American bombs again fell
on our dear Tunisia yesterday.
Since it is a war of Jewish origin,
especially the invasion
of North Africa
organized by international Jewry,
we thank the German authorities
for compensating the bombs' victims
by giving the Jewish community
a hefty fine.
Try to understand the huge threat
that the Jews represent
wherever they live.
The fine is set at the fair sum
of 20 million francs,
to be paid immediately
to avoid bloody reprisals.
May God destroy them!
Jewry as a whole
is the greatest and staunchest enemy
of our cause and the Third Reich.
Wait in the living room
Thank you.
Do you know Paris?
I studied medicine there.
I stayed until the occupation,
when I had to come back here.
And you,
tell me things.
-What do you like to do?
-Nothing.
Do you like my house?
Not very talkative.
You were more outspoken at school!
How do you know about that?
-The entire city knows.
Go back and see him.
-Be nice to him.
I don't want to marry him.
When you're poor,
you can't be choosy.
You eat and stay quiet.
You want me to die in poverty?
This man was sent by God.
He'll bring you fame and joy.
And he'll help us pay the fine.
At first, I too thought
I didn't love your father.
And then...
I got to know him.
there's a war on.
Now ask your god about the fine.
"Almighty God,"
"give Myriam  20 million francs
to pay the fine."
We'll See.
If it doesn't work,
you'll have to ask Raoul.
You'll end up liking him one day.
No chance of that.
And he lives far away!
We won't be able to see each other?
First...
First of all...
Have you finished it?
-And the Arabian book?
-That too.
That's good
Have you found work?
Not yet.
You have to, Khaled!
I know.
Why did you want to see me?
My father
wants to call off the marriage.
Don't worry.
I'll soon find work.
I have to go.
Myriam will be worried.
-What's that?
-The Americans.
-This is for you.
- For me?
Think it's my size?
Try it on.
You'll wear it when you see Khaled.
Fits perfectly.
Thank you.
Did you kiss Khaled last time?
-Yes.
-What's it like?
It's scary.
"The bride has blackened her eyelashes"
"and made up her lips"
"She has been to the hammam"
"and hennaed her hair."
"She has put on
her most beautiful dress"
"and all her bracelets"
"But she is still missing something
The groom..."
My God...
Where's the baker?
What do we do?
- I don't know.
They're not going to bomb us
every day.
"The Americans and the British bomb you"
"in order to invade your country."
"They're friends of the Jews,
"We're friends of the Muslims."
"Show this pamphlet"
"and you'll be treated as a friend."
Let's go..
-She makes couscous without salt?.
-I asked her to.
but she's such a scatterbrain.
Why so much oil?
I told you already.
-Sorry. ma'am.
They never understand a thing.
These natives are a disaster..
Calm down.
The roundups make her edgy.
-This is terrible service!
I'll see to it....
-Mother, it doesn't matter!.
-You always say that.
She hasn't given us spoons.
It's all right. Let's eat.
Fire her if you're not happy.
Every meal,
we talk about the maid!
Can we eat?
-The meatballs are good.
-I haven't had meat.
since the war began.
We'll have it
at the wedding.
We need your guest list.
Only family.
With this fine to pay
we need to cut back.
-I don't know how to pay.
Don't worry.
Thank you, Raoul.
-I'm sorry, but I will leave
after the lunch.
-I have a patient later too.
Why does the hospital
give you so much work?
I'm lucky I kept my job!
Thanks to you, Sid Mustapha.
- God bless you.
-The pleasure is all mine, lady.
Three other doctors backed me up.
And I left France
to be safe here!.
Such a pity....
Sid Mustapha, what do you think of
the political situation?
No one is fooled by the Nazi propaganda.
Grave?
The Communists have asked me
to contact the Nationalists.
We'd like them to take a stand
against the Axis.
I think they will.
We share the same goal:
independence of the Tunisia.
-I saw Moslems pick up pamphlets.
Help my mother clear the table.
May I take your plate now?
-Yes, the fine's spoiled my appetite.
-We'll sort it out.
Thank you, Raoul.
-Excuse her.
-Where are you going?
What's happening?
Come back for the table.
Make an an effort, dear.
You don't understand.
There's a war on.
You're very beautiful..
-do you know her?
-Yes.
Could she wait outside?
I don't want customers seeing a native here.
Raoul!
Nour!
Show me what your Raoul bought you.
It's beautiful!
You're so lucky.  Khaled never buys me anything.
Don't worry,
He'll buy you presents one day.
We'll see.
-He still hasn't found work?
-It's hard right now.
It's hard for us too.
-Here, you have it.
-No keep it.
-Take it
-No, it's a gift.
Please, take it.
What about Raoul?
I'll say I lost it.
-He won't believe you.
-He will, don't worry.
What about me?
What do I tell Khaled?
I don't know.
Say you found it.
Found it while collecting some pamphlets.
That's true.
Can I ask you something?
Yes.
I'd like to see Khaled again.
All right.
Don't worry,
I'll get myself a pass.
-You can?
-Yes.
And I'll even get work.
and money.
- Have you told my father?
- No, not yet.
Does March suit you?
- For what?
- Our wedding.
Your eyes, your lips...
Come here.
- No.
- I've been waiting for years.
- Like everyone.
Let me, please.
I beg you, my love.
-Don't you love me anymore?
-Yes. I love you.
Forgive me.
-Tell me about
when you first saw me..
I already told you.
Tell me again.
-Come on tell me.
As soon as I saw you,
I knew you were the one.
And then?
Then, my father told me
you were the cousin I'd marry.
But I already knew it was you.
How do you know?
-I was trembling.
-And now?
-Yes.
Don't be afraid.
Here I am.
What are you doing?
Who is that?
Who is that, Myriam?
Have you done it?
My God,
my daughter is a slut!
-What will I tell Raoul now?
-I don't want to  marry him.
Shut up!
If your father was alive,
he'd slap your face!
He'd never marry me
to a man I hate!
Shut up, you whore!
Seen this?  It's all spoiled.
I'll buy you another one.
When do you start work?
I don't know.
Tomorrow,
I have to go to the "Kommandantur".
You're working for the Germans?
Yes.
They're decent people.
They've promised us independence
after the war.
I didn't know that.
There are a lot of things
you don't know.
I'll teach you.
Who is he?
-What did you do with him?
-Everything.
Meaning?
Everything. He lay down on me,
blew in my mouth and..
Ah Myriam...
Give this to your mother,
for the wedding expenses.
-Well?
-I've sorted it out.
Thank you, you've saved us.
There's no problem.
Everything is fine.
No problem, Tita!
I forgot to ask you
for the wedding night...
Do you want the bride
Oriental or European style?
Oriental...
Oriental.
Be brave, you have to be beautiful
for your wedding night.
How did it go with Khaled
the other night?
-He found work!
-What kind of work?
He didn't say.
Stand up!
I have a friend
whose jealous neighbour
wanted her fiance.
On the wedding night
she cast a spell:
and she became like a baby!
Didn't the father kill her
when he saw the unstained sheet?
The poor man lived with the shame
all his life!
-Which family was it?
-The whole neighborhood knows!
I know who it is.
You have to be clean
to please your husband.
Don't be afraid.
Your husband
wants you as soft as silk.
It's all right, it's all right.
Relax, the pain will pass.
Everything's fine.
You see, your skin is silky.
There, it's all over.
I have to tell her and show her.
Answer!
Where are your children?
Your husband?
I don't know,
I don't understand French.
-What did she say?
-She doesn't speak French.
For hostages,
it's best to take men.
Where's her family?
There's no one else.  My husband is dead
and  my daughter's married.
-She  lives alone.
-Is that true?
No, she has a daughter.
But she isn't home from school yet.
I beg you...
I've done nothing,
I've paid the fine, I...
-We'll come back.
What do we do?
Search the place
Take the jewels,
money and sewing machine.
-There's nothing.
-They hide everything.
Bitch!
Good morning, Myriam, everything well?
Good morning.
Everything well?
Everything well.
What's wrong with her?
I don't understand.
God only knows, my daughter.
-What are doing here?
-Nothing.
Why did you pick
those leaflets up on the square?
I was curious.
Has Khaled told you about his work?
No.
-Nothing?
-No.
He came to our place
with the Germans and French.
They stole from us
and hurt my mother.
-He did wrong nothing.
-I saw him with them
-It wasn't him!
-I saw him.
You saw wrong.
What do you have against Khaled?
Are you jealous?
No.
I'd rather die than live your life.
You know nothing
about what I'm going through.
...An office will be opened
at the high school.
And now a final reminder.
In application
of Colonel Rauf's decision
and in accordance with
the bill posted in the city,
German authorities require
a contingent of 2,000 Jewish workers
for excavation work
and trench digging.
All able bodied Jewish men
must be presented tomorrow
Raoul!
to the 08:00 of the morning
in the Jewish workers recruitment center
with shovels and a picks.
No Jewish inhabitant is
exempt of that obligation. ..
Shalom Hajaj.
-Age?
-Thirty years.
-Profession?
-Locksmith.
-Any health problems?
-I cough a lot.
Come hear.
Cough!
Again
That way.
Felix Haddad!
-Age?
-Fifty.
-Profession?
-Doctor.
I know you.  You're a carpenter.
Not a doctor.
You damn traitor!
-Traitor!
- You're not a man!
If I'd been in their shoes,
I'd have spat in your face too.
I wasn't my  decision
to send only the poor.
You're an accomplice.
Who's decision was it?
The community leaders.
We had orders to protect the elite.
That's horrible.
What can I do?
Resign.
If I do, I'll be sent away too.
They'll need doctors there.
You really want that?
I don't want my fiance
to be called a coward.
Know why I chose you
at the synagogue?
No.
For what you did at school.
I  wanted to help you.
Where's this bra from?
It's new.
Where did you get the money for it?
It was a present.
Who from?
Why do you want to know?
You mustn't wear
another girl's clothes!
We're not beggars.
-Who gave it to you?
-A woman.
A woman? Who?
Myriam?
Take it off!
-Why?
You don't need to dress
like a whore to please me!
Take it off!
You mustn't see Myriam again.
Yes.
All right.
The bride
has blackened her eyelashes
And made up her lips.
She has been to the hammam
And hennaed her hair.
she has on her most beautiful dress
and all her bracelets
but she is still missing something
What is it?
Her ring.
-No.
Give me a son.
I want a son when I get back...
Here.
Get dressed.
We'll talk about it when I get back.
Thank you.
Have you packed  my things?
I've put in some food too.
Thank you.
I should go.
Your father's waiting outside.
I know.
-Raoul!
Yes?
Don't go.
It's too late now.
Don't worry, Oum Khaled.
My daughter is in good health.
She looks a bit skinny to me.
Here's your's money.
Better late than never.
Go on in.
Inspection!  No one leaves!
Men aren't allowed in here now!
Stay here!
-She has no veil.
-They respect nothing.
-Catch them!
-They're hiding in the steam bath!
She's my sister.  A Moslem.
-What's to prove you're Moslem?
-Here's her veil.
"There is no God but allah
and Mahomed is his prophet."
"There is no God but Allah"
"and Mahomed is his prophet."
All right!
We're taking ten hostages.
What came over you at the hammam?
Nothing.
Answer me!
You'd let someone
be mistreated like that?
No, never.
She's not someone, she's a Jew.
Khaled,
Don't talk like that.
I don't recognize you.
Come here.
I'd like to live
in a beautiful house.
Me too.
I'd like our son
to go to university.
Me too.
Ever wondered why the Jews
were allowed to do that?
Why did the French allow them to
and not us?
This is our country!
Think that's normal?
You agree with that?
It's their country too,
and they're poor too.
That's not true!
You don't know!
You've never read anything.
What do I need to read
to understand?
It's hard to read.
Your French isn't good enough.
Read the Koran.
You won't do it again?
You promise?
Yes.
Come to see me at the villa.
I can't. It's too far.
Come by bicycle. It's quicker.
-You know I can't ride one.
-I'll teach you.
You know, I saw Khaled.
Did you speak with him?
No.
Did you talk to him?
What about?
-About me.
-About you?
Listen Myriam, it's politics.
You can't understand.
Explain to me then.
Put yourself in his shoes.
He didn't have any work
We're exploited in our own country.
The French exploit us!
and you, the Jews.
You help them.
You take our wealth and work.
Why do you go to school
when I don't?
Why do I wear a veil
when you don't?
Why can you go out
without being criticized
when I always am?
Why can't I go out?
Why?
Why do you say that?
-Because it's  true.
-It is not.
Get that into your head!.
It's not true. Raoul helps Mustapha
to rid us of the French!.
You like your Raoul now?
-What about Khaled?
-You still like him?
Yes, I do!
He stepped in
to spare us any problems!.
Besides, politics
has nothing to do with you.
You're different.
No, I'm not different.
Myriam, you're different.
-You're different!
Let me go!
Mum!
What's wrong?
What's wrong, my daughter?
If anyone desires a religion
other than Islam,
never will it be accepted of him,
and in the hereafter, he will be
among those who have lost.
Nour, what's wrong?
Nothing.
I am looking at the well.
"Hello, here's the bride"
"Hello, Nour, my dear"
Come on, let's go inside.
You read Arabic now?
No.
I just saw you reading.
Who taught you?
-I learned on my own.
Impossible.  Who taught you?
Myriam.
Don't lie!
And where did she learn Arabic?
At school.
What are you reading?
The Koran.
So Myriam told you
to read the Koran?
Yes.
Go on, read it. I'm listening!
If anyone desires a religion
other than Islam,
never will it be accepted of him,
In the hereafter, he will be
among those who have lost
So Myriam told you to read that?
No, I found it by chance.
Read this for me!
"Those who believe,
those who follow Judaism,
Christianity and the Sabians,
and who believes in God,
and on the Last Day
and who does good,
shall have their reward
from their Lord.
On them shall be no fear
nor shall they grieve.
Thank you.
Now let me sleep.
The bride has blackened her eyelashes
And made up her lips.
She has been to the hammam
And hennaed her hair.
She's wearing her pretty dress
and all her bracelets
"But she is still missing something.
What is it?"
-Her husband.
-Yes.
I love you.
-Nothings happening.
-Leave them! They'll come out!
I've read the Koran.
-On your own?
-Yes.
But not like you said.
What do you mean?
I found beautiful things in it
about Myriam.
I told you to stop seeing her!.
I can't...
She's my best friend.
I'm the one who decides
Give me your foot.
Thank you.
Let's hear it for them!
In name of God,
the Lenient, the Merciful one.
Say: God is one.
Hark, Israel.
The Lord is our God.
The Lord is One.
Subtitles by j0seph
The Lord is our God.
The Lord is One.