[Music plays]
# Oh, the streets of Rome #
# Are filled with rubble #
# Ancient footprints #
# Are everywhere #
# You can almost think #
# That you're seein' double #
# On a cold, dark night on the Spanish Stairs #
# Gotta hurry on back to my hotel room... #
Wendell?
Please hurry. I can't be late today.
I'm coming, Doreen.
I'm just looking for my boot.
Let's go. Come on.
# She promised she'd be there with me #
# When I paint my masterpiece #
Wendell: [Narrating]
They say you don't know what you have till it's gone.
Well, me, I knew what I had.
I just didn't know
it was about to be gone.
- Hey, Junior.
- [Dog whines]
[Music plays]
# Oh, the hours we'd spend #
# Inside the Coliseum #
# Dodgin' lions #
# -And a-wastin' time... #
- [Radio switched off]
I've been thinking a lot about you, Wendell.
- Yeah?
- And... And us, together.
I just... I love you so much,
but sometimes I feel like you think
the grass is always greener on the other side.
Doreen, there are some things out there
I want to do and occasionally I...
But you won't get, or keep, a steady job.
I'm a venture capitalist.
Wendell. You're lucky to have me.
- I know it.
- And I'm lucky to have you.
Yeah. I mean, I'm not exactly
a consolation prize.
I mean, Doreen,
I think it takes a certain strength of character
to endure the occasional failure.
You know Mozart
didn't sell a single album while he was alive?
If there was a named job
out there I could do, I'd do it.
There wasn't,
so I had to make my own.
Turns out there's
no one else doing it.
- So I'm pretty darn successful.
- Yeah.
But unfortunately, selling fake I.D. cards
to migrant workers isn't a real job.
Texas State certified driver's licenses.
Oh, Wendell.
With the holographic seal
of the State of Texas.
Come on. Right?
Can I turn the radio back on?
# ...lifornia wanted man in Buffalo #
# Wanted man in Kansas City #
# Wanted man in Ohio #
# Wanted man in Mississippi #
# Wanted man in old Cheyenne #
# Wherever you might look tonight #
# - You might see this wanted man #
- Goodbye.
# He might be in Colorado... #
- Good boy.
- [Sing-song] Take the ribbon from your hair
Shake it loose and...
You should really be satisfied
with what you have.
I'm not satisfied.
And that's exactly why I'm so optimistic.
Thanks for letting me use your car.
I appreciate it.
- Thank you.
- Bye, Junior.
Bye, Wendell.
Bye.
Hey!
You're my gal.
- Uh-huh.
- You know it?
- You are.
I'll pick you up at 5:00.
And thanks for having this talk with me,
I really appreciate it.
I'm gonna change.
Woman:
Larry's pissed you're late.
Was it Wendell?
He overslept a little.
Then he couldn't find one of his boots.
Don't you get tired of it?
I mean, I could maybe understand
going on, like, a few dates with Wendell.
But what's the point?
The point is that I love him.
He's a dreamer,
yeah, I know, but I'm part of his dreams.
Okay. I'm just
trying to say be careful.
'Cause once a dude like Wendell runs
out of dreams to chase, he'll just start to run.
[Music plays]
Wendell:
A little early in the day
to have her take a chunk
out of my ass, Junior.
I mean, I could use a little support
from the ol' backup band.
Just came charging
out of the gate at me.
No coffee for the kid.
She just decides to light into me.
I mean, Doreen, let me
get my bearings at least.
I've always been crazy
And the trouble that it's put me through...
Good morning, Travis, my man.
- Been busted for things
- [Car horn beeps]
- Still can see ya.
- That I did and I didn't do
[Laughing]
Here you go, man, my man.
-Yeah. Whoo!
- I ain't sayin' I'm proud...
See you tomorrow, Travis.
...Of all of the things that I've done
But I can say
I've never intentionally hurt anyone
[Music plays]
Top o' the mornin' to you, Irma.
Good morning, Wendell.
Say, is ol' what's his name still in there
hugging the biscuit?
- No. He's in back waiting for you.
- Oh.
I like your dress.
[Car horn plays fanfare]
[Gravel sprays]
# So far I ain't found a rhyme #
# Or a reason to change #
[Music plays]
# I've always been crazy #
# But it's kept me from going insane #
- Morning, Reyes.
- Hey, Wendell.
[In bad Spanish]
¿Que paso?
Feeling good.
You ready to go to work?
- I'm ready.
- Let's do it.
[Music plays]
I love you, baby. Mwah!
Wendell: [Narrating]
Me and Reyes headquartered the home office
of Wendell Baker International
along a bend of the mighty Rio Grande...
Tigris of Texas.
It was perfect for border crossings,
perfect for new beginnings.
Wendell:
Crop production predicted to be at an all-time high.
The number of Mexicans coming
across the border to work those very crops
also predicted to be at an all-time high.
Congress, you know, they just increased
minimum wage to 5.60 an hour?
Farmers can't afford that.
Even if they could, they can't find
Americans who'll work for that in the fields.
So they pay half that to our hardworking Mexican
brothers and sisters, our clients.
Well, I hear they're increasing the number of
border patrols to stop the flow of illegals.
- Well, I mean our clients.
- Hey, good for them.
But there's enough to go around,
if you know what I mean.
More border crossings,
more border patrol.
Everybody's working.
It's a pretty good deal.
Both: [Off-key]
Can sing it
I've got to piss like a racehorse.
I'll meet you down there.
[Music plays]
Yeah.
# Went to a garden party #
# Reminisced with my old friends... #
Jesus.
Come on, partner,
you need a little help.
Did you have a little orange juice
with your Pop Tart this morning?
- [Toilet flushes]
- Wendell: Here we go.
Come on. Come on.
[Howling]
Oh-h-h-h!
What in the hell?
Sonny Junior.
No! It's not what
it looks like. It's not.
Set him loose, goddamn it!
There you go, stay right there.
Uh, you're Sonny Senior, right?
Me, I was just helping the boy.
I was just helping him.
You are a godless hound from Hell!
No, I'm Wendell Baker.
Oh!
[Grunt]
Come on, baby.
[Sobbing]
Pay no mind to the evil man.
Hnnnn...
Let's go home, baby.
# There was magic in the air #
# Over in the corner #
# Much to my surprise #
# Mr. Hughes hid in Dylan's shoes #
# Wearing his disguise #
# But it's all right now #
# I learned my lesson well #
# You see you can't please everyone #
# So you got to please yourself #
- You okay, Wendell?
- Oh, man, mornings can be tough.
Feel good, though.
Feel like a million pesos. Thanks.
That... That's, like, four bucks.
That much, huh?
Let's get to work, buddy.
[Sighing]
This coffee's good, Reyes.
It's about to be great.
[Music plays]
Say, Reyes?
Can I interest you in a little mezcal?
A dash of tequila for your coffee?
Uh, maybe when the day's done?
Good man. Take it slow.
Hello. I'm Wendell Baker.
Mr. And Mrs...?
We'll get to that.
Are you familiar with holographic technology?
You're about to find
out all about it.
#I fetch my brazos hardcore #
# Down from the click-hi #
# Who's that emanatin' funk through the speaker? #
# Bass gets to pumpin,'rucka's get to pumpin' #
# Who's that rap king
got the party start jumpin'? #
# Blastin' too high
no need for the boo-ya #
# My hammer with the one knuckle #
# I shot through ya #
# - Step into the madness
- Madness #
Wendell:
So let me talk to some of y'all
about some of my past clients.
Jimmy Smits.
I mean, I'm straight, but the guy smoulders.
Never quite broke through like I hoped.
Fernando Valenzuela. Good guy, great arm.
Not the biggest advocate of
physical conditioning.
Ultimately I think it hurt his longevity.
I get out of a relationship with...
Salma Hayek, the frying pan,
and go right into the fire.
Jenny Lopez. Nice girl.
Dated her briefly.
Said some stuff about me around town.
I hold no ill will.
Chi Chi Rodriguez calls me,
says, "Wendell?
I'm having trouble with my game."
I watch him swing a couple of times
and I give him one note.
One note: "fire the knees.
Fire them right at the flag stick."
Next week he wins
the Greater Hartford Senior Open.
[Crash]
Goddamn it.
And all this business...
Slaying the dragon,
he saw me do it on the 12th hole
of the Laredo Country Club in 1978.
...The backroad but I'm delinquent
This is how I freak it
- When I'm speaking to the gente
- Gente
[Music plays]
Herve Villechaize.
He had more heart
in that little chest than...
Sorry. Just give me
one second, one second.
Phew.
Goddamn it, I miss you, Herve.
I really do.
[Dog grunts]
So, that's how we do it
here at Wendell Baker International,
where we've been
serving the Southwest since 1971.
So, uh, I just got one question.
Who wants to get American?
[Music plays]
Yeah.
Thanks. What do you think, Reyes?
I think we're drawing too much attention
with all these people.
Come on, Reyes.
We're changing
the course of people's lives here.
You know, we want more for these people
than to just be farm hands.
We want them to own the farms.
These are potential
politicians, doctors, lawyers.
And it started right here, this Airstream.
It's the Ellis Island of the Southwest.
Goes all the way
back to the pilgrims, Reyes.
- All right. I can dig it.
- Huh.
Torres brothers.
Wendell:
Here's the deal, fellas.
For a short time we're offering
flawless reproductions
of Texas State
driver's licenses with your name
[Muttering]
or name of choice,
[In bad Spanish]
con image holographia.
You get one of these,
you go anywhere. You interested?
That's what I thought.
You guys want a shot?
I'm going to shoot straight with you.
You get one of these, you're going to be able
to go to Houston, San Antone, Dallas.
You ever been to Dallas?
¿Vamo Dallas?
- No.
- Whoo.
Boy, you got a lot to look forward to.
Here, take a look at it.
That there's the upstairs merchandise.
V.I.P. only. Solamente.
My only question is,
what do you want from me?
Hell, I want you on your feet.
With your hands locked
behind your head.
[Mixed yelling]
[Music plays]
Sir, for starters,
you can call me Wendell.
[Groan]
You're busted, dumb-ass.
Run, Junior, run for your life!
[Music plays]
[Mixed barking/whining]
Wendell:
We can beat this thing. We can beat it!
Their evidence seems pretty strong.
Are you kidding me?
They could have done this on some back lot
in Burbank, California, man.
Come on.
Same place they did the lunar landing.
Look at it, Otto.
I've finally done it, haven't I, Otto?
[Heavy sigh]
Look...
Can you just make
sure that Reyes gets off?
Don't worry.
I'll get Reyes in the clear.
Good.
[Sigh]
You're looking at a couple
of years at least.
So y-you started drinking again?
I'm off the wagon.
Okay.
Can I get them to deport me?
Wendell, you're a U.S. citizen.
Goddamn it.
I should've gone down there a long time ago.
Mexico's what the U.S. could've been.
Oh, God.
[Sniffling]
[Reading] "Children's photographer.
Can you make children smile?
Will train right person."
So they seized your car?
The police are auctioning it off
because it was used to commit a felony.
But it's not the car, Reyes.
It's Wendell.
We've known each other since we were kids,
and he doesn't even...
He doesn't even say he loves me.
And I tell him, "Wendell, I love you."
And he says,
"Doreen, I think about you all the time."
I know it, Doreen, but...
But he does.
And he always says
you're the reason he works so hard.
I've given him a lot of chances.
And he's deserved them all.
I just always wanted to be with him.
[Music plays]
# People say that I'm high class #
# But I'm low-down all the while #
# People think that I'm crazy #
# When I flash that California smile #
Guard:
On your feet, off the bus.
This is Huntsville.
# But I can still #
# Paint the town... #
How're you doin'? Wendell Baker.
How's it... Oh... Ow.
# ...Of your evening gown #
# While I'm waitin' #
# For your blonde hair to turn grey #
# People say... #
Whoo!
- Whoo.
- Good shot, Wendell.
- Yeah.
- [Applause]
Man:
It says here
that although you were
the unwanted child of an unwed mother,
you believe that, in your words...
You have the blood of kings
running through your veins.
Mr. Baker.
You can call me Wendell.
Did you say that, Mr. Baker?
"Blood of kings"?
Yeah.
# - Thank God
- Domino! 20! #
# Forgivin' life to you and me #
# Wherever you may be #
Whoo!
Crips and Aryans together.
Come on, guys.
That's how it's got to be.
# Filled with selfishness and greed #
# There remains the glory fountain... #
We're going to get it
all done tonight, boss.
I guarantee ya.
# You can find it in the temple #
# With a welcome on the door #
# But be sure to count your blessings #
# Before you ask for more #
- Thank God...
- Man.
- Uh...
- Huh.
- Hi.
- Hi, Doreen.
[Chuckle]
Can I get you anything?
Anything at all.
I could use some cleats.
Cleats?
Yeah.
I worry about you.
Don't.
Boy, you look beautiful.
Really do.
I'd take a month in solitary
for just one kiss.
I would. I would.
Huh.
[Clock ticking]
Thanks for stopping by.
[Music plays]
Leon! You're out.
Damn.
[Distant shouting]
[Music plays]
Guard:
Dodge, you're up.
You've got a visitor. Let's go.
Let's go.
- Williams, visitor.
- Henry.
- Hey, Donny.
- Donny: Mm-hmm.
- Hey, Leon.
- Guard: Come on, George. Get up. Visitor.
Keep it in a line, ladies. In a line.
[Music plays]
Baker, you've got some love letters here.
They're from yourself, asshole.
Return to sender.
[Music plays]
I had a dream last night, Leon.
Me and Doreen had a child.
Walked into our room late at night and
climbed up in bed beside us.
A son, Leon. Huh.
Yeah, I have a little boy.
You do?
Yeah.
We've got to get out of here.
[Sigh]
Yeah, I know.
You've got to get back to your family
and I've got to start mine.
[Music plays]
Good morning, Mr. Baker.
Wendell:
Good morning, Dr. Van Horn.
Do you remember what you used to say to me
when I'd say, "good morning, Mr. Baker"?
- Yes, sir.
- Mm-hmm.
What was that?
I'd tell you to call me Wendell.
Why would you do that?
I... I think I did it to...
Oh, create a false sense of
familiarity between us.
Kind of make you
think we were pals,
maybe possibly
expedite my release.
Well, we've come a long way,
haven't we... Wendell?
Huh. Yes, sir, we have.
I understand you've learned quite a lot
about the hotel business
in recent months.
Yes, sir, I've tried to. I mean, uh...
I like being around people
and working with them,
and hotels seem like
a good place to do that.
Congratulations, Wendell.
Your parole's been approved.
Through our employment program,
a job, a room, board have been secured for you
at a state-run residential retirement hotel.
Thank you, Dr. Van Horn.
# Well, it's been rough and rocky travellin' #
# But I'm finally standin' upright on the ground #
Thanks, Captain.'preciate it.
# And after takin' several readings #
# I'm surprised
to find my mind's still fairly sound #
# I thought Nashville was the roughest #
# But I know I've said the same about them all #
# We received our education #
# In the cities of the nation,
me and Paul #
Wendell: [Narrating]
I was really looking forward to seeing Reyes.
He hadn't gotten a chance
to visit me as much as I'd hoped.
It had to have been hard on him.
I understood.
It was probably like seeing
a lion or some kind of panther locked up.
And Irma wouldn't allow it.
[Music plays]
# But if you're stayin' in a motel there and leave #
# Just don't leave nothin' in your clothes #
You seen Doreen lately?
Not in a long time, Wendell.
What'd she say?
Did she say anything about us?
She made it sound
like she was moving on.
That she started dating some guy.
Runs a grocery store.
Boy.
Goddamn, I wish I didn't have
such a good imagination.
Just vivid as all hell.
[Indistinct]
# I thought Nashville was the roughest... #
Reyes, I'm sorry if I caused
you and Irma any problems.
I am. I'll apologize to her
when I see her, okay?
No, we're fine.
I mean, she wouldn't talk to me
for a few months after we got arrested.
But we got through it.
But I'm thinking it's probably better
that you just don't mention it to her...
- At all.
- You bet.
I've just got to thank you
for taking Reyes back.
I mean, I'm the one locked up,
but this kid was down.
I'd talk to him on the phone, say,
"good morning, Reyes,"
and he'd say, "is it?"
So, Irma, thanks,
'cause this fella was flying low.
You were.
Nothing beats a home-cooked meal.
Man, this is good.
She's still tough, isn't she?
Oh, you have no idea, man.
You're a lucky dog that
she took you back.
- Mm-hmm.
- How'd you do it?
She put a few conditions on me.
- Yeah, I bet.
- Yeah.
Like, uh, try to get my old job back.
- Oh, man.
- [Laughing]
Driving that truck?
- Yeah.
- Whoo.
And not to hang out with you anymore.
[Sigh]
Really?
Yeah.
I understand. I do.
'Cause of that whole driver's license deal?
Ah, that and she was pretty upset
about that insurance scam in Lubbock.
- [Engine revs]
- [Tires squeal]
[Music plays]
I got an idea.
Wendell?
Wendell:
[Laughing]
Whoo! Yeah!
[Scream]
Wendell!
You okay, buddy?
Hey. I got that old pick-up
up and running while you were gone.
Really?
It's yours.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Really.
- Huh. Really?
Hot dang, man.
Huh.
Wow.
Hey, you mind if we hang
on to Junior?
Irma got kind of attached to him.
Sure.
Thanks, buddy.
You got it.
[Whining]
[Music plays]
# You've been so long #
# Your blind eyes are gone #
# Your old bones are on their own #
# So take off your coat #
# Put a song in your throat #
# Let the deadbeats pound all around #
# We will go nowhere we know #
# We don't have to talk at all #
[Birds twittering]
Wendell: [Narrating]
So this was it.
A new beginning.
First day at my second chance.
[Music plays]
[Birds squawking]
Man:
So what's the word, boss?
The news is... Good.
Baker's a three-time loser
fresh out of Huntsville.
Just a pure idiot,
imminently frame-able,
even more than you, McTeague.
- I mean, he's perfect.
- [Fart]
Oh, hey, that reminds me.
Get Mr. Baird's estate documents,
and then give him
the Greyhound Treatment.
- Th-the Greyhound Treatment?
- That's right.
You heard me.
Send him up to mother's.
She called.
She did?
- How'd she sound?
- Pissed, man.
She drove all the way out to Western Union.
That money order
you were supposed to send...
Wasn't there.
Damn it, Neil. Think.
Sports commentator: [On TV]
Diaz delivers a fast ball.
That one catches the outside corner.
That'll even up the count...
Man: [Reading]
"Earl Graham Walsh
was called home
by the Lord on Tuesday the 14th."
[Chuckling]
"Called home by the Lord," Skip.
Well, if the Lord our Jesus Christ himself
called looking for me, do me a favour.
Tell him you haven't seen me.
Under any circumstances,
I'm not here.
Roger.
[Funk music plays]
Oof!
[Music plays]
[TV chatter]
Y'all know y'all late. Let's go.
Everybody out on the lawn.
Whose birthday is it?
Ain't nobody's goddamn birthday.
It's a wake for Marietta Davis.
Condolences.
But I think we're going to take
a rain check on this one.
Thanks though.
Get up.
[Grunt]
Get your ass out there.
Hi, Reverend.
McTeague.
What the hell you doing, Fullbright?
Just trying to figure out
what to do with the rest of my life,
all 15 or 20 minutes of it.
Don't mess with me, old man.
Fullbright:
McTeague, buddy, me and the boys are just relaxing.
Listening to the ball game.
[Turns radio off]
I think Marietta
would have liked it that way.
I don't give a damn what Marietta
would have liked.
She dead.
Neil:
I didn't know Marietta that great.
The fact that she didn't know my name
even after five years
made it kind of tough
to get to know her.
But I know from the files
she was an accomplished seamstress
and a singer
and a mathematics teacher.
I guess it was Alzheimer's
that finally brought the old gal down.
- And...
- Stomach cancer.
- But didn't she have a little Alzheimer's too?
- Huh?
Well, sh... I thought
she had Alzheimer's.
She couldn't remember jack shit.
Okay, well, cancer makes sense also.
She wasn't exactly Larry Csonka
there at the end.
She only weighed about 90 pounds.
Now having said that,
she would knock you on your damn ass.
If you got between her and
her morning medicine,
forget it. You were gone.
Now, I know they say
cancer's pretty painful.
I don't know,
I've never had it.
But you can't tell me that
that old gal wasn't partying
just a little bit
there at the end.
McTeague would see her
coming down the hall
and she'd be all hopped up,
just a-working her jaw back and fo...
Woman:
Excuse me.
- What?
- I... I'd like to say a word about Marietta.
- She was a very go...
- Okay, no.
Unfortunately,
the policy is only the staff speaks.
We've let that happen in the past
and people that know the deceased
have a tendency to get
a little too sentimental.
Grab someone
after the meeting.
Uh, so we're going to miss her.
God bless her. That's it for me.
McTeague, you got anything?
About what?
Both:
[Chortling]
Come on. Have some respect.
Okay, that's it for me.
Oh, wait. We'll let
the, uh, new member of our staff,
Wendell Baker,
add something. Thank you.
Wendell:
A-afternoon.
Uh, I didn't know Marietta Davis,
but I can see here by you folks here
that she was real loved
and even now I'll bet
that means the world to her.
I recently lost someone
that meant a lot to me.
She didn't pass away.
She just sort of passed by.
And it'll make you realize
that there's some people that...
That you don't forget.
But if you can remember
the things that she loved,
those things that made her happy,
if you see those things
and can remember her smile
and just know that
she's doing fine,
you'll be all right.
And so will she.
Thank you.
I have absolutely
no idea what he just said.
New age double-talking jive.
Maybe he could get us laid
or something.
[Laugh]
[Chuckling]
Check this out.
Our son ain't yours?
- How can you tell?
- I've only been with one person,
Travis, and that's you.
- Travis: Good.
- [Snoring]
Woman: [On TV]
It's only you, and I'm the one
- Two-double jack.
- that forced you to marry me?
I didn't. You married me.
And you asked me to
marry you and you weren't drunk.
Travis: [On TV]
The hell if I wasn't.
Woman: [On TV]
You don't understand. You don't.
You don't understand
how much I love you and want to be with you.
I gave up everything.
Man:
[Hacking cough]
Woman: [On TV]
I gave up my family...
What's he doing?
He's letting the sunshine shine.
What the hell you talking about,
Ms. Oglesby?
[Cheerful music on radio]
[Music plays]
Wendell:
Just like golf.
Just keep your head down...
[Indistinct]
When you get better at it
you can learn to fire your knees.
[Music plays]
Neil, you all right?
You okay?
Hey, how's
the graffiti business?
How's that?
Shut up.
I'm talking to this fossil.
Easy, Tonto.
Hey, I want to get to the bottom
of this as badly as you do.
Now, you want to tell me what
the hell this is?
"Neil King..."
Shut up!
Now, talk.
Or do you want a little of this?
'Cause I'll give it to you.
Uh, if... If my memory
serves me right,
I... I saw McTeague
in this area with a...
A magic marker.
[Scoffing]
"If memory serves"?
Your memory couldn't
serve a cold bowl of chili, Boyd.
Come on.
You know, I actually get
a kick out of you, surprisingly.
But listen to me...
You lovable old has-been.
If you keep messing with me,
I'm going to have to bury you. Literally.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Would you bury me upside down so
it's easier for you to kiss my ass?
Ooh.
Oh-la-lay.
- You got a lot of heart, ese.
- Yeah.
- Maybe too much.
- Wendell:...Really tight
- [Door opens]
- Skip: Sorry, guys.
I didn't know
you were in here. My bad.
No. Hey there, guy.
No problem at all.
I don't think I got
to meet you earlier.
Neil King, head nurse.
How are ya?
Hi.
Sorry about putting you
on the spot earlier.
Oh, I also spoke to my good friend,
Junior Warden Taggert,
and we're going to be in close contact
throughout your tenure here.
Well, I'm real excited to be here.
This is my first job
in the hotel business.
Hey, guy, it's the retirement
hotel business.
It's a different animal.
You've got to
contend with kooks like this.
[Chuckling]
That being said, we strive to make
the most of their time
before they head on to
their rewards and...
I think we do a pretty darn
good job.
I guess you can always do better.
I don't know though.
I like to think
we do a good job.
Wouldn't you agree, Mr. Summers?
Mr. Summers? Speak honestly.
[Stammering]
Absolutely.
Uh, as a matter of fact
when I lay down
for that eternal dirt nap...
[Chuckling]
- I'll know...
- That's enough, Mr. Summers.
- That my time spent here...
- Ah, we got it.
You're a satisfied customer.
...Be blessed.
[Chuckling]
God, I just love to see
their wrinkled old faces light up with smiles.
Give me one.
You see, Wendell,
these two old cooze hounds
still have a lot to offer
even if they do got sawdust
in their balls.
Let me through.
Okay. Come by my office anytime.
Open door policy.
Okay. Thanks, Mr. King. I...
Thanks for taking me on the tour.
I appreciate it.
So, uh, you lost someone?
Yes, I did.
I'm Skip Summers.
Boyd Fullbright.
Hello.
And I'm sorry for your loss.
I appreciate that.
[Music plays]
[Engine ignition]
Back to work, Baker.
[Music plays]
[Leaf blower roaring]
[Crickets chirping]
Man:
November, 1986.
We're playing against TCU.
I turned to Coach Royal, I say,
"put me in the game."
And he took me
by the shoulder pads
and said, "listen to me,
you big, dumb idiot.
You blow this, I'm going to ship
your ass out of Austin."
Sure enough... I got transferred.
Hey, how are ya?
- Good, thanks.
- Good.
- How you doin'?
- Boy: Hi.
I got eight lights here.
Okay.
#Lovin' on a roll #
# Lovin' on a good roll #
Man:
You having a good night?
[Beeping of cash register]
# Usually I'm in control... #
It's going to be,
uh, 18.27 for the lights.
# Told me this morning #
# She said this is my day #
# The look she gave me #
# Sent a shiver down into my soul #
Out of 20.
# Lovin' on a roll #
# Lovin' on a good roll #
Ah ah ah
# Lovin' on a roll #
Here's your change.
Keep it.
Okay.
Have a nice night.
Wendell:
Whatever.
[Music plays]
Grady, get back to work.
- Hi.
- Hey.
There's my favourite customer.
Let me help you.
Great.
# Lovin' on a roll #
Wendell: [Narrating]
Turns out there was something I'd forgotten
to put on my grocery list
but I really needed to get.
Doreen, my girlfriend.
[Music plays]
# Ever I chance to meet #
# An old friend on the street #
# They wonder how
does a man get to be this way #
# I've always got a smilin' face #
# Uh, anytime and anyplace #
# And every time they ask me why #
# I just smile and say #
Hmph!
# You've got to
kiss an angel good morning #
# And let her know you think
about her when you're gone #
# Kiss an angel good morning #
- Hi, handsome.
- Hey.
# And love her like the devil #
# When you get back home #
Her name's Doreen.
Yeah? That so?
Pretty fine.
Oh, and you just kind of sit there
and ogle her all day long?
That how you do it, kid?
What are you doing, dude?
Hey, don't call me dude, bro'.
And another thing,
nobody likes a wise ass, kid.
Trust me.
Now, beat it.
# A woman and a man in love #
# And the answer is in this song #
# That I always sing #
# You've got to
kiss an angel good morning #
# And let her know you think
about her when you're gone #
# So kiss an angel good morning #
Can I help you?
Nah, I already found it. Thanks.
Oh, yeah.
Thanks.
Say, uh, where's the cottage cheese at?
Cottage cheese?
- Yeah.
- Oh, just right down over...
Just tell me if
you don't stock it.
You're Wendell Baker, aren't you?
You're a real
character, aren't you?
God, you're a real character.
Now, look,
I don't want you around, Baker,
following Doreen,
trying to screw her life up too.
I'm warning you. You get lost.
Do you hear me?
You get lost!
There's trash on aisle six, Grady.
Doreen:
Wendell?
Wow.
You look great.
Healthy as a horse.
I mean, a little horse.
A Shetland pony.
How are you?
I'm good, Wendell.
Besides your boyfriend jumping me while
I'm grocery shopping,
I'm all right, I guess.
He said you
were stalking me.
Watching, that's all.
I'd watch out for
this Grady kid, though.
So, is this your boyfriend's place?
Uh-huh.
He runs it with his brothers.
So lunkhead's pretty successful?
'Cause once I'm back on my feet
the money will come.
I've never cared
about money, Wendell,
and I've always
taken care of myself.
You know that.
I'm with Dave
because I care about him
and he feels the same way
about me.
[Clears throat]
Pretty vague.
I'm not going to be with someone just
for the sake of not being alone.
I've been alone.
It doesn't scare me.
Now, being with someone
and still feeling alone,
that's a feeling I don't like.
I'm glad you're out of Huntsville.
But I can't be in your life anymore.
You'll find someone else.
You just
have to find yourself first
and figure out
what you want out of your life.
And you found somebody else?
- Yeah.
- [Door opening/closing]
I have.
Doreen? You all right?
Hey, Dave. Yeah, I'm good.
I'm fine. Thank you.
Really.
[Mouthing]
Dave:
Sure?
Doreen:
Yeah.
[Mouthing]
- Yeah.
- [Mouthing]
You know, Wendell.
I went through a hard time,
but now I'm happy with my life.
Wendell:
You could be thrilled.
Doreen:
That's what you always said, Wendell.
Wendell:
Yeah, but things are different now.
I-I mean, I can't believe you have
as much fun
- with some guy as you did with me.
- [Indistinct yelling]
I mean, for every tough time
we had together,
I'll name you five
great times we had.
Doreen:
When you were sent away
it was just
another adventure for you.
For me, it was
the saddest, hardest time of my life.
But I got through it.
And I got through it alone.
And it ended it for me.
I need you to accept that
and move on, Wendell.
Will you do that for me?
I'm not going to tell you that
I'm going to forget about you, Doreen.
'Cause I'm not. Ever.
But I'll stop coming around.
It's good to see your face again.
I'll always be hoping
that you're doing fine.
[Music plays]
[Door opens/closes]
Neil: [On P.A.]
Well, we're shutting it down
here at Shady Grove
for the night.
Great job, everyone, today.
The yard looks terrific.
The new paint on
the upstairs awning, wonderful.
It was a great day.
I'm proud of each
and every one of you for staying alive.
I guess that's about it.
This is Neil King,
your head nurse, signing off.
[Microphone feedback]
- What a nut.
- Yeah.
So you think this guy Wendell Baker's
going to be a problem?
Are you kidding me?
The guy's too dumb.
Uh, "thank you very
much for this job.
This, it's my first job
in the hotel business."
[Laughing]
What was that at
the wake? "I recently lost someone.
They didn't pass away,
they just passed me by."
"Passed me by."
[Laughing]
Oh, and I'll tell you this about Baker.
He's the perfect guy to frame.
Like I said earlier, if the heat
comes down, we frame Baker so fast
it makes his head spin.
That's harsh.
Neil:
Hey. Don't go getting soft on me.
You're the only person I trust on this.
And you're my best friend.
[Softly]
Don't go chasing waterfalls
Listen to the rivers
And the lakes
that you used to know
[Crickets chirping]
[Clatter of film projector]
Oh. Excuse me, sir,
I... I noticed the light
and I wanted to introduce myself.
I'm Wendell Baker.
I'm Nasher.
It's good to meet you.
Um, you know, uh, uh, I ju...
I just wanted to introduce myself
and, uh, yeah, if you need anything,
just... Just let me know.
And, uh, yeah, so.
- Baker?
- Yes, sir?
Could you pick up
the September "Popular Mechanics"?
I'll reimburse you.
You bet.
I'll, uh, I'll pick it up tonight
and bring it by tomorrow morning.
And by the way, sir,
you can feel free to...
Call you Wendell.
Yeah. That's right.
And yeah, so I'll pick that...
You know,
I'll have... Have it for you in
the morning, sir.
Excuse me.
[Groaning]
Skip?
How are your spirits?
I'm fine.
You sound a little down.
Maybe you want to talk to me.
Is it Lynn?
Goddamn it.
I really miss her.
I know, Skip.
She was my girl.
Couldn't have loved her more
and I damn sure didn't need her
to be taken away to appreciate her.
I know it, Skip.
Those trees are lit up.
[Knocking]
[Door opens]
Mr. Fullbright?
Mr. Summers?
Hey. It's Wendell Baker.
How you two doing?
Man down, Baker.
Skip's missing his wife.
I understand.
I'm missing my girlfriend.
Doreen.
Is she alive?
Yeah. She is.
Do you love her?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
Does she know it?
I sure hope so, Mr. Summers.
That's a no.
Well, if she's out there
and you love her,
- you've got to tell her.
- Yeah.
Boyd:
But only if it's the real love
and not just because
you don't like the idea
of some dude sweating on her.
[Exhale]
Got a light?
Will you guys help me
with something tomorrow?
Will you help us get laid?
We'll help you, Wendell.
[Music plays]
Hey, Marianna.
- Hello.
- I'm looking f...
- She's not here, Wendell.
If you'll just let me finish, Marianna.
If you could just let me finish
what I was going to say.
I'm looking for Doreen.
She's not here.
I'm looking for her because I love her
and I want to tell her right now.
Okay. Well, she's still not here
because she doesn't work here anymore.
And to be honest, she's over you.
Look, Marianna.
I know you
and I never really hit it off
and at times you might not
have even liked me all that much.
I don't.
Jesus.
Wow.
Did she get my letter?
It was a postcard.
Don't be a wise ass, honey.
Nobody likes them. Trust me.
And I don't expect you to understand,
Marianna. I don't.
Because you have never, ever had
somebody feel about you
the way that I do about Doreen.
- So I'd appreci...
- Wait in the car, big guy.
Boyd:
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
W-we just need to know where
Doreen's working now.
Thank you.
Boyd:
Or at least her phone number.
Yeah, well, I'm not
exactly authorized to tell you that,
whoever the hell you are.
Is there anything
you're authorized to do?
Besides not knowing
a goddamn thing?
Yeah.
Rolodex.
Jesus.
What's your story?
Come on, Skip. Let's go.
[Ripping]
I'm glad she wasn't there.
She said she doesn't want to see me.
Told her I'd stop coming around.
The truth is, if I love her,
I'll keep my word.
Man, that chick's crazy.
[Music plays]
Who are you guys?
This is Skip "Landslide" Summers
and I'm Boyd "Flood" Fullbright.
Flood?
Yeah, baby. Because when the levee
breaks, the river gonna rise.
Hmm.
I'll have three cans
of this cold gold
- for me and my pal, Shiloh.
- [Mouthing]
And a carton of those easy gliders.
You need anything, Skip?
This'll do.
Okay, three beers is 3.11.
May, will you get the price
on his t-shirt?
I don't care who thinks we're silly
You be daffy and I'll be dilly
We'll order up two bowls of chili
Settin' the woods on fire
Aren't you a little old?
For what?
You know. Too old to...
Well, that would be wasting
a lifetime of experience, wouldn't it?
I'm serious.
So am I. Many a fine tune
has been played on an old guitar.
[Giggling]
I'll find your G-spot,
five seconds.
[Gasp of disbelief]
Ten max.
May?
7.99.
Girl:
Thank you. 19.98's your total.
[Music plays]
Here, hold this.
Be right there.
Wendell:
Mr. Summers, what's going on?
We're coming!
[Music plays]
May.
My friend Skip would like
your phone number.
May, don't.
You'll get hotter than a poker
You'll be broke but I'll be broker
Tonight we're settin' the woods on fire
We'll sit close to one another...
Thanks, May.
Hey, mister?
Yeah?
Did you really mean what
you said about being able to find my, um...?
Every word.
To fix a flat or two
My tires and tubes
are doin' fine...
Here you go.
What's this?
May's phone number.
Wow.
Gee, thanks, Boyd.
We'll do all the law's allowin'
- Tomorrow I'll be right back ploughin'
- May?
- Huh?
- Setting the woods on fire
I used to come on a little stronger
in my younger days.
"Hey, baby, let's jam right now."
Simple. Direct.
Uh, w-with all due respect, I'm not here
to drive you two around while you play grab-ass.
- I really...
- Skip just had a connection with this girl.
So take it easy, okay?
The guy hasn't
been laid in 20 years.
I'm sorry. I-I apologize.
Good morning, ladies. Hmm.
Put the rake down, Draper.
I'm taking you on an errand.
Buzz off.
Drop it.
I'd think twice before tangling with me.
Or we can get it on...
Guadalcanal style.
- Give me that thing.
- [Grunt]
Put him in the car.
[Grunting]
Mind your business!
Back to raking.
[Radio turns on]
Get down
Man:
[Speaking French on radio]
Hello, Mr. Nasher.
Talk to anyone interesting?
A young woman from
Iceland said her country's very beautiful.
She said it's Greenland
that's cold and icy.
Well, I wouldn't know.
I haven't been to either place
and probably never will,
so I should probably,
you know, get one of those radios.
Where'd you come here from?
Huntsville.
Uh, I was, uh, I was actually, uh,
incarcerated down there.
You learn anything?
Think I figured
out what I want to do.
What's that?
Uh, r-run a hotel or a motel,
someplace down
around Galveston or Padre Island,
just a real nice place for people to stay.
Yeah, I mean, that's
all way down the road though,
or if it even happens at all.
It's an interesting business.
Skip:
[Singing softly]
Hey-ya, Baker.
No, no, come here. I want to talk to you.
Come here, have a seat.
No, no, no.
No, no. Come here.
My voice is shot.
I don't want to have to yell.
How're you doin', Baker?
I'm pretty good.
I've been watching you.
I like the way you carry yourself.
Thank you.
Pervert.
[Chuckling]
Ah-h, you got
time to hear my story?
Sure.
Here's the deal.
This is a state-run place,
and like the prison system,
it's overcrowded.
You know about that.
So, I take a select few
of these folks
and I give them
the Greyhound Treatment.
I send them up to
mother's farm in Oklahoma.
Now, it's a beautiful
Georgian home that she has.
It's right in the middle of
God's country and she welcomes them.
But I do take a... A reasonable percentage
of their Medicare cheques.
And I sell their medication
on the black market.
Neil, why...
Why are you telling me this?
Because I want you to know me.
You think I'm a piece
of shit, don't you?
No, I don't.
Anyway... I think you can help me.
McTeague is... Frankly,
he's not carrying
his weight anymore.
I don't like him
and I don't trust him.
I mean, you just
look into his eyes,
you see how stupid he is.
[Sigh]
So, you're either with me
or you're against me.
Oh, and if the cops
come a-callin',
I wonder who they're going
to believe,
young man who
spent his life trying to help the elderly or...
A lifelong crook?
Did you ever not get caught?
[Music plays]
[Crowd cheering]
[Thunder rumbling]
[Panting]
[Music plays]
[Dog growling]
Junior. You're back.
So am I.
[Music plays]
Wendell:
Times change, Reyes.
But not me.
I came to the end
of the road late last night.
You know what I found there?
A mirror.
Yeah.
Did you get born again... Again?
Well, I've rededicated my life, yeah,
but it's a different
ball game this time.
'Cause you look like
you got a lot on your mind.
A lot on my mind, a lot on my plate,
a lot to do and not a lot of time.
Not a lot of time for what?
Well, I'm going to turn this place
around, Shady Grove,
and then
I'm going to get my girl back.
Then she and I are going
to start a family.
Want some eggs?
Thanks.
Irma:
How are you, huh?
Did you sleep?
Or did you stay up all night?
I pretty much tossed and turned all night.
I don't know that I slept at all.
But I did have a real moment of
clarity around dawn.
Wendell Baker? Who's that?
I don't know who that is.
People that gave me
that name gave me away.
Look at that face.
Where'd you get
such pretty eyes?
Uh, they're just green,
but thank you.
In answer to
your question, though...
I don't know.
I never met my dad.
The only picture I got
of my mom's black and white.
See, Reyes,
I came over here to let you know
that, uh, Wendell Baker International's
back in business
and you're going to
be getting called back to active duty.
So, uh, I'd get ready
to get pulled off the bench.
Maybe you ought to stay out of it.
Just think about it.
Just think about it,
that's all I'm saying.
You remember Miss Rand
back at the state home in Carthage?
Took us in.
Taught you how to read,
tried to teach me?
Well, she's real old now.
And wouldn't you hope she's being treated
like she should, which is great?
I mean, where will
she be tonight?
And if she wasn't doing all right,
wouldn't you do something about it?
You know I would.
[Approaching footsteps]
[Music plays]
Thanks for the eggs.
May I make a call? It's local.
Sure.
Hi. Wendell Baker
for Mr. Fullbright or Mr. Summers, please.
- What's going on?
- I don't know. Here, want some eggs?
Hey, Mr. Summers. It's Wendell.
Wendell: [On phone]
Wendell Baker.
Hey. It's Wendell.
Wendell: I'm calling 'cause I'm worried
about your friends at Shady Grove.
See, Neil King's got
this scheme called the...
Greyhound Treatment.
You know about it?
H-hell. We're prime candidates for it.
Yeah, well, Lily McCoy, Mr. Draper
and a couple of the others are already gone.
We've got to go get them.
What?
Wh-wh-what do you mean, all of them?
Yeah! All of them.
Wow. Hold on.
Boyd, Wendell thinks we ought to go
out to Wanda King's farm
and get everyone that's
got the Greyhound Treatment.
You up for it?
I can't be ready any sooner
than two minutes.
We're on.
All right. I'm on my way.
[Knocking]
Wendell:
Hello, Mr. Nasher.
I'm just going to be
gone for a couple of days,
but I'll have those magazines you
asked for on Monday.
It's "Forbes"
and "National Geographic", right?
I know the coordinates
of Wanda King's farm in Oklahoma.
You do?
It's nine miles due south of Durant.
Goddamn.
All right, well, c-can you write
that down for me, sir,
because I...
I've got to get going.
I got a lot of driving ahead of me
and I don't have much time.
I'll come back and get it.
I can get you there faster.
Faster how?
In a plane.
Whose plane?
My plane.
[Mouthing]
I know where everyone is.
Nasher's going
to fly us to Oklahoma.
This Nasher?
Yeah. That Nasher.
Are you kidding?
No. I'm not. Let's go.
Jesus.
[Music plays]
Hey, Nasher.
I'm ready.
Okay.
[Music plays]
# In the time of my confession #
# In the hour of my deepest need #
# When the pool of tears beneath my feet #
# Flood every newborn seed #
# - There's a dyin' voice within me #
- Let's go, partner.
It's all right.
# Reaching out somewhere #
# Toiling in the danger... #
Hey, Nasher, when was the last time
you were outside, anyways?
Seven years, four months, nine days.
# Don't have the inclination #
# To look back on any mistake #
# Like Cain I now behold... #
[Music plays]
Whoo!
Yeah!
Nasher, baby, you still got it.
[Music plays]
[Funk music plays]
# I got it #
# Got the funk #
# Funky funk #
Hey.
Guess who died tomorrow?
[Laughing]
[Music plays]
Fort Worth Center,
this is Beechcraft N-6-11, whiskey Romeo.
Transitioning into
an area of five miles north. Over.
[Music plays]
Feel good?
I always loved to fly.
You know, I don't
know you too well, Mr. Nasher,
but I think you might enjoy getting
out of Shady Grove
and seeing the world a little bit.
I seen it.
What about family?
I raised myself.
So did I. I mean, with help
from Reyes and a girl named Doreen.
Where is she?
She left me before
I realized she's the one for me to marry.
I thought to get married meant you'd
found what you were looking for and I hadn't.
I didn't realize
it was about searching together.
And in a life full of mistakes
that's the biggest one I ever made.
[Music plays]
[Airplane roaring]
Skip:
Bob. How goes it?
Boyd:
He's chained to the damn billboard.
What happened?
Neil King sent you here.
Bob:
Somebody's always a-sendin' me someplace.
I just want to go home.
That's why we're here.
[Horn honking]
Man:
Hey, that look Wendell Baker from Tejas.
Maybe that is Wendell Baker from Tejas.
Hola, Wendell.
Oh, hey!
Torres brothers. How's it goin'? All right.
Hey, you guys mind
giving me a hand with something?
Both:
You got it.
[Music plays]
Wendell: [Narrating]
I can't say I was looking forward
to meeting the woman
who'd spawned Neil King,
but I had a job to do.
[Music plays]
[Knocking]
Howdy.
Stuart Axelrod,
county geological survey.
I'm, uh, here to check
the mineral content of your soil.
[Lock turning]
Where's your vehicle?
My vehicle is parked...
Uh, right out there
in the distance there.
Just a sec, hon,
I got a pie in the oven.
How sweet.
[Music plays]
[Mixed shouting]
[Inaudible]
[Music plays]
# I looked for trouble and I found it, son #
# - Straight down the barrel of a lawman's gun #
- Oh, Wendell.
Yes, ma'am.
I mean, who?
You make one move
and you're a dead man, friend
You want some pie, mother...
# Can't live at all like this #
# Can I, baby? #
All right.
My name is Wendell.
# He slipped the handcuffs
on behind my back #
# And left me
reeling on a steel reel rack #
# They got 'em all
in the jailhouse, baby #
[Music plays]
# Ain't living long like this #
Come on, come on.
# Can't live at all like this, can I, baby? #
# Grew up in Houston off of Wayside Drive #
# Son of a carhop at some all-night dive #
# Dad drove a stockcar
to an early death #
# All I remember
was a drunk man's breath #
# Ain't living long like this #
Neil:
W... You got g...
Woman:
What are you doing?
Neil: [Laughing]
I don't know.
- Well, am I?
- [Disco music plays]
- [Turns off radio]
- [Muttering]
Neil:
What were you saying?
I don't have the faintest idea.
[Laughing]
What is it?
- King!
- What?
I can't find
Fullbright, Summers or Nasher.
Okay, Nasher...
Well, where's Baker?
I don't know. He said something
about a family commitment.
That's bullshit.
Wendell Baker's got no family.
You better get down here.
[Music plays]
# I left my home
in Norfolk, Virginia #
# California on my mind #
# I straddled that Greyhound #
# Rode him into Raleigh #
# And on across Caroline #
# We stopped in Charlotte
but we bypassed RockHill #
# Never was a minute late #
# And 90 miles out
of Alabama by sundown... #
Back off.
Just a second.
You're not coming back, are you?
No. I'm not.
That's good.
When you get where I am,
late in the day,
late in the game,
you got yesterday,
today and tomorrow
all in the same room.
I never cared
much for advice, Wendell.
And you helped me without even talking.
But I just don't want you to have...
Regret in your life, that's all.
I'm going to miss you, Mr. Nasher
but I know you
were meant to be up here.
It's hard to hold on to your idealism
after you lost your innocence.
That's what I like about you, Wendell.
[Music plays]
My friend.
Wendell: [Narrating]
We were going to miss Mr. Nasher,
but we didn't have time to dwell on it.
Messieurs Fullbright and Summers
had devised a plan
to take down Neil King.
Good news, McTeague.
Baker, where you at?
The old gas station
out on Ranch Road 12.
Stay put.
Neil:
Well, all I can say, Baker,
is I'm glad you found these guys
'cause I know I get down on you two, but...
You're old, but you got a lot of wisdom
and I learn a lot from ya,
even though you do
got sawdust in your balls.
[Laughing]
Well, I found these two wandering
around out in the middle of nowhere.
I don't even know
where Mr. Nasher is.
Mr. Summers here,
he says he's looking for some land
that he's been
thinking about selling.
I... I'm just glad I found them, Neil.
Oh, I feel funny.
Neil:
Funny? Funny how?
I feel like I'm sitting in a bathtub
full of warm water.
Well, you're not, man.
Aw, he's urinizing all over himself!
Come on. Cross your legs!
Act like a man!
Stop! Not on the car!
Stop yelling at me.
I wanted to stop ten minutes ago
so I could go to the bathroom.
I'm not yelling at you!
McTeague:
Glad it's not my car.
It's going to be your job to clean it up,
I can tell you that.
McTeague:
Come on, King.
Hey, Neil. Are these seats heated?
Oh, he sprung a leak too.
Both of them.
Now, come on, stop the car.
Pull over. Get out.
- Neil: Out.
- Boyd: Okay.
Neil:
Come on. Have a little pride.
All right. All right?
My back! I fell on my back!
Wendell:
You okay, Mr. Summers?
- Come on!
- Wendell: You okay?
- Ow! McTeague!
- I got you.
Ow! McTeague! McTeague!
- No, no. Easy.
- Okay, okay.
Boyd:
Hit it!
McTeague:
Hey!
- Get your ancient asses back here!
- Whoa! Whoa!
[Music plays]
Will you tell me what the hell
is going on?
We got jacked by some 90-year-olds.
Skip:
[Laughing]
- [Car approaching]
- What's that?
Wendell: [Narrating]
So far, so good.
Now it was up to
Lucy and May to do their part.
Whoa, whoa,
what do we got here?
Hey, fellas, need a lift?
I can only think of a couple things
to do in this sort of heat,
and standing by the side
of the road ain't one of them.
Oh, really?
Okay. Yeah.
Yeah. Make way for ducklings.
Here we go.
McTeague:
This is why I go to church.
- [Giggling]
- What a blessing.
Uh, hey, 911.
It's Bobby Culpepper,
concerned citizen here.
Yeah, I just witnessed some
real strange activity out on Ranch Road 12.
Define strange?
Uh, okay.
Underage girls
and men of questionable character.
That strange enough for ya?
Just going to take
my pants off here 'cause it helps me relax.
Oh, I'm
already relaxed.
- Damn-near butt naked.
- He's already relaxed.
Look at that. I have a dream.
Let me see this little blouse
you got on.
- Yes indeedy, feed the needy.
- Oh, it's like a rainbow colour.
- You like it?
- Oh, my lord, I love it.
I need to see some I.D.s.
Scoot over, scoot over.
You two go back and
wait by my bike.
I.D.s.
My I.D. is in my pants, sir.
Uh, mine too, sir.
You gentlemen aware these young ladies
are 16 years of age?
Is that wrong?
Neil:
McTeague!
You okay, Wendell?
I've got to make
one last try for Doreen.
We're coming with you.
[Music plays]
[Brakes squealing]
Here.
What's this?
A wedding band.
You know where it needs to be.
You just have
to see that it gets there.
I'll try.
"I'll try." You'll try.
Say that again. Say it.
I'll try.
Now say "I'm doing it."
I'm doing it!
Now you say "this is for your stuff.
pack what you need, 'cause you're
going with me. Right now."
Skip:
Wendell, it's a rare thing
for a man to reveal his heart.
But any woman with
substance will demand just that,
because it shows strength.
[Music plays]
Listen.
I grew up thinking somebody had it in for me
'cause some of the cards I was dealt,
and I ended up realizing somebody
was looking out for me
'cause I met you.
And the stronger I felt about you
the more I braced myself for the day you'd be gone.
[Tires squealing]
Loneliness was always the wolf
at the door in my life
and I let him right in on both of us.
I'm so sorry
you ever felt lonesome.
I think this is Dave.
You're going to miss her.
I'm sorry?
He said you're going to miss her.
It'll probably
get pretty bad sometimes.
Yeah.
What they call a high lonesome
in the Old West.
I love you.
I love you, Doreen.
You're where
it all starts and ends for me.
[Music plays]
You guys are
with Wendell Baker, aren't you?
We're his compadres.
Good.'Cause you can take him
to the emergency room
when I get done with him.
I don't know
about all that, dog.
Did you just call me dog?
That's ridiculous.
It's absolutely ridiculous.
Classic asshole.
Loser.
[Music plays]
What's he doing here?
We can try it again, Wendell.
No, Mr. Summers.
I said what I was feeling and
she listened to me.
She really did.
I'm lucky that
I ever even met Doreen...
Much less that
she once loved me too.
I'll never get over her,
but I'll never regret it.
The crazy thing is, is we're the victims.
These two sick old men,
they stole our car,
exposed themselves
to those poor girls.
Pissed on us.
That's why we had to take
our clothes off.
Back to the car.
[Music plays]
Wendell: [Narrating]
Sometimes things don't work out perfectly,
they just workout.
So it was an elaborate
kidnapping scheme.
[Music plays]
Are you Wendell Baker?
Nope.
We'd like to talk to you,
Mr. Baker.
I'll, uh, I'll let him know if I see him.
It concerns Mr. Nasher.
[Music plays]
Man:
Nasher's real name was William Harris Rayburn.
Among other things,
he's an international financier,
a shipping magnate, a casino owner
and a producer of motion pictures.
He made the bulk of his fortune in 1948
with the discovery of what was called
the Black Ocean.
In actuality, it was an enormous
basin of crude oil
spreading from West Texas
to Southeastern New Mexico.
All right.
Mr. Rayburn... Nasher to you...
For lack of a better term,
dropped out of conventional society in 1967.
I met him one time.
The day he hired me.
From 1967 on
he lived anonymously in hotels,
communicating only
by handwritten memos.
He made a request that you take over
the management
of his line of luxury hotels,
the flagship hotel being
the Lake Travis Villa and Spa.
[Music plays]
# I'm gonna live forever #
# I'm gonna cross that river #
# I'm gonna catch tomorrow now #
# You're gonna wanna hold me #
# Just like I always told you #
# You're gonna miss me when I'm gone #
# Nobody here will ever find me #
# But I will always be around #
# Just like the songs I leave behind me #
# I'm gonna live forever now #
[Music plays]
McTeague?
Was it ever tough for you being such
a hard-ass back at Shady Grove?
No, not really.
You just get in kind of a groove.
Truth be known,
I kind of enjoyed it.
You know, it was
kind of like playing a part.
Though I now realize
that I was a very unhappy person.
[Chuckling]
Well, I've got to go find Wendell.
Wendell.
I was just looking for you.
- Yeah?
- I need you to go down to the beach with me
and show me how
to set those tables up and...
Yeah? Just set them up
like I showed you last week.
- Thanks.
- And you mind, uh, buttoning that up?
Oh, no problem, Wendell.
Tuck, tucking it in too.
Oh, yes. I got you covered.
I... I want you to show me.
A successful manager has
got to be involved
in all aspects of his business.
I.. I understand that,
Mr. Summers.
It's just I'm kind of busy, is all.
Yeah, well, too busy to see
that it's done right?
No, Mr. Summers, it's just that I thought you
and Mr. Fullbright could handle it.
I mean, where is Mr. Fullbright?
I don't know.
Girls.
Have you seen Boyd?
No, I haven't. Hi, Wendell.
You know, I don't mind helping you guys
every now and then, Mr. Summers,
but I just... I can't do it every day.
I got a lot of stuff to do here.
And come to think of it,
I didn't even see Mr. Fullbright
all day yesterday either.
[Music plays]
# When we come to the place #
# Where the road and the sky collide #
# Throw me over the edge #
# And let my spirit glide #
# They told me I was gonna
have to work for a living #
# But all I wanna do is ride #
# I don't care where
we're going from here #
# Honey, you decide #
# Well, I spend my time at the bottom of a... #
- Skip: Wendell.
# -...Wishing well #
# And I can hear my dreams #
# Singing clear as a bell #
# I used to know
where they ended and the world began #
# But now it's getting hard to tell #
# I could be just around
the corner from heaven #
# Or a mile from hell #
# I'm just rolling away
from yesterday #
# Behind the wheel of a stolen Chevrolet #
# I'm gonna get a little higher #
# See if I can hotwire reality #
[Music plays]
# But can you see
those dark clouds gathering up ahead #
# They're gonna
wash this planet clean #
# Like the Bible said #
# Now you can hold on steady #
# Try to be ready #
# But everybody's gonna get wet #
# Don't think it won't happen #
# Just because it hasn't happened yet #
# I'm just rolling away
from yesterday #
# Behind the wheel
of a stolen Chevrolet #
# Gonna get a little higher #
# See if I can hotwire reality #
[Music plays]