A tisket, a tasket,
a biscuit for me breakfast...
Come on, Cec,
stop your blabbing.
We're... Almost there!
Look, Rufus, shadow puppets.
I haven't had me breakfast yet, either.
Ratter!
Whoa!
Shadow puppets?
Seriously, mate,
you are one kidney short of a meat pie!
Uh, I was just...
Ah!
What the... Oh!
Get off of me,
ya good-for-nothing fleabag of a cat!
A sailor can't even get
a night's sleep without some...
Blimey! Signal fire
off the starboard bow!
Signal fire! Starboard bow!
Cap'n? Cap'n, wake up!
You wakey, wakey!
Ah! Attack!
Board the ship. Take no prisoners.
Oh. Oh, Bosun, it's you!
Yeah. Sorry to be wake you, Cap'n,
but there's a signal fire
on a small, uncharted island
off the starboard side.
What course of action
shall we be taking?
Let me have a look.
Hmm. Some sort of house on fire.
What's this?
Fire a broadside,
drive those bloody beasts off!
Aye, aye, Cap'n.
Then go and bring back whoever he is.
And Bosun,
make sure they leave
nothing behind of any value.
Will do, Cap'n.
Oh...
Humans?
What's yer go-by, fellow?
Crusoe...
Robinson Crusoe.
Oh, looks like them wild beasts
nearly had ya for dinner!
Lucky we found ya when we did.
No, they are my...
Hold on a second, lad!
Let's have a look in there.
Aw!
Not a single gold tooth in his head.
On. Pity-
Pirates?
You be one lucky bloke.
Crusoe, is it?
I'm in your debt, Captain.
Nay, 'twas me eagle-eyed night watch
who done saved your hide.
Away with ya, you blasted bird!
No, Captain, he's with me.
No, Captain, he's with me!
A talking parrot?
What skulduggery is this?
Taught him to talk yourself, did ya?
Yes, Captain.
Drink up!
That'll stir your stumps, mate.
Now, tell me more about
this island of yourn.
Is there anything of,
shall we say, value on it?
All I can say is that
I was shipwrecked, marooned,
fending for myself with nothing
but time and very few skills to survive.
Sorry about that.
I see the bird has taught you
how to drink as well.
That's not very polite, Tuesday.
You'll have to wait outside, I'm afraid.
Fending for myself?
Really?
Listen, you two want to hear
the true tale of Robinson Crusoe?
Oh! Oh, sure.
We're all ears,
or at least Cecil here is.
Hey, come on, Ruf.
It all began like every other day
before Crusoe came to my island.
Just another day in paradise.
Every day was the same.
Beautiful turquoise water,
blue skies
and lots of delicious fruit. Mmm.
Sounds perfect, right?
Boring if you ask me.
How much paradise can a bird take?
I really wanted to get off this island.
Let's see what's been washed up today?
Of course, more of these.
Oh!
What's this?
This could be promising.
- Hey, guys! It's luau time!
- Yeah, yeah. Be right there.
Yee-haa!
Oh!
Hi, Rosie!
Check out these delicious treats!
Gorgeous. Just gorgeous!
Just look at all those bugs.
Mmm.
The beetles are the best.
Crunchy on the outside
with a soft, gooey centre.
Hey! Where did it go?
- My kind of bug.
- You thief!
Carmello, that wasn't very nice.
Aren't you joining us for our
luau today, Mak? We're all here.
Yeah. Yeah. I'll...
I'll be right there.
Do we really need
a luau every day?
So what did you bring today?
I'm not sure what it is.
I meant food for the luau.
Of course he didn't
bring anything for the luau.
Oh, this is beautiful! Hey, guys, guys!
I think I really found
something important this time!
Check this out!
Where? What?
Scrubby, you're really going blind.
Over here.
Ooh, smells delicious.
No, Scrubby, no. It's not food!
It's proof that there's more
to the world than just our island!
Here we go again.
It's true!
Can't we just eat in peace for once?
Sure, no problem,
as long as you can tell me
where this came from!
- From the water.
- I vote for Carmello.
I too vote for Carmello.
I too vote for Carmello!
Oh, come on, this isn't an election!
This thingamabobble is... is...
ls what?
You know what I think, Mak?
That thingy is whatever
you want to believe it is.
Exactly.
You are one hopeless dreamer.
Did you forget
you almost died of exhaustion
flying across the ocean
looking for this other world of yours?
My dear macaw,
you must wake up and smell the papaya,
for this is the world!
I don't care what you guys say.
There's a bigger world out there
and I intend to find it.
♪ I ply my trade for the Union Jack
♪ Upon the seven seas
♪ And unless I eat some rancid meat...
♪ Bury me soul with a mermaid,
please ♪
Look, boyos!
Our wannabe map-maker's
a bit green around the gills!
We ain't hankerin' to be
sharin' your lunch with ya, lad.
Sorry, I'm not much of a sailor.
You got that right.
If you're fixin' to upchuck,
find your way downwind!
Ah.
Oh... Your poor stomach...
Just ye wait till ya get
one of them strange islands
and ya meet your first cannibals!
Cannibals?
We made our choice to go to sea,
right, Aynsley, old pal?
And I swear, I'll not regret it.
Whoa!
All right.
Go and bring me something to eat!
Right, lovey. I won't fail you.
Hey, which of you lucky clucks
wants to join me
for a little snack?
Here, chicky, chicky!
Come on, now,
no need to be shy, my plump little...
What business might you
be having above decks?
Oh, I was, uh, just making sure
my chicken food...
friends were...
were fresh.
No, warm. Warm and comfy.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hold on!
Don't get your fur all in a knot.
So, then, where were we?
Knock it off!
You cats belong down below.
And stay away from our chickens!
And that goes for you as well!
Who does that green-gilled
landlubber think he is?
Uh, the human
who threw us into the hold?
This is our ship!
Wretched as it is, it's home!
Mark my word, Mal,
someday, somehow,
that canine and his human will pay!
I'm with ya there, May.
They'll pay, all right.
Uh, how much exactly
are we charging 'em?
That should teach them to mess
with our egg supply, huh, old boy?
Eggs.
Oh, no, not again.
Buck up, boyo.
Ah, looks like we've got one doozy
of a storm brewin'.
So much for a peaceful meal.
- Whoa!
- Oh! Oh, nobody saw that one coming!
- Hang on, Carmello.
Perhaps it would be wise
to move this soiree to the cave.
Let's get moving.
This is going to be a nasty one.
I'm with you on that call.
And Mak, grab the pineapple!
Like we really needed this pineapple.
All hands on deck!
Get them sails down!
And secure the yardarms tight!
Get yourself below, mate!
Best you ride out the storm there!
Ah!
Oh!
Ah! Aynsley!
I got you!
Oh!
Hey! Hey!
Help! Help!
Look out!
- Runaway pineapple!
- Whoa!
Oh!
Sorry, Pango. Careful, Scrubby!
- I got it! Whoa...
- Scrubby!
Help!
Quick! Rosie, the tree!
Easy, Scrubby, don't panic!
OK, I got ya now!
Well, come on, you old goat!
Get your hooves moving!
We ain't got all day!
That's it, easy.
Don't be afraid, one step at a time...
Whoa...
Scrubby!
- Help!
- He's not going to make it!
Do something! Carmello, grab him.
I got...
You!
H-H-H-Help!
Help! We're in here!
Someone help!
Help!
Ah! Ah!
Whoa...
Oh...
No, no. Ah!
Away!
Payback time!
I can't hold on, Mello!
This is the end, little buddy.
There's not much time!
They're gonna fall!
Hold steady! I'm coming, mates!
Pango, what are you doing?
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Whoa!
How's it going, mate?
Nice try, Pango, but it's hopeless.
I'm a goner.
Mak!
Oh! Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Oh.
Come on, come on, come on.
I'll get you guys out of there!
Ah! We have to do something!
- Oops!
- Oh, no.
- Mak! Look out!
- Ouch!
- Mak!
- Oh...
This just went from bad to worse.
Don't worry, guys,
that branch looks pretty solid to me.
Right, but how do we get down?
You got me there.
Oh, I can't believe it.
They're alive!
It's a miracle!
Hey. anybody want some pineapple?
Whoa, whoa! Did you hear that sound?
- What's out there, Mak?
- I have no idea.
I've never heard a sound
like that before.
Can you see anything?
Not a thing.
Unfortunately, we're going to
have to wait until morning.
Same old stuff. Shells and more shells.
Small ones, big ones...
That's a new taste.
Earthy, with a slight touch of salt.
Come on. Come to papa.
Huh?
Hey, Scrubs, what did you find?
What is it you're eating?
I don't know but it's delicious.
Aw, Scrubs!
You know I collect stuff like this.
My nose tells me there's more goodies
up at Rocky Point.
Look at that!
Woolly c-c-caterpillars!
See? I was right.
This is the most incredible proof
that there's another world out there!
No.
Look behind you.
What are you talking about? Behind me?
Ah!
I can't believe it.
It's the thing
we heard dying last night.
What do you think it is?
The other world.
I've got to get a closer look.
Mak, don't! We have no idea what it is.
It's too dangerous, Mak!
But this is amazing! I was right!
I knew it, I knew it. I knew it!
This is from the other world!
I have never seen anything like this!
Incredible!
Huh?
Ah!
- Mak should be more careful.
- Pangy's right.
We should keep our distance.
What's going on?
Easy now, whatever you are.
I just want to talk.
Sea monsters.
Wow! Look at this.
There's hardly any ship left, Aynsley.
Hello!
Is anyone out there?
- Hey! Can anyone hear me?
- Ooh. Look at it.
Captain! Bosun!
- Anyone?
- It's... hideous!
Where did they all go?
I can't believe everyone is really gone.
Looks like there's just the two of us.
Let's go to shore.
Hang on, Aynsley,
the current's really strong.
Uh-oh.
Oh, land, sweet land!
Oh. It's so good to be alive, Aynsley.
Bob's your uncle,
sea monsters walking on land?
Uh-oh, we're in big trouble.
Only one thing has two legs.
A bird!
And that ain't no bird I've ever seen.
Yeah. He can't even fly.
That monster is going to eat Carmello!
What's going on, Aynsley?
We gotta do something, now!
Hurry, make as much noise as you can.
We have to scare those sea monsters off!
Come back here, Aynsley!
Stay close together.
We don't know what's out there.
What was that?
Aynsley! Aynsley, what's that noise?
Ah! Cannibals, Aynsley, Cannibals!
We have to get off this island!
The sailor warned us.
They'll skin us alive and eat us!
Hurry, old boy. They're coming for us!
Uh, get inside the barrel. Go, boy, go.
There. Yes.
Guys, guys, guys. What are you doing?
Scaring off the sea monsters,
thank you very much.
And what if they aren't sea monsters?
Did you see the furry one's teeth?
He'll rip us to shreds!
Everybody calm down! We're safe here.
Are we?
We really don't know
what those creatures are capable of!
I know one thing they're capable of,
leaving the island!
What?
Oh, no!
Come on, this can't be happening to me.
He's actually leaving.
We did it! We got rid of him.
Yeah, we scared them big time!
Will somebody tell me what's happening?
I'll tell you what's going on.
You guys have ruined my chance to
get off this island and see the world.
You really don't get it, do you?
You think this paradise.
Well, it is not!
It meant so much to me.
- He's back.
- Oh, no, here we go again.
Back? Are you serious? Let me see!
Here's what we're going to do.
We stay out of sight
and we keep an eye on them,
see what they plan on doing. OK?
OK, then.
Nobody goes on the beach.
That goes for you, too, Scrubby.
Yeah, yeah. I heard ya.
Didn't even get to finish my breakfast.
All those new smells
are driving me crazy!
I gotta go check it out.
Where you going, Scrubby?
Psst! Come back.
It's not safe out there.
Can't let all those tasty morsels
get washed away.
If I recall correctly, didn't Mak say
we should all stay out of sight?
He did!
Speaking of which, where is Mak?
Sorry about today, old friend.
That was a pretty inept attempt.
Oh, what was I thinking?
I haven't the foggiest idea
where we are,
nor, for that matter,
the slightest inkling
in which direction to set sail.
Someone's bound to come
and save us, old boy.
I'm sure of it.
If those cannibals come back,
we'll be ready for them.
Who's out there?
Show yourselves!
My dog'll tear you to shreds!
And I have a musket!
Huh? A goat?
It's just a goat.
And a bird.
Maybe there aren't
any cannibals after all.
Mak, what were you doing
out there all by yourself?
I thought you said
we should stay hidden?
I was just checking things out is all.
What's all the commotion about, anyway?
Well, Epi just made a good point.
I just suggested, hypothetically,
that possibly the sea monster
lost that thingamajig you found.
And maybe he's come to get it back!
Along with us!
It's one of two things for sure,
a coincidence or a bad omen.
Either way, you need to get rid of it.
Why not just give it back
to the sea monsters?
Peachy idea.
No way!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
- You're kidding?
You're so selfish!
Selfish?
OK. Uh, maybe.
Just give me time to think about it.
But if I do give it back,
you're all coming with me.
Well. All right, then, Aynsley,
we've got some work to do.
Let's save whatever we can
before it is all lost to the sea.
How's it looking, mate?
They're taking over our beach.
He's pulling strange stuff
out from the sea.
I suppose this means
they're not leaving any time soon, then?
Looks that way.
Do you see how
the four-legged one sleeps all day
while the big one does the work?
No, but I'll take your word for it.
I'll bet ya
the sleeping one's the boss.
Look, he stripped off his skin!
Ugh, I'm going to be sick.
None of us knew it at the time,
but we were being watched
by the real monsters on the island.
Some luck, huh, May?
That green-gilled human
and his mangy mutt made it safely here.
How are we gonna deal with him?
He might be a problem for us.
Don't you worry.
I'll figure out a way
to get rid of them quick enough.
For the time being,
we sit, watch and wait.
Aw, come on, May, I'm starving here.
And what did I just say?
Sit. Watch. Wait.
That's right. Now, stay focused!
We've got the upper claw.
No one knows we're here.
Which means we take our time
and we pick them off one by one.
Ah, look, Aynsley!
These could come in very handy.
I'd better practice a bit
before we venture out there
to get our dinner, right, boy?
♪ I ply my trade from the Union Jack
♪ Upon the seven seas
♪ Unless I eat some rancid meat
♪ Bury me soul with mermaid, please' ♪
Steady...
- What's he doing?
- Shh.
Pull back the hammer and...
I don't know about you, Scrubby,
but I plan on staying as far away
from that monster as possible.
What was that all about?
I have absolutely no idea.
But what we need to find out is
what these newcomer's intentions are.
From the sound of it,
they're up to no good.
Obviously they're trying to kill us.
Maybe. But maybe not.
The truth of the matter is
that these newcomers have brought
nothing but trouble to our paradise.
That is a fact.
Fine. Then do like I asked
and stay out of sight.
They're proof that
there's another world out there
and I'm going to find out
whether they're friend or foe.
You really don't get it, do you?
Whoa!
That was close.
OK, let's give this a go
one last time.
Ah! Did you see that, Aynsley?
I did it! I hit the mark!
Let's go fix something to eat, old boy.
That was a miracle,
I never thought I'd hit it!
Well, maybe we'll eat
something after all.
I was starting to wonder
if everyone wasn't right.
The new world was finally here
and I had no idea
if I was ready for it or not.
Mmm...
That's the biggest rat I've ever seen.
Go for the throat,
let's make this quick.
Wait, the human!
Oh, I can't do it, boy.
Go on! Shoo! Go!
What now?
Sorry, pal,
I've never shot anything before.
What say we try fishing?
What's burning?
U-
That would be me.
You smell like burnt biscuits.
Shh! Something's coming.
Looks like Rosie was here.
That's strange,
Rosie never leaves any food behind.
Oh!
Oh, no.
Would you prefer white
or dark meat for brunch, darling?
I prefer... Dog!
Time to get even, ratter!
Hold on, Aynsley! I'm coming!
Those blasted ratters,
they did survive after all!
Ah, I'm hit!
Run for it!
Good dog.
You all right, old boy?
Did you hear that?
Over there.
Oh, look, it's a bird,
a beautiful parrot.
So, Aynsley,
that's what all the fuss was about.
Those ratters were after the bird.
You've done good, old boy.
And you...
We're going to fix you up straight away.
Look, Aynsley, a ring!
That can only mean one thing.
Sailors have set foot
on this island before.
I believe there's hope for us after all.
You can come out guys,
there's no one around.
It's too dark,
I can't see a thing.
This is the very spot
where that sea monster attacked me.
Well, sort of.
Oh, are muse...
We shouldn't have let him go alone.
Maybe he's moulting.
Oh, that's a bit of a stretch, Pango.
Just wait till I get my hooves on them.
Any way you look at it,
this is not good.
Mak can't be gone.
What's that?
And who are you two?
Just two homeless castaways.
We were held captive by that human
for months
with nothing to eat
but the crumbs from his table.
What about our friend?
Did you see him, by any chance?
Oh, 'tis a true tragedy, all right.
Oh, an unfortunate turn of events.
You see, we caused...
We saw the whole thing.
Well, come on, let's hear it.
What are you waiting for?
We'll tell you
what happened to your friend
but I'm warning ya, it ain't pretty.
You see, the human loves to eat birds
and I am afraid your friend got...
Trapped.
Mmm-hmm.
This should only take a minute.
It's just dislocated.
But it's going to hurt a bit...
Don't worry,
you'll feel better in a day or two,
though you won't be able
to fly right away.
Well, then,
I suppose you'll need a name if
you're going to stay here for a while.
Let's see.
By my reckoning, today's Tuesday.
That's as good a name as any, eh?
Can you say Tuesday?
Tuesday?
Well, not quit. But that's a start.
Take care of our new friend, boy.
I'd better offload
as much stuff as I can.
No telling how long
the ship will stay in one piece.
They're nothing but cannibals!
Murderers!
I say we run 'em off our island!
Drive them monsters back into the sea!
Perhaps a plan might be to force them
to live on Curse Island!
Yeah! Oh, yes, yes, yes!
Curse Island!
Uh, what exactly is Curse Island?
Ooh! The end of the earth, mate.
No one's ever made it back from there.
Yeah. There's nothing there but bugs.
Lots and lots of nasty bugs.
Sounds perfect.
Drive them to Curse Island.
That's not going to work.
You have a better idea?
Uh, no.
Right. So, then, where were we?
Stop your flapping about, bird.
You need to be resting
that wing of yours.
What do you want from me?
I just want to talk.
The name's Aynsley,
and from what I understand,
yours is Tuesday.
Call me whatever you want,
except dinner.
Dinner? We're not going to eat you.
We saved your life!
Either way,
you'll not make much of a meal.
Not like the fat, juicy turkeys
we have back home.
Relax, my master likes you.
You said your master?
You did not think that I...
Oh, I like you. You're funny.
I've never seen a bird like you
in England.
Eng-land. Tell me more, Aynsley.
Aye, laddie.
England, my island,
just one fantastic place
in a sea of many lands.
I knew it!
Crusoe wants to explore them all.
If we ever get off this one.
You know, you're the first to come
from the outside world.
Oh, dear, that's not good news.
Uh, hold on a second.
We're made up like this because...
Because you look fierce.
Now, get your heads
in the game, everyone!
We have the perfect opportunity.
The dog and that bird
are still on the ship.
Right.
Listen up! Here's the plan.
We'll deal with the hairy beast
on the ship.
The rest of you
go for the human on the beach.
What's a ship?
That wooden thing on the beach.
As soon as we're on the ship,
the wooden thing, you attack!
Right, then. Fierce, fierce, fierce.
So, I'm a fierce coconut?
I should go tell my friends
that I'm OK.
You'd better stay put,
you're in no condition to fly.
Well, look at this.
We can kill two birds with one stone.
Hmm? There's two birds now?
Oh, shut it! Just follow my lead.
Look, look! That tail feather.
He's wearing Mak like a trophy!
That is so wrong!
Attack! Let's get him!
Whoa...
Yee-haw!
Whoa!
Aysnley, we'd better go.
What's going on out there?
They've all gone mad.
- Ah!
- It appears as if your friends
- have come to avenge your death.
- I'm not dead.
Oh, we're going to
take care of that right now!
Aynsley! Help!
I have had it with you!
Ah!
Aynsley!
Whoa...
Come on down, then!
Get off me!
Aynsley!
Tuesday?
- Hold on! That sounded like...
- Mak!
Aynsley!
Mak, get out!
Kiki!
Mak.
I'm coming, boy!!!
Rotten cats!
You're to blame for all this!
You must leave the ship now.
Go!
- Aynsley!
- Go!
What's happening here?
I thought Mak was dead.
We all did,
but I don't think he made it this time.
That would be horrible!
Come on, guys,
we'd better move back now.
Oh, no! Aynsley.
What have I done'?
Land.
Land! We're saved, May!
I thought we were goners.
Oh, will you just shut up?
What's that noise?
- That would be bugs.
- Bugs!
Curse Island!
Rest in peace, old boy.
Tuesday!
Psst! Mak!
Kiki!
- Mak, you're hurt.
- I'll be OK.
I'm sure glad to see you.
- I was worried!
- Me, too.
Come on, now's your chance to get away.
- I can't.
- Let me help you.
No, no... I... I just...
I don't want to get away.
What?
You don't understand.
It's all those cats' fault.
- What do you mean?
- They attacked me.
He fixed my wing.
And his dog gave his life to save me.
I can't leave him now.
Oh, I see.
So, he's going to take care of you?
Look, he's going to
need my help to survive.
I owe him that.
Exactly how do you plan on doing that?
I mean, look at him!
Tuesday, help!
I don't believe it.
Those cats used us and Mak as well
and what do we do?
We attack the human.
Hold on, then.
So what you're saying is
Kiki's to blame for all this?
- Oh, afraid so!
- That's not fair.
We all thought Mak was dead. Didn't we?
Oh, this is not good, mates.
Yeah. We've made a real mess of things.
Ah, it looks that way, Epi, gal.
Where you going, Rosie?
Off to clean up our mess!
I'm in.
Well, let's get cracking then, mates!
Wait a second!
You're going to make
an even bigger mess of things.
The wild beasts!
They're going to get us!
Stay right where you are.
I've got a special treat for all of you.
Oh.
I just want to
give you some biscuits is all.
They're quite good.
I finished off your dog, human,
and I promise, one day,
you and the rest of your lot
will join him.
Now, that is the taste of desperation.
Try the red ones.
They taste just like chicken. Mmm!
What... What?
Do you want to show me something?
All right. All right, let's go.
Oh, Tuesday,
this is fantastic!
Fresh water!
Good job, Tuesday.
What? You want me to follow you?
OK, I'm coming.
Hey, guys, look who's here.
Relax, there's nothing to be afraid of.
Stay right where you are.
I'll be right back.
What got into him?
- Why is he running away?
- Beats me.
- Maybe it's your smell.
- Huh?
Try one of these, it's really good.
And some for you. Enjoy!
Say, Tuesday, where is pretty bird?
I haven't seen her yet.
Pretty bird!
No need to yell, Mak,
I mean, Tuesday. I'm right here.
There you are, pretty bird.
Here, you see? I won't hurt you.
Come on, don't be afraid.
Come on, pretty bird.
Ouch!
Well, friendships aren't made in a day.
We'll take it one step
at a time, right, Tuesday?
One step.
I can't, May.
The current's too strong.
- So you failed again, did you?
- Oh...
Oh, stop feeling sorry for yourself.
Our time will come.
Soon there will be more of us.
Revenge will be sweet.
Oh!
Ah!
Oh! That hurt.
Why, you can't see a bloody thing,
can you, you old goat?
We're going to have to fix that.
There you are. That should help.
Whoo-hoo!
Why, Rosie, you're no pig.
Hey! What's gotten into you?
You're gorgeous!
Easy. big boy.
Whoo! Oh! Ow!
Oh. Oh, no! Whoa!
No, no, no, no, no! No, no. Ah!
Oh!
No. Oh, no!
Tuesday, help!
Hey. guys!
Oh, never mind.
This is hopeless.
How am I ever going to survive
on this island?
Yes, of course, that's it!
I have to build a treehouse.
Ha-ha!
It's raining tree limbs.
Ooh.
Hmm, tastes good enough to eat.
Is there anything you wouldn't eat?
Hey, Pango. What's he doing?
Don't know, mate.
This cobber's gone b-b-bonkers on us.
He's destroying the tree!
Must keep sawing...
Need to finish shelter.
Must build...
Mmm.
Ah! Yes, sir. More porridge, please.
We had no clue
what Crusoe was up to.
Sawing? Porridge?
Yep, as Pango would say,
he was bonkers to the max.
How are you coming along, May?
Can I have just a little a peek'?
Can you just wait?
I'm cleaning them up.
Well, could you at least tell me
how big a litter we have?
More than we'll ever be
able to feed, I'm afraid.
Oh, look at it...
Hey!
Ow!
That smarts.
I'm trying to work here.
Go eat somewhere else.
At this rate, I'll never get this built.
I told you, go!
Ah, never mind.
What I wouldn't give
for an extra set of hands.
For all his pounding and sawing,
we couldn't figure out
what he was actually doing.
Whoa! Now what is going on?
Argh, really?
I couldn't blame Rosie.
When you've got an itch,
you've gotta scratch it!
But poor Crusoe,
he didn't see it that way.
He had had enough.
And that's when it hit me! A nest!
- Mmm-mmm.
- Hey, guys!
I figured out what he's doing.
Uh, making a mess?
No. He's building a shelter!
Huh? Don't follow ya, mate.
He's building a nest!
- A nest?
- So he is a bird.
Scrubs. He's building
a human nest in the tree!
Oh! Pretty clever!
I've never slept in a tree.
If he stocks it with food,
you'll sleep in a tree.
Good point!
So, guys, I got an idea.
What do ya say we help him out,
get this nest of his built?
I must have been crazy thinking
I could build this all by my... self.
We didn't really have
any idea what we were getting into.
We just figured let's help,
use whatever abilities we had
and hoped it all worked.
Well, I'll be gobsmacked!
Slowly, slowly.
That's it, just a little more.
Hi, Epi! Where are you headed
with all that food?
Whoa! I need a little help here, guys!
- Easy.
- Hmm, salty.
Not that kind of help.
No, no. That tickles!
Epi, hold up. I'm starving!
Whoa!
Help!
Things didn't
always go smoothly.
And we had our ups and downs,
that's for sure.
But everyone was in fine spirits.
And Crusoe seemed, well, happy.
He made a funny little door for Epi
and Pango to get into the nest.
It was a pretty good idea.
After a few modifications, that is.
We became a real team,
playing all these funny games
Crusoe came up with.
He had all sorts of crazy ideas.
Oh! Like hiding seeds in the ground.
Crusoe had a funny way of eating.
He peeled the fruit.
And boy, did he eat slow.
Ah!
It took quite a while,
but despite his awkwardness
and all of his flaws,
Crusoe surprised even
the most sceptical among us.
That's it, that's it. Watch your step.
I just put the finishing touches
on our new home.
New home.
Hold it right there.
First thing we must do
is christen the place.
It's good luck, you know.
I christen thee... Oh!
Oh, never mind.
Three cheers for us.
Wow! Now, look at that.
It's so beautiful!
Hip, hip, hooray!
What in the world is that noise
he's making?
- Sounds like Scrubby when he needs food!
- Hmm!
It's painful, mates.
Let's get outta here.
Oh!
Personally, I think it sounds beautiful.
A party and we weren't invited.
Mal! Quit your daydreaming.
I am starving here!
Oh, coming.
You know how difficult it is
in my condition to hunt right now.
Have you tried to make it
to the other island lately?
Oh, May. You know the last time I tried
I almost drowned.
I'm afraid we're stuck
with just the bugs and spiders.
They sound delicious.
Now, go and hunt some up for me.
Right, darling.
I'll wrap 'em in seaweed
just the way you like 'em.
With the nest completed,
Crusoe moved on to a new project.
We didn't have to forage for food,
we had this great nest.
And we even had indoor plumbing!
Paradise just got better.
That human sure has made life
peachy for us.
Rosie, he's bonzer to the max.
I tell ya, old girl,
if this new world Mak
talks about is this cushy,
it may not be that bad after all.
Getting a little plump, aren't we?
Sitting around all day.
Ain't nothing wrong with a few curves,
Kiki, honey.
With Crusoe doing the fishing,
we'll be putting some curves
on you too in no time, Kiki.
Ooh, what do we have here?
Hmm. Looks like Crusoe is going to
put your fishing skills to shame, Kiki.
As time passed, life became
more and more comfortable for us all.
Yet Crusoe seemed very sad at times.
He missed his old world.
He built a strange tower
an the highest point of the island,
with bright lights burning every night.
Another day, no ships in sight,
little fella.
What I wouldn't give to see the sun
set over the Thames.
Thames?
Come on, partner.
I don't get it.
Why does he light this every night?
In the hope that some other humans
will pass by.
If they see the signal,
they'll come and rescue him.
I knew the chances
of leaving this island
were becoming slimmer as time went by.
I just didn't know how slim.
More humans on our island?
That's not going to happen.
And now, my friends,
like all good Englishmen,
a moment of silence to give thanks
for this bountiful harvest.
Psst! Mind your manners.
- Our host is...
- Taking a snooze, it appears.
Or worse.
Psst! Hey, stop fooling around.
At least we're not out in that weather.
Oh, it's miserable out there.
Listen to you guys!
We're meant to live in the weather.
Have you all gone soft?
Whoa, whoa, Kiki.
Why get so worked up?
Oh, you haven't seen worked up.
Answer me this.
What happens to us
when Crusoe leaves this island?
I mean, have you thought of that?
Kiki, now... Now, listen.
Oh, I'm listening.
I'm listening loud and clear, Mak!
Shall we eat'?
If I could just find
one little morsel.
One measly little morsel.
It's mine! It's all mine!
Mine, mine, mine, mine!
- What's yours?
- Nothing.
You wouldn't be depriving your family,
now, would you, sweetheart?
Yes. I mean no.
Oh!
Oh, May, that hurts.
Shame on you! I should...
Look, the ship's falling apart.
Our luck is turning.
Maybe we'll be able to make it back
to the main island after all.
Hey, what do you say we go outside
and have some fun on the waterslide?
Great idea!
I love all the smells after a good rain.
I'll catch up with you guys later.
I'd better find Kiki first,
make sure she's all right.
Why didn't that ship just vanish
into the sea?
Our lives are never
going to be the same again.
Shall we have a little snack before
we move on to the main island?
Oh!
Help!
Scream all you want, little bird.
No one's going to save you now.
I'll be the son of a sea cook!
Watch out, children, it's the human!
Get your filthy paws off my bird!
Epi, Pango, to the left.
We'd better get out of here, quick!
Come on, everyone,
we've got them surrounded!
Attack! Ka-boom!
Oh, he got me.
If this is heaven, why are you here?
They're heading for the big island!
They're everywhere! It's all my fault!
We have to warn the others!
Get to the nest! Now, hurry!
- Predators!
- What?
Did he say predators?
Oh, no! Hang on, everyone,
I'll get my musket.
Oh!
Batten down the hatches!
I just need a little powder
and then some shot.
That's it, Tuesday, close everything up.
Ow!
Ah! They're everywhere!
Get off of me!
Ah!
Stay away, you bloody ratters!
Tuesday, ah!
Help!
Get me down from here!
I may not know human
but that's "help" in any language.
Carmello! Crusoe needs our help.
Oh!
Ah!
Uh-oh!
Oh, duck!
Ooh!
Hurry, Epi!
Whoa!
Oh!
Yee-haa!
Uh-oh.
Pango! Over here! Jump!
- Stand back, Epi!
- Ooh! Hurry! He's right behind you!
Yee-haa!
Go. go!
I need my musket.
Now look what you've done!
You guys stay put!
Oh, not again!
Stay away, you mangy cat!
Hang on, Crusoe!
Good job, buddy.
Huh?
That wasn't so bad.
Keep pushing.
I'll take care of these blighters!
Whoa!
Pango!
Help!
Whoa! That's awful high.
Come on, you can make it. Jump!
Oh, my. Here goes.
Ooh!
- Oh, dear.
- Good work!
Now, let's get out of here.
OK.
So long, furball!
Hungry, are we? Well, then, take that!
And how about a banana?
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
So long, Knucklehead!
Scrubby, the door!
Come on!
My turn!
Hello there.
Many thanks, Scrubs.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Over here, Epi, girl! Get in the bucket!
Going up!
Pango, get him off!
Get off, you mangy cat!
Good work, Epi!
They'll never get me.
We got rid of 'em, didn't we?
Epi!
Pango!
Huh?
Whoa! Help me.
Look out behind you, Epi!
Whoa!
- Help!
- No! Epi!
Hang on, I'm coming!
Whoa!
Let go of me!
The cats are trying to get in
through the hatch!
No! Rosie, no, that was Crusoe.
- Oops!
- Help me get this open.
Oh, I hope you didn't hurt him.
Oh! Everybody OK?
Everybody except Crusoe.
Come on guys, all together.
It's heavy.
Spread out, Rosie.
We need all the muscle we can muster!
Really? OK, OK.
One, two, three!
Well, that's a bit of a bummer, mates.
We need Crusoe! How's he doing, Kiki?
He's alive
but he won't be of any use to us.
We're going to need a miracle
to hold all these cats back.
I got it. The musket!
Watch out, guys, it's going to be noisy!
Are you sure that's a good idea?
It's worth a try. What else can we do?
Uh-huh. This could be a bit more
complicated than I thought.
Hmm, the human's out.
Time to make our move.
Hurry!
We can't hold them off much longer.
He always pulls that
thingamajig back first!
OK, get ready.
Huh? That's weird. Hmm.
What's happening in there?
Hey, Tuesday, maybe this thingy
has something to do with it.
What thingy?
Ah!
Now what?
You know they're going to come back!
Maybe Crusoe will come to and save us.
I hate to break it to you guys.
We're on our own.
We have to get out of here,
hide someplace.
What about Crusoe?
Pango's right! We can't leave him here.
Guys, guys, it may not be perfect,
but I think I've got a plan.
Well, you'd better lay it out,
cos we're out of time.
All right, children, calm down.
They just got lucky this time.
We're going to sneak up on them
and make them pay.
Now let's show them what we're made of!
Oh. yeah!
Aw, you've got a broken wing, have you?
Don't worry.
We'll put you out of my misery.
Stay back or I'll shoot!
Not so brave now, are you?
Uh-oh!
Appears your luck has just run out.
Oh!
Whoa!
You'll have to be quicker
than that, ratter!
Get him! He can't fly!
That should take care of you
quite nicely.
Sweet dreams
from your favourite ratter.
Get ready!
- We got him cornered, May.
- Then, let's finish him off
once and for all.
Catch me if you can, ratter!
Whoa! Hold on!
Rosie, stop!
We have to wait for the signal.
This is it, give it all you have, Rosie!
- Huh? What's going on?
- They tricked us.
Hold on to that tail,
I'll take care of him.
We're not so cocky any more, are we?
Tuesday's in trouble!
Ah!
Oh, ho! That was a bonzer plan
you had there, mate.
Couldn't have done it without you guys.
Huh? The fire! Crusoe!
Crusoe!
Over here.
Ouch, that must have really hurt!
We pulled Crusoe out to safety,
unconscious but alive.
And then, out of the blue,
we get cannon-blasted from your ship.
Aye. The Captain can be one tough bloke.
What do you expect?
They're pirates, after all.
Pirates?
You know,
like them nasty ratters,
only worse.
I had a pack of crazed cats on my right.
I was sure I was a goner!
I took my musket in one hand,
my sword in the other
and carved a swath to the savage hordes.
Whoa!
It was horrible, Captain!
That is the most fantastical yarn
I've heard in all me life!
'Tis no yarn, Captain.
Mmm. So you say.
Well, then, 'tis time to set sail.
You and your bird can take a bunk below.
Oh, Captain. I cannot tell you
how I long to see England again.
England?
We'll not be sailing for them ports.
Lest we want to be hanging
from the gallows.
Right, me mates?
But you see... We... I must...
Can you at least drop me off
a bit closer to home?
You're with us now.
Once a pirate, always a pirate.
Have you got a problem with that?
- But Captain, if I might...
- Enough talk!
Off with ya! And I'll be expectin' ya
to carry your weight, lad.
Or you'll be walkin' the plank, ye will,
OI' worse.
Look! ls it a mirage, May?
It's not a mirage, you idiot!
It's a ship! Children, start paddling!
♪ I ply my trade for the Union Jack
♪ Upon the seven seas
♪ And unless I eat some rancid... ♪
Hey, give it here!
That be my rum ye be drinkin'!
Oh, you want some rum, do ya?
How's me fists instead?
These are some nasty pirates.
It won't end well, I'm afraid,
if we stay another moment.
Hey! What you be fixin' to do there?
Oh, nothing. Nothing at all.
Is that right?
That ingrate we done rescued
from the island
is trying to steal one of our rowboats!
If anybody gonna be stealing anything,
it be us!
No, I was just...
Hey! What's going on out here?
Bosun, he's trying to jump ship.
Get him and throw him in the brig.
Right! Let's teach him a lesson.
Take that!
Go get him!
Hey, he's gettin' away! Grab him!
Ha, give me a piece of him!
There's no way off this ship, you fool!
Ah!
Whoa!
- Get him!
- Tuesday!
- He's mine!
- I'll grab him.
Whoa!
A raft!
You fools couldn't hit
the broadside of a barn!
Come on, lads, show me
what ye be made of.
Bosun!
Get your scurvy excuse for a pirate
down to my cabin! Now!
Aye, aye, Cap'n. Right away!
And the rest of you fools,
back to work before I give you each
ten lashes of me whip!
Blasted bird.
Cap'n, he's getting away!
- Shall we send some men after him?
- Nay. Let him go.
Oh, Captain!
Can't we fire a cannon shot,
blow him to smithereens'?
Why waste a good cannonball?
Let him spend the rest of his life
on that long-forgotten island.
That is, if the wild beasts
don't devour him first.
Aye, aye, Captain!
It's been nice knowing ya, Ruf.
We did have ourselves
a good run there, didn't we, Cec?
Jump!
I wasn't going to
let those ratters get you.
We friends gotta stick together.
Nice of you to think so.
Where we be headed off to, then?
We're going home.
♪ We're dreaming about a new world
♪ Nature removes the borders
♪ The looks are stronger
than the words
♪ People are not strangers
♪ A place where dazzle our friendships
♪ Where we can read happiness
on our lips
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ As long as the sun shines
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ And we can take it higher
♪ We take it higher
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ We're dreaming about a new world
♪ Everybody can understand
♪ Every language, every colour
♪ It's for these things that we stand
♪ A place where dazzle our friendships
♪ Where we can read happiness
on our lips
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ As long as the sun shines
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ And we can take it higher
♪ We take it higher
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ As long as the sun shines
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ And we can take it higher
♪ We take it higher
♪ The world belongs to us
♪ To us, to us, to us
♪ To us ♪