[Man]
Yeah!
[Woman] There are certain hours of the night
when I awake to the sound of a train.
It roars right through my apartment.
At times it feels as if
it will lift me out ofbed.
All that earsplitting thunder
and then silence.
- I'm alone, Exley!
- [Man] I'm gonna stop you.
Would you mind singing?
- Like a song?
- Yeah, like a song.
But l- I didn't prepare that!
- That's okay!Just go for it!
- Like any song?
Anything you like.
Whenever you're ready!
Dd [Singing]
Dd [Ends]
I don't know the rest! I'm sorry!
That's okay! That was great!
Thanks!
Take care!
You too!
Thank you!
Methinks there is
an air comes from her.
What fine chisel!!!
Could ever yet cut breath?
Let no man mock me!!!
For I will kiss her!
[Gasps]
Oh, she's warm!
If this be magic!!!
Let it be an art lawful as eating!
Yeah, we just got done!Just now!
I'm in the dressing room!
No, my stomach's been fucked up all day!
Valuables! See you tomorrow.
Hold on! I know we're winding down,
but the snow was clumpy again tonight!
- Oh, I'm sorry! I'll get it fixed!
- It's not your fault!
[Water Running]
[Faucet Turns Off]
Dd[Woman Singing, Indistinct]
Dd[Continues]
- You going out?
- Maybe for one, yeah!
I think I'm gonna head home.
I'm tired.
[Woman] Sorry these are late, everyone.
Payroll had a computer glitch.
Reese, there's a woman out there
asking for you!
She said she'd wait by the stage door!
Very classy looking!
- Thanks, Ruthie!
- Thanks, Ruth!
- Reese?
- Yeah!
- Hi! Lori Lansky! It was a great show!
- Thanks!
The ending is so moving.
And that thief-he was just mesmerizing.
- Glad you liked it!
- Hey!
Hey! Hey, Ray, this is Lori!
- Hey, Lori!
- Hi, Ray! It was a great show!
- Thank you!
- Thanks! You're going to Niagara, right?
- Mm-hmm!
- Cool! See you there!
- Later!
- Bye, Ray!
There goes our thief!
So, can I buy you a drink?
- Um, who are you?
- I'm a book editor!
I, um, have to go meet our thief!
Well, can I join you?
It's this way!
Is this about my dad?
Sort of, yes!
- What's up?
- Not much!
- Staying out of trouble?
- Trying to!
- I'll get this!
- That's okay! It's on the house!
- Oh, thanks!
- Cheers!
So, about your father!
You want to know about
the, um, hidden manuscripts!!!
What he puts in his Cherry Coke!!!
If he finger fucks his pen pals!
All the deep, dark, spooky shit?
Oh, I can see the wolves
have already gotten to you!
- You people are relentless!
- He hasn't shared his work in almost two decades!
- Trust me-you're not missing out on much!
- Apparently there's a novel!
- I doubt it!
- The first two chapters were sent to his publishers!
Yeah, seven fucking years ago!
It was 37 pages of crap!
There were so many spelling errors!!!
His editor thought he was trying to
capture the voice of an illiterate!
Well, I like to think that he's
working on his masterpiece!
Anyway, I'm not here about the novel!
Early in your parents' relationship!!!
There was a three-year
letter-writing correspondence!
Apparently-
and I'm sure that you know this-
your father fancied himself as
a rather angry American expatriate!
For most of their courtship,
he was living in the south of France!
Now, if I have my chronology correct!!!
Your father was writing
the early chapters of People's Park...
and your mother was completing
her degree here in the States!
At some point
before your mother's death!!!
Your father returned
her letters to her.
- Your mother arranged them in a box.
- And?
And left the whole collection to you!
And this is one of the letters?
It's a xerox of one
of the early ones, yes.
There are approximately 150 pairs!
- How'd you get the xerox?
- Your mother's brother!
- Uncle Dick?
- Richard was the executor of your mother's will!
- How'd you find him?
- I attended the funeral!
- I was hoping to meet you there.
- I was opening a show!
Of course!
Hey, Spicer's in the turtle shed.
What?
Excuse me for a second!
[Snorting]
Oh, God!
[Laughs]
[Grunts]
- dd[Hip-hop]
- dd[Man Rapping]
So, you want the letters!
- I'd like to buy them from you, yes!
- What's your offer?
$100,000-
half on delivery of the letters!!!
And, uh, half on publication!
L-I would be very happy
to recommend a literary agent to you!
How gracious!
- Reese, do you and your father speak?
- Doesn't matter!
Why not?
'Cause I'm not gonna do it!
Wait a minute! Look, just-just
think about it, would you?
If you change your mind, call me!
My home number's on the back of the card!
Just think about it!
Please leave!
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Mews]
[Drawer Sliding Open]
[Sniffles]
[Weeping]
Reese.
- Rob!
- Hey!
Hey!
- So, what's up?
- Not much!
Same old shit-
auditioning, working!!!
Watching my laundry multiply!
What are you doing downtown?
I'm, uh, house-sitting
over at this loft on Bond Street!
Sort of semipermanent couch surfing!
I heard you're in a show!
Yeah! Winter's Tale.
Over at La Mama!
We close this weekend!
You working on anything?
I was doing this weird Molière workshop
set in a boxing ring!
That ended a few weeks ago!
I was actually thinking
about moving to Colorado!!!
Working on a ranch or something!
Real people, cows and shit!
Hey, I heard about your mom!
I'm really sorry about that!
Oh, thanks!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine!
If you ever feel like talking me out
of moving to Colorado!!!
Give me a call!
Uh-
I still got this stupid thing!
Minutes galore!
See you around!
Fifteen years ago!!!
I thought he was the funniest,
sexiest, smartest person I'd ever met!
And now the idea of even being in the same
room with him makes me physically ill!
What time does to people!
I'm just glad we never had kids!
Are you okay?
Yeah! Why?
I don't know!
You just seem so far away!
You've hardly touched your salad!
I think I'm just a little run-down!
The show closing,
what's next and all that!
You can tell me stuff, you know!
I'd hate to have our little
mutual admiration society disband!!!
Just because the play is closing!
What about your family?
Will you see them for the holidays?
- No!
- Where are your parents anyway?
I've never heard you talk about them!
- Not much to talk about!
- It's like that, huh?
If you'd like to spend Thanksgiving with me,
you're more than welcome!
I'm having some friends over for dinner!
We're doin' a turkey and pumpkin pie
and homemade stuffing!
And I got my grandma's
stuffing recipe with apples!
- Thanks, Didi!
- What happened to your hand?
Oh, I banged it while I was feeding Spike!
It's just a bruise!
How is Spike anyway?
Is she still keeping you up at night?
She's good!
It's so sweet-you saving that kitten!
[Chuckles]
I couldn't do it, not in this city!
What?
Hmm! There's no pay phone!
- You can use my cell!
- Are you sure?
Of course!
- Here!
- Thanks, Didi!
No problem!
[Didi]
Hey!
Hey, kiddo!
Mmm!
Hmm!
Dd[Piano]
Dd[Ends]
[Rob]
That was nice.
Thanks.
I didn't know you could play!
- Where are you going?
- I have to feed my cat!
- Stay!
- I can't!
Feed her in the morning.
- She's sick!
- Reese.
What are you so afraid of?
I don't know!
[Door Closes]
[Woman On Phone] Hi, Reese.
This is Dr. Barrett from St. Mark's Veterinary.
I'm sorry to have to tell you
that Spike's test results...
yielded positive for feline leukemia.
- Please give me a call
at your earliest convenience...
- [Grunting]
So that we can discuss her options.
[Gasps, Grunts]
[Pants, Shudders]
[Murmurs]
- So, I got your message!
- [Man] Hey, Reese. Can I get a beer here?
I'll need money to get home!
- We'll be glad to arrange a flight for you!
- Oh, I don't fly!
Okay!
And I'll, uh, need cash!
Uh, I don't know if I'm gonna
be able to arrange cash, Reese!
I'd have to talk to my boss, put through a
check request. It could take a couple of weeks.
- Then fuck it!
- Well, wait a minute!
[Male Voice On Game]
There's two!
You got all three!
- Will you be renting a car?
- I'll take the bus!
And I'll need money for cigarettes.
And food.
A girl's gotta eat, right?
[Cash Register Bell Dings]
[Man]
Take it easy.
Well, that's that!
Can you tell me when you plan
on heading to Michigan?
I'll leave in a few days.
- So, uh, how can I get in touch with you?
- You won't! I'll call you!
I'll look forward to it!
- Okay!
- Thanks for the drink.
Good luck, Reese.
Dd [Humming]
[Mewing]
[Sniffling]
Dd[Woman Singing]
- Dd [Fades]
- What happened?
Smoking break!
Are you all right?
Oh, I'm fine!
Do you know where we are?
We just passed Traverse City!
Dd[Electric Guitar]
[Car Safety Bell Dinging]
[Car Door Closes]
[Engine Starts]
Dd[Guitar Continues]
Dd[Stops]
- Hi!
Who are you?
Corbit!
Is my dad around?
- Who's your dad?
- Don Holden!
Got any I!D!?
- I!D!?
- Yeah! Preferably passport or driver's license!
- Seriously?
- Seriously!
- What's your date of birth?
- April 6, 1980!
- Zodiac sign?
- Aries!
Are you, like,
his secret service guy or something?
Sort of! He's in the garage!
- What's he doing in there?
- That's where he lives now!
- Who lives in the house?
- Me!
Me and Shelly!
- Who's Shelly?
- She's a girl!
Just this girl! You don't know her!
You look different than your pictures!
Yeah, well, people change, right?
Well, I gotta go rock!
Okay!
If you see Mr! Holden,
tell him his balls are clean!
Dd[Electric Guitar]
[Man]
What? Who's there?
Corbit? Shelly?
Reese!
Hey, Daddy!
Come in! Come in!
Here! Sit!
Oh, I've been sitting all day,
but thanks!
[Chuckles]
What a surprise!
- You want a drink?
- Sure!
[Cork Pops]
What are those pills for?
Those were your mother's!
They!!! help me sleep!
I hardly use 'em!
[Drawer Closing]
So, what brings you home?
Oh, I don't know!
I just thought it was time!
If you need me to write you a check
or something, all you gotta do is ask!
[Grunts]
Whew!
- How was the funeral?
- Pretty low-key!
Fair amount of her fans showed up!
No Pin the Tail on the Donkey
or anything like that!
- Where is she buried anyway?
- They cremated her!
Your Uncle Dick took her ashes
back to Louisville!
So that guy in the house said
you were living in here now!
Yeah. Pretty easy.
I got my books and my bed, my worktable.
Got this- Got a new stove here!
Are you writing?
A little here and there!
[Door Opens]
Shelly!
This is my daughter, Reese!
- Reese, Shelly.
- [English Accent] Hello!
- Hey.
- Reese just arrived from New York!
Well, it's such a surprise!
- Here you are!
- Mmm! Good! Thank you!
The car's making strange noises again!
Probably the transmission.
Have Corbit take a look at it.
Well, I should go put this stuff
in the fridge!
- Nice to finally meet you, Reese!
- Bye!
- [Liquor Pouring]
Wow! Where's she from, Wimbledon?
She's one of my former students!
She needed a place to get away
from things for a while!
She's been a big help.
- You still teaching?
- I stepped down a few semesters ago!
Why?
I got tired!
- [Knocking]
- Corbit!
- [Door Opens]
- Come in!
Corbit, I understand you've
already met my daughter.
She'll be staying with us...
for an undisclosed period of time!
- In the house?
- In her old bedroom! Yeah!
What about Shelly?
She'll be okay
on the sofa for a while!
- The upstairs study's open!
- I don't want anybody in there!
I'm sure Shelly won't mind!
Right on!
Uh, Shelly told me
to tell you that dinner...
will be served promptly at 6:30!!!
And if Reese doesn't like chicken...
there's meat loaf and twice-baked potatoes
left over from Monday.
Tell Shelly
Reese is fine with chicken!
Okay!
Tee time's in 55 minutes?
I'll be ready!
[Door Opens]
- [Door Closes]
- Tee time?
- Golf game!
- Since when did you start golfing?
Oh, I mess around with it a little!
- Is Corbit a former student too?
- No.
When I was still living in the house,
I came downstairs!!!
He was sleeping on the sofa!
Well!!!
It sounds like you got yourself
a little utopia here!
Works pretty well!
I'm sure Mom would be intrigued!
Mary'd probably get a kick out of it!
I guess I'll see you at dinner!
- Okay!
- [Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
- Hey.
- Hey!
Wow!
Um, the hot water isn't working.
Just, um-Just flush the toilet
a couple of times!
- That will help with the hot water.
- Okay!
Yeah.
It's pretty cool-plumbing.
Well!!!
Enjoy your shower!
Thanks!
[Toilet Flushing]
- [Tearing Sound]
- [Corbit] Here. Just relax.
[Clattering, Ball Bouncing]
- Watch the ball.
- [Don] Yes.
- Nice and easy.
- [Loud Clattering]
- That's it. That was beautiful.
- Yeah, that was pretty good.
[Chattering]
Sorry!
Ow! Shit!
Run cold water over it!
If you've come down to help, I'm grateful,
but I think I have everything under control!
I was wondering if you could fill me in
on the little golf game that's going on upstairs!
- Don hits a bucket of golf balls
every night before dinner!
- [Clattering]
What happened to all the furniture?
Don had the movers
put it in the backyard!
[Wind Howling]
- Corbit, would you like to say grace?
- Sure!
- Grace?
- Yes! Grace!
Since when does anyone in this house say grace?
I thought you were an atheist!
- Grace is okay!
- Wow.
- Wow what?
- Nothing.
I just can't believe that
this is the same man!!!
Who told his six-year-old daughter!!!
That Christmas was a Republican
capitalistic conspiracy...
created by the Hallmark Corporation!!!
And that,
ifJesus were alive today...
he'd be down in Nicaragua
rallying the Sandinistas!
- Grace away!
- Corbit?
Dear God!!!
Thank you for the food!!!
And the company.
Reese seems pretty cool!
It's nice to have her here.
And thank you for a nice home.
- Amen.
- [Shelly, Don] Amen!
You want some?
- [Shelly] Do you want some salad?
- Please! Thank you!
Mmm. Shelly,
your breasts are delicious.
Glad you like it, Corbit!
So, how were the links?
Mmm!
He was really whackin' 'em today.
We need to get a new driver though.
Also would like to get a four wood.
- It's just a nice club to have!
- Is that something you can sort out?
We can just order one
through the catalog!
Great.
Don?
You've hardly touched your plate!
Corbit, did you get a chance
to look at the car?
The filter's old!
I'll replace it tomorrow!
Corbit here's quite the mechanic!
He used to repair speedboats.
Right, Corbit?
Mmm!
Evinrude Outboard Motors, actually!
And he's a musician too.
What are you working on now, Corbit?
Just some new stuff!
He used to be in a Christian rock band
down in Flint.
- What did you call yourselves?
- Punching Pilate!
L- I had to leave the band though
'cause they were trying to get all ska.
So!!! I left 'em!
Reese, would you mind
passing the potatoes?
Thank you!
[Loud Clank]
There you go!
[Fork Clanks]
You need to eat, Don!
I need to borrow the car!
Did you hear me?
I said I need the car.
- Do you have a license?
- Of course I have a license!
Where are the keys, please?
- She has one!
- Where are you going?
Nowhere!
I just need to clear my head!
Please, can I have the keys?
Please, Shelly? Thank you. Yes?
- They're in the ignition.
- Thank you!
[Door Slams]
Dd[Man Singing On Radio]
Dd[Continues, Indistinct]
Dd[Continues]
Dd[Stops]
Dd[Man Singing On Jukebox]
- What are you having?
- [Pool Balls Clack]
Jameson's on the rocks!
[Ice Clattering]
That'll be three bucks.
[Bell Dings]
Thanks!
Where are you from?
Well, uh, here originally!
- Born and bred?
- Born and bred!
- Where do you live now?
- New York City.
Where a pint of domestic beer
costs five bucks!!!
And you get tipped at least a dollar!!!
Unless they're European,
in which case, they don't tip at all!
- Ouch!
- Yeah!
And they wear such nice clothes!
- You're obviously a bartender too!
- Mm-hmm! I am!
Well, this is the place to come
if you want some cheap whiskey...
or if you're looking for
a decent open mike!
Wednesday nights, 9:00!
- What's your name?
- Reese!
- Nice to meet you, Reese! I'm Brian!
- Nice to meet you!
- So, uh, Brian!
- Yes, ma'am!
Do you, um!!!
Know where I could score
something around here?
I assume you're not talking
about Packers' tickets!
- Not even remotely!
- I'm sorry.
I can't help you out there, Reese!
[Snorts]
Crack cocaine, huh?
I've seen that stuff on Cops.
Crack cocaine will fry your brain!
Now, there's a rhyme!
You should get in the habit of knocking!
I'm sorry!
You want to listen to some music?
Got a pretty sweet sound system
set up in the basement!
I don't think I can right now!
I'm pretty tired, Corbit!
- Okay!
- Maybe some other time!
No, that's cool! You don't have to!
You probably got more important things to do!
No, I'd really like to hear your stuff!
Just not-You know, not right now!
Hey.
Are you wearing eyeliner?
What?
Right on!
Um, so I'll catch you later?
Yeah, okay! Good night, Corbit!
Good night, Reese!
[Dryer Buzzing]
Hi!
I put some fresh linens on your bed!!!
And there's a wool blanket
at the bottom of that trunk!
It gets fairly cold at night!!!
And Don's not a big fan
of turning the heat up!
Yes, thank you! I know!
I lived here for 18 years!
- By the way, what happened to my comforter?
- I'm washing it!
You're quite the reader.
Yeah, well, when you grow up in a house full
of neo-Marxist, anti-TV, ex-hippie workaholics...
Nancy Drew can become your best friend
pretty fucking quickly!
- Can I ask a question?
- Ask away!
Were they competitive?
Not really.
Their work was so different.
You think so?
He writes literary nightmares
about Berkeley undergrads!!!
Pulling out Uzis at People's Park!
She wrote about upper-middle-class
American executive types...
stranded in post-I!B!M! Poughkeepsie!
I would say your mum wrote
her fair share of literary nightmares!
I actually think she wrote pseudo-literary
love stories disguised as social satire.
Well, obviously you would know
better than I do!
I mean, I've read everything
by both of them, but!!!
I wasn't around
when it was happening!
But you are now!
I am!
And I've never seen someone
agonize over each sentence!!!
The way he does!
And it's funny.
As a teacher, he was always preaching
compositional velocity!!!
And boring your fingers into the keyboard
as though fiction is some kind of sport!
And now,
getting a paragraph out ofhim...
is like pulling a piano out of a pond!
Would he ever show you his stuff?
I've had to buy every book he's written!
Must have been an interesting childhood!
Yeah!
Competing for attention with
twin No! 3 Underwood typewriters!!!
Won't do much for your self-esteem!
And now you're an actress!
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Nothing.
It's just interesting!
The attention thing!
- Shelly!
- Yeah?
- How old are you anyway?
- Twenty-three! Why?
Just wanted to do the math
in case you're fucking my father!
- Can I help you?
- Um, yeah, I hope so!
My name is Dean Gerald!
I've been camping
over near Whitefish Point!
I was told this is where
the novelist Don Holden lives!
Are you, like, one of
his former students or something?
I am currently in the M!F!A!
Writing program at Iowa!
Mr! Holden was a visiting lecturer there
a few years ago!
I wasn't there yet,
but!!! I, like, heard about it!
So you've never actually met him?
- I'm basically just a fan!
- Excuse me, Reese!
What the fuck, dude?
Get off!!
That's a $500 camera, man!
No cameras on the premises, mister!
Photographs are not allowed!
- Okay!
- Mr! Holden has- has recently expired!
- Expired?
- That's right- expired!
- He died?
- He's officially concluded
all of his earthly business!
And he's no longer around
to talk about it!!!
So please remove yourself from the premises
or I'll be forced to seize your person!
- Is that understood?
- Totally understood!
And I know karate.
I've amassed several belts.
Okay, I'm removing myself.
But, hey, if, um, Mr! Holden!!!
Ever decides to revive himself...
and officially resumes
his earthly business...
Would you give this to him?
It's!!! a harmless fan letter!
Well, if there is ever
an official revival!!!
I'll make sure Mr! Holden
gets this letter!
[Thunder Rumbles]
Looking for something in particular?
Jesus, Shelly!
You scared the shit out of me!
That box is full of Don's
old interview transcripts!
Could you please stop
calling him "Don"in front of me?
It makes me imagine him at some weird
swingers' beach wearing a Speedo!
Don insists that his students
call him by his first name!
How egalitarian!
All you're gonna find in that one
are royalty statements and tax documents.
Why does the idea of you being
his little attaché make my skin crawl?
I'm not the one lurking around!
I'm not lurking, Shelly!
This is my house!
I know, Reese.
You grew up here!
You suffered all the calamities
of being a daughter!!!
Of two self-indulgent,
brilliant artists!!!
And then you ran away
and never looked back!
Oh, is that what he told you?
That I ran away and I never looked back?
- He didn't tell me anything!
- Don't you have your own family to psychoanalyze?
For some reason
I imagine you as an only child!!!
Growing up in some vast,
impenetrable mansion with turrets!!!
Daddy modeling perpetual tennis wear,
Mum playing badminton!!!
And having biscuits and tea
on the front lawn!
Why don't you go back to Narnia or wherever
the fuck you're from and leave my dad alone?
As it turns out, Reese...
I am an only child!!!
And my Daddy did play a bit of tennis!!!
And me mum rather fancied
her biscuits and tea at 4:00 p!m!!!!
Every day after a rather bracing
game of croquet!
But, if you must know...
I grew up in a two-bedroom council flat
in Shepherd's Bush!!!
And, although it's really none of your
fucking business, my parents are dead!
When you work out what it is
you're looking for, let me know.
I might be able to help you!
- [Sighs]
- [Pills Rattling]
[Hammering]
- What you doing?
- Workin'!
What's this thing for anyway?
So Mr! Holden can get in the house
without having to walk outside!
Did something happen, Corbit?
- What do you mean?
- I mean, this whole hiding-in-the-garage thing!
- Did one of his stalkers
freak him out or something?
- Not that I know of!
He just likes it better inside!
Hey! Do you know anything about these?
Oh, those are Shelly's!
- Is she sick?
- I think she was!
But she doesn't really talk about it!
Hey, so do you want to
hang out after dinner?
Sure!
Right on!
Hey, Reese?
I'm not really an officer of the law
or anything!!!
But, uh, I'm pretty sure it's illegal!!!
To take someone else's
prescription medication!
Dd[Man Singing]
[Screaming]
No, no, no, no!
Dd[Continues]
Dd[Ends]
[Typing Continues]
Hey!
- Hi, Reese!
- What you doin'?
I'm just wakin' up!
[Whispers]
Jesus!
Are you okay?
[Sighs]
Yeah, I'm fine! l-
Just a dizzy spell!
Would you hand me my bourbon, please?
Yeah!
Ooh!
So, what are your plans today?
I don't know!
- Thought I might go to the lake!
- Well, be sure to layer!
- Daddy!
- Hmm!
Did Mom leave anything for me?
Regarding any money from her estate,
I'm sure a lawyer will be in touch!
No, I mean, besides money!
Was there anything else?
Your Uncle Dick mailed that box
a couple of months ago!
Haven't gone through it, but feel free!
[Typing]
What's in there?
Just some old junk!
So, Corbit said that Shelly's
had some medical problems!
Yeah, she was in pretty rough shape
there for a while!
What was wrong with her?
She had endometriosis!
The doctors tried a lot of things.
Nothing really worked,
so she had to have a hysterectomy!
- Jesus!
- Yeah, I was all she had there for a while!
She's a good kid, Reese!
You oughta give her a chance!
- Thanks!
- There's a plate for you in the oven!
Reese, are we still on for later?
Is something wrong?
What room did she do it in?
I don't think this is the time or the place
for this conversation, Reese.
- What room?
- Reese-
Shut up, Shelly! What room was it?
The basement? The bathroom? Tell me.
The study upstairs!
In the middle of the night, I found her hangin'
on a coat hook on the back of the door!
She used a necktie!
Dd[Guitar]
Dd[Man Singing]
- dd[Continues]
- [Dial Tone Hums]
[Line Rings]
Hey, this is Rob.
Leave me a message.
[Machine Beeps]
Dd[Piano]
Hey.
Hey, hey!
- Mom used to play that!
- Yeah.
I think she played it in a different key!
It sounded nice!
I'm gonna go do some work!
Daddy-
Are you, like,
mad at me or something?
I guess I'm just a little disappointed!
Why?
I don't know, Reese. I th-
I think it would have been nice
if you'd made it back for the funeral!
She wasn't perfect,
but she was your mother.
Is that who she was?
My mother?
The woman who treated me like a!!!
Mild curiosity all my life?
- She suffered, Reese!
- She suffered?
We all fucking suffered!
This house was one big,
silent museum of suffering!
We did our best!
Yeah, well, don't fault me
for being just a little disappointed.
Do you know how many times
you guys saw me act?
Once!
One fucking time in the seventh grade
when I played Wendy in Peter Pan!!!
And you had to nudge Mom awake
during the curtain call!
So I missed her funeral.
- Her fucking loss!
- Please don't swear!
- Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fu-
- Stop it!
[Door Closes]
Dd [Rock]
[Bangs]
Hey, Reese!
Hey-
Are you a faggot?
Are you a fucking faggot, Corbit?
- God is my copilot!
- God is your fucking copilot?
Yeah. Jesus loves me,
and he loves you too.
Corbit? Don was just asking for you.
[Typing]
[Typewriter Platen Recoils]
[Typing On One Key]
[Stops]
[Shelly]
In your mother's third letter...
she talks about killing herself.
How... drowning would be
too terrifying...
and a bullet to the head
would be too messy!
She was in St. "Looey"at the time,
working on her second novel.
Your father replied...
that he would do anything she wished
to make that not happen!
He said he would
get on a plane if he had to!
In her next letter she said
that she felt better...
and that her thoughts of suicide
had subsided!!!
And that she had a new idea for a novel!
Can I borrow a cigarette?
Thank you!
It's St! Louis!
St! Louis!
The later letters...
particularly!!!
77 through to 123!!!
Are less passionate!!!
And almost approach bitterness!!!
Perhaps even jealousy!
And then by 130...
they dissolve down
to two or three...
very uninformative half-sentences!
And then they end!
Are you going to publish them?
I honestly don't know, Shelly!
Well, I hope it's worth it!
Thanks for the cigarette.
Shelly, I found these under my bed.
Oh, thank you!
You know, Reese,
if it wasn't for your dad...
I don't know if I would have made it!
In his own quiet way, he cares
a great deal about other people!
I think he really
wants to get to know you!
It's probably gonna take some time.
Thanks for these!
Daddy, are you okay?
Leave me alone!
I thought maybe we could talk!
Please go away!
[Sobbing]
Shit!
- You okay?
- Yeah!
Can you- Can you make a fist?
- Yeah, like that!
- [Moans, Hisses]
- Does that hurt?
- A little bit!
Hey, Corbit, I'm-
I'm really sorry about
what happened last night!
Yeah, that was pretty weird!
Hey, what happened to your eyeliner?
It was too Adam Ant!
I thought it looked!!! cool!
- Really?
- It looks really good on you!
Made you look kinda like a wolverine!
- Wolverine?
- Mm-hmm!
- Wow!
- Yeah! Wolverines rock!
Wolverines do rock!
Hey, you know,
there's this bar in town!!!
That has open mikes
on Wednesday nights!
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, the Great Notch Inn!
You should go in, play a song!
Oh, man, I don't-
I don't know, Reese!
Why not?
Um-
In front of anyone, l-
I have this thing that happens to me!!!
When I have to play and sing
at the same time!
What happens?
- I sort of freeze up!
- Mmm!
If I'm alone, it's cool!
And if I'm just playing
or just singing, it's okay too!
But when I have to do both, it's bad!
Well, what did you do when you
were in Punching Pilate?
I was pretty much
the designated rhythm guitarist!
- Mmm!
- They had me go up to the front once,
but that was-
- That was a disaster!
- Well, what happened?
Let's just say I l- lost my shit!
Excuse my French!
I just froze up,
and they stopped the show!
And then for some reason, l-
I kicked the drummer!
He was this total
Black Sabbath wannabe and-
We got in this big fistfight,
and I broke his collarbone!
So, they kicked me out of the band!
It was a pretty big mess!
I've never done
an open mike before, Reese!
It- It would be pretty scary!
I think you should just do it!
I mean, you only live once, right?
I'm sure Shelly would come!
- You think?
- I totally think!
And I'll be there!
Right on!
Karate!
"Kara-tay!"
It helps me relax!
[Chuckles]
Wow!
Yeah! You need not worry!
I'm a total pacifist!
- Can I join you?
- Sure!
How far do you usually go?
Uh, about two miles if I'm lucky!
I think my jock days
are pretty much behind me!
Do you wanna sprint
some telephone poles?
- Are you sure?
- Yeah! Feel okay!
Okay, but if I have a heart attack,
it's your fault.
- dd[Guitar]
- dd[Man Singing]
- dd[Ends]
- [Applause]
[Woman] All right. Let's keep it going.
Next up we have Corbit.
Come on out, Corbit!
All right!
So where you from, Corbit?
Uh, Pontiac, originally, but I've been
in the U!P! about seven months now!
All right! Well, welcome
to the Great Notch Inn!!!
Where luck and love come
from the same hairy family!
Right, guys?
What song are you gonna
do for us tonight, Corbit?
"I Can't Tell You Why"
by the Beatle- by the Eagles!
All right, that sounds great!
Let's give it up for Corbit!
Testing!
Testing! One, two!
[Clears Throat]
Testing! One, two, three!!!
17, 18!
Uh, I'm kidding!
Before I start, I just want to, uh-
I wanna dedicate this song to Reese!
Sorry!
[Exhales]
Plan "B!" Hold on!
Dd [Electric Guitar]
Dd [Singing]
Dd[Continues]
Dd[Continues, Fades]
That was great, Corbit!
I'm really proud of you!
Thanks, Shelly!
Yeah, and your plan "B" was genius!
Right on!
Oh! Thanks, Reese!
- That was an awesome show!
- Thank you!
I'm gonna say good night to my dad!
- Good night!
[Door Closes]
Daddy?
Daddy? Daddy?
Wake up, Dad!
Why would you do that? Wake up!
[Crying]
Come on!
Miss Holden? I'm Dr! Staley!
- Hi!
- Pete Staley!
- Corbit!
- Shelly!
Um, maybe you and I
could have a word?
- You wanna step down the hall
with me for a moment?
- Sure!
[Dr. Staley]
His heart never actually stopped.
Fortunately,
the sleeping medication he took!!!
Is designed to time release
in such a way!!!
That!!! he never got
a potent enough dose!!!
To execute the desired effect!
Is he gonna be okay?
I don't anticipate any cognitive deficit!
And his vital signs are all back to normal!
He has a strong heart!
We're rehydrating his system
intravenously!
We'll give you a call if there are
any further complications tonight.
[Shovel Scraping]
[Hollow Tap]
[TV, Indistinct]
He was up earlier.
He mumbled something, fell back asleep!
His vitals are good!
Just hit the call button
if you need anything!
Thanks!
How long you been here?
Awhile!
Do you need anything?
I'm thirsty!
Okay!
Thanks!
Do you want some more?
No, but I'd love a cigarette!
Yeah, me too!!!
But we'll set off the alarms!
What's that?
That is, uh, your novel.
I dug it up out of the backyard.
Corbit was supposed
to keep that under his hat!
How far are you into it?
I'm about halfway through!
I think it's the first time I've seen anything
of yours in manuscript form!
The imperfections are really charming.
- I spell like a gorilla!
- [Laughs]
- Do you hate it?
- No! I like it actually!
It's really different
from your other stuff!
- You're not bullshitting me?
- No.
Shelly thinks
it's borderline sentimental.
Do you think it's sentimental?
A little!
But it's a love story, right?
I guess!
Think I'm getting soft?
Absolutely!
- Daddy.
- Hmm?
About the stuff I said the other night-
I'm!!! really sorry! It wasn't fair!
Well, we messed up pretty bad, Reese!
No! You guys did the best you could!
Like you said!
What was she doing at home anyway?
I think she was lonely!
We were both lonely!
I just can't stop thinking about her!
Come here!
- Okay! Stop it now!
- [Sniffles] Okay!
How's Corbit?
He and Shelly okay?
Yeah, they're fine! They're fine!
They're out in the waiting room.
You want me to go get them?
Stay!
- I feel like I'm hogging you.
- Please stay!
- Okay!
- Okay.
When you finish readin' that,
you let me know what you think!
- I will.
- Promise?
- I promise!
- [Footsteps Approaching]
Hey, Corbit!
- Hey, Mr! Holden!
- Hi!
Hi!
- How, uh- How are you feeling?
- Okay!
- A little tired!
- Yeah!
Well, we won't keep you!
We just wanted to say hi!
- Hey, Mr! Holden!
- Hey, Corbit!
[Shovel Scraping]
Dd[Guitar]
Dd[Woman Singing]
Dd[Continues]
Dd[Ends]
[Reese] There are certain hours of the night
when I wake to the sound of a train.
It roars right through my apartment!
At times, it feels as if
it will lift me out of bed!
All that earsplitting thunder
and then silence!
I'm alone, Exley!
I'm very much alone in a city
that at times!!!
Makes people feel old and used!
But I am somehow lucky!
Even during the darkest hour!!!
I always manage to pull through!
[Applause]
- [Knocking]
- [Man] Great show, ladies.
Thanks, Ben! You too!
- Thanks for the Zippo!
- Oh, no problem!
Thanks for the flowers!
- Fan mail!
- Oh!
Dd[Guitar]
Dd[Man Singing]
- Hey!
I thought you left!
Aww! Thank you!
- Congratulations!
- Thank you!
They comped you, right?
Yeah, they were cool about it!
- You were great!
- Thanks!
You wanna walk?
Let's walk!
Dd[Man Singing Resumes]
Dd[Fades]
Dd[Guitar]
Dd[Ends]
Dd[Woman Singing]
Dd[Vocalizing]
Dd[Ends]