I love you.
I'll kill you.
The reason why a generation seems confusing
is because the viewer's mentality itself is in chaos.
-Jean Cocteau-
You bitch.
Don't make a fool of me!
You asshole!
I'll kill you.
Last night at 2AM
3 persons were found dead in a convenience store in Northern Saitama.
The victims were cashier Kawamoto Hitoshi-san,
a worker who lived nearby, Yasuda Ayaka-san,
and photography student Koyama Junpei-san.
All 3 bodies had knife wounds.
The police was alarmed but when they arrived at the scene,
the victims were already dead.
Fujishima Akikazu...
It's been 5 days and the police are still investigating.
No clue for a suspect has been found so far.
Ex-Police Lieutenant of Omiya North Department,
retired January of this year.
He was rather fired, wasn't he?
Now working as a security patrol.
Is there anything else
that you remember about the case?
Nothing at all.
I heard he lost everything.
His house, his daughter, his wife.
Maybe he's the one who committed this crazy murder.
(Schizophrenia/Manic Depression?)
How are you doing?
You're taking your medication, right?
One more beer!
Okay.
Are you ill?
He lost his job and family at that age.
This is the weapon that was used.
Fujishima-san?
I did it.
I killed these three people.
That's what you think, right?
You stink!
Shut up!
Senpai!
Take a look at these.
Have you seen one of them?
All I saw were corpses.
How is your family doing?
Your daughter is in high school now, right?
None of your business.
Don't touch me!
Let go of me!
Shut up, asshole!
(3 persons stabbed in a convenience store in Omiya)
(The madness that destroyed a young man's dreams)
Do you sleep properly at night?
Do you dream?
I'm so glad you picked up.
Sorry to bother you.
Were you asleep?
But I have to talk with you.
It's about Kanako.
I thought maybe she was over at your place.
Please, do not hide her.
Why would Kanako be here?
She hasn't come home for several days
and I can't contact her at all.
So...
tell me the truth. Are you ...
You think I kidnapped Kanako?
No, that's not what I mean.
Bullshit!
Kanako is...
You piece of shit!
(Kiriko)
You have no dreams?
Dreams?
A Life full of Love, A Family full of Love
Sponsored by Narita Homes
Such a thing...
Come in.
Can I?
Have you called the police?
It's too early for that.
Take a look at Kanako's room.
Go and you might know what's going on!
Maybe I'm wrong.
Her bag!
What's with her bag?
It's all normal stuff.
There's nothing.
Isn't that ...
Oi!
How long has she been gone?
Five or six days.
Have you contacted her friends?
No, I don't know anyone of them.
What is this?
Neurology?
What!? She told me she was going to the dentist.
Did she have a part-time job?
There were expensive clothes in her closet.
No, I dont think so.
Who is this? Her boyfriend?
I have no idea.
You don't know anything, do you!
Don't act so high and mighty!
Do you even remember her face!
Did she lose weight?
Did you pay attention to her appetite and her eyes?
Drug addicts usually get thin.
There's no way she would do such a thing!
She is our daughter!
"Our"?
So...
What shall we do?
I'll find her.
You won't.
I better call the police.
What will happen to Kanako if you call the police!
After all, someone like you can't...
Calm down,
Idiot!
You think you can give yourself airs, right?
It's none of your business anymore!
Don't touch me!
Why can't people live in the water?
It's so peaceful here,
whereas over there is hell.
Why am I a human?
These hands and feet,
eyes, mouth, and ears,
my hair,
my nose that's bigger than other people's,
I don't want any of this.
The kiss Hiromi-kun gave me changed my world.
If I'm only gonna get hurt, I don't want even my heart.
I'm definitely
not cut out to be a human.
Probably, he wasn't too.
Damn it...
Damn it!
Were you crying?
Fujishima...
No...
It was pretty obvious.
Fujishima Kanako,
the one and only beautiful creature on Earth.
What's wrong with your face?
Come on.
Here you go.
My eyes, mouth, ears, and nose
all exist in order to feel you.
- My hands
- No, keep it.
exist in order to touch you.
And my feet
Kanako!
See you!
exist in order to follow you.
The reason why I'm still willing to be human
is definitely because you're in this world.
That's how it is,
Fujishima.
We already told everything we know to her mother.
Then tell it to me in detail one more time.
As I said, we were aiming to go to a private university.
Kanako wanted to go to a national university,
so we only have morning classes together.
What happened after that?
I called her in the evening but she didn't pick up.
Do you have any idea where she could have gone?
Like some guy's place?
Is it this guy?
Who is this?
Do you know him?
She can't be contacted for several days now.
As her friends, shouldn't you be a little worried?
Friends?
Well, you could say we are friends.
But isn't this fairly normal?
We don't constantly contact our parents.
She's different from you.
What?
Say, do you really know Kanako?
Did she have a part-time job?
No idea.
Can we go now?
You easily get thirsty when you're addicted to drugs, right?
What is this?
You know that, don't you?
What do you want?
Don't get mad.
I just want to find my daughter.
If you tell me everything you know, you can keep it.
Don't give that to us!
You guys don't look like proper high school students.
We have nothing more to say.
Let go!
You're a nuisance!
I prescribed anti-anxiety pills and light sleeping pills
Your daughter has no real problems.
She is intelligent.
No smoking please.
But she wouldn't come without a problem.
We're in a hurry to find her.
What were the symptoms she was having?
Sleeplessness, irritations,
attacks of sweating,
subconsciously reaching for a cigarette, things like that.
Would you like me to prescribe you a medication?
No, I'm alright.
Then, was there anything she was worried about?
Apparently there were some family problems.
You know about her parents' divorce, don't you?
Can you give me her medical records?
Her father's occupation was also...
You have her medical records, don't you?
I'm sorry.
We cannot disclose a patient's privacy.
Not even to the police.
That shitty doctor!
I have my own medicine!
What is it!
What's the matter?
I was able to contact Kanako's friends from middle school.
Wow! I was so fat!
It's been so long!
You know Kanako, right?
Were you guys together in elementary or middle school?
Ah, yeah.
What kind of person was she?
Her personality? Super good!
She was serious and clever.
I heard this guy switched jobs again!
Do you know him?
Who is this?
Oh, he committed suicide when we were in 8th grade.
Suicide?
Ogata!
Right, Ogata, Ogata!
Were they dating?
No way!
It's Ogata!
He was lame and bullied all the time.
Who would want to go out with him!
Right, but at his funeral...
I'll order pizza.
They also were Kanako's friends.
Really? You treat us?
Great.
Did Kanako and Ogata get along well?
Kanako got along with everyone.
She has a lot of charisma.
Ogata must've taken it the wrong way.
He thought he was Kanako's only one.
That's so true!
There were many boys who thought that.
Well, it wasn't just boys.
Remember that ugly...
Endo Nami!
She was a drug dealer, wasn't she?
Yeah.
Which one's the drug dealer?
This one! Endo Nami.
- What about him?
- Matsunaga?
That's Matsunaga!
He's scary!
He's totally crazy.
I suddenly really wanna go to karaoke!
- Is karaoke okay?
- Wait until we've finished eating!
I wonder what kind of person that girl was.
Don't think about it, just eat.
It must be a prank.
She wants us to worry about her.
It's because we left her alone all the time.
That's why...
Why can't people fly?
Stop squirming!
And why did he fly nonetheless?
Where has the person I was in those days gone?
Playing tug-of-war with these idiots for this tiny place on Earth.
Die!
Okay, let him go.
What's wrong?
You asshole!
Shut up, you piece of shit.
Once again, you came to my rescue.
No.
I just wanted it to be quiet.
Because this is his and my special place.
His...
Ogata's?
Wanna drink?
Here is where I first met him.
Is this Sake?!
I was alone, and he came here to be alone too.
He looked at me and said,
"You want to disappear too, right?"
Disappear...
Wasn't it cruel?
Leaving me here alone.
Doing this on his own.
Fujishima!
What?
Like Ogata...
You thought I was going to jump off like him?
No...
Fool.
Can't I become like Ogata?
What are you talking about?
I don't get it.
That's funny.
You're really weird.
Shit.
It's embarassing, but
I've always been working day and night
so I know next to nothing about my daughter.
So you come here to ask her old teacher?
Yes.
Well, it's a bit late, but ...
But?
Nothing.
I understand how you feel.
I have a young daughter myself.
Sometimes I have no clue what she's thinking.
Is Kanako-san doing well?
Yes.
At that time, she
now and then seemed to be considering suicide.
As if...
What?
As if she thought it was her responsibility.
As if she had driven Ogata-kun to his death.
Specific details?
Long-term absenteeism, pale looks,
weight loss...
Drug use!
So, was it drugs?
And these kids ...
Did she hang around with these pupils?
Kanako!
I'm sorry that I did not report it to you.
But,
I could not believe it back then.
Where are they now?
Endo Nami passed away last year.
In the end, she died of drug abuse.
Of course.
It's only natural that such a piece of junk dies.
It all makes sense now.
These assholes passed drugs to her.
The school knew, but didn't take action.
That is not true.
What is not true!
Are you trying to make excuses?
Hey, Senpai.
Did you remember anything?
That picture you showed me last time...
That paled faced guy with piercings...
Ah, yes, yes.
Who is he?
Well, it seems
he belongs to a gang to which the murdered Koyama had connections.
Tell me everything.
What's his name?
The one with piercings.
His name?
It's Matsunaga Yasuhiro.
So it was that Matsunaga
who gave the drugs to Kanako.
That piece of shit!
It's hot in here!
He sells drugs for a gang called Nishimaru.
Really?
He's the one who depraved Kanako.
It's all his fault.
I even know his home address.
Don't worry.
Once we've caught this guy, we'll find Kanako right away.
Are you happy?
Now that you know that Kanako takes drugs.
Don't talk nonsense!
Why should I?
But your face is smiling.
Are you crazy?
I'll find Kanako, so...
What are you talking about!
What are you doing?
Our daughter is missing!
How dare you!
I want to start over.
Get out!
Can you find Kanako by yourself?
What's that supposed to mean?
If I don't let you touch me, I won't find her?
Do you have the nerves to say that?
I have.
Actually, you don't give a shit about Kanako!
You don't care about Kanako either.
Let go of me!
Get lost!
Stop it!
Don't!
It happened because you were with that guy!
You left your daughter alone
for that baldie!
Stop it!
Go die, you lunatic.
Stop kidding me!
I love you.
Stop it!
Make breakfast.
I'll stay here.
Then, I'll move out.
This is my home.
I will protect you and Kanako.
You have the nerve to say this shit?
Because I love you.
What kind of joke is that?
Something's wrong with your brain!
Shut up and make breakfast!
Kanako...
Leave her alone too.
She has long forgotten about you.
Shit.
Then I'll make her remember.
She is my daughter!
What's wrong with that?
Get out, you psycho!
I'll kill you, you piece of shit!
What's wrong with me loving my family?
One morning, when I opened my eyes,
my world had changed.
It seemed just like magic.
Are you okay?
That was mean of you.
I'm not afraid of that guy.
That guy?
Don't play dumb!
I'm talking about Matsunaga!
He and his gang...
It was you, wasn't it!
I have nothing to do with it.
I've never spoken with Matsunaga.
You quit baseball
to hang out with such guys?
What do you mean?
You're wrong!
Then, why?
Why did you quit so suddenly?
Because I realized
I'm not made for chasing baseballs.
My position is not right-fielder No 8.
There was no special reason.
What did you say!
Sensei, Shimazu hit him!
Shimazu hit him!
Sensei!
Matsunaga sends his compliments.
My world changed like by magic.
And the one who casted this magic spell
certainly was...
(Alice in Wonderland)
Don't play dumb with me, you old bitch!
Matsunaga Yasuhiro is your son!
That guy is not my son.
Who are you?
I'm from the police of Omiya Police Department!
Where is he?
Who knows?
Don't play dumb.
Do you understand what your son has done!
That has nothing to do with me!
You're his mother!
I don't care about that piece of garbage.
That's right, your son is garbage.
Because you are garbage yourself!
Parents must take responsibility!
Take the responsibility and kill your son!
What are you saying?
Hey, you!
Hey, who are you?
It reaks of old man in here.
Senpai!
Are you alright?
Your skull isn't broken?
- Shut up!
- You're scary.
Who are these guys?
Why are you here?
I was taking a stroll.
Did something happen to your daughter?
Kanako-san was her name, correct?
She had connections with Matsunaga, right?
You answer my question!
Okay, okay.
The truth is, Matsunaga is chased by
his own gang and the Ishimaru group.
You just unfortunately happened to get involved in the fight.
What did he do?
Who knows what stupid kids do?
But the murder victim Koyama Junpei
was Matsunaga's senpai
and an ex-member of the same gang.
Matsunaga has a connection to that case?
There is a connection... probably.
Did one of them hit you?
Well, it's hard for you too, Senpai.
Your wife just moved out of her apartment.
I bet it was because you came back.
Right?
Are you observing me?
Well, sort of.
After all, you are a witness for the convenience store murder.
Kiriko! What are you up to?
I was about to ask the same thing.
Oh, Father-in-Law...
Where is Kanako?
Where are you hiding her?
Huh?
I'm hiding her?
Don't play dumb.
Kiriko told me everything.
I know you are hiding Kanako.
Stop talking nonsense.
Why would I hide her?
It's a misunderstanding.
Please put Kiriko on the phone.
What's wrong with you?
Do you think by kidnapping Kanako
you can make everything alright again?
You're crazy.
I said put Kiriko on the phone!
I have to talk to her!
Give Kanako back at once.
Give her back?
She is my daughter.
Kiriko's and my daughter!
Kiriko and Kanako have nothing to do with you anymore.
You were the bastard who engaged a lawyer and disbanded our family!
I will report it to the police.
Just do it!
It's you who's gonna be humiliated!
Where is she?
I said I didn't know where Kanako is.
No, I am asking where that skinny friend of yours is!
Who?
Nagano?
I don't understand what you mean.
Don't play dumb, you ugly bitch!
Hey!
Listen to me.
I don't give a shit what happens to you.
But my daughter...
Let go of me!
Let me!
I only want Kanako.
Kanako...
Your daughter did it!
She sold drugs to Nagano and ruined her.
She scammed her, threatened her, drove her into prostitution.
It was all Kanako's doing!
Don't act so fucking high and mighty when you don't know anything!
I have to find her.
I want her to...
None of my business!
I wish she'd die!
Do you want something?
No.
It's just that my situation changed recently.
It's you who told Matsunaga, right?
That's right.
Do you want to go with me?
It's okay.
No one is home.
Where are your parents?
My dad has run away,
and my mom is having an affair.
I'm all alone and I'm... kind of falling.
What does that mean?
If the hole you fall into is too deep,
you keep falling and falling.
It's a tale about such a girl.
(Alice in Wonderland)
Did you have trouble?
Because of Matsunaga?
No, I'm just a little surprised.
I had not expected you'd know Matsunaga.
I thought you had nothing to do with such people.
Do you want to meet Matsunaga?
There's a party tomorrow.
But I don't know him that well...
Me neither.
We just occasionally hang out.
When I'm all alone.
I feel weak
when I'm alone.
You want to disappear?
By the way, you speak like Ogata.
You resemble him.
You said you wanted to become like Ogata, right?
Then I want you to learn more and more about me.
I also would like to learn
more and more about you.
I guess I'll go... to the party.
Fujishima.
Hey! Have you drunk alcohol?
None of your business.
I'm a cop.
Aren't you guys minors?
- What are you doing out so late?
- Let go of me!
Have you ever thought about how much your parents worry?
Okay, I get it!
No, you don't!
How much I worry
as a father.
Where are we here?
Damn it!
Kanako!
Who is that?
Hey, pay me some...
What's going on here?
Where are the things your daughter hid?
Stop it.
They're in her bag.
We're not looking for drugs.
Then, what is it?
Who are you guys?
It seems you don't know how much trouble your daughter has caused.
I have no idea what that little bitch did!
Yes, your daughter is shit.
It proves that she's related to garbage like you.
Garbage...
Stop it!
spreads its stench everywhere.
Garbage... destroys innocence
and purity!
That's why I'll kill you.
I'll let you taste the death of your daughter first.
And then it's your turn.
I have nothing to do with this!
I have even forgotten her face!
Then smell this and remember.
The smell of the garbage
that you produced.
Wait a moment!
Go away.
You said you didn't want anything to do with this.
Yeah, but Nagano insisted on giving you this.
This is the key to a locker box
next to the North exit of the train station.
Take it!
Who cares, bitch!
Get lost!
It's your responsibility as parent!
What did you say?
This is the key that Kanako entrusted to Nagano.
Matsunaga.
I really don't know anything!
Then get lost!
Nagano...
None of my business!
I have nothing to do with your drug addicted friend.
Don't touch me!
Nagano is a total nervous wreck.
She's frightened, terrified.
Tell me in detail.
But I don't know any details!
She didn't tell me anything!
I told her to go to the police if she's so much in danger.
Since when has she been afraid?
Since
this happened.
After he was killed,
each time when she saw the news
she said she might get killed too.
Who killed him?
How should I know!
But,
I guess it's
Kanako.
Nagano has always adored Kanako.
She's like a goddess to her.
She did whatever Kanako told her to do.
She was even forced into prostitution.
Even so, she still loved her.
Kanako is really beautiful.
But,
she is a total lunatic.
Let me meet Nagano right now.
Nagano doesn't want to see you.
I don't give a shit about what she wants!
But...
You want to save her, don't you?
Nagano.
Can this car even drive?
I love you.
Follow me.
Don't come!
Alice.
Senpai,
you leave a girl alone and run away.
Isn't that rude?
Can I speak with you?
Let's meet and talk.
Shut up!
How often do you want to do this yet?
Piece of shit.
Fujishima.
Where are you taking me?
This guy is...
Damn.
Damn!
You want to become like Ogata, right?
All this
seems to occur in a different world.
My mother's voice
seems like it's in another language.
I can't understand a word of what she's saying.
Shut up!
Is this also a magic spell
that you
casted on me,
Fujishima?
Senpai, you said we should meet and now you back down?
Under the table.
The guy with glasses in a sailor suit,
that's Misawa from the Department, right?
Not quite right. It's Officer Miura.
Where did you get such things?
Did he cause this, this killing?
What do you mean?
Nagano's cellphone memory.
Listen, you can't tamper with evidence as you please.
The last call Nagano made was to Omiya North Police Department.
What?!
Don't play dumb!
She called the police, yet she was killed. Why is that?
We're still investigating.
We don't know yet.
Just admit it. It was the police who killed her.
Who did it? Was it you?
Perhaps it was you, Senpai.
What are you up to?
Nothing.
We just want to solve this case calmly.
Where is Kanako?
Do you really not know?
Then, how about we cooperate?
Who would want to cooperate with you!
Can't you give me those photos?
Shut up!
Don't get in my way if you want them, you assholes!
Don't get in our way too, old man.
Please. Surrender us the photos.
Would you kneel down and lick my ass?
We have our own rules.
And we have the power to enforce them.
Senpai, you should know.
There's nothing you can do after quitting your job.
Fujishima.
Because of your magic spell
I begin to become someone else.
Do you like kids with runny noses?
Is fucking girls dressed up in doll clothes
a hobby of yours?
What are you?
What are you, bastard!
Fujishima.
Kanako!
Hey, do you realize how stupid you are?
If you dare to tell others, we'll definitely kill you.
We'll publish these too!
At home, at school, and on the Internet.
Fujishima.
Kanako was laughing.
She said you came running to her with a wagging tail
just because she pet you.
Do you love her?
Say, how often have you been turned on by Kanako?
Tell me!
I was seduced.
It was
your daughter!
Sensei,
you like young girls, right?
Eh?
I understand you.
I understand you completely.
Of course, I didn't do anything with her.
But a few days later,
a man called me.
Who?
A businessman named Cho.
Is it him?
Answer me!
Yes.
Tell me everything about Kanako!
What has she done?
What has she said?
What the hell is she?
She is your daughter.
Kanako called and said
you should keep your body clean
and ready for action!
Did you get it, Alice?
This is your new name!
If you fall into such a deep hole,
you keep falling and falling.
It's a tale about such a girl.
The police called me.
Kanako's friend was killed.
They asked me questions.
But I don't know anything.
What is going on?
Say! Where is Kanako?
Kanako is...
your daughter.
I understand you.
I understand you completely.
Just like him.
He...
You...
I...?
...did it with me.
You want to do it as well.
Right, Sensei?
Bullshit!
I'm not lying.
That's what she said.
Your daughter said
you
abused her.
Stop kidding me!
Bitch! I'll kill you!
What is it?
I...
What's wrong?
Something must have happened!
I...
What do you want?
Papa.
You bitch!
Do you want me to kill you?
She was almost killed by her beloved father.
That's not true!
Why?
You love me, don't you?
She is my daughter!
So what?
Because you love me?
I...
Is that why you hit me?
I understand you, Papa.  Completely.
I love you.
Bitch!
You bitch!
Die! Die!
Is she still alive?
Kanako...
Where is she? Tell me!
Where is she now?
Shut up, bitch!
Shut up! Disappear!
Let me alone.
Go die!
Kanako is scary.
She lures people by telling them what they want to hear.
I love you.
And then she ruins them.
What are you laughing, you bitch!
Fujishima.
Because of your magic spell
I am
no longer the person I was.
Where is Kanako?
Where are you?
Do you really know where you are?
Shitty yakuza.
Does it hurt?
This is the punishment for what your daughter has caused.
What has she done?
There once was a man named Cho.
Your daughter was his darling, but
she took the liberty of taking strictly private photos
and sold them all to dirty old geezers.
This is not a joke, Papa.
Your daughter allows herself too much.
See you!
Good night.
I keep falling down this deep hole.
Even so,
I'm not afraid.
Because I feel close to you,
Fujishima.
You bastards are all scum.
We are scum, but we follow the rules.
Rules that provide happiness for everyone.
Rules?
Your daughter broke them.
That's why
I'll kill her.
The culprit is Matsunaga.
That kid plotted everything.
Kanako was used by him.
It doesn't seem so.
I took good care of him.
But he fell in love with your daughter and betrayed me.
Idiot!
That's Fujishima Kanako's father.
Say hello to him.
Matsunaga ...
You're finished.
You should better say
this is the beginning.
Where?
Where do you want to be cut?
How about here?
Fujishima,
where is she?
You are crazy.
She's at a hotel.
The hotel at the North exit, Hotel Eden.
You did that to Ogata too, right?
Ogata, who died, experienced the same as me.
We killed Ogata.
Because he was so small and cute,
we brought him to old men countless times.
That's why he committed suicide.
Kanako became close to us to avenge his death.
I knew it all the time.
Fujishima loved Ogata, right?
You can't really understand Kanako's feelings.
Kanako...
I love you.
She is so gentle
but somehow soulless.
And then she ruins them.
If I can be with her,
I would do anything.
Even if you would get killed?
I wouldn't care.
She is so crazy and so soulless.
She ruins everyone's life.
So why...
Why does everyone become obsessed with her?
Kanako is...
She is ...
a demon.
Papa.
Guess how many times I've done it with her.
Don't get carried away by him, Papa!
This kid just wants to die already.
He wants to get killed and have his peace.
You're going to go see Kanako?
Yeah.
Do you love her?
You will get killed.
Then,
I should leave a mark.
This is the proof that I've lived.
Please. I'll give you the photos and anything.
So let Kanako...
I will do anything.
You love your daughter so much, even if she's a lunatic?
What a joke! That little bitch!
Then, why?
I have no clue.
I must, one more time, with those hands of mine...
Embrace her?
Beat her!
That bitch, how dare she look down on me!
I'm going to beat her
with these hands of mine!
That little bitch,
I'll beat her up!
I love you.
This is Cho's dog.
Can you kill him?
He's a police officer but became one of Cho's men.
A cop?
Yeah, and a tricky one.
He kills everyone who threatens Cho.
He has killed too often.
In the convenience store, the Internet cafe,
perhaps even your daughter.
He's crazy.
A psycho!
But Cho gives that crazy dog so much money
that his wife and kid live a comfortable life.
She's a great woman, eh?
He has everything
that you have lost.
Do you envy him,
Papa?
Such a thing...
Do you dream?
You have no dreams?
Dreams?
I have.
Of course I have dreams.
What kind of dreams?
I have a beautiful wife and daughter.
Both of them
love me.
This happiness,
with my own hands
I destroy it.
That kind of dream.
Let go of me!
Bitch!
Die.
Die!
Bitch!
Lord, please forgive us our sins
as we forgive others.
Deliver us from temptation
and give us salvation...
(Papa)
It's destroyed, your precious thing!
You bastard are scum!
Where is Kanako?
Did you kill her?
I haven't killed her yet.
And you won't.
If you kill her, I'll kill your family as well.
Don't touch them.
Okay, I'll give your daughter back.
It's an exchange.
How dare you command me!
You shitty killer!
Killer?
Taking a trip with your family?
How nice.
Where are you going?
Don't play dumb.
You policemen are connected with the yakuza, aren't you?
What?
That again!
What rules! You piece of shit!
That guy...
He told you about me, right?
Can you forgive it?
Can you forgive me?
I...
Be grateful, old man!
You are crazy.
You even killed your own master.
He commanded me to stop killing.
He wouldn't shut up so I silenced him!
Papa!
I'll kill as I please from now on.
I'll make my own rules.
Where's Kanako?
You'll meet her in hell.
Bastard!
Papa!
Why don't you shoot that kid as well?
I bet you can't wait to kill him!
Whether it's me or your son,
as long as you can kill anyone, you don't care!
You pervert!
Shut up!
The garbage is you, Bastard!
I'm going to kill you.
You and your daughter.
Is Kanako still alive?
I'm going to kill her!
She is
still alive.
Papa!
Drop the gun!
Arrest him!
It was suicide.
That old man!
She's alive,
that girl.
Perhaps the hole was too deep.
Alice kept falling slowly.
(Alice in Wonderland)
She looked around while she sank down.
Lots of time for her to think what would happen next.
Suddenly she hit the ground.
The fall had finally ended.
Only with a small scratch, Alice stood up.
She looked up at the dark ceiling
and saw a rabbit running, late for his time.
She wondered how she could get out of here.
Each of the castle doors were locked.
(Eden Hotel, Room 818)
Alice was irritated.
How in the world
should she escape from this place?
I've been waiting.
I knew you would come.
Did you trick me?
Are you crying?
Shut up!
It's pretty obvious.
Answer me!
Why did you do this to me?
Because you
were always watching me.
Fujishima.
It made me happy.
Very happy.
Fujishima Kanako.
But I'm sorry.
That's not me.
That's not me, it's another girl.
But...
I've been in here all the time.
In here...
Alone...
I've been dreaming the whole time.
What kind of joke is this?
I don't understand what you mean!
What dream?
Was it to come close to me, deceive me,
throw me into this chaos?
That's right, chaos.
There are no rules because it's a dream.
Anything goes.
You can love anyone
and you can do anything to the one you love.
Kiss them.
Kill them.
What do you want to do,
Papa?
Occasionally, some disoriented people appear in my dreams
But they run away at once.
Because freedom is scary.
Fujishima.
Look at this.
Isn't it hilarious!
Fujishima Kanako.
The one and only beautiful creature on Earth.
I'm going to kill you.
What are you laughing about?
Is it me?
Am I that funny?
Then, I'll beat you up now!
I will beat you up
and then laugh myself!
You bitch.
I love you.
Are you scared?
I'm scared.
Very much.
It's okay
Did you love him?
Did you love Ogata?
Yes, very much.
That's why I killed him.
I wanted to love him more and more.
Fujishima...
Fujishima Kanako...
I love you.
Who...
are you?
(Akiko, I'm picking up the cake.)
(I'll be back soon so wait for me! -Mom)
Sensei, do you remember me?
I am Fujishima Kanako's father.
What do you want?
I've been searching for my daughter since then.
I've found out a little about her.
Why do you do this?
My daughter was scum.
It proves that she's definitely my daughter.
She got involved with gangs and drugs.
When she entered high school, she began selling drugs
and forced students to sell their bodies.
I didn't know anything of this.
You did know it.
Fujishima-san!
Sensei!
The customers were rich, perverted businessmen.
Kanako even used schoolmates who were a lot younger than herself.
Is Aki-chan doing well?
Yes.
To be true, I just wanted to talk about her.
Yes?
She suddenly had her own cellphone.
I asked her and she told me you gave it to her.
Is that true?
Sorry that I did not inform you.
It's true.
She helped me a little so I gave her a reward.
Look closely at it.
I've looked at this crap a hundred times
and finally I understood.
What is this?
The girl on this photo is your daughter.
I'm not forcing her into prostitution.
I just suggested to try it and Aki-chan...
What are you saying!
I don't understand.
Why did you do this to her?
Because she's so cute, of course.
I will never forgive this.
Whom?
Kanako?
Or your daughter?
Don't joke with me!
It was your daughter who incited her!
This is what Aki-chan decided on her own free will.
She doesn't know any better.
She doesn't understand...what you incited her to do.
I wonder about that.
How old do you think she is!
Akiko is still...
But that's what's popular among older men!
She's a demon, that girl.
A demon?
So what did you do to that demon?
Tell me.
What did you do to her?
Give her back.
Give her back?
Give me back the purity of that girl!
Her purity?
But look, Sensei, Aki-chan...
Don't say a word!
What do you know about her?
Then, do you understand her?
Do you look closely at her?
Watch her, touch her...
Do you know the sensible spots on her body?
Where she wants to be touched?
What are you saying?
Aki-chan told me,
"Mama doesn't understand me at all."
"She knows nothing... about my feelings."
She said she felt lonely.
Where is she?
Where did you put my daughter?
Is this how you killed her?
That's right.
Why?
You don't know?
Because I love her.
Akiko, my daughter.
I guess you can't understand
these kind of human emotions.
You...love her?
There's no way you would know!
Because here
and here
you're completely empty.
You love her.
Enough of that.
Sensei.
That was very funny.
You bitch.
Find her already.
You buried her, so dig her up.
That's impossible.
I don't care how many years it'll take.
As long as you don't find Kanako,
you won't see your own daughter.
You are crazy.
You, and your daughter as well.
Of course.
We have the same blood.
Hurry up and find her!
Take me back.
Let me see my daughter.
No way.
Then kill me!
That would be too easy.
As long as you don't find Kanako,
this hell will continue.
I...
don't know anything about her.
Nothing at all.
I only remember
when I attempted to strangle her
what a feeling I had in these hands.
It's birthday.
Today is her birthday.
She's 18 now.
Find her quickly.
Where is she?
I don't know!
But she's a dead body now.
She is still alive.
As long as I live,
she's alive too.
She...
is me.
I will
with my own hands
personally
and mercilessly
kill her!