Whoa.
This is big. I know this is big.
I... I... I mean, I know Iraq was big,
but this... This might actually be it.
Sophie, please.
This...
This can't be.
Go get Alberts.
Get Alberts, quick.
This is it, isn't it?
This is it.
Man, you are out of it today.
You know she just looked at you.
She was lookin' at you.
She's got good taste.
Look, man,
you should go in with a different approach.
Something unique.
Yeah, well, I'm sure I should,
but we can't all be you, can we?
Yeah, I'm pretty awesome.
All right, this is what you do.
Guys talk too much, right? Go up to her
all mysterious,
just stare.
Chicks dig that.
- You ever heard the term "creeper"?
- Yes. Yes, I have.
- Professor Martin! Hey.
- Jennifer.
- How are you?
- I'm good, how you doing?
Aww, man.
Your dad gets to spend an
hour with her every week.
That's not fair.
Yeah, you were great.
Do you think you wouldn't mind
helping me study for another one?
And she pays him.
God, I would tutor her for free.
I would tutor her all day.
You should be proud... oh.
Oh, she's... She's a hugger.
- She's a good hugger.
- Good to see ya.
He just melted into that. He just...
Good morning, Professor Martin.
- Good morning.
- How's Jennifer today?
I'm sure she's fine.
Mm-hmm. I'm sure she is.
How you doin', bud?
What'd you like?
Uh, nothing for me. I just...
Hey, Joel, um...
Jennifer needed some more cream.
Can you, uh, run this out to her
- for me, please?
- Totally.
Thank you. I appreciate that.
Thanks.
You know you... You should ask her out.
She's a nice girl.
- Just like that, huh?
- Yeah, just like that.
From the man forced to
use online dating sites
is giving me advice? Hmm.
Hey, Roger.
Yeah, well, hold off using
your phone for a while, okay?
Nah, I don't need any coffee.
It's free, you can afford it.
You know, under Sumerian law,
a son who disrespects his father
would have his tongue torn out.
Well, I'll remember that the
next time we're in Sumeria.
Sumer. The next time we're in Sumer.
Whatever.
Oh, come on, Colin.
Seriously another Setag book?
Shouldn't you be studying calculus?
He was building holograms
in his garage at 15.
He was a millionaire by 22.
I think he's worth studying.
Yeah, according to you.
I should get going.
Mortgage isn't gonna pay for itself.
A rare phenomenon known as ball lightning
on a scale never seen...
...has caused severe fires
throughout the Chinese fields.
We are now receiving reports...
- Wow.
- Holy...
- Hey, Colin, come back!
- Jennifer!
Hey, you all right?
Just stay with me.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
- Run.
- You're okay. You're okay.
What is it this time?
Colin!
Joel!
...the meteor on Wednesday
is only the latest...
No, Colin, he's...
he's pretty shaken, but he's okay.
No, no, the town's basically shut down.
Talk to, uh, Aunt Jackie?
No, I...
I can't get a hold of anyone. I... I...
Yes, of course.
I know, I know. I'll keep trying, okay?
All right, stay safe.
We have received eyewitness reports
- describing the size...
- Hey.
Hey, buddy.
You, uh... Look, you hungry?
I can... I can make you some pasta.
I'm fine.
Hey, I should take a look at that.
Meteor-like activities
that have been seen in various
areas in North America...
Look, Colin, I don't...
I said I'm fine.
Colin, I...
Hello?
Can I help you?
Uh, is Professor Martin home?
- And you are?
- Kathryn Keen, Polydynamics.
Really? Today?
You don't think there's a
better time you can come back?
Actually, no.
It's quite urgent that I speak with him.
Wow. All right. Dad!
Look, my dad's a nice guy.
He's a bit awkward at
first, but he's smart.
Probably too smart for his own good.
Just give him a chance
to open up and relax.
- Once you get to know him...
- I'm sorry, I don't... I don't follow.
Well, to be honest,
he hasn't had a lot of luck lately.
Dad,
a woman from the dating service is here!
Excuse me?!
- Uh, hello?
- Professor Martin, I'm Kathryn Keen.
I represent Polydynamics,
which is not a dating service.
Uh, can I have a moment of your time,
please?
Uh... Let me call you back.
Polydynamics is a research company.
We look for solutions for global issues:
water shortages, poverty, climate change.
Okay.
A few days ago, one of our field teams
found something... unique.
What is this?
I was hoping you'd tell me.
It's a zodiac. Where'd you find this, Iraq?
A lead mine in Peru.
No, that's... That's not possible.
This style of writing was never
used outside of the Middle East.
But, look, don't take my word for it.
The world's preeminent authority is...
- Dr. Robert Bowles.
- That's right.
Dr. Bowles died two days ago.
The meteor showers caused
a cave in at the dig site.
I didn't know.
- Well, then there's Paul...
- Alberts?
Yes,
they were both killed in the meteor shower,
but this now leaves you as
our authority on this matter.
Come with me to the site.
I need your expertise.
What... what, now?
It shouldn't take more than a week.
We'll pay you, of course for your time.
- Say... say $50,000?
- It's not about the money.
Uh, yes, it is.
Look, I haven't done field work in years.
But you said it yourself,
I mean, it's extraordinary.
This is... This is the find of a lifetime.
- No.
- We want double.
What? The mortgage isn't gonna pay itself.
Done. Done.
Well, when do we leave?
You look like a seven-year-old
on a field trip.
It feels good to be back in the field.
Thanks.
So they finished clearing out the tunnels.
Just watch your step inside.
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
- Stay here.
- No, don't even think about it. I'm...
- Colin, I'll be right back.
- Just, please, okay?
- You can't be serious.
- Colin.
- Dad, come on.
Be right back.
So much for stickin' together.
Thanks for the eight-hour flight, though.
At least I got to watch
the news in Spanish.
- You need a minute with him?
- No, not right now.
After you.
- You say this is a lead mine?
- Why?
They didn't mine much
of the lead out of it.
It's right through here.
Careful.
This is incredible.
It's a heliocentric zodiac.
Wait, wait, what?
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight planets.
The sun in the center.
This is... This is incredibly detailed.
I've never...
I've never seen an ancient civilization
with such an accurate
idea of the solar system.
Are those traditional zodiac symbols?
Those are astronomical glyphs.
- What does it mean?
- I have no idea.
I thought you were the expert.
Are you kidding? On what?
This is unprecedented. This is...
pre-Babylonian, pre-Sumerian. This is...
It's like asking a
zoologist about a unicorn.
Screw this.
Cancer.
Sagittarius.
Huh.
What?
Some of the zodiac signs are upside down.
Wait.
There's eight rings,
eight planets.
So what is this ring?
It goes around and comes back here.
Why?
Why the hole in the center of the sun?
Unless...
ninth planet.
- Excuse me?
- Nibiru.
Planet X. I'm sure you've heard of it.
What, not up on your doomsday prophesies?
Guess not.
Dad!
See, Bowles, he...
He loved legends.
Especially ones based on historical facts.
He chased lots, but there was one...
one that he was absolutely obsessed with.
He searched his entire life.
Maybe he was cl...
Maybe he was close after all.
You think the stone is hidden here?
How do you know about the stone?
What's happening?
Stay back.
Dad?
Kathryn!
Interesting.
It's not just some kind of puzzle, it's...
- It's a machine.
- What did you do?
I don't know. I didn't do anything.
Kathryn.
Here.
Should we be doing that?
Ancient civilizations built
all kinds of elaborate puzzles.
Even complex devices.
In Greece,
they found an analog computer device
that's over 2,000 years old.
Look.
I just found your unicorn.
Uh...
Hello? Dad!
Don't touch it.
What is that?
Why do you have that?
Dad!
Colin. Colin!
Colin!
You okay? Dad!
- Colin!
- Are you okay?
Colin!
You okay?
What's... what's going on?
- There's someone in here!
- What?!
There's someone buried in here.
Give me a hand.
There, got it.
Oh, my God. It's Sophie.
Is she alive?
Kathryn, call for a helivac now! Go!
Here, help me.
That's all right.
- Careful, grab her hip.
- Watch your head.
We gotta get her outta here!
Come on, we gotta go!
Colin, we gotta get her outta here!
Get the other side.
Come on.
Yeah, come on!
This way!
This is Keen,
we need immediate air lift evac onsite!
I repeat,
immediate evac at the mine entrance.
Chopper inbound. ETA in six minutes.
Come on, Colin!
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
- Almost there.
- Okay.
- Yeah, come on!
- You got her?
We gotta go!
Come on!
Get in the car. Just get in the car!
- Where is it?
- Come on! No! Keep going!
- Go, go, go!
- Is she breathing?
Hold on! Hold on!
Oh! Come on!
It's getting closer!
Hang on everybody! Hang on!
Why are we still here?
- Dad?
- Huh?
Oh, they just need to ask their
questions then we're free to go.
If we want to.
We do want to, right?
Honestly, I'm getting tired of this
whole extreme archaeology thing.
What does this even mean?
I'm not 100% sure yet. Have you seen...
What does this look like? Huh?
I don't know. A hair pin?
No, have you seen...
have you seen this shape recently?
Look closer, Colin.
I don't know.
Back home... Back home, the meteors.
I think they... I think this is Leo.
Leo as in what?
- The zodiac sign Leo?
- Exactly.
Here. Then there's this.
Look at this.
The twin peaks rushing at us, right?
- Tidal wave.
- Dad.
Colin, what if... what if the zodiac
isn't birth signs, or astrology.
What if it's a prediction?
That would make, what?
Wait a second.
Aries.
Okay, you need to take a step
back and just listen to yourself
because honestly I...
Kathryn, you gotta see this.
Professor Martin, I'm Agent Tyler.
We're ready for you.
Terrific. I need to speak to Kathryn Keen.
Dad, you're gonna want to
get your facts straight
- before you go public.
- Come on.
Please.
You sure you're up for this, Soph?
Yeah. I'm fine.
It helps being here.
Miss Keen? Professor Martin...
Kathryn, the carvings in the cave
I think I found something.
You did.
And your country is grateful.
Uh...
You're welcome.
- Woodward, D.O.D.
- Neil Martin.
You don't look any worse for wear.
If it wasn't for you,
I'd be under water so...
thank you.
The zodiac.
I think it's some kind of warning.
- Zodiac?
- What if the disasters
that we've seen across the globe
are tied to the zodiac symbols we found?
Look at this.
Ball lightning in China.
Capricorn.
See the similarities?
And then we saw... We saw Leo firsthand.
Meteors wreaking havoc across
the Northern Hemisphere.
Then we have Scorpio.
Scorpio, tsunamis across South America.
That's three signs, there are nine left.
I think it's some kind of, uh...
like a countdown.
And, if I'm right, Aries is next.
We need to figure out what this is.
- Looks kinda like a fountain.
- Possibly.
Yeah, look,
I think it's some kind of energy.
Like forcing upwards. Possibly a...
Professor, what does any of
this have to do with the stone?
The stone?
Dad, I think we should go.
Thank you, Professor.
Can we start the test?
- Two minutes.
- Dad...
Wait, wait.
Now that you have the stone, that's it?
Years of research by Bowles led to this.
This...
this could be a revolutionary power source.
- All of our global energy issues...
- Energy? This isn't about energy.
Yes, it is, and we're grateful
for your help, Professor,
but we'll take it from here.
No. Kathryn, you're...
What is this?
Images from the space
agencies heliospheric feed.
Apparently our solar
system has a new member.
How long have you known about this?
Just discovered.
We think a combination of
the extremely long orbit
and... and the path that it
tracked behind the sun...
Wait a sec... That's the cave.
One elongated path crossing the
orbit of the other eight planets.
Like somehow they knew.
Nibiru, the stone, the ninth planet.
- Nibiru?
- Look, it's all connected.
Professor,
that's a really interesting theory.
Look, if this is real,
the legend of Nibiru is
about the end of the world.
Okay, Professor. Thank you.
Agent Tyler will make sure
- you and your son get home safe.
- Kathryn, wait a...
Miss Keen, can we please start the test?
- Let's go, Professor.
- Kathryn!
Final positions.
Remember when you taught me
to always lead with the facts?
I was leading with the facts.
I'm not some crazy person
ranting about the End of Days.
The zodiac is a roadmap
to coming destruction?
Exactly.
Dad, if it sounds crazy, it usually is.
Get in the car.
What if he's right?
- Not now, Sophie.
- I'm just saying.
I see the similarities.
Bowles trusted him, and from what I saw...
Bowles knew to temper his theories
until he had concrete evidence.
We believe the stone was encased in lead
to shield it from specific rays of light
that would trigger a powerful reaction.
Our test will blast the stone
with the whole spectrum of rays
from radio to gamma so we can isolate
the frequency that triggers it.
Go ahead.
Fire up the D.E.W.s.
Directed-energy weapons activating.
Nothing.
Moving to infrared.
Infrared activating.
Moving to ultraviolet.
Ultraviolet activating.
Moving to gamma.
Gamma activating.
Still nothing.
Copy that.
Yes, you think I'm crazy.
I get it. I understand.
Indulge me, all right?
Look, we need to figure out what Aries is.
Enough. Shut it down.
I just need about an hour
to run some diagnostics.
- Don't bother.
- Shutdown commencing.
Yeah, it's me.
Tell the senator I'm available after all.
- Wait.
- Miss Keen,
I wanted this to work
just as much as you did.
- Energy level rising.
- What's that? What's happening?
- The stone's reacting.
What did you do?
Nothing, we're shut down.
Sophie.
That's not us.
What is that?
Ugh!
Wha...
- He's out cold.
- What was that?
Proof.
Field team, report!
The scopes are dead, I can't see anything!
Field!
Someone tell me what's going on out there!
- What happened?
- I don't know yet.
You've never even gotten a speeding ticket
and now you're stealing trucks
from the Department of Defense.
- Borrowing.
- It's government property.
- I pay my taxes.
- I don't think it works like that.
Please,
please tell me this is not about the rock.
Okay, I won't tell you.
- You're scaring me.
- Colin! Look...
you've seen everything I have seen.
There's nine signs left, nine disasters.
And based on what I've seen,
I don't see how we survive any of it.
And the stone is somehow involved.
I need to get it before Woodward does.
He doesn't trust the end-of-the-world guy.
Shocking.
Colin, just... Just stay right there.
Dad, we can't be here.
You saw what that thing did. We...
Oh, my God.
This is so stupid.
Woodward.
Frakkin' Tyler.
This is Agent Tyler.
I'm on my way to the test site now.
Dad, we gotta get out of here.
- Copy that.
- Dad, we gotta go.
We have to go.
All right. Go! Go!
Come on!
Now you're scaring me.
My flight response kicked in.
I can't control it.
Slow down and tell your flight response
to stay off the main roads. Okay?
Keep an eye out for Aries.
Oh, and being chased by
government agents isn't enough.
I want checkpoints. I want phone taps.
I want the works. Yeah.
- The hell happened here?
- The stone happened here.
Which the professor still has.
Which I want back.
This time let's, uh,
try not to lose any vehicles.
- This is unbelievable.
- Yes, sir.
How could the stone do this?
I don't know.
Absolutely.
This facility and everything in it
is now property of the Defense Department.
What?! Why?
National security.
You can't do that!
That power cannot be in civilian hands.
Not Polydynamics, not Professor Martin,
not you, nobody.
Do you understand that?
Yeah, I'm here.
Yes, they've been informed.
- We need to find Neil.
- We've secured the site.
Absolutely. I'm on my way there now.
So, where we going?
We need to get back to that cave.
You can't seriously want to go back there.
- It was wiped out by a tsunami.
- No, you don't know that for sure.
Well,
you don't know the world's ending for sure.
Look, Colin,
I don't have all the answers yet.
But I know what we've seen is only
the beginning of what's to come.
The drawings in that cave,
the mechanism that's there,
this stone... It's all part of a puzzle.
We solve that and maybe we can stop this.
Drive careful, all right?
We've got a 100-mile perimeter in place.
Good. I wanna know as soon as he's spotted.
One more thing.
Kathryn and Sophie are missing.
Well, we can't drive to Peru,
and if we go to the
airport we'll be arrested.
- What the hell are you doing?!
- Where's the stone?
- You lied to me.
- I risked my career coming here!
- Dad!
- Aries.
Kathryn, grab the bag!
Let's get outta here! Come on!
- Go! Let's go!
- Go!
What is it?
Look out!
Dad!
It's everywhere!
Watch it!
Ah!
I think it's over.
You were right.
You described it almost perfectly.
Yeah, well, I wish I was wrong. Come on.
Yes, sir. We'll all be praying.
Yes, sir.
Woodward.
Hang on. What do you got?
Found remnants of the truck
off-road about 15 miles out.
- No bodies.
- Text me that. The stone?
Negative.
We did pick up a signal
from Kathryn's cell.
It's faint, but we're triangulating it now.
Okay.
Woodward.
- What?
- Sir.
Those geysers or whatever you wanna call
'em,
they did look a bit like the Aries sign.
Hang on.
Yeah,
and atomic explosions look like mushrooms,
but I don't put 'em on my pizza.
I don't wanna hear about...
that zodiac theory from that nut job.
Yes, sir.
Hang on.
Volcanic eruptions happened
as far away as Moscow,
Paris is completely obliterated.
The president has declared marshal law
and moved the entire cabinet
into emergency shelters,
and what do I have?
Oh, a nutty professor runnin'
around with a suitcase nuke.
You find that professor,
you find that stone, you secure it,
you do your job, and you do it now!
Yes, sir.
Idiot!
No, not you. I don't have that information.
Let me ask you something.
You actually buy into all this stuff?
Some guy from Sumeria
foreseeing the future?
Sumer, not Sumeria.
Seriously? You're worse than him.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I'm just worried.
My, uh, folks are
traveling overseas.
- First time in Europe.
- Ah.
My mom was nervous.
I told her she'd be safe.
Now I can't get ahold of her.
The phones are probably down.
How about your family?
My parents died a long time ago.
Colin's mom, she...
She left when he was five.
Other than the occasional
birthday and Christmas call,
- we don't hear from her.
- I don't mean to pry.
No, it's okay.
I'm the lucky one, I got Colin.
Colin... that's why you haven't
been in the field for 15 years.
It's tough to trail after Bowles
when your kid's in kindergarten.
I have no regrets.
Yeah, well, you're in the field now.
That I am.
Okay.
All right, look.
This is next, okay?
Okay, everyone?
- This is Libra.
- Another tidal wave?
No, that's a different zodiac sign.
It'll be a completely different event.
Each... each sign is associated
with an element, okay?
Scorpio is a water sign, tsunamis.
Aries is a fire sign.
That sure seems to make sense, right?
Right, Leo is also a fire sign...
Exploding meteors.
- Libra's air.
- Exactly.
Okay, so air...
a tornado?
No, the line is parallel to the ground.
- Heavy winds?
- Then what's that arch on top?
- A cloud?
- Meh.
Well, I don't know,
I'm lookin' at two lines in the dirt.
Look, there's a way to figure this out,
right?
The cuneiform in the cave
called the stone the shield.
Now I believe it has the
power to shield us.
Oh, wait.
- I've seen this before.
- What?
In Iraq. Yeah, we found these tablets
with paintings of ancient
schematics on them.
- Sophie.
- Here.
That was all over them.
This is what led us to Peru.
Looks like some kind of machine.
Wait, this is it.
This links the stone, Nibiru,
and the zodiac disasters all together.
This...
this is what we've been missing.
Wait.
There are only half the tablets here,
at best.
Where are the rest?
Where would Bowles have kept them?
Okay...
anything of value that
we acquired with Bowles
would have been auctioned
off to fund other digs.
Auction, okay. Auctioned to whom?
There's a database listing,
if I can get online.
Great, we need to find a computer.
Let's go.
And a car.
You guys hear that?
- It's a car.
- Ooh.
Hey, come on! Hey!
- Stop!
- Hey!
Look!
- Okay.
- You certainly made my job easier.
The stone. Now.
Look, just take it easy, all right?
We're on the same team.
- We just need to get online.
- We found the missing piece.
Tyler, with your help, look,
we can stop this, all right?
Come on, Tyler Stand down.
- Stand down!
- Tyler, just... God...
- Give me the stone.
- Tyler, this is insane.
Here.
Look, you can have it,
but take us with you, all right?
I need to speak to Woodward.
You want a ride? Try my truck you stole.
- Let's go.
- Yes, sir.
- He can't just leave us.
- Just...
Get me Woodward.
I've got Agent Tyler for you, sir.
Put him through.
Mission accomplished.
Tyler, do you have the stone?
Affirmative, sir.
Holding the canister as we speak.
The canister? Ty... Tyler, Tyler,
say again, you have the canister?
Tyler? Tyler, you looked inside right?
Tyler, tell me you looked inside.
Aah!
Tyler! Where'd he go?
Tyler!
Tyler, say again. Tyler!
That was the stone.
Tyler.
What happened?
Swing around.
Take me to his last coordinates.
Go!
Oh, my God.
What happened?
They must have taken it
out of the canister.
Colin, no. Don't...
Don't touch it.
Okay, we need to find that canister.
Everyone...
look for it.
It discharged.
Just like it did at the test field.
The stone and Nibiru react to each other.
The closer Nibiru gets,
the harsher these disasters.
We need to find that canister.
I got it!
Here.
Careful.
Okay, come on.
Let's go!
Let's keep moving.
We're almost there, sir.
What made the stone react?
I thought your experiment
did it the last time.
We were powered down, the test was over.
The stone erupted out of nowhere.
Like I said before,
they must have opened up the canister.
The lead seals it.
It would've kept them safe.
That's why they buried it in a lead mine.
What is that?
Run! Run! Come on! Run!
What the hell?
Holy, sweet mother.
Um, let's not... Go, go, go!
Holy...
What in the hell is that?!
Hey!
- Look, come on!
- Come here!
Get in, get in, get in, get in!
My name's Marty.
Come on in, stay a while.
Thank you. Thank you.
What's the fun in havin'
a bunker if you can't share?
Ah.
Okay.
Come on.
Ah, thanks. Do be careful of the first step
it can be precarious.
And the third. Uh-huh.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm. Anytime.
Welcome to my pride and joy.
- What is this place?
- Abandoned munitions storage.
Until I invoked the native rule.
- And what's that?
- Any government land not used
in 20 years automatically reverts back
to the original holder of the deed,
in this case... me.
Okay.
This is the last line of defense, man.
Independent power grid, recycled water,
two years' food supply,
and a whole lot of beer.
Some people call it a hideout.
I call it Suzanne.
Pretty sweet, huh?
- First sign of a banjo, I'm outta here.
- I'm right behind ya.
Um, why did you build it?
You kidding me, right?
Hey, we got lucky with Y2K and 9/11.
But World War III
and the antichrist...
These things are happening, man.
And the only thing about it...
- Marty?
- Huh?
The antichrist?
No, kid.
That's old news. Don't
get mixed up in that.
Mayans.
That's the thing. 2012.
- It's 2014.
- Any day now.
So, Marty, how long you been down here?
Boom.
That's the proof.
And who's ready for it?
Marty friggin' Fitzgerald, that's who.
Me, that's me.
Now I don't know if we'll ever
actually land on the moon,
or if we'll ever expose
reptiles in the royal family,
but what I do know is that
the Anunnaki are coming, man.
- dNibiru.
- What?
d Nibiru.
How do you know about Nibiru?
Oh, it's on the wire, man.
Ninth planet.
Does this work?
Oh, yeah, it works.
Everything works. Solar powered.
Internet via satellite. There's no wires,
- there's none of that bull...
- So you're actually online?
Is Picasso a Freemason?
- May I?
- Yes, please.
Wait a minute.
- Are all these recent?
- Yeah, those are, yeah.
This was Southeast Asia two weeks ago.
That is Eastern Europe six days later.
That's four days after that and
this was the day before yesterday.
Oh, my God.
I thought Capricorn was
first. Then after Libra
there was seven signs left,
but this has been...
- this has been happening for weeks.
- Oh, yeah.
The news has just been writing
it off as natural events.
I'm so lost.
When Nibiru appeared, the disasters began.
That's why half the signs in the cave
were already turned when we got there.
Scorpio turned right in front of our eyes.
Just as the disasters were beginning.
Marty...
you're a genius.
I been sayin' that for years.
Back to the Dark Ages.
Planet's been ripped apart piece by piece.
Last nail in the coffin is that stone.
I gotta get it back.
Let's go.
There's Taurus, Aquarius, Pisces, Virgo,
Gemini, Capricorn, Leo,
Scorpio and Aries, the lava shoots.
And thanks to Marty, we
just survived Libra.
That's 10 in total.
There aren't seven signs left,
there are only two.
Cancer and Sagittarius.
Right, so that's the entire zodiac.
- Then what?
- The apocalypse.
Here.
We need to figure out what these two mean.
Well, you heard the man,
let's put our heads
together and get Cancer.
You really have a way with words there,
Marty.
You, too.
No. Dueling cyclones,
which seems like the most obvious guess,
right?
Wait, but Cancer
is a water sign, so... whirlpools?
- Maybe, we should be safe on land.
- Got it.
The tablets were sold to
a business in Davenport.
It's only about 90 miles away.
Well, that's a long way to hitchhike.
You guys wanna use my car?
My cousin Chantelle tried
to get me into this huge RV,
but ever since my operation,
I can't drive a stick.
Marty...
- you're a Godsend.
- Well, before you say that,
the gas mileage is total crap.
But you got a full tank.
Take care of her.
I will.
And... thank you.
For what?
For believing.
All right.
Yeah, you get outta here.
Go, go. Get outta here.
I'll go.
Go save the world.
Kinda takin' the slow road, aren't you?
Cancer's a water sign,
I want to stay away from the water.
On higher ground.
What in the...
Look at that.
Dad?
Oh, my God!
Hold on!
Be careful, Dad. Be careful!
- Dad!
- It's okay.
Oh, my God!
Faster!
I'm trying to! Hold on, everyone!
Come on!
Go, go, go! Gotta get out of here!
- It's coming!
Go!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Go, go! Come on! Come on!
Where we going?!
Come on!
The stone!
Kathryn, no!
Grab it!
Hold on!
No!
We have base on the com for you, sir.
- Go.
- Kathryn Keen's login
was used to access the Polydynamics server.
- What did she access?
- Only one file.
A shipping receipt going from Polydynamics
to an address in Davenport.
- What was shipped?
- They were crates. Artifacts from Iraq.
Gotcha. Let's go.
Thought it was supposed to be a water sign.
- It is a water sign.
- It came out of the sky!
Yeah, after it came out of the water.
Well,
how are we supposed to predict these things
if these elements keep changing
from one thing to another?
It was a water sign.
- Just like Sagittarius is a fire sign.
- Sagittarius is an arrow.
- It could be anything.
- Dad, come on, help me.
Just stop! Both of you, just...
stop.
- We're just trying to help.
- Yeah, well, so was I...
and now Kathryn...
- You weren't wrong.
- Colin, just...
- Colin...
Kathryn's dead because of a disaster,
not because...
You don't understand.
I can't protect you, Colin.
This is it. We're here.
S.C. Engineering?
You gotta be... you gotta be kidding me.
This is one of Harry Setag's companies.
Who's Harry Setag?
His hero.
- You okay?
- Yeah, thanks.
S.C. Engineering has
one of the most advanced
biometric security systems in the world.
Nice job, son.
Hello?
- Hello?
- What was that?
- Bye.
- I don't know. It's up there.
Come on.
Hello...
scotch.
Uh, hello...
people.
You're...
you're...
- you're Harry Setag.
- Am I?
That I am.
Uh...
drink?
- I...
- His name is Colin.
My name is Neil Ryan and this is Sophie.
I heard somewhere you didn't drink.
I don't?!
But this 70-year-old single malt...
best sex you'll ever have.
I'm told.
- Cigar?
- No.
No, we're... We're fine, but thank you.
Mr. Setag,
we're looking for some Sumerian tablets
that you bought from Polydynamics.
- Show yourself to the door!
- What?
And tell that bastard
Woodward he's not getting
- one damn thing from me. Ever!
- Wait, no.
- No, no, no, look.
- That's a fact.
We don't work for Woodward.
Really?
Please, Mr. Setag.
The tablets that you bought,
they may contain information
that could save the world.
Well...
knock yourself out.
As far as saving the world goes,
you're a little late.
- What is that?
- Wait a second.
I appreciate your enthusiasm.
You know?
When I came by my first billion,
I started to wonder.
If I could do anything I want...
what is it I wanna do?
I invested in promising
avenues of discovery,
but the richest opportunities
often lie where others
have given up looking!
To the creative mind...
There are no dead ends.
You read my book.
Why...
have a cigar.
I've read all your books.
I have, too.
This machine, the scale of it.
- We can't build it.
- But we have to at least try.
Even if we had the entire Army
Corps of Engineers, we wouldn't...
It would take years, Sophie.
Uh, 18 months.
- What?
- It took us a year and a half
to make that damn machine.
What? You... you built this?
Wait, wait, wait. Wait, what?
Gave my accountant a heart attack.
You funded Polydynamics.
Eh, it doesn't make any difference.
The machine is useless without the stone.
Mr. Setag.
You actually found it.
There are no dead ends.
Aah!
To the car! Come on, get out of here.
Colin, let's go! Come on!
Open the door!
Put it back in my backpack.
Here, here! Take this one.
- Put pressure on it.
- It's okay.
Get downstairs, cover the other exits!
- Open the door!
- Is there another way out of here?
By the staircase on your way to the lodge.
- Dad, you're shot!
- On three, come on.
- Help me!
- No, no, no, no. Absolutely not.
One thing I've learned
in my career is to know
who's an asset and who's a liability.
You need to get to the machine.
Go.
Drive it to Mt. Franklin. Go!
- Go!
- Let's go, let's go!
Colin, here!
Go. Save the world!
Thanks.
Damn it!
Hello, Harry.
Woodward.
- Okay.
- Hold still.
Eyes on the road, all right?
I'm sorry,
I've never seen my dad get shot before.
So how does this machine even work?
- It's a shield.
- A shield? A shield from what?
- Sagittarius?
- Yes.
According to Setag's tablet,
it's comin' from the sun.
It's a solar eruption.
I need that stone.
I would...
no, actually, I wouldn't.
Okay!
Aah!
Hand me... that bottle.
The Bordeaux.
See, I know you don't have it.
I know that Neil has it.
What I need from you...
- Where's Neil?
- I don't... I don't know.
He left.
Went for a stroll.
Okay!
Give me that.
What is this?
- Blueprints.
- I know it's a blueprint!
What...
is it a blueprint of?
A machine built by...
a primitive civilization
that shouldn't have even had
the knowledge to make it.
You built a 10,000-year-old weapon
powered by that stone,
and you just sent Neil out
to go turn it on?
No, what you should be asking
is how did they access the materials?
How did they even know
the power of that stone?
How did they know
that it had to be built
in a lead deposit?
- How did th...
- Lead...
Huh?
...deposit.
Harry, Harry.
What lead deposit?
Do you hear that?
It's Woodward! Go!
Nice and low. Get right on 'em.
Get right on 'em!
Keep up, keep up, keep up!
Stay with 'em. Stay with 'em!
Stay with 'em!
Colin!
Plea... oh, sh...
Get right down on 'em!
Get moving.
Come on, go!
- Be careful.
- He's closing in!
Stay with 'em. Stay with 'em.
Stay with 'em.
All right, down, down, down.
Go! Just go, Colin!
- Colin!
- Go!
Where the hell'd they go?
They got nowhere to go.
Look out!
Now I gotcha.
- Colin, it's a dead end!
- There are no dead ends.
What?!
Where'd they go? Where the hell'd they go?!
Where the hell did...
They just disappeared!
Circle around!
Great Scott!
It worked.
One of Harry Setag's first inventions.
Holograms.
I think I just crapped
my third grade homework.
They went right into that mountain.
Where the hell did they go?
Take us down.
Take us down now!
Come on.
He really built it.
Okay.
Unbelievable.
This is where the stone goes.
Okay, how do we get it open?
Okay, we gotta...
Put everything in sequence.
- Watch out!
- Go fast
All right, get the machine open.
I'll get the stone.
Uh... okay, uh...
No, wait, don't. It has to be in sequence.
Sagittarius is last.
Taurus. Taurus is first.
- Uh, okay.
- Um...
Wait a second.
- Okay.
- Taurus...
- Uh...
- Aquarius.
Yeah.
Ugh!
- Uh, Pi... Pisces!
- Pisces.
Uh... uh, Virgo!
- Virgo, uh...
- Um...
- Gemini!
- Yeah.
Aah!
Capricorn.
Uh, a little help here.
- Little help.
- Okay.
Okay.
Okay, okay, let me think. Um...
Uh, I can't remember what's next.
- Scorpio.
- Yes.
Aries.
Cancer.
Good. Good.
Okay.
Sagittarius.
We did it!
Now all we need is the stone.
Here!
Okay.
Go. Go! Get out of here! Go!
Go. Go! Run! Run!
We gotta get outta here. Run!
Go, go, go! Come on!
Dad, you drive!
Oh, my God.
Aah!
Go, go, go, go!
That's good, right?
You did it.